<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description>The Scottish Roller Derby Blog: an international blog for Roller Derby based on Scotland.</description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 18:30:01 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>South Africa's National Derby Fest 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/nationalderbyfest-102019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The South African National Roller Derby Festival ("National Derby Fest") may be the smallest of the National Tournaments we covered &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/31/south-africas-national-derby-fest-2018-three-years-of-festivals/"&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt; , but it's also potentially one of the more important to its community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we covered in our article on the South African roller derby community &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/rollerderby-za-2019/"&gt;earlier this year&lt;/a&gt; , the population of South Africa is concentrated in a small number of widely-separated areas, so it's very expensive for the teams to play each other (let alone teams from other nations). As such, having this one big event at the end of the year is an achievable focus, and the community time it provides is all the valuable for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In last year's NDF, Johannesburg's &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://goldencityrollers.com"&gt;Golden City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; , and Cape Town Rollergirls competed for the final rankings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Golden City Rollers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cape Town Rollergirls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The third team present, Durban Roller Derby, participated in the first two bouts, mixed teams games with skaters from all three teams.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt='The flyer image for this National Derby Fest: crouched jammer ready to sprint at start of whistle (in black and white, with red star), against horizontally divided yellow and red background box; yellow bar at top of flyer, red at bottom. Second box (positioned "on top" of the background, but "behind" the skater) reads "National Roller Derby Festival 2019". The logos of all three leagues with full teams are aligned along the bottom of the flyer.' src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/NDF2019.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/403124207306199/"&gt;National Derby Fest&lt;/a&gt; has a change of format, designed to maximise the amount of game play each team got. As such, this is National Derby Fest is a double round robin: each team will play the others &lt;em&gt;twice&lt;/em&gt;, in half-length games (two 15 minute periods). As numbers for all teams are a little low this year, this will allow everyone to participate in as much derby as possible, whilst still playing WFTDA-rules otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth league in South Africa, Pretoria's P-Town Roller Derby, will be donating a skater to the Cape Town team, and we assume will be donating volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The winners on points will go forward to play each other in a full-length WFTDA-regulation Final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golden City Rollers told us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
NDF is the highlight of the local derby calendar, so we're super excited to host it this year, and to see all our sister leagues again. Of course, the most important thing is to play some derby and enjoy every second, as we don't often get a chance to compete in SA. Secondly, it's an opportunity to introduce new spectators to the sport, so we're hoping it will help grow roller derby in SA.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National Derby Fest 2019 will be hosted at: &lt;strong&gt;Uniao Portuguesa&lt;/strong&gt;, 4 Eastwood street, Turffontein, Johannesburg, South Africa, on &lt;strong&gt;9 November&lt;/strong&gt;, starting at 0930.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>golden city rollers</category><category>national derby fest</category><category>south african roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/nationalderbyfest-102019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 18:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 26 October 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-26102019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is another exceptionally busy weekend, so again we're moving Sunday-only events into a separate update later in the week.
Even doing that, it's a packed schedule, including: Bologna's Hyenas hosting two days of roller derby at the Ferrara Tattoo Convention, a double header of derby up in Aberdeen, Nantes and Gdańsk both hosting events to celebrate their leagues' respective anniversaries,  a whole sur5al tournament in New Zealand, and a &lt;em&gt;two-track&lt;/em&gt; international tournament in Hull! (And more - the first MRDA-sanctioned triple header in Spain, a weekend of derby in Querétaro... !)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're trying to stick to our rules below, so a lot of events - especially in Australia, which is currently at the height of its Spring events schedule - are having to be missed off the list. (We're open to considering treating very large countries in terms of their constituent States, for the purpose of allowing events, but we'd like the community to let us know how they feel about that.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've bent the rules a bit this time, because it's important to highlight derby in regions which need more attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/26Oct-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-26102019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>australian roller derby</category><category>belgian roller derby</category><category>bootcamps</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>italian roller derby</category><category>mexican roller derby</category><category>new zealand roller derby</category><category>polish roller derby</category><category>short track roller derby</category><category>south african roller derby</category><category>spanish roller derby</category><category>swiss roller derby</category><category>thai roller derby</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-26102019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 20 October 2019 (Sunday)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-20102019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the Sunday addendum for this week's highlights; and it's a busy Sunday (some two-day events are already covered in the Saturday highlights, and there are still triple headers here!). Sunday also remains a place for scrimmage, though, with many of these events being more informal affairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the above, remember that there are two open Short Track events this Sunday: the low-contact event in Halifax, and the introduction to Short Track in Worcester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've bent the rules a bit this time, because it's important to highlight derby in regions which need more attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/20Oct-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-20102019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>australian roller derby</category><category>belgian roller derby</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>mexican roller derby</category><category>national tournaments</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-20102019/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Roller Derby Nations Committee 2019 -Regional Representative Nominations open!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/RDNC-noms-171019/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most people associate the Roller Derby World Cups with the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; committee, the small organisation which has been running and organising the events since 2011 (although its membership has changed over the years).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2015, however, the National Teams competing at each World Cup have also been represented by their own organisation, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rollerderbynationscommittee.org"&gt;Roller Derby Nations Committee&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2018 Roller Derby World Cup was a product of both organisations working together, for the first time; the RDNC providing valuable direction to the planning for that event from the very start (as the teams were involved in the evaluation process for host nations, as well as voting on the structural considerations for the event). The RDNC also exists to help new National Teams to get their foothold, via the Emerging Nations process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the Roller Derby Nations Committee has representatives from all eligible Nations, it also has an executive - the Regional Representatives and Global Chair - who progress the business of the Committee, and do the work of liaising with the RDWC, and other International Roller Derby governing bodies, like the WFTDA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For much of 2019, several of those Regional Chair positions have been empty; and with many of the National Teams also having been quiescent, or in the process of reforming, it has not been possible to democratically replace them. Whilst the RDNC, in concert with the RDWC, has managed to progress work - in improving and formalising the meaning of a “National Team” to reflect modern political concerns; and in modelling and developing solutions for the next World Cup itself - it cannot work as effectively without a complete executive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, with a quorate set of National Team Representatives now in place, it is possible to start the election process for new Regional Representatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The positions up for election in this cycle (to be voted on by the Nations represented by each region) are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;North America Regional Representative&lt;/strong&gt; [representing: Canada, Mexico, Puerto Rico, Team Indigenous, USA, West Indies.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;South and Central America Regional Representative&lt;/strong&gt; [representing: Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Costa Rica.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Southern and Central Europe Regional Representative&lt;/strong&gt; [representing: Austria, Belgium, Czech Republic, France, Germany, Greece, Italy, Netherlands, Poland, Portugal, Romania, Spain, Switzerland]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Northern Europe Regional Representative&lt;/strong&gt; [representing: Denmark, England, Finland, Iceland, Ireland, Norway, Russia, Scotland, Sweden, Wales]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Currently filled are the positions of Emerging Nations Regional Representative [Jammit Janet | Janet Vincent], Pacific-Indian Ocean Regional Representative [ShortStop | Christine Murray], and the Global Chair [Booty Queen | Michelle Dosson])&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the allocations of nations between the Representatives are currently uneven, one of the first actions of the new committee will be to address this. (The imbalance is the result of a large number of Emerging Nations graduating via the 2018 World Cup, and there not having been a quorate committee to action changes to the remits of the Representatives since.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Application to the Executive is via &lt;strong&gt;nomination&lt;/strong&gt;. Anyone may nominate a candidate for any of the posts, by &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:RollerDerbyNationsCommittee@gmail.com"&gt;emailing the RDNC executive&lt;/a&gt; ( &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:RollerDerbyNationsCommittee@gmail.com"&gt;RollerDerbyNationsCommittee@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; ), stating the legal (or commonly used, non-Derby) name, the current region they reside in, and the specific post they are being nominated for. You may nominate yourself, as well as being nominated by others.
The closing date for nominations is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;end of day, &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 20th October&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On close of nomination, nominees will all be offered the chance to decline their nomination, if they didn't self-nominate. If they accept, they will have a few days to prepare a statement of intent; and they will also be invited to the RDNC Podio group to be questioned by the National Representatives.
At the end of this process, the Nations will vote, via their Representatives, on each position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full details are available on the RDNC Facebook, here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/RollerDerbyNationsCommittee/posts/2458998574382903"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/RollerDerbyNationsCommittee/posts/2458998574382903&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We strongly encourage the community to engage with this process, as it really is essential to bring you the next World Cup in good time, and with the best interests of the Nations represented.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>national teams</category><category>roller derby nations committee</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/RDNC-noms-171019/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 19 October 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-19102019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a surprisingly really exceptionally busy weekend, so we're definitely going to split this update into two bits (and even then, we'll be unable to cover all the things deserving of highlights this Saturday.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're not even mentioning the Short Track Roller Derby events this weekend to save space - they're all in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/shorttrack-102019/"&gt;this roundup post&lt;/a&gt; if you want to catch up with them (although we've marked them on the map). They're all highlights, but this is a super busy weekend, so something has to give.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 3rd fixture of the Chilean national tournament happens this weekend, as does the final of the New Zealand Top 10 Championshops 2019; as well as a number of large tournament events (perhaps the largest being in Sydney, Australia, and Lille, France). There's charity derby in Teesside, and even an international roller derby bootcamp up north in Iceland!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've bent the rules a bit this time, because it's important to highlight derby in regions which need more attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/19Oct-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-19102019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (8 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentine roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>austrian roller derby</category><category>belgian roller derby</category><category>bootcamps</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>chilean roller derby</category><category>czech roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>icelandic roller derby</category><category>korean roller derby</category><category>national tournaments</category><category>new zealand roller derby</category><category>northern irish roller derby</category><category>short track roller derby</category><category>south african roller derby</category><category>swedish roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-19102019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Short Track Update October 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/shorttrack-102019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's been a while since our last update on happenings with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://rollaskateclub.com"&gt;Rolla Skate Club's&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://rollaskateclub.com/short-track-roller-derby-resources/"&gt;Short Track Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; rules, so we thought it was overdue another post.
There are exciting things to write about, across the world, as well, so we'll break this up region by region! Because of the prevalence of Facebook (and the fact that its Events are one of the few useful things about it), all links to events will be there; but we'll include enough info for you to get to the event without needing anything owned by Mark Zuckerberg. Where possible, we link to league websites, or to their Instagram when it isn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt='Team photo of the RollaCon 2019 "All Stars" bout roster, and officials. Two rows, front row on one knee. In the background, two people are waving at the camera.' src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/RollaSkateClub_AllStarsRollercon2019.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The Rollacon 2019 "All-Stars" bout teams photo. [Photo, rights: Rolla Skate Club]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/shorttrack-102019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (9 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-in community roller derby</category><category>argentine derby</category><category>canadian roller derby</category><category>cape town rollergirls</category><category>fort mcmurray roller derby</category><category>korean roller derby</category><category>latin american roller derby</category><category>low contact roller derby</category><category>oh! roller derby</category><category>rolla skate club</category><category>rollercon</category><category>short track roller derby</category><category>south african roller derby</category><category>vendaval roller derby</category><category>worcester wyldings</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/shorttrack-102019/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Stance 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/derbystance-2019/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the past three years, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com"&gt;Rule 56&lt;/a&gt; have been helping to drive and develop coaching in Roller Derby; both in terms of coaching itself, and also resources for developing those coaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt='The Derby Stance 2019 logo: 3 brown solid circles of increasing darkness overlapping left-to-right, with blue whistle inside the last. Text "Derby Stance Online Coaching Summit Nov 22-24 2019".' src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/DerbyStanceEvent.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very visible part of this has been their &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/derby-stance"&gt;Derby Stance&lt;/a&gt; branded coaching community events; starting with a physical &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/03/uks-first-coaching-summit-derby-stance/"&gt;Coaching Summit&lt;/a&gt; back in &lt;em&gt;2016&lt;/em&gt;, and developing into a more extensive, and entirely virtual event in 2018 (2017 tested the concept with a series of individual webinars across the year). Holding the event online, with dedicated conference hosting services, was a response to the global nature of Roller Derby, and the global need for coaching resources and community; having to travel half-way across the world for a conference is not only expensive, but also wasteful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2018 Derby Stance was extremely successful, with attendees describing it with terms like "mind-blowing" and "by far the most helpful coaching training I’ve received in five years"!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Derby Stance Online Coaching Summit is returning for 2019, and Rule 56 have continued to build on and improve on what has been before. As the name suggests, this is, once more, a virtual-only event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with 2018's edition, individual "webinars" which make up the entire 3 day event, are separately bookable; you can buy tickets for just the sessions you're interested in. (If you're planning on attending a lot of the event, though, there's also whole-weekend tickets available, for a discount.).
In a change from last year, these are organised into two types: &lt;em&gt;"Seminars"&lt;/em&gt; (60 minute presentations, with time for questions) and &lt;em&gt;"Workshops"&lt;/em&gt; (90 minute interactive sessions led by the session leader; these are limited to &lt;em&gt;20&lt;/em&gt; attendees each).
(Regular attendees of EROC, the European Roller derby Organisational Conference, will recognise this division from there, where it is pretty effective at supporting different kinds of interaction.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that's not all: just like a physical conference, the 2019 Derby Stance will have fringe and break-out events, organised as ad-hoc Facebook Live mini-streams. (Rule56 has already been trialing this with a series of "5 minutes with ..." events over the past year, and they work very well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike most physical conferences, a benefit of the virtual nature is that all Seminars (but not Workshops) will be available after the fact as recordings if you miss them; and simultaneous automated real-time transcriptions will be available during each session, including translated into a range of languages, to aid inclusion and understanding. (For those who can't attend at all, "watch-later" tickets will also be available to access all the content purely post-hoc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="3x4 Checkerboard of portraits (with names) of all of the Derby Stance 2019 speakers and workshop leaders, with Rule56 logo in the middle." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/Derbystance2019.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Photo credits: Nadia Kean and Jennifer B Gaskins (by Zakas Photography); Devoida Mercy (by Louise O'Rourke Photography); Furrocious (by No limit Lien); Dr. Astrid Coxon (by Martin Quadling); Squirrel Power (by Robin Dodd / Purple Turtle Photography); Miss Tea Maven (by David Dyte); Kaio-kensi (by Owen Clayton); all other photos uncredited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any Conference or Summit lives and dies by its roster of speakers, and this year's Derby Stance has a very exciting line-up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smarty Pants (Strong Athletic)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is your Coaching actually working? (Workshop)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Squirrel Power (Monterey Bay Derby Dames)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coaching Slower Learners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rosie Peacock (New Wheeled Order, Power of Scotland)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategic Coaching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Devoida Mercy (Philly Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bridging the Perception Gap about Coaching between Adults and Juniors (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Furrrocious (Amsterdam Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to structure feedback, and adjust to different training styles (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structuring and building your training session (Workshop)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michelle Welton and Gie ‘uppercase’ Carr (Rose City Rollers)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coaching mixed-level practices in Adult and Junior programs (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kaio-kensi (Montreal Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organic Drill Design - replicating real game scenarios in drills. (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building a healthier brain safety culture (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr. Astrid Coxon (Suffolk Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coaching the 'un-coachable' (Workshop)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jennifer B Gaskins (New Jax City Rollers)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to coach when you don't have a coach (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rita Giddens (Fort Myers Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coaching for a Positive Culture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miss Tea Maven (Gotham Girls Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to design optimal training plans for your Jammers. (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Processes and Steps to designing best Practice, including footage analysis. (Workshop)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, Rule 56 will be chairing &lt;em&gt;"Round Table"&lt;/em&gt; discussion sessions throughout the event, with topics decided dynamically as the Summit progresses; and the entire event will be introduced with a &lt;strong&gt;WFTDA Keynote Presentation&lt;/strong&gt; the day before the Summit itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets for both individual sessions, and the whole event, are &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/derbystancetickets"&gt;on sale now&lt;/a&gt; . Advance sales for "watch later" tickets for Seminars are cheaper than they will be post-event; and remember that there are only 20 spots for each Workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby Stance Online Coaching Summit 2019 will run from &lt;strong&gt;22 November 2019 to 24 November 2019&lt;/strong&gt; (with the keynote on the 21st).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Derby Stance would like to thank: WFTDA, Roller Dirty Soaps and Steaks Contact Wear for committing to sponsor this event, and help develop coaching resources.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>coaching</category><category>derby stance</category><category>rule 56</category><category>webinar</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/derbystance-2019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 12 October 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-12102019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a surprisingly busy weekend - apart from the MRDA Championship in Denver, there's the first ever bootcamp in Indonesia, hosted by Hot Lava Rollers and Derby Without Borders, the next fixture of the mysterious Derby Nights 4x4 tournament in Tokyo, the continuing Tasmanian Tournament, the next Suomi Cup and German Bundesliga fixtures... and more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've bent the rules a bit this time, because it's important to highlight derby in regions which need more attention, and because it's quiet enough that we have the space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/12Oct-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-12102019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentine roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>austrian roller derby</category><category>bootcamp</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>chilean roller derby</category><category>danish roller derby</category><category>derby nights 4x4</category><category>ecuadorian roller derby</category><category>finnish roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>hungarian roller derby</category><category>indonesian roller derby</category><category>japanese roller derby</category><category>mrda</category><category>mrda championships</category><category>ota</category><category>roller derby sevens</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-12102019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mea Culpa (29Sept)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/meaculpa290919/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst we try to catch all the highlights for a weekend, sometimes some escape us. Facebook's event search tools are not good at finding events unless they're physically close to you; and they've disabled or limited most of the ways of reading lots of data from their site. Instagram doesn't provide any way to search for events at all; and not enough leagues have websites with rss feeds or calendars that we can pull from to make this reliable. (And, whilst &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; games get listed on Flat Track Stats, not all do; and not all events are bouts, or bouts which are suitable for ranking!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd like to encourage leagues, again, to &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;email us&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/scottish.rollerderby/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; message us, or &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/scottishrollerderby/"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; message us (or join our &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://discord.gg/8CJPyjq"&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; server and talk to us there) to let us know about your events; or tell us how to (automatically) track your calendars if you have them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd like to return to a few events we missed last weekend, though, just to restore the balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, in Uppsala, first fixtures of the Division 2 Swedish Nationals series for 2019/20 saw the hosts ( &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.uppsalarollerderby.se/"&gt;Jackdaw City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; ) compete in a round robin with Örebro's Nerike Knockouts and Sundsvall's Demolition Rollers, over 2 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/735468933551752/"&gt;[FACEBOOK LINK]&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/111774/overview"&gt;[FTS EVENT]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Flyer for the Seriespel Division 2, showing times and attendees." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/jackdawcityseriespel.jpg"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire event was streamed on the Sweden-based Solidsport platform, and at the time of writing, "replays" [saved copies of the stream] are available at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://solidsport.com/uppsala-roller-derby/replays"&gt;https://solidsport.com/uppsala-roller-derby/replays&lt;/a&gt; although registration is required to view them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;caption&gt;Div 2 Swedish Nationals&lt;/caption&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="25%"&gt;
&lt;col width="25%"&gt;
&lt;col width="25%"&gt;
&lt;col width="25%"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead valign="bottom"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class="head"&gt;Team1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Score1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Score2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Team2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Uppsala&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;350&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;63&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Örebro&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Örebro&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;130&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;252&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sundsvall&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Sundsvall&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;186&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Uppsala&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next Division 2 fixture is in the December, and sees Uppsala face Helsingborg's Helltown, the final member of the series; before the division completes in the new year for the final games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hosts of this event, Jackdaw City Rollers / Uppsala Roller Derby, are currently experiencing significant difficulties with their training venue, having had their practice times and halls abruptly curtailed at short notice. For more information, and to support them by signing a petition, go here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.mittskifte.org/petitions/rattvisare-fordelning-av-halltider-i-uppsala"&gt;https://www.mittskifte.org/petitions/rattvisare-fordelning-av-halltider-i-uppsala&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over in Brazil, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/capivaras.rollerderby/"&gt;Capivaras Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; (of Piracicaba) hosted a double header event with guests Gray City Rebels of São Paulo on Sunday. The Capivaras have been avoiding Facebook Events, so we missed this when it was just a flyer...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/B22p2wWpEIt/"&gt;[INSTAGRAM FLYER]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Image of some of the action from the first scrimmage." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/Graycity.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Action from Brazil (Photo: Gray City Rebels)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Capivaras told us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
This Sunday’s (09/29) Match, which happened in Piracicaba, a city in the countryside of the state of São Paulo, was a friendly mixed match between two leagues: the home team, Capivaras Roller Derby, and the Gray City Rebels, from São Paulo, the state capital. A large part of the refereeing team was also from São Paulo.
We held two mixed matches in order to provide the opportunities for all the skaters present. In the morning, we held a full-contact game with the debut of some players from the Grays and one from the Capivaras team, and in the afternoon a non-contact game with the return of some Capivara players to the track and the debut of some of the Grays' fresh meat!
More than a great opportunity to put players in the track and train their abilities in the game; the matches were also an opportunity to make new friends and strengthen the full potential of the roller derby in Brazil!&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, a significant event which deserves more coverage, although being wholly-North-American, it's outside of our self-imposed limit on highlights...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hawai'i saw their annual Battle of the Islands event last weekend. This year, the event was hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.pacificrollerderby.com/"&gt;Pacific Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; (O'ahu), with teams competing from Maui Roller Girls, Garden Isle Renegade Rollers (Kaua'i), and the "Big Island Mashup Team" (representing Echo City Knockouts and Waimea W ), as well as the hosts themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/680267739053588/"&gt;[FACEBOOK EVENT]&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/111728"&gt;[FTS ENTRY]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Maui's jammer escaping through a Pacific pack; skaters in black+green and green+black." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/PacificVMaui.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Champions, Maui, versus hosts Pacific Roller Derby [Photo: Matt Radaker]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as the main tournament, run as a 4 team round robin, the event also featured a Junior Roller derby exhibition bout by the Honolulu LeiOuts, and a closing Black v White scrimmage. The Friday before the tournament additionally saw an Officiating Clinic, for all visiting officials (referees and NSOs), run by the very well travelled Mass The Ref.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire tournament was also livestreamed on YouTube, and we link to the video in each game in the table (none of these videos are full-length, as far as we can tell).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scores were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;caption&gt;Battle of the Islands Results&lt;/caption&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="17%"&gt;
&lt;col width="17%"&gt;
&lt;col width="17%"&gt;
&lt;col width="17%"&gt;
&lt;col width="17%"&gt;
&lt;col width="17%"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead valign="bottom"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class="head"&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Team1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Score1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Score2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Team2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Video&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;0900 Sat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Maui&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;271&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GIRR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dEe3Yj74eTU"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dEe3Yj74eTU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Big Island&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;148&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pacific&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=szsRRbh4PQ8"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=szsRRbh4PQ8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1430&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pacific&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;148&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;149&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GIRR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i3V3Qv5eR8Q"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i3V3Qv5eR8Q&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1630&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Big Island&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;161&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Maui&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vNK5RiUNAfE"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vNK5RiUNAfE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;0900 Sun&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pacific&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;142&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Maui&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8IPptzux4OE"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8IPptzux4OE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Big Island&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;243&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;121&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GIRR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2BHRhk-k4ME"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2BHRhk-k4ME&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making the undefeated &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mauirollergirls.com/"&gt;Maui Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; the Battle of the Islands Champions for 2019!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope to bring you a detailed article on the state of Roller Derby in Hawai'i later in the year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>brazilian roller derby</category><category>capivaras roller derby</category><category>gray city rollers</category><category>maui roller girls</category><category>mea culpa</category><category>pacific roller derby</category><category>roller derby hawaii</category><category>sundsvall roller derby</category><category>swedish roller derby</category><category>uppsala roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/meaculpa290919/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 07:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 05 October 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-05102019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an exciting week for Scottish Roller Derby, with both Edinburgh's Auld Reekie, and Glasgow Roller Derby competing in international tournaments (ARRD in the Continental Cup in Helsinki, and GRD in the Kick Ass Cup in Hamburg). And, to add to that, this is the weekend of the annual Big Blether Scottish Roller Derby Conference, so all the leagues will be coming together there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also two-day international tournaments in Sweden, the Mexican National Division 2 Championships in Léon, Sudestada Roller Derby's debut bout in Necochea, and more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've bent the rules a bit this time, because it's important to highlight derby in regions which need more attention, and because it's quiet enough that we have the space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/05Oct-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-05102019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentine roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>big blether</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>continental cup</category><category>finnish roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>indonesian roller derby</category><category>italian roller derby</category><category>mexican roller derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>new zealand roller derby</category><category>swedish roller derby</category><category>swiss roller derby</category><category>uruguayan roller derby</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-05102019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>