<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about 2011 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup)</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/2011-blood-thunder-roller-derby-world-cup.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:54:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Italy</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/26/world-cup-interview-team-italy/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Completing our look at the teams of Southern Europe heading to the &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup&lt;/a&gt; this year, is &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamitalyrollerderby/"&gt;Team Italy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In common with all of the Southern European teams, Team Italy is new to the World Cup this time around. Unfortunately, unlike Spain and Portugal, they did not attend the European Championship earlier this month, so it is hard to get the measure of their performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Sikki Sixx and Robscene Behaviour of London Rockin Rollers for responding to these questions on behalf of Team Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamitaly.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-3876 size-large" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamitaly.jpg?w=614" alt="Team Italy logo by ..." width="614" height="614"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Team Italy logo by ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most of Team Italy is sourced from Italian leagues, but the outliers are based in relatively distant leagues. How did selection work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;When we discussed the idea of Team Italy there was relatively little experience in the country and the representative of the Italian leagues at the time asked 4 Italian skaters playing for London, Berlin and Copenhagen to be in charge of the tryouts process and the selection of the team.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;We organized two tryouts dates: one in Turin and one in Rome and encouraged everyone that had passed minimum skills to participate. The tryouts consisted of a selection of individual and group drills and a mixed scrimmage. Following these two dates, 23 skaters were selected based on skating skills and game/rules knowledge for a training squad.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With the majority located in the north of Italy, how are practices organised? Are you managing whole team practices?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;We definitely are having more training dates in the north of Italy, but we’ve made sure to include at least a date in Rome. Our selection of location was more based on resources available that skaters location: we would have loved to train all over Italy, but we decided it was best to use already tried halls that were easily accessible for everyone and we’ve had pretty good attendance for each training session. We are indeed managing the whole team practices: taking it in turn to coach and participate in the drills and each session ends with a mock game/scrimmage&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Italy is a noticeable absence from the European Derby Tournament in September. What bouts are you having to promote &amp;amp; hone Team Italy before Dallas?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;We didn’t feel Team Italy would be ready for the September Tournament, but we are planning a game against the ‘best of the rest’ of Italian skaters and against Team Switzerland. For a lot of skaters these will be the first bout experience, so it will be very exciting.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What have you been doing to raiae funds, awareness + sponsorship for the big expenses of getting to the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1f497d;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;"&gt;We have a gofundme campaign &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1f497d;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gofundme.com/teamitalyrollerderby" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.gofundme.com/teamitalyrollerderby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are Team Italy's aims for Dallas ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Our main goal is to gain experience and raise the profile of the sport in Italy. We are realistic about what we can achieve, given the other team’s profile, but that doesn’t mean that we won’t try our hardest to make an impression and let the whole world know that Italian roller derby is here to stay.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does the English language focus of derby make it harder for Italian derby?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;It doesn’t make it easy that’s for sure: one of the first thing we had to do was to ask each skater to memorise their shirt colour and number in English. Not everyone can speak English, but they surely know what the penalties mean.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The last published Team Italy Roster was :&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Bloody Wheels Roller Derby (Torino/Turin)
Lara Bertolotti aka Mocking Phoenix #D12
Federica Calbini aka Sixxi Blitz #NME1
Elisabetta Cusati aka Hate's Blades #8
Marta Lo Bracco aka Lille Hammer #313
Claudia Schiavone aka Claw D Hella #MC5Harpies Roller Derby (Milano/Milan)
Alice Garbocci aka Vanity Fierce #117
Antonella Giannotti aka Sylph # 21 -
Eleonora Luca aka Elo-c-Raptor #8
Anna Magonara aka Voodoo Doll #78
Elena Managlia aka No Brain No Pain #N3N0
Barbara Modolo aka Kill B #5
Elena Tagliente aka Electric Lemon #12Alp'n Rockets RollerDerby (Bolzano)
Giada Cembran aka Hellga the Murdmaid #77
&lt;p&gt;She Wolves (Roma/Rome)
Serena Paccagnella aka Seitan Helle #L7
Giulia Santandrea aka Bad Attitude #14
Katia Stefani aka Kat Er Pillar #7
Giulia Terrosu aka Steamroller #88
Sara Vichi aka Lady Psycho #22&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bear City Roller Derby (Berlin)
Aurora Facciola aka Ouch Capone #96
Chiara Parducci Santini aka Mad Meid #9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;London Rockin' Rollers
Robi Borgonovo aka Robscene #46
Roberta Venturini aka Sikki Sixx # 666
Verronica Venturini aka Ace Venturini # 911&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copenhagen Roller Derby
Marta Campaner aka Martattack #4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2011 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team italy</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/26/world-cup-interview-team-italy/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 09:23:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Germany - Roller Derby World Cup 2011</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/19/team-germany-roller-derby-world-cup-2011/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;Team Germany (or "Roller Derby Germany" as their logo and website has it) are potentially the most dangerous team in the World Cup, other than the USA and the host nation. They are the only seeded team from Europe, and Germany is one of the longest standing centres of Roller Derby outside of North America.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter" src="http://74.220.215.84/~rollerde/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/WCgermany.jpg" alt="" width="216" height="216"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Team Roster&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BamBule #66 &lt;/strong&gt;BCRD Berlin
&lt;strong&gt;Call of Booty #3 &lt;/strong&gt;RPRG Essen&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chibi Abuser #00 &lt;/strong&gt;SVRG Stuttgart&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ellie Minate #8 &lt;/strong&gt;SVRG Stuttgart
&lt;strong&gt;Heavy Miss Gale #0 &lt;/strong&gt;Harbor Girls Hamburg&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heavy Rotation #505 (Co-captain) &lt;/strong&gt;BCRD Berlin&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kiddo #10 &lt;/strong&gt;BCRD Berlin&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kitty Carrera #4 &lt;/strong&gt;SVRG Stuttgart&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mercedes #0049 &lt;/strong&gt;Philly Roller Girls USA&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noxious Angel #17 (Assistant Co-captain) &lt;/strong&gt;SVRG Stuttgart&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polly Purgatory #13 &lt;/strong&gt;SVRG Stuttgart&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psycho Annie #67 &lt;/strong&gt;RPRG Essen&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Enemy #1 &lt;/strong&gt;SVRG Stuttgart&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resident Shevil #28 &lt;/strong&gt;BCRD Berlin&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silicon Sally #85D &lt;/strong&gt;SVRG Stuttgart&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snowblood #101 &lt;/strong&gt;SVRG Stuttgart&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spacy Tracy #35 &lt;/strong&gt;BCRD Ludwigsburg&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sweet Gwenrolline #9 &lt;/strong&gt;RPRG Essen&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Titty-Twista #81 (Captain, Head Coach)  &lt;/strong&gt;SVRG Stuttgart&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vegas #80 &lt;/strong&gt;SVRG Stuttgart&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coaches&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChefXecutioner &lt;/strong&gt;RPRG Essen
&lt;strong&gt;Rockdog &lt;/strong&gt;BCRD Ludwigsburg
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The only possible weakness that the German team has is their lack of ability to train as a complete team. Mercedes, being based in Philadelphia, will only be training with the others when they arrive in Toronto. Of course, the rest of the team has practiced together, but not bouted publicly, since the selection; with the majority of the skaters from Stuttgart Valley Roller Girls, however, we can assume that they will work together even more coherently than this suggests.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;They are keen to show that European Derby is a force to be reckoned with, and will not be pulling any punches, in the preliminary pool (where they are drawn against Australia, one of the unknowns, and Finland, who they should probably beat) nor in the elimination tournament itself.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2011 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>articles</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><category>team germany</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/19/team-germany-roller-derby-world-cup-2011/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2011 22:09:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interviews: Team Sweden coach Swede Hurt.</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/18/world-cup-interviews-team-sweden-coach-swede-hurt/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every nation has a few famous skaters, who have brought a large influence on the development of roller derby. For Sweden, arguably one of the most well known is Swede Hurt, who has a strong involvement in both of Sweden's leagues in Stockholm and Crime City, and is coaching Team Sweden to boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught up with her to get her opinions on the state of modern roller derby, with a slightly European perspective.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="mceTemp mceIEcenter" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;dl class="wp-caption  aligncenter"&gt;&lt;dt class="wp-caption-dt"&gt;&lt;img title="Swede Hurt" src="http://www.trishries.com/teamsweden/res/img/players/sh.jpg" alt="" width="295" height="327"&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd class="wp-caption-dd"&gt;Swede Hurt by... Swede Hurt (or Mad Maloony, possibly)&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;You got into Roller Derby mainly in the 'States, how does the experience of playing for the big US teams compare with European Derby?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;It has been about finding a different place for me, I am extremely competitive, and I miss playing in US, but it has also been an experience to move back home to Europe and helping derby here. I have been able to coach all-over Europe, and it has also taught me about myself and derby. European Derby is for sure on the right track, and I love to see how there are new teams popping up every month, I love that so many girls realize that it is not about the fishnets but about being an athlete. I always try to tell girls that you cannot skip your basic skating and derby skills, and you cannot forget the off-skate parts either. Both is really important in the process of building a team, that and being a good listener and resolve conflicts before they become gigantic.
I had to take a decision when I moved back to Sweden; if I was gonna sit around and be upset that people weren't playing derby on the level I was used to OR if I was gonna start coaching people and bring them up to the level I wanted to play on. And since I don't really like just sitting around being unhappy - I started to coach and push people upwards.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As someone who's played in the highest levels of American roller derby (with Gotham), how has this influenced your coaching of Team Sweden?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Keep it clean, know the rules, be confident and have fun and keep fit. I loved being a part of Gotham, and  I admire many of the Gotham skaters for their dedication and hard work. Becoming a great derby player is about hard work, dedication to your team and lots and lots of fun. I expect lots from my skaters, but they also know that I listen to them, and that I only push them because I belive in them.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it a problem that most of the national teams seem to have tried to get a "US skater" to make themselves seem competitive?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I think it is a problem if you get a coach just for the name, but if the coach is there to work with them, I do not see a problem. Mad Maloony (my assistant coach) and Titty Twista (head coach Team Germany) are two good examples of girls that are coaching national teams and they never skated for a US team - but they are both very competent coaches that do good work with their teams.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You're also part-owner of the SwedeVix store for roller derby supplies. How has your experience of skating and coaching informed the company's policies?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Well, of course we always listen to skaters about how they like equipment, and if something isn't working out for our customers, we will not sell it anymore. I try to ask around how different skaters like different plates, wheels, etc. etc. Of course I could try it all myself (and I do try lots of our products) but something I like might not work for a shorter and lighter girl. I don't sell things just to sell, I sell things because I want girls to get great derby gear, that will make them perfom better.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it a foregone conclusion that Team USA and Team Canada will take &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the two top spots in the World Cup? Which teams are you most worried &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;about competing against?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I think that England is underestimated, I for sure think they can give Canada a run for their money. I am quite confident in saying that Team US will take the number one spot.  I have no clue where Australia are at, and same goes for New Zealand. I think that every team is a challenge, in different ways, I never write a team off until the last whistle.  I think it be fun to play any team, and we will get on the track and do our best no matter what team we are playing - with a smile on our lips.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-World Cup, would you like to see Team Sweden continue in other &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bouts? You've already played Team Finland - does a European cup sound &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;out of the question?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I think that a European Cup would be fun, I am always up for playing/coaching more derby. And I think Team Sweden has been a great place for Swedish derby to grow, and I hope that we can continue to play, maybe a re-match with Finland next year, maybe play Germany.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; I would love to stay as a head coach for Team Sweden and keep playing, but I would not be able to help organizing such a fun thing. I am going to concentrate on Stockholm Roller Derby's WFTDA status, it be great if we could get through the Apprentice Program during 2012. And me and Vix are also arranging Battle of Nordic Light again in Malmö.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generally, when do you think European Derby will be seriously &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;competitive with US derby, in both actual skill and perception?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Once again, I am impressed by lots of the Euopean teams, LRG are really great, and I was very impressed by their performance during Eastern Regionals. There is a thirst for knowledge all over Europe, and a drive that is amazing. Derby girls are getting fitter, studying strategies and playing smart. I think with implementing minimum skills and leagues getting more structure, and also introducing off-skate sessions, we will not be very far behind, there is so much talent all over Europe - just coaching CCR has been so rewarding.  Now with so many teams joining into the WFTDA Apprentice Program I'm hoping for a European Regional Tournament in 2013 - that really would be amazing.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Swede Hurt blogs at &lt;a href="http://swedehurtgoesfit.blogspot.com/"&gt;Swede Hurt Rambles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2011 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><category>swede hurt</category><category>team sweden</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/18/world-cup-interviews-team-sweden-coach-swede-hurt/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 22:16:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Sweden-Roller Derby World Cup 2011</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/14/team-sweden-roller-derby-world-cup-2011/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/14/team-sweden-roller-derby-world-cup-2011/www.teamswedenrollerderby.com"&gt;Team Sweden&lt;/a&gt; might be relatively new on the scene, but their constituent teams have both been performing well in bouts across Europe. They could be a surprise for the more established teams out there.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/11/teamswedenlogga1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-495" title="teamswedenlogga" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/11/teamswedenlogga1.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="614"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Roster
Swede Hurt - Head Coach + skater (ex of Gotham Girls Roller Derby and Rat City, now Stockholm Roller Derby, after coaching Crime City Rollers)
Mad Maloony - Assistant Coach + skater (ex of Copenhagen, now Stockholm Roller Derby, after coaching Crime City Rollers)
Sloppy Boggins - Assistant Coach (GTAR (Toronto), exStockholm)
Alotta Riot - Crime City Rollers
Ankefar - Crime City Rollers
Barbara Barfight - Crime City Rollers
Becky Lawless - Stockholm Roller Derby
Bess I’rv Cold - Stockholm Roller Derby
Fenix Fortsomfan - Crime City Rollers
Firebird Steele - Crime City Rollers
Fisty - Crime City Rollers
HussInsane - Stockholm Roller Derby
HyperNova - Stockholm Roller Derby
Jazz Ass - Stockholm Roller Derby
Jo Evil Eye - Crime City Rollers
Kit Kat Power  - London Rockin' Rollers
Kix deVille - Stockholm Roller Derby
Knickerblocker Glory - London Rollergirls
Ninja - Crime City Rollers
Twist’d T - Stockholm Roller Derby
Vix Viking - Crime City Rollers (ex of London Rollergirls)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is plain from the roster, Team Sweden draws almost entirely from the two Swedish leagues, Stockholm and Crime City (Malmö). As with many of the national teams, however, they have a smattering of impressively sourced coaches and head skaters, of which Swede Hurt, who has previously played for East Region champions Gotham Girls Roller Derby and for Rat City (including a trip to West Regionals), and will presumably be bringing her intimidating experience to her Head Coach role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Sweden have played one public bout, against Team Finland, which they won handily. Since then, they have been engaging in regular practices to build team cohesion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Sweden is sponsored by the SwedeVix skate store, which just happens to have been founded by two of their players, Swede Hurt and Vix Viking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be getting more information about Team Sweden in a later article, as I interview Swede Hurt on various topics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2011 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><category>team sweden</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/14/team-sweden-roller-derby-world-cup-2011/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 14:45:38 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>