<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about 2x4 roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/2x4-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Derby without Borders: One year catchup</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/derby-without-borders-one-year-catchup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, we brought you an &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/05/derby-without-borders-an-interview-with-founder-mae-dae/"&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Mae Dae, to talk about their fantastic project, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://derbywithoutborders.org/"&gt;Derby Without Borders&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, less than a year later, the project has gone from strength to strength, helping more leagues in more countries across the world, in more ways. With so much happening, it is past time to write an update on events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby Without Borders was founded in 2017, as a project initially intended to help leagues in places where it was cost-prohibitive to get kit and other basic resources (sometimes because roller skating just wasn’t a thing in that country, often also because the cost of items was just much higher than the average wage allowed). The idea was, and still is, that donor leagues or individuals could donate “lightly used” or even new, kit to DwB, and the project would distribute items to leagues in need worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="All the places Derby without Borders has provided help to teams, so far. (Black: kit donations achieved, Blue: “start up” support, Green: advice and translation, Yellow: coaching bootcamps (and other additional support), Red: pending kit donation.)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/DwB2019.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;All the places Derby without Borders has provided help to teams, so far. (Black: kit donations achieved, Blue: “start up” support, Green: advice and translation, Yellow: coaching bootcamps (and other additional support), Red: pending kit donation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we talked to Mae back in 2018, DwB had already successfully helped Sailor City Rollers (Buenos Aires, Argentina), Golden City Roller Derby (Johannesburg, South Africa) and the Cairollers (Cairo, Egypt) with donation packs. They’ve also collected for Roller Derby Beirut (Beirut, Lebanon) (in collaboration with Quad Skate Shop), but have had difficulties getting the kit into Lebanon. Since then, they’ve also been able to support Bangkok Roller Derby (Bangkok, Thailand), Toxic Lima Roller Derby (Lima, Peru), Kyoto Roller Derby (Kyoto, Japan), and Roller Derby Beijing (Beijing, China)…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…but Derby without Borders have also been extending their goals in order to help Roller Derby in other ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, DwB is no longer just Mae Dae: since the last time we spoke, DwB has recruited a second body in the UK, in the form of Rosie Peacock (who has also set up a third donation collection point in the UK). They’ve been providing much needed support, Mae admitting “Rosie has been absolutely pivotal and an amazing addition to the team - I don’t think DwB would have gotten this far without their commitment to the project”.
The project has also grown an Advisory Board, positioned to steer the project in the right directions. In recruiting for the board, Mae tells us that they “reached out specifically to have Skaters of Colour on the board: they’re on the board to help steer the project in the direction it wants to be heading, which means engaging with intersectional, inclusionary and anti-oppressive practices.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rosie and Mae were both representing the cause at this year’s European Rollerderby Organisational Conference (EROC 2019) in Berlin with a stall, and a session on “Removing barriers to accessibility in roller derby”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“It was great to be able to talk with the theme of diversity and inclusivity, and how it relates to DwB, because it really is at the foundation of all of the work that we’re doing - this idea that we need to take down barriers to access in order to make this a more inclusive sport,”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;said Mae. In addition, every time DwB has a stall somewhere, more people learn about the project, and offer to support it. At EROC, one of the attending leagues offered to host a collection at their next bout, and to raise funds for the project.
That said, DwB and EROC in some senses were looking in different directions whilst supporting the same ethos. EROC is, intentionally, focused on improving Roller Derby within Europe; whilst Derby without Borders is inherently about looking outside, and working on how to support Roller Derby in other places, building in inclusivity and adapting culture to support other regions from the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- comment
Add images --&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Mae Dae on the Derby without Borders stall at EROC 2019 (Image copyright: Michael Wittig / Bear City Roller Derby)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/MaeDae-EROC.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Mae Dae on the Derby without Borders stall at EROC 2019 (Image copyright: Michael Wittig / Bear City Roller Derby)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that spirit, then, EROC was also the last event that Mae attended before leaving Europe themself. With Rosie positioned in the UK, Mae has courageously moved to Bangkok, Thailand, allowing them to be physically closer to one big region that would benefit significantly from DwB’s support – South East Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“Moving to Bangkok to help develop SE Asian roller derby has definitely been huge, and really pivotal.” Mae told us,  “I’m really understanding the needs of the region a lot better than I did before - and just how different the scale of roller derby is in all of Asia!”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since being closer to the action, they’ve launched an initiative to provide “consultation” services to newer leagues, giving them support and advice from the ground up (not just on how to start up a league, but also on developing local cultural competency). The first beneficiary of this is the first ever Roller Derby team in Bali: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/hotlavarollers/"&gt;Hot Lava Rollers&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with many of DwB’s new initiatives, this started with a conversation, as Mae relates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“Someone who used to skate with Crime [City Rollers] - Glitter Punch - reached out to me; she’d heard about the project, from Hanna P, and she said ‘I live in Bali now, and I’m so sad that there’s no Roller Derby. I really kinda want to make a team, and I was wondering if you could help me’”.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present, Hot Lava Rollers are just two people, and one set of kit (Glitter’s), and the team is just starting to recruit and look for spaces and other resources. Meanwhile, Mae is actively providing mentorship, on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“I’m trying to get them all the other resources that they would need, so helping them develop everything from bylaws, policies, through to making a logo, getting them social media, just… everything.”
“We’re trying to focus on consistent communication - we talk once a week, even if it’s just a 20 minute check-in. I think also it will be a learning experience in how to help support someone in starting a league without being there - I’m in Bangkok and it’s not far, only an hour’s time difference - but still, not being physically there to put in the work in the same way that I would / am with Bangkok [is a challenge].”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst advice and support is very important, when it comes to developing Derby-specific skills, there’s nothing better than a good coach. So, DwB has also been using its connections to organise specific Coaching Bootcamps in those regions involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 27th April, DwB and Bangkok Roller Derby are co-hosting a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2104905746467908/"&gt;bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; run by Canberra Roller Derby League (and Team Korea)’s ShortStop; on the 12 October, Atlanta Rollergirls (and Team USA)’s Baller Shot Caller will be running a DwB &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/781786125525096/"&gt;organised bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; in Bali! A future Bootcamp is also planned for Cairo (to be hosted by the Cairollers, with Zipblock and Freight Train), but dates and funding are still in progress on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Hot Lava Rollers founders, Rustamia Primanisa and Glitter Punch, after their first meeting with Mae [Thanks to Hot Lava Rollers &amp;amp; DwB]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/HotLavaRollers.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Hot Lava Rollers founders, Rustamia Primanisa and Glitter Punch, after their first meeting with Mae [Thanks to Hot Lava Rollers &amp;amp; DwB]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to run a bootcamp in Bali, in particular, came as a pleasant surprise even to Mae themself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“When Baller [Shot Caller] had reached out to me to ask what she could help the project with, I said, ‘well, here’s all the places I could use help with coaching’, and I let her pick.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
And she said, ‘If I have to choose one, I would say Bali. It seems more secluded, and they probably have less resources’!&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“I said, ‘it’s just two people - there’s the potential you could be teaching 5 people minimum skills’.
Baller was completely okay with that, as the gain in awareness, and value in increased representation was worth it. We did choose a date later in the year to give time for recruitment, though.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having already organised their first DwB bootcamp with Hong Kong Roller Derby (coached by Rosie Peacock and Optimus Grime of Glasgow Men’s Roller Derby), Mae is confident, however, that both bootcamps will have significant regional attendance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“The fact that we had 3 girls from the UAE travel all the way to HK just so they could attend a bootcamp and play a game , just goes to show you how isolated people are - but also how hungry they are for it. What I’m discovering about SE Asian roller derby, and Middle Eastern roller derby. is that when these things happen people will come from across the region to attend and come together.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Bali, though, the bootcamp in Bangkok will also be significant for another reason, being the first time that Bangkok Roller Derby will field a full team to compete. The bootcamp will see two games - the usual Pan-Asian Spring Rollers v Pan-Asian Spring Rollers setup, followed by the history-making Bangkok versus Hong Kong bout!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bout flyer for the next DwB bootcamp, hosted by Bangkok Roller Derby. [Image: Bangkok Roller Derby, photo by Teddy Tse]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/DwB-Bangkok-flyer.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bout flyer for the next DwB bootcamp, hosted by Bangkok Roller Derby. [Image: Bangkok Roller Derby, photo by Teddy Tse]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mae has also been active in providing resources and accessibility in other ways: at present, Roller Derby resources are overwhelmingly available in English (with Spanish probably the next largest). Whilst the WFTDA rules have a translation to the second most widely read language in the world (Chinese), there’s almost no availability in Hindi (the 3rd) and Arabic (the 6th – and 3rd most read as a second language) – and the most spoken Slavic language in the world, Russian, has a similar lack of support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DwB has projects underway to translate resources into under-represented languages to increase accessibility – in the case of Arabic, with the support of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/UAERollerDerby/"&gt;UAE Roller Derby All-Stars&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.cairollers.com/"&gt;Cairollers&lt;/a&gt;. (We’ll be catching up with the Cairollers shortly in another article, as they also have exciting news.) Russian translations of the Short Track Roller Derby ruleset have already been produced, thanks to efforts from the White Night Furies, and Abu Dhabi Roller Derby’s Spinky, as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, Mae dreams of having a “database of different resources for leagues, in all the languages; so if a league needs a framework for a code of conduct in Spanish, they can just go to the database and find something to base it on”. That’s for the future, however: the current effort is focused on getting basic rules and coaching resources translated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as translation, another issue, especially for countries with more filtered access to the Internet, can simply be access to resources at all. In China, for example, common hosts for Roller Derby resources like YouTube, Google Drive, Facebook, Twitter, Twitch, Medium and WordPress are all either permanently or irregularly blocked. Derby Without Borders is actively working with the Chinese Roller Derby community to provide access to the resources that the community needs, using hosts which are acceptable to the Chinese government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Derby without Borders continues to pursue its original goal of providing kit for skaters, as well. One of the first things that Mae noticed at Bangkok was that many of the skaters had inflexible, heavy mouthguards designed for Muay Thai. As theytold us, this isn’t really ideal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“you can’t really speak when you’re wearing them, and can barely breathe in them. So I just emailed SISU and said ‘hey, can you like just give us 20 mouthguards’ and they were like ‘yeah, sure, and just shipped them over’.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as SISU, other derby-related businesses - Steaks, Riedell, and Bont - have shown interest in supporting the project, especially as it has gained more visibility in the community. (Bont-sponsored skater Shortshop has managed to provide a set of wheels as a “prize” at her bootcamp in Bangkok, for example.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bangkok Roller Derby with SISU donated mouthguards, thanks to DwB [Image: Derby without Borders]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/Bangkok-SISU.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby with SISU donated mouthguards, thanks to DwB [Image: Derby without Borders]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this additional activity, however, is only sustainable if Derby without Borders continues to grow itself. Mae is currently working towards a new model for the organisation: regional “chapters” which can help to organise and manage the effort which DwB brings. (The Asia chapter will almost certainly be the first to be established, with recruitment happening now.)
The project is already growing fast enough to need this right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“One thing that I’m learning is understanding my own bandwidth and capability - how much I can do as one person.” Mae told us “Particularly, at this point, I’m doing all of this work because I want to do it - there’s no funding. Understanding my own bandwidth has been important because I’ve had two people reach out to me who were interested in doing the same thing in India, and whilst I absolutely want to help someone start a league in India, I think I might need to focus on one at a time, for now. I think with them I’m going to have to take a step back.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team India Roller Derby have since agreed to help support these potential seeds of Roller Derby, in collaboration with DwB, but the project still needs more people - and leagues - to join in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One Derby without Borders initiative which has been active for the start is the idea of “Sibling Leagues”: an opportunity for established leagues to pair up with specific leagues elsewhere in the world to offer them support. This support could be in terms of equipment donations, as the scheme was originally formulated with Texas collecting kit to donate directly to the Cairollers. However, as DwB evolves, it could equally be provided as knowledge exchange, guidance, and political and social support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“I would love to see that kind of Sibling league relationship develop with more leagues.” Mae told us, “instead of needing to come through DwB [to give support], it could be more like a mentorship: one league can mentor another league, and develop all their resources between the two of them. That’s what’s going to make it more sustainable in the long run [and] that’s the point of the project, creating these things for the sake of sustainability.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Quito, Ecuador’s Forajidas Roller Derby, post-recruitment in January. (Photo: Forajidas Roller Derby)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/Forajidas_roller_derby.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Quito, Ecuador’s Forajidas Roller Derby, post-recruitment in January. (Photo: Forajidas Roller Derby)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst we’ve mostly focused on activities in Asia in this update, that should not imply that DwB is not working for other regions as well. Mae told us that they have been in contact with Forajidas Roller Derby, who are currently trying to (re)establish the only league in Ecuador (in Quito, the capital).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the Forajidas have a GoFundMe ( &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gofundme.com/help-bring-roller-derby-to-ecuador"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/help-bring-roller-derby-to-ecuador&lt;/a&gt; ), they also need guidance and support in forming their league. Mae is actively looking for either a Sibling League, or a coach, or both, who can help to support the new team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, as well as helping to nurture and advise new and developing leagues, DwB is also working to support Roller Derby in other ways. Derby Without Borders can host crowdfunders for such leagues to allow them to raise funds more easily: at present, they’re hosting a GoFundMe to support Buenos Aires’ 2×4 Roller Derby on their current international travel requirements. (You can donate here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gofundme.com/2x4-international-tour-2019"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/2x4-international-tour-2019&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby without Borders is open to assisting any league or team who need their support: regardless of if that’s in SE Asia where Mae is currently focused, or in Latin America, the Middle East, Eastern Europe or Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you, or your league, or your company, want to support Derby without Borders in any way mentioned in this article (or another way you can think of), we encourage you to join in. Derby without Borders can only get better as it gets bigger - and it can only get bigger with more of the community pitching in to support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can support DwB via their Donation page [ &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://derbywithoutborders.org/donate"&gt;https://derbywithoutborders.org/donate&lt;/a&gt; ] and by buying their merch (which also lets you raise awareness of the project by wearing it everywhere) [ &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://derbywithoutborders.org/merchandise"&gt;https://derbywithoutborders.org/merchandise&lt;/a&gt; ]. Mae Dae and DwB central can be contacted by email at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:maedae@skatingoutofbounds.com"&gt;maedae@skatingoutofbounds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2x4 roller derby</category><category>argentina</category><category>bali</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>bootcamps</category><category>cairollers</category><category>china</category><category>crowdfunding</category><category>derby without borders</category><category>dubai roller derby</category><category>ecuador</category><category>egypt</category><category>forajidas roller derby</category><category>hot lava rollers</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>russia</category><category>thailand</category><category>uae roller derby all-stars</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/derby-without-borders-one-year-catchup/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 11:17:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Torneo Violentango 6: Argentina's biggest tournament goes B/C</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/22/torneo-violentango-6-argentinas-biggest-tournament-goes-b-c/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we reported &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/29/violentango-5-latin-americas-continental-tournament-returns/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;last year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Torneo Violentango, 2x4 Roller Derby's yearly tournament, has taken various forms over recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting as a smaller scale tournament, Violentango 4 (2016) was already a Latin America-wide event, with teams from Argentina, Brasil, Chile, Peru and Uruguay in two divisions. Violentango 5 (2017), which we reported on for the first time, was similarly large in scope, with only Uruguay missing, and more teams from the other regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1774791899244174/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Violentango 6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is changing things up a little again - driven by the demands of WFTDA rankings, 2x4 Roller Derby's Team OSOM will be taking a pass from the tournament for the first time, as the event is remoulded into a "B/C" level tournament, with teams from Argentina and Uruguay attending the two divisions. We're especially happy to see Uruguay returning to the tournament, given the general lack of Uruguayan derby in the popular eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26862" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/violentango_map_crop1.png" alt="Violentango_map_crop" width="2160" height="1893"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In the B-tier, competing are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Pibas (&lt;em&gt;2x4 B&lt;/em&gt;, Buenos Aires)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Alianza Rebelde Roller Derby (La Plata)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Mandrágoras Roller Derby (General Roca)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Wonderclan (Buenos Aires Norte)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;MDQueens (Mar del Plata)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Desalmadas Roller Derby (Piñeiro, Buenos Aires)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The C-tier is a little larger, and also slightly more diverse in origin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Team C (&lt;em&gt;2x4 C&lt;/em&gt;, Buenos Aires)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Fawkes Roller Derby (Merlo, Buenos Aires)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Morón Roller Derby (Morón, Buenos Aires&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Sarcásticats Roller Derby (Mendoza)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Atomic Bombs Roller Derby (Lanús, Buenos Aires)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Centellas Rayo Naranja Roller Derby (San Miguel de Tucumán)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Hienas de la Calle (Neuquén)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Pájaros Pintados (Montevideo, &lt;strong&gt;Uruguay&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With just 6 teams in the B Tier, this will be organised as a 2 groups of 3, feeding into a 4 team single elimination from the top 2 teams in each group. (With unseeded teams, this is the second best possible arrangement to guarantee accurate final placements, and the best using a single elimination phase. It also guarantees a minimum of 3 games per team.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;B Tier: Group 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;B Tier: Group 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2x4 B: Las Pibas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Desalmadas Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alianza Rebelde Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MDQueens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mandrágoras Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wonderclan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="2"&gt;B Tier Elimination Structure&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Round 1 (Semifinal)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Round 2 (Final)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Group 1 Winner&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="2"&gt;Winner (1,2)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Group 2 Second&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Group 1 Second&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="2"&gt;Winner (3,4)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Group 2 Winner&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
Meanwhile, the 8-team C Tier will run as a standard 3 round single elimination, with consolation/repechage bouts for teams knocked out in round 1. (Guaranteeing either 2 or 3 games for each team.)
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="3"&gt;C Tier Tournament Structure&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Round 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Round 2 (Semifinal)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Round 3 (Final)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Centellas RN&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="2"&gt; Winner (1,2)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hienas de la Calle&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sarcásticats Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="2"&gt;Winner (3,4)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fawkes Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Atomic Bombs Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="2"&gt; Winner (5,6)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pájaros Pintados Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2x4 C: Team C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="2"&gt; Winner (7,8)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morón Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Consolation 1: Losers Game 1 v 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Consolation 2: Losers Game 2 v 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
It's hard to make predictions for the tournament, due to the relative sparsity of data in Latin American derby, especially for teams which play infrequently, however, we expect a strong showing from the home teams, &lt;strong&gt;Las Pibas&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Team C&lt;/strong&gt;.
With the limited bout data we have available, we expect strong showings from &lt;strong&gt;Mandrágoras&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Desalmadas&lt;/strong&gt; in particular in the B Tier.
The C Tier is very hard to predict, with 4 teams having too little data in public records to predict (Hienas de la Calle, Atomic Bombs and Team C don't have recent enough public bout results, and Morón can only be rated with a small subset of the Argentinean teams). Of the teams we can try to rate, we expect a strong performance from the &lt;strong&gt;Sarcásticats&lt;/strong&gt;, in particular (who we rate higher than some of the teams in the B Tier...).
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Violentango 6 will run from &lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;9 July&lt;/strong&gt; 2018,  at &lt;strong&gt;Martín Fierro&lt;/strong&gt; Oruro 1310, &lt;strong&gt;Buenos Aires&lt;/strong&gt;, Argentina. Tickets available online &lt;a href="https://articulo.mercadolibre.com.ar/MLA-719453253-torneo-de-roller-derby-violentango-6-pase-completo-_JM"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2x4 roller derby</category><category>alianza rebelde</category><category>articles</category><category>atomic bombs roller derby</category><category>desalmadas</category><category>fawkes</category><category>hienas de la calle</category><category>international derby</category><category>latin american derby</category><category>mandrágoras</category><category>mdqueens</category><category>morón</category><category>pájaros pintados roller derby</category><category>rayo naranja</category><category>sarcásticats</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments2018</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>violentango</category><category>wonderclan</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/22/torneo-violentango-6-argentinas-biggest-tournament-goes-b-c/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 10:20:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Torneo Violentango: The Teams</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/11/torneo-violentango-the-teams/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just as we did for Nantes' West Track Story last weekend, we thought it was only proper to do a quick rundown of the teams at 2x4 Roller Derby's WFTDA Recognised Tournament: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TorneoViolentango/"&gt;Violentango 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many of these teams are pretty new to WFTDA, they have no WFTDA Rank - most of them are playing a large number of WFTDA Strength Factor Challenges [a special kind of pseudo-Sanctioned bout which counts only towards the "new" teams' rating with WFTDA] in order to fix this. Buenos Aires Roller Derby is not a WFTDA member at all, and so does not have a WFTDA Rank. The advantage of Strength Factor Challenges is that they do not reduce the ranking of the "experienced" team - so all of 2x4's games at Violentango 5 are SFCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A full schedule, with time-zone adjustments and links to streams when available, is hosted on our site here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/violentango5.html"&gt;https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/violentango5.html&lt;/a&gt; (a smaller article on the tournament is &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/29/violentango-5-latin-americas-continental-tournament-returns/"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;. )&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2x4 Roller Derby&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17687" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/2x4.jpg" alt="2x4" width="200" height="196"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2x4 are the first WFTDA member league in Argentina. Founded in Buenos Aires, Argentina in 2010, they joined WFTDA fully at the start of 2016, at the beginning of the current trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2x4 has organised Violentango tournaments for the last 5 years, although this is the first WFTDA Recognised Tournament version. (We've written a little about the history &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/29/violentango-5-latin-americas-continental-tournament-returns/"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as their A Team, Team OSOM, 2x4 also maintains a B Team (Las Pibas) and a C Team. After Violentango, Team OSOM are preparing for attending someone else's tournament, as they feature at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1356059051113408/"&gt;The Big O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, in Eugene, Oregon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2x4 are rated &lt;strong&gt;#43&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/rankings-march-31-2017/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;#94&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Mar-ranking.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (World, all gender) and &lt;strong&gt;#32&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (WFTDA) [&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Apr-ranking.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New SRD Rank&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;#111&lt;/strong&gt;]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Sailor City Rollers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17686" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/sailorcity.png" alt="sailorcity" width="200" height="188"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second team at Violentango based in Buenos Aires, Sailor City Rollers were founded in 2011, and (as is a theme) joined WFTDA fully in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sailor City also have A, B and C teams, all of whom are active around Argentina and beyond. Most recently, Sailor City played 2x4 only a month ago, losing by around 70 points - they will be wanting to show that this was a fluke, given much closer games in the past (and a win at Violentango 4!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sailor City Rollers will also be at the WFTDA World Summit hosted by Rainy City Roller Derby on the 21st to 23rd April, as a "Scholarship league" selected to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sailor City are &lt;strong&gt;not rated&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/rankings-march-31-2017/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;#87&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Mar-ranking.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (World, all gender) and &lt;b&gt;not rated&lt;/b&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (WFTDA) [&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Apr-ranking.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New SRD Rank&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;#138&lt;/strong&gt;]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Buenos Aires Roller Derby&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17681" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/bard.jpg" alt="bard" width="200" height="205"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buenos Aires Roller Derby, or B.A.R.D., is the third Buenos Aires based league at Buenos Aires. B.A.R.D. has a rather complex history, re-formed as the merger of the Cougar Rollers and Black Mambas in 2015; it could also be said to date back to the formation of the original teams in 2010!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B.A.R.D. have A, B and C teams, all of whom are active participants in the Latin American (especially Argentine) derby community. Of the teams at Violentango, B.A.R.D played Sailor City and Bx3 at the Third Latin American Tournament, losing to both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B.A.R.D. are &lt;strong&gt;not rated&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/rankings-march-31-2017/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;#248&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Mar-ranking.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (World, all gender) and &lt;b&gt;not rated&lt;/b&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (WFTDA) [&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Apr-ranking.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New SRD Rank&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;#417&lt;/strong&gt;]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Bogotá Bone Breakers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17685" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/bx3.jpg" alt="bx3" width="200" height="200"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first of two teams from Colombia, Bogotá Bone Breakers were founded in 2009, but only became full WFTDA members in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bx3 participate in the yearly Bogotá district tournament, which is also ongoing at the moment, along with the large number of other leagues in Bogotá. (Hosting of fixtures is shared amongst all participants.) Bx3's B team, the Baby Breakers, also play in the Distrital, as well as playing the lower rated teams in Colombia. At the Third Latin American Tournament, BX3 played Metropolitan (a loss by 1 pt), and took convincing wins against Ladies of Helltown and B.A.R.D.. They took a significant 670+ pt win over R'nRQueens B ("Queens") in the Distrital...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bx3 are &lt;strong&gt;not rated&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/rankings-march-31-2017/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;#175&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Mar-ranking.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (World, all gender) and &lt;b&gt;not rated&lt;/b&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (WFTDA) [&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Apr-ranking.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New SRD Rank&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;#237&lt;/strong&gt;]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Rock'n Roller Queens&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17683" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/rocknroller.png" alt="rocknroller" width="200" height="200"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second of the Bogotá, Colombia teams, Rock'n Roller Queens date from 2009, and are one of the earliest WFTDA members in this tournament, having been full members since 2013. (In fact, they are the first WFTDA member in Latin America.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R'n R Queens have been very active in the development of Roller Derby in Colombia, having essentially gotten all of the "firsts" - the first bootcamp in 2011, the first tournament in 2012, and the first World Cup Qualifier in 2013. They are now active members of the Bogotá based "Distrital Torneo", as are Bogotá Bonebreakers above, along with their B-team (known simply as "Queens"), and brother-league, "Kings".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R'n R Queens are &lt;strong&gt;#177&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/rankings-march-31-2017/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;#289&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Mar-ranking.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (World, all gender) and &lt;b&gt;not rated&lt;/b&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (WFTDA) [&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Apr-ranking.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New SRD Rank&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;#341&lt;/strong&gt;]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Metropolitan Roller Derby&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17684" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/metropolitan-logo.jpg" alt="Metropolitan logo" width="200" height="150"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santiago, Chile's Metropolitan Roller Derby are the only Chilean team at Violentango. In common with several teams here, they only became WFTDA members in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metropolitan attend a large number of the tournaments organised in Latin America, as do their B-Team, the Bayonetas. (Most recently, the Bayonetas could be found at the Quad Wars tournament, competing with teams across the continent.) In the last year, Metropolitan have played BX3 (winning by 1 point!), and Sailor City (winning by more) at the Third Latin American Tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metropolitan are &lt;strong&gt;not rated&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/rankings-march-31-2017/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;#125&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Mar-ranking.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (World, all gender) and &lt;b&gt;not rated&lt;/b&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (WFTDA) [&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Apr-ranking.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New SRD Rank&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;#161&lt;/strong&gt;]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Ladies of Helltown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17680" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/ladiesofhelltown.png" alt="ladiesofhelltown" width="200" height="200"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From São Paulo, Brasil, Ladies of Hell Town were founded back in 2009, but only joined WFTDA fully near the end of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the first league to be founded in Brasil, the Ladies of Helltown have driven the development of  roller derby in the country. (Back in 2011, they arranged for Bonnie D Stroir to hold a bootcamp in São Paulo, and it has grown since then...) They have recently won the 2016 Brasilian Championship, and acquired their own permanent venue for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ladies of Helltown are &lt;strong&gt;not rated&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/rankings-march-31-2017/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;#931&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Mar-ranking.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (World, all gender) and &lt;b&gt;not rated&lt;/b&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (WFTDA) [&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Apr-ranking.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New SRD Rank&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;#1008&lt;/strong&gt;]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Gray City Rebels&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17682" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/graycity.png" alt="graycity" width="200" height="201"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also from São Paulo, Brasil, Gray City Rebels were founded in 2010, joining WFTDA fully only near the end of 2016. (The league like to note that, whilst they were the second league in São Paulo, after the Ladies of Helltown, they managed to be first to join WFTDA, if only by a few months.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gray City's travel team, The Humming, compete widely in the tournaments across Latin America. (Most recently, The Humming competed against Rio de Janeiro' Sugar Loathe - with a 206-64 victory, and "the rest of the World", a challenge team.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gray City Rebels are &lt;strong&gt;not rated&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/rankings-march-31-2017/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;b&gt;not rated &lt;/b&gt;by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Mar-ranking.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (World, all gender) and &lt;b&gt;not rated&lt;/b&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (WFTDA) [&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Apr-ranking.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New SRD Rank&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;- &lt;b&gt;not rated&lt;/b&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2x4 roller derby</category><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>latin american derby</category><category>tournament</category><category>violentango</category><category>wftda recognised tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/11/torneo-violentango-the-teams/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 10:11:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Violentango 5: Latin America's continental tournament returns.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/29/violentango-5-latin-americas-continental-tournament-returns/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps a little less on people's radar than the big tournaments in Europe, Latin America has been holding continent-scale invitational tournaments for at least the last 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, the regular "Violentango" tournament, hosted by 2x4 Roller Derby of Buenos Aires, Argentina, is returning in April for its 5th edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-16738 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/violentango5.jpg" alt="Violentango5" width="960" height="359"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The previous Violentango (Violentango 4, November 2015) saw two categories, featuring teams from Argentina, Brasil, Chile, Peru and Uruguay divided between the two based on skill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Violentango 5 is almost as wide in its net, featuring new and returning teams from Brasil, Colombia, Chile and Argentina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Brasil&lt;/em&gt;: Both returning from VT-4, Sao Pablo's Ladies of Helltown and Gray City Rebels are both competing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Colombia&lt;/em&gt;: new to VT-5, Bogotá's Bone Breakers (BX3), Combativas Revoltosas and Rock N Roller Queens are all competing (Bogotá is also in the middle of its own national series - the 4&lt;sup&gt;to&lt;/sup&gt; Torneo Distrital Roller Derby -  which all are also participating in).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Chile&lt;/em&gt;: returning from VT-4, Santiago's Metropolitan Roller Derby&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and &lt;em&gt;from Argentina&lt;/em&gt;: all returning from VT-4, Sailor City Rollers, Buenos Aires Roller Derby (B.A.R.D.) and hosts 2x4 Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Violentango 4, hosts 2x4 Roller Derby took first place in the "upper" tier of the tournament with their A team, OSOM. In the "second" tier, Rotten Vicious Dolls (B team for Dirty Fucking Dolls of Buenos Aires) took the first place position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Violentango 5 is working with a reduced format - a single tier tournament with only A teams competing - so only the one championship will be available. We expect that 2x4 will be challenged strongly by last year's second place Sailor City Rollers, who also recently became full WFTDA members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of WFTDA, it's the current spread of WFTDA memberships in Latin America which has inspired this change to Violentango 5. As European teams well know, it is particularly difficult to gain a representative Rank with WFTDA if you can't play a large number of Sanctioned games - and particularly if you can't play high ranked teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the attendees at VT-5 are either WFTDA members (apprentice or full), or are intending to join. By holding a large number of WFTDA Sanctioned games at one time, the intent is to give a big boost to Latin America in the Rankings, partly ameliorating the issue. As part of this change to the aims of Violentango, this iteration of the tournament is also a WFTDA Recognised Tournament for 2017 - in fact, it may be the first ever WFTDA Recognised Tournament in Latin America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as the tournament, VT-5 will also feature a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1902699419974335/"&gt;Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; run by 2x4 Roller Derby on the 15th. As well as covering all aspects of derby track skills, there will, in keeping with the theme of the tournament, be a special section covering the optimal choice of bouts in order to improve your WFTDA Ranking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, they're not finished, as the event also includes one of the new WFTDA Officiating Clinics, also on the 15th, to allow Latin American officials to participate in best practice from WFTDA Level 4 Certified Referee, Wernher VonBombed and WFTDA Level 5 Certified NSO Intejill! (This is a "One Day Clinic", as defined on the WFTDA website &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/events/officiating-clinics/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with all significant tournaments we cover, we are hoping to provide a viewing guide in the event of streaming, and other resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Violentango 5 can be found on the 2x4 Roller Derby Website here: &lt;a href="https://www.2x4rollerderby.com.ar/torneo-violentango/ediciones-anteriores/vt-5/"&gt;https://www.2x4rollerderby.com.ar/torneo-violentango/ediciones-anteriores/vt-5/
&lt;/a&gt;or in the WFTDA Recognised Tournaments page here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/events/wftda-recognized-tournaments/"&gt;https://wftda.com/events/wftda-recognized-tournaments/&lt;/a&gt;
Tickets available here: &lt;a href="https://www.2x4rollerderby.com.ar/shop/tickets/"&gt;https://www.2x4rollerderby.com.ar/shop/tickets/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;(options for whole tournament, day pass and whole tournament + commemorative teeshirt)&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="text_exposed_show"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2x4 roller derby</category><category>articles</category><category>bootcamps</category><category>international derby</category><category>latin american derby</category><category>officiating clinics</category><category>roller derby bootcamps</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>violentango</category><category>wftda recognised tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/29/violentango-5-latin-americas-continental-tournament-returns/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 12:38:26 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>