<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about a chat with...)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/a-chat-with.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Silver City Cup - A Brawling Interview</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/06/silver-city-cup-a-brawling-interview/</link><dc:creator>davidlewis8891</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen, September 2018&lt;/strong&gt; - Granite City Brawlers are making history with their very own MRDA sanctioned tournament called 'Silver City Cup'. Whilst MRDA has Champs and Playoffs, there has never been a sanctioned tournament held in Scotland. Granite City Brawlers, Super Smash Brollers, Crash Test Brummies, Kamiquadz, South Wales Silures and Tampere Rollin' Bros are all looking to take the inaugural 'Silver City Cup'. With the Brawlers hoping to make their mark in the MRDA rankings, we took some time to speak to GCB's Co-Captain, Pudz (Chris Mathieson) about the upcoming tournament.
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27393" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/09/34909209_2057023227701408_2544234365819289600_o.jpg" alt="34909209_2057023227701408_2544234365819289600_o" width="1920" height="1280"&gt;
Photo by: Len Rizzo&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Straight off the bat, tell us how this tournament came about?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We joined the MRDA last September and as part of this the team is required to play 5 sanctioned games a year in order to gain ranking. The bigger teams can get their games quite easily in a tournament weekend through Champs and Playoffs, however there wasn’t much opportunity for the lower seeded teams. So we put our organisational heads together and decided to put on a tournament weekend for those below 40 or unranked in the MRDA. This allows 6 teams (including Brawlers) to gain 3 of their games in a single weekend!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does it feel to be able to host/create the first MRDA tournament in Scotland as well as it having quite the international flavour to it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are over the moon at having 6 teams coming from 5 countries to our little tournament in Aberdeen. We even been working with some local bodies to promote the tournament and the city. VisitAberdeenshire have even put together a web portal (&lt;a href="https://www.visitabdn.com/cp/silver-city-cup"&gt;https://www.visitabdn.com/cp/silver-city-cup&lt;/a&gt;) full of information to help our tourist friends. A lot of people see Aberdeen as this grey city with not much going on but there is such a history to it! Three top things to check out on your visit would be Dunnottar Castle (for the Game of Thrones fans), Footdee (a small area of quirky houses, 5 minutes from the venue) and Slains Castle (the backdrop of our fab logo, you might even see one of the ghouls).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As for this being the first MRDA tournament in Scotland we are delighted to showcase to the rest of our international association just what Scotland has to offer and that we can put on one hell of a tournament!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think we all want to know, how do you think GCB will fair given the tough competitors and the grueling nature of a tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is GCB’s first ever tournament and as such we’re going to need to bring our A game up against some tough opponents! With a few Scotland skaters at the helm, we have some tournament experience that will hopefully help the rest of the team prepare mentally and physically. We’ll be aiming for the win and to keep the Silver City Cup in the Silver City but every team has a good chance of taking that trophy home, the very nature of a tournament weekend is that anything could happen!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You say you’ve been preparing for the tournament, how have you done this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last month we hosted a double scrim with skaters from almost every league in Scotland. This allowed us to prepare for back to back games against some high level skaters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We also have our weekly outdoor fitness sessions with Intrepid PT, these have worked doubly as both exercise and team bonding. Though its been a year and we all still hate burpees!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Should the tournament fair well, could we be seeing an annual Silver City Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ask me when its over! Maybe not an annual tournament in Aberdeen but we’d love to see a division two type structure appear within the MRDA as it continues to grow. Obviously our end goal is MRDA Champs but that’s a few years away yet!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any final words that you would like to share with us?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We really want to put on a good tournament, representing all of Scotland and we’d love a big Scottish home crowd behind us – get your tickets now - &lt;a href="https://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/3446103"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/3446103&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some inspiring words from Granite City Brawlers own, Pudz. From the sounds of it, this will be an exciting weekend of roller derby so make sure you get your tickets and be a part of Scottish history on &lt;strong&gt;September 22-23 at the Beach Leisure Centre in Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;! You can check out further information at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/616684768693015/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/616684768693015/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27394" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/09/35151282_840046892864311_5399712130972778496_n.jpg" alt="35151282_840046892864311_5399712130972778496_n" width="810" height="450"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Article written by Brawlers correspondent HaJuken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>crash test brummies</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>kamiquadz</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mrda</category><category>silver city cup</category><category>south wales silures</category><category>super smash brollers</category><category>tampere rollin' bros</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/06/silver-city-cup-a-brawling-interview/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 11:21:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City host Double Header</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/24/granite-city-host-double-header/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A double header to hit Granite City on the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28th of July&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;! The &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beach leisure centre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; of &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is home to Granite City Roller Derby's &lt;strong&gt;Fight Hawks&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Northern Fights&lt;/strong&gt;; both taking on tricky opponents in this derby day duo! &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doors open at 12:30&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; with the first whistle at 1pm, entry on the door for&lt;strong&gt; £4 (under 12's go free!).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27076" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/36548337_10157716666129012_6781758626013904896_o.jpg" alt="Granite City Roller Derby" width="2048" height="1153"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start off the day it's the battle of the B teams, with the &lt;em&gt;Fight Hawks&lt;/em&gt; taking on Dundee Roller Derby's &lt;em&gt;Bonnie Colliders&lt;/em&gt;! We caught up with the captains to see how they are preparing for the weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-27075 alignleft" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/37395447_1902795173120396_2721404236385484800_n-e1532295713922.jpg?w=200" alt="Image courtesy: Len Rizzo" width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fight&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Hawks Captain&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Skeevy Wonder #64&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How long skating:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;4 and a half years apparently! Time flies.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How long captaining team:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;About 8 months&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the season been for your team so far?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We're only really just kicking into gear, but it's been great figuring out our team's strengths and helping build the confidence of our newer skaters. We had a great time in Portugal, where we may not have come back with any gold medals, but we came back with heaps of goals and ideas.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have you been preparing for the upcoming game:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Following on from those pointers from our tournament in Coimbra, we've been drilling our weaknesses and honing our strengths. Practice, practice, practice!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you find playing teams within Scotland, does it change your game prep playing such a geographically close league?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;As a team, the Hawks have played teams all over Scotland, a few in England, and even teams from Spain and Portugal. We haven't played the Colliders in a long time, but being closer to Dundee and knowing more of their skaters and their styles and preferences, we have a better idea of what kind of game we are going in to. As far as I'm concerned about geographical closeness, it means I can have a proper breakfast that's not from a service station and a bit of a lie in! Boost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything in particular you say to your team to get prepped for the game? Any words of wisdom?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;As a B team, we're here to learn constantly, and get as much from every game as possible. That doesn't mean we're not competitive however, it just means win or lose we're taking away valuable experiences.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonnie Colliders Captains&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; ALLY-J &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;#92 &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;amp; Tiny Tearaway #931&lt;img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-27090" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/37711946_10156238091771068_2068850209923792896_n.jpg?w=141" alt="37711946_10156238091771068_2068850209923792896_n" width="141" height="300"&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Long Skating:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; 3 years, 6 years respectively.
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long Captaining Team&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; our first year!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the season been for your team so far?:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; It’s been a really good start, our focus skating as a team has been awesome! We constantly strive to do our very best, even if we lose a game we can still be really proud of each others performance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How have you been preparing for the upcoming game?:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; We've been pushing ourselves a lot at training. Working alongside the Tayzers to increase our knowledge of the game and to build our skills. &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you find playing teams within Scotland, does it change your game prep playing such a geographically close league?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We've played further afield against Copenhagen which was many of the Colliders' first game outside Scotland. Playing teams closer to home is just as exciting. Seeing the talent that Scotland has is incredible and being able to play alongside these people makes it all worth it. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything in particular you say to your team to get the prepped for the game? Any words of wisdom?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Don’t let the other team get into our heads! That every single person has an amazing set of skills to use, and not to forget it!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this B-team-bust-up Granite's A team &lt;em&gt;The Northern Fights&lt;/em&gt; will be taking on &lt;em&gt;Vagine Regime UK, &lt;/em&gt;a team formed by a fully inclusive community of LGBTQIA+ individuals and their supporters across the UK. We put a few questions to each of the captains to understand the teams individual run ups to games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-27098" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/37753945_1909703029096277_5673277440076546048_n.jpg?w=300" alt="Image Courtesy: Len Rizzo" width="300" height="199"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Northern Fights Captain:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Lizzee Rascal #314&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How Long Captaining?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;First year
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Long Skating?: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;5 Years&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the season been for your team so far?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;This season has been great so far. We had quite a change in the team at the beginning of the year and sadly said goodbye to old friends and welcomed some new ones. We have been focusing on British Champs, where we've been competing in Tier 3 North. It has been a fantastic challenge for us and has really pushed us to train hard. We have finished second in our tier and I couldn’t be prouder of the Fights.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have you been preparing for the upcoming game?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We've been focusing on developing and building as a team for champs throughout 2018. The upcoming game, being an exhibition game, will be a refreshing change from this, with a lot of the pressure of champs being taken off. We have still been training hard and want to bring our best game at the weekend.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you find playing teams such as VR? Does it change your strategy or prep at all?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Playing against VR is a different experience for us, as they bring a pool of talent from across the UK and will perhaps use tactics that we haven’t been up against before which will make for a challenging yet fun game.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vagine Regime captain:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Kami-Tazzy #360&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-27096 alignright" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/37825317_1875280102519140_1499359558181584896_n.jpg?w=200" alt="Image Courtesy: Nick" width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How Long Skating:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; 7. 5 years&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How long Captaining:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;First time for VR.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the season been for your team so far, do rosters change a lot?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It's been great so far. Back in April we had a tough but close game with the Rainy City C team, a great game to kick off the season with. We're really looking forward to playing Granite's awesome Northern Fights. VR UK contain a very large number of members, of all levels, from all over the UK, including some of the best players the UK can offer. Because of that, rosters are always changing, but it mainly depends on location, bout clashes, level and availability.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you prepare your skaters for upcoming games?:&lt;/strong&gt; S&lt;em&gt;ince skaters are generally from different leagues/teams it's difficult to prepare physically. Therefore communication and trust is key here. We'll have discussions on positions, and other strengths that everyone can bring. This will help the captains, LUM and Bench to come up with line up plans and strategies to fully challenge our opponents. It's certainly a bonus to have skaters on the team that have played together before, but things still may get shuffled around on the day to maximise our full potential.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How do you find putting together a mixed team to play established leagues, is there anything in particular you look for in skaters?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Depending on availability, we try to put together a strong as possible team to challenge our competitors to the max. We try to get the right mix of skaters of every position. However this is not possible at all times, we have had jammer heavy rosters in the past or vice versa. This is not really a problem, as a lot of the players are very adaptable and give it thier absolute all. We may be a challenge team but we're still a competitive team who like to rise to the challenge and aim to triumph in every game that we play.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything in particular you say to your team to get them prepped for the game? Any words of wisdom?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I ask them to bring all their focus, good sportsmanship and determination on and off the track. Additionally teamwork, integrity and to set individual as well as team goals. This sport is brilliant but it can also be mentally tough at times. One main advice I give to a lot of people is that if things don't go as planned in a jam, I encourage them to put it behind them, store it away if needed, reset and focus on the next jam. Also most importantly enjoy yourselves and embrace all the achievements, no matter how small or big they are.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;Event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/235019877294396/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;
Date: 28/07/2018
Price: £4 on the door&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was co-written by Dundee's correspondent G. Patterson and Granite's Correspondent C. Meikle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2018 season</category><category>a chat with...</category><category>aberdeen</category><category>articles</category><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>up coming games</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>vagine regime uk</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/24/granite-city-host-double-header/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:45:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Roller Derby comes to Kyoto! ローラーダービーが京都に来る。</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/12/roller-derby-comes-to-kyoto-roradabigajing-du-nilai-ru/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here at SRD, we always like to see Roller Derby expanding into new places; especially places where there's been no roller derby before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst Roller Derby has been in Japan (in Okinawa and Tokyo, and, until this year, Misawa), there's been little growth outside of those regions. (Tokyo Roller Derby have expanded to contain teams based in the surrounding cities, such as Yokohama, but not outside the Kantō region; the most recent independent team, Kamikaze Badass, is also based in Tokyo.) So, it was particularly exciting to see the announcement this year of a new league, based in Kyōto, in the Kansai region!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught up with Kyoto Roller Derby's founders, Kat and Josie, to find out a bit more about them, and what inspired them to seed more roller derby in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26824 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/kyotord.jpg" alt="KyotoRD" width="621" height="480"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's been a while since the last Roller Derby league was founded in Japan. Can you tell us a bit about yourselves as founders? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Kat: I skated with Bath Roller Derby Girls in the U.K. and I absolutely loved it! The team was in its early stages back then and it was so nice to be a part of something at the ground level. After moving to Japan and being really far away from any teams here, I kept writing messages of desperation on Facebook forums hoping to pique some interest. Eventually someone replied! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Josie: That would be me! I had been living in Japan for two years, teaching English and loving life up in the mountains, but every day I was still pining for the outlet that is derby. I messaged Kat having seen a plea of hers, and was thrilled to meet another skater out here. At the time we lived a few hours apart, so it wasn’t easy to meet up. But quickly we realised that a derby team was needed in the Kansai area. I began skating first at drop-in sessions with Bristol back in 2012, then for Severn Roller Torrent in Gloucester. I skated with SRT for two years, before moving to Japan in 2015. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The moment we met we couldn’t help reminiscing about all the things that derby meant to us. It’s such an important space and community that we felt could really bring a lot to Kyoto. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All but two Roller Derby leagues in Japan were founded by non-Japanese skaters; how are you reaching out to the people of Kyoto to grow the league? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Josie: We’ve been fortunate enough to work with and become friends with some amazing people out here, and we are really keen for all of our practices, future events and bouts to be a community thing. We are committed to using Japanese and English in all of our communications on social media and really strive to be as inclusive as possible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Kat: This is definitely really important to both of us, and we want to encourage as many new Japanese members to join us as possible. I recently watched the animation Aggretsuko, and couldn’t ignore the parallels between that and derby as a form of stress release. The show is about an awesome red panda who works in a sh&lt;em&gt;tty office, full of sh&lt;/em&gt;tty male bosses who talk down to her all day, and although she is sweet during working hours, at night she blasts out thrash metal karaoke to release her stress. I basically feel like derby could be this for so many of my friends! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kamikaze Badass Roller Derby Tokyo found that one issue they've had is with the conflation of Roller Game and Roller Derby in the minds of potential recruits. In the short time you've been in existence, have you identified any specific issues to deal with?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Often staff at venues have a negative view of it and think it’s going to be too dangerous, because of the associations with Roller Game.  Also a lot of younger people see roller skating as very dated, and don’t consider it as a sport for the modern age. We’ve reached out to a lot of leagues for help and guidance on this type of thing, as we are aiming to be as transparent and respectful as possible, whilst also smashing any preconceptions, as respectfully as possible of course.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting a league off the ground also needs resources as well as people power. How can the Community help Kyoto Roller Derby - and how are you planning to grow your resources? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We’ve actually just announced our first fundraiser at our local Japanese-run burrito joint, where we’ll be selling baked goods and our first official merch &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;[&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/162229187965089/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;see here for this event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;. Ideally we hope to hold a number of fundraisers throughout the year in order to spread the word and purchase essential kit for our fresh meat team. We’ve also been in touch with the wonderful Derby Without Borders &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;[&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/05/derby-without-borders-an-interview-with-founder-mae-dae/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;see our interview here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; who provide second hand kits for up and coming leagues across the globe, and that was after a tip from you, and from another within the Tokyo derby community. Worldwide derby spirit is definitely already pushing us in the right direction and we are so grateful, so we hope that as many people as possible will want to help us get going. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where do you see Kyoto Roller Derby in the future? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We want to see Kyoto Roller Derby as an active league in Japan, visiting teams around the country as well as worldwide! We want to have a really positive influence within the local community, with as many people as possible coming to watch our games, and feeling encouraged and empowered to get involved. Roller derby has had such an incredible impact on both of our lives and we can’t wait to watch it grow in Kyoto.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about Kyoto Roller Derby, and support them, on their social media platforms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/kyotorollerderbyjapan"&gt;www.facebook.com/kyotorollerderbyjapan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Instagram: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.instagram.com/kyotorollerderbyjapan"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;www.instagram.com/kyotorollerderby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;You can also email them at:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; &lt;a href="mailto:kyotorollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;kyotorollerderby@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;And support them via GoFundMe here:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.gofundme.com/kyotorollerderby"&gt;www.gofundme.com/kyotorollerderby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>international</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>japan</category><category>kyoto roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/12/roller-derby-comes-to-kyoto-roradabigajing-du-nilai-ru/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 18:39:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Without Borders: an interview with founder, Mae Dae.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/05/derby-without-borders-an-interview-with-founder-mae-dae/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes Roller Derby doesn't live up to its reputation, but when it does, it really does. One of the recent great examples of the way the Roller Derby community can band together to support itself is the &lt;a href="http://www.skatingoutofbounds.com/derby-without-borders/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby Without Borders&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Project, which has been working to supply resources to Roller Derby leagues in need since last year.
As the project continues, we caught up with founder Mae Dae to find out where the project came from - and how you can help it to continue to help Roller Derby everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26810 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/derbywithoutborders.png" alt="derbywithoutborders" width="600" height="400"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;So, for people who don't know you: let's start with "who's Mae Dae, and what is Skating Out of Bounds?"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well I’m 28 years old and I love roller derby. I first started skating with a small league in Northern California, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://sonomacountyrollderby.org/"&gt;Sonoma County Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, in 2014. In 2017 I left my league, and home, to go on a back packing trip through Europe. I knew I couldn’t possibly live without derby in my life so I brought my skates with me. Skating Out of Bounds was originally a blog about my travel and derby experiences elsewhere. Mainly it was for my friends to read. I also would send people little care packages from different places I visited through the site as well. Since then, it’s evolved into something entirely different. I’ve actually deactivated the blog even, because it doesn’t feel relevant to it’s purpose anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we're here to talk about is something which started as a spinoff of Skating Out of Bounds - the Derby Without Borders project. I think the idea first came to you at the 2017 WFTDA &lt;a href="https://wftda.com/rdws/"&gt;World Summit&lt;/a&gt; in Manchester, so can you talk us through the background?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, at the Summit there was a panel of skaters from what were identified as “emerging regions” in derby. They all discussed different struggles they had with making derby accessible in their own leagues. One of the struggles that was universal was that for varying different reasons they all struggled with getting skates and protective gear. This is a huge barrier for the sport to grow in these areas as it can be so discouraging to wait months for skates to arrive. It was sort of a lightbulb moment and I chatted with several of the panellists after to see if they would somehow be interested in receiving some donations if I could get some together. I also chatted with Master Blaster there and she thought it was a great idea. I told her about my blog and travels so she said to come by her shop in Berlin and we could make it happen. She was the first of several people to believe in my idea, and well the rest all kind of fell into place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby Without Borders' first "concrete goal" was to provide kit to support &lt;a href="http://sailorcityrollers.com/"&gt;Sailor City Rollers &lt;/a&gt;in Argentina - for which you ran a &lt;a href="https://www.gofundme.com/derbywithoutborders"&gt;GoFundMe&lt;/a&gt; , as well as a stall at RollerCon. What was the support like for the project at RollerCon?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t even expecting to have a booth at Rollercon to be honest. But I figured if I didn’t ask I wouldn’t so I emailed to see if they would be ok with me having a booth. I was so excited when they told me they’d donate a space to me! I think the support was great, people who heard about the project were happy to help and we got a considerable amount of donations. I struggled to get the information out to enough people ahead of time so there were a lot of people who had said they wished they had known sooner and they would have brought more donations with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you have any unexpected help, or setbacks?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My neighbouring booth at Rollercon, F Yeah Printing, were so sweet and we made good friends! They have been so supportive since then and have offered a fundraiser through their printing service, [&lt;a href="https://fyeahprinting.com/collections/derby-without-borders"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;link]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; where you can buy Skating Out of Bounds and Derby Without Borders merchandise and a portion of the proceeds go to helping fund the project. They’ve also been really helpful with sharing social media posts about the project which is a lot more helpful than people think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t call them setbacks, but definitely some big learning moments. I had a bit of a mix up with travel plans at the end of Rollercon and had to leave mid day on Sunday. Which meant packing up the booth early. I didn’t think about it at the time, but of course, everyone wanted to leave donations at the end of the event. So even though the booth was packed up people still left quite a few donations behind. I definitely changed my approach for the World Cup booth because of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Following up on that, the project's next appearance was at the &lt;a href="http://www.rollerderbyworldcuplive.com/"&gt;Roller Derby World Cup 2018&lt;/a&gt;, back in Manchester. As well as passing on the kit the project had collected for Sailor City to Team Argentina's skaters, you extended the project to a huge number of other teams - can you tell us a bit about the current beneficiaries, and how they were selected?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure! So I already had a contact with &lt;a href="http://goldencityrollers.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Golden City&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; [Johannesburg] in South Africa and knew that Team South Africa would be at the World Cup so it made sense to collect for them too. Everything we collected at the World Cup went with them, and the Rollercon donations got passed on to the Team Argentina skaters from Sailor City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the other beneficiaries have been through word of mouth for the most part. Either friends of mine have mentioned a league somewhere and I’ve reached out, or leagues in need have heard of the project and reached out to me directly. Our list keeps growing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-26811" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/miraclewhipsdwb.jpg" alt="MiracleWhipsDWB" width="960" height="720"&gt; Team Canada's Miracle Whips hanging out by the Derby Without Borders stall at the Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Running Derby without Borders must be a big logistical task. Can you tell us who is currently involved in the project with you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would be completely lost without all the help I’ve gotten so far. I’ve had tons of friends help out in all kinds of ways. Two of my former league mates, WiFly and H.A.M. Slice, helped design my two logos, and I had amazing volunteers at both booths. My two closest friends, KT Wrecks and Leethal, have also been amazing cheerleaders and sounding boards for the project since it started. I also had to work out some serious logistics for getting the Rollercon donations from my storage unit in California to Manchester for the World Cup. That was a combination of a good friend, Wicked Lizard, driving my donations to an event she was reffing at and Pia Mess, who would be coming to World Cup, picking them up from her and then me paying for an additional checked bag to get them there. Totally doable, but a lot of figuring out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my closest friends in London, Jem, has been a cornerstone for me since re-igniting the project here. She’s helped out a lot with planning, the booth at the World Cup, helping transport donations and being supportive of the project even when I feel like giving up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current league mates at &lt;a href="http://www.londonrockinrollers.co.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;London Rockin’ Rollers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; have donated tons of items and quite a few volunteered at the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been so grateful for the support of Master Blaster and Smarty Pants. They’ve both been really supportive and have offered several resources throughout the whole project. Both &lt;a href="http://www.quadrollerskateshop.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quad Skate Shop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://strongathletic.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strong Athletic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; have sponsored the project in some way. Smarty also connected me with Sisu mouthguards and we were able to get a new mouthguard donated for every set of kit we got at the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quad Skate Shop helped collect donations and sent them to the league in Beirut [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Roller-Derby-Beirut-763063127094159/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roller Derby Beirut&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]. During World Cup they offered a discount at the shop, if you donate an old item you get 10% off the new one, so bring in old wrist guards get 10% off your new ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smarty has been working with me on several ways to make the project more accessible too. We started a league sponsorship program where her league did a collection and sponsored the shipping to the league in Cairo [&lt;a href="http://www.cairollers.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CaiRollers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jes Rivas has also reached out about supporting the project with donating some of her old items since she’s now retired and helping with social media blasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve also connected with &lt;a href="https://www.doublethreatskates.co.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Double Threat Skate Shop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in London and they’ve donated items and are continuing to collect items for the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m so thankful and inspired for all the support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you see Derby Without Borders growing bigger with time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely. I think with a little more time and some work it can become something great that helps support people in the sport and increases accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's your "vision" for the project - do you want to support emerging derby in other ways, beyond just kit?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had absolutely no boundaries on how the project could grow I would love to see it develop in the following ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continue to get kit to beneficiaries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsor experienced Coaches to host bootcamps for beneficiaries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Host roller derby after-school programs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A scholarship fund to get individuals from beneficiary leagues to large scale derby events such as Rollercon, Camp Elite and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If people want to help out with Derby Without Borders, how can they help out?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything helps. At the moment I managing the whole project, but my skill set does not lie in logistics. The biggest things I need at the moment:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Website management/rebranding&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Social Media (both with managing the page but also just sharing posts so more people hear about it)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Logistics/Admin: organising beneficiaries, potential sponsors etc&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Shipping expert: anyone who knows a lot about international shipping and estimated costs&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Charity/Nonprofit Management: I’d love to register the project as a charity&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Outreach: finding new beneficiaries and potential sponsors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;What kinds of items of kit are most in demand - and how second-hand is second-hand?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely skates. Most people want to sell old skates to help offset the cost of buying a new pair, which is totally understandable. But skates are also the hardest thing for people to access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second-hand: meaning it has to be still safe for people to use. I’m not interested in putting people at risk. I always ask if helmet donations have taken any impact and don’t take helmets that have. As long as pads are relatively usable, even with some tape, I’ll take them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you don't have kit to donate, how else can people help out?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest ways people can help are donating time, money or publicity. I can definitely use volunteers in a number of ways, both here in London and digitally from anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial donations help cover shipping costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply spreading information about the project is really helpful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do want to donate to Derby Without Borders, you can do so via their &lt;a href="http://www.skatingoutofbounds.com/derby-without-borders/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/derbywithoutborders/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facebook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donations of funds can be made via the store at Skating Out Of Bounds: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skatingoutofbounds.com/shop/sponsor-a-league"&gt;SPONSOR A LEAGUE &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mae Dae and Derby Without Borders can be contacted to offer other kinds of help via their Facebook page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>derby without borders</category><category>fundraising</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/05/derby-without-borders-an-interview-with-founder-mae-dae/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 19:36:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2018 Seasons beginnings for DRG!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/28/2018-seasons-beginnings-for-drg/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a late start due to the very wonderful &lt;em&gt;Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/em&gt; earlier this year in Manchester (!), Dundee Roller Girls are hosting their Season Opener on &lt;strong&gt;15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of April 2018&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;D.I.S.C. in Dundee&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boasting an action packed day for both DRG's A and B team, doors open at &lt;strong&gt;12:30&lt;/strong&gt; with tickets on the day at &lt;strong&gt;£6.&lt;/strong&gt; You can look forward to &lt;em&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/em&gt;' Fear Maidens facing off against the Bonnie Colliders at 1pm, with &lt;em&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/em&gt;' All Star Reserves taking the track against the Silvery Tayzers at 3pm!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a new season of games, come new captains! So we thought we would have a wee chat with both teams' captains to see how the season is shaping up. First up is ALLY-J and Tiny Tearaway captaining the Bonnie Colliders!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="26529,26530" type="circle" columns="2"]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table style="width:100%;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Questions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;ALLY-J&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;Tiny Tearaway&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;931&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Position&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Jammer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Jammer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Derby Hero&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Hubs &amp;amp; Mayhem&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Lady Trample and Mayhem&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Motto&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Lets do dis"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Nothing is impossible, the word itself says "I'm possible""&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How long have you been skating?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I’ve been quad skating with DRG since March 2016, so 2 years now (time flies!) but used to inline skate from the age of 10!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I have been skating 6 years this coming May (scary) and I have been with DRG for 2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;What does this season hold for the Colliders?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We've had the opportunity of playing in Copenhagen, Newcastle and in our home town, and this season we're going to build as a whole Team! We totally found our feet working with each other, and we are looking at focusing on attendance, positivity and building our knowledge of the game!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Yes its going to be very exciting for the Colliders. We have some fantastic games lined up already and a strong team full of skaters determined to be the best.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;As a B team, what challenges to you face?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Finding our way of working together as a team. Fitting in our newest skaters and helping them gain lots more skills and understanding of the game.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We are all part of a very supportive league so the challenges I see aren’t limited to us as a team. We face the same challenges as the A team; attendance, working together well and pushing ourselves to the best of our abilities.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How does the league, as a whole, carve space for the B team?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;As a league, our A and B team train together, which is an amazing opportunity. We are constantly learning from each other, talking over drills and skills; with us skating alongside folk from Team Scotland, really being able to learn from the best is our greatest asset.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;B team, A team who? We're a league that trains together. Skaters for both teams, crossovers and new skaters. We all do the same drills and are expected to put the same amount of hard work and effort into every one from the newer skaters to those who were on Team Scotland.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;And if you could set goals for yourself and for the team this season?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;My personal goal is to work on my jammer skills and tactical knowledge. I want to work well for the team and push myself this season! For the Colliders: to focus on ourselves as a team. Although we are all building our personal skills, I really want everyone to bring positivity and sportsmanship to the Colliders.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Our B team has played and flourished with smaller numbers the past season. It would be great to see us play with higher numbers. This would give us the chance to have a solid jammer rotation and walls that are to be reckoned with. To be part of that jammer rotation is my goal for this season.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Second up is the captains of the Silvery Tayzers, Seaton and Bosies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="26532,26531" type="circle" columns="2"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table style="width:100%;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Questions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;Seaton&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;Bosies&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;102&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;37&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Position&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Pivot/ Offence&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Blocker&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Derby Hero&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Serelson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Kid Block&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Motto&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Shitemare"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"SITFU"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How long have you been skating?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;6 years, started and stayed with DRG since then.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Skating for six years, initially with GCRD and have been with DRG for almost 2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;What does this season hold for the Tayzers?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I'll probably cry and give dramatic speeches alot. Hoping that as a league we'll be able to continue to perform like we did last season but also move passed that, honing in our skill set. The Tayzers have always performed under a "get the job done, nae fancy shit" mentality and I want to continue that while progressing within the WFTDA rankings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We are continuing to evolve the skills, tactics and endurance that we've developed last season. Which will set us in good stead for the exciting and tough games we have lined up for this year.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;As an A team skater, how do you stay ontop of your game&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I hydrate and then spew it up if I go too fast.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Pepsi Max, avocados and hummus. And cross training.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How has becoming a WFTDA league changed your priorities and training?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I think it gives us clear global equivalents to try to compete against, which we haven't really had before. It's good to be able to feel super involved with the development of the sport as a whole, as well as having access to more teams.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;It allows us to skate against teams of a similar calibre at national and international level, as well as competing in tournaments! This emphasises the need for a strong mental game, the ability to work as a tight unit and to continue to function when the fatigue sets in!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;And if you could set a goal for yourself and your team?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Finish a game without a spew or a cry, working on my mental game is a constant priority as well as my on track skills. As a team, I just want to end every game as a happy wee unit proud of what we have just done.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;My personal goal is the same as it was when I first started skating, which is to get lower! As a team if we can continue to work together, support each other on and off track and leave each game with a sense of achievement, then that's a job well done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26534" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/fbimage-01-1.png" alt="FBImage-01 (1)" width="6035" height="8534"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15th April 2018&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; Dundee DISC&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/908750512641504/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Event Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; 12:30-5pm&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; £6 on the door&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>interviews</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/28/2018-seasons-beginnings-for-drg/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 09:00:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A chat with: Team Middle East Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/08/14/a-chat-with-team-middle-east-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a break from podcast style interviews, Scottish Roller Derby podcasts are back with an interview with one of the co-chairs of new Men's Roller Derby National team, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TMErollerderby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Middle East Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Middle East are actively recruiting for any skaters with eligibility to represent any of the Middle Eastern countries, with an aim to compete in the 2020 Men's Roller Derby World Cup. This would make them the first men's team representing any nations in the middle east, and only the second team representing a Middle Eastern Nation at all (after &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamIranRollerDerby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Iran Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - also still open to applicants - who will represent at the Women's Roller Derby World Cup 2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[soundcloud url="https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/337873869" params="auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true" width="100%" height="450" iframe="true" /]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>team iran roller derby</category><category>team middle east roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/08/14/a-chat-with-team-middle-east-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 20:20:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>DRG's Bonnie Colliders Battle Bairn!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/18/drgs-bonnie-colliders-battle-bairn/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller girls' are hosting their second home game this season as a single header! On the &lt;strong&gt;22nd of July &lt;/strong&gt;at the &lt;strong&gt;D.I.S.C.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Dundee&lt;/strong&gt;, the Bonnie Colliders are taking on Bairn City (&amp;amp; pals!) which looks to be a mighty match! With doors opening at &lt;strong&gt;12:30 &lt;/strong&gt;and first whistle coming in at &lt;strong&gt;1pm,&lt;/strong&gt; it's gonna be a short and sweet single header. Differing from DRG's usual doubles hitters,  these two familiar sides will most certainly make the trip worth while!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-22412 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/19621172_1505774156154661_5391157900722134871_o.jpg" alt="Photo Courtesy: Laura MacDonald" width="520" height="736"&gt;
We thought we would catch up with the Bonnie Colliders Co Captains for 2017, &lt;strong&gt;Breezy Does It #289&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;HullabaLou #17&lt;/strong&gt;, to learn a bit more about leading and shaping a B team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="22420,22421" type="circle" columns="2"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q1: How has the season gone so far for you guys? You've have a few games already and you seem to come out strong both sides.
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breezy:  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;This season has been amazing so far, we've played those two games and won both, which is super exciting! The team is really starting to gel together and we are getting better every time we play. We've had a few newer skaters join us and they are coming on great and are fitting in well with the team.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HullabaLou: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's just been so epic this season, I am so so proud of everyone! To see our wee team taking the skills that we drill together every week at training and scrims, and put them into practice during games is fantastic – whether it’s fancy new toe stop spins, some super controlled one-one blocking or crushing offense; the commitment and effort from every person on the team is something that I respect hugely and do not take for granted as a Captain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q2: And so the Colliders have played a Bairn side a few times, with the most recent in 2015 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/71209" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;[FTS]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;. How does that change your look on this match-up?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I was off on maternity for all of 2015 so unfortunately wasn't part of the team on that one but I was there for the previous year and it was such a tough game! Bairn have continued to grow so much since then, really we're looking at them as a brand new opponent. Which for a lot of our Colliders this season - they will be!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The 2015 game&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; was one of the firsts for quite a few of us who had just been rostered for the B team, and was definitely quite an experience for us haha! Bairn are so lovely and we genuinely can’t wait to play them again, but will definitely be needing as many of our Collidoscopes (our loyal fans) to support us as possible!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q3: How do you guys approach a game when you are captaining, what goes through your mind?
&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;B:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I approach all games in a similar manner, nervous anticipation! The difference as a Co-Captain is that I like to check in with all the skaters to find out how they're feeling, as Lou and I want each skater to enjoy themselves and feel comfortable on game day. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ll we want as Captains is to ensure our team has an absolute blast on game day, I just want to help them smash their goals and whip out those hard-practiced skills! Colliders are definitely all about soaking up the sheer enjoyment of simply playing roller derby together! To quote our wonderful co-chair Milky “It’s just a made-up game on roller skates” and so I try to focus on that…we are from Fundee after all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q4: With the Silvery Tayzers (Dundee's A team) getting quite a lot of focus now with the league being full WFTDA members, do you feel that adds more pressure for you guys, or is it the opposite and you loose some track time as a B team?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DRG train as a league, first and foremost. We all skate together. We have skaters who've just passed their minimum skills alongside our Team Scotland skaters. It is a huge benefit to all our skaters as we work together to push each other on in every aspect. As a team, the Colliders do get lots of track time together to work as a unit, and practice our tactics and skills, but training alongside the Silvery Tayzers really pushes us out of our comfort zones and helps us develop further. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DRG definitely think of ourselves as a league rather than 2 teams – we train together, scrim together and thoroughly support each other; the success of the Tayzers and their sweeeeet wftda ranking (266th!)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;[16/07/2017 FTS]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; has only boosted our league spirit. And likewise when the Colliders smash it, the mad support from the rest of the league is just unparalleled. Personally, that’s one of the things I love most about DRG: Our wonderful bouting committee have always placed an equal importance on getting games for both Colliders and Tayzers….so short answer – no, we never lose track time!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q5: With that in mind, what do you guys aim for, for yourselves and your team? It must be hard to maintain such a close-knit team, with skaters moving on to the A team or with the new intake coming up.
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; My aim is to work alongside all of our current skaters and those moving up from the new skater programme to encourage them to practice in the hopes that our team can grow stronger. As for keeping the team close knit, I think that comes from our training atmosphere. Lou and I are very open in terms of communication and encourage skaters to bring any issues to us in the hopes that everyone feels driven but not pushed, as being a Collider is always about having the best experience possible and taking away as much as you can from both training, scrimmage and game days!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I think that as a team we definitely drive ourselves forward and regardless of experience-level our training committee has always worked us hard to constantly improve our play. Being a B team, the roster is a lot more dynamic; newer skaters come up, more experienced skaters move to the A team, and it changes a lot. We do actively focus on learning how each other blocks/jams so can we gel on track but because we all train together, even when a skater does reach a certain level experience and makes that tough decision to bout exclusively with the A team, it doesn’t really feel like we’ve lost them because we'll be drilling/scrimming with them the week after anyways. Saying that we did have a very emotional locker-room-team-cry after a speech from last season’s stepping down Captains… but I think that just goes to show how much we bond as a team…or perhaps how emotionally unstable a bunch of us are…possibly both.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out more about the upcoming game (&lt;strong&gt;Saturday 22nd July&lt;/strong&gt;) Check out the facebook event page here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/146108915947622/?acontext=%7B%22source%22%3A5%2C%22page_id_source%22%3A133126163419474%2C%22action_history%22%3A%5B%7B%22surface%22%3A%22page%22%2C%22mechanism%22%3A%22main_list%22%2C%22extra_data%22%3A%22%7B%5C%22page_id%5C%22%3A133126163419474%2C%5C%22tour_id%5C%22%3Anull%7D%22%7D%5D%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Colliders vs Bairn and pals!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open: &lt;strong&gt;12:30
&lt;/strong&gt;Tickets: &lt;strong&gt;£5 (on the door)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>captains</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/18/drgs-bonnie-colliders-battle-bairn/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 08:30:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>We're All Going on a Summer Brawliday</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/11/were-all-going-on-a-summer-brawliday/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/granitecitybrawlers/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (GCB) are preparing for their next game. This one promises to be extra special, not only is this the first Brawlers game outside of Scotland BUT it's also the first Brawlers game outside of the U.K.! The Brawlers are heading to Tenerife to play against &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Tibicenas-Mens-Roller-Derby-796092177146242/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tibicenas Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (TMRD).
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22166" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/img_0039.jpg" alt="" width="724" height="1024"&gt; Bout Poster courtesy of Tibicenas Men's Roller Derby&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to check  in with captains Pudz and Momo to ask about how the team are preparing for their next game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TMRD have previously played Madrid MadRiders but despite some serious snooping, I can't find any teams to link GCB to TMRD. Since this makes it super hard to make any predictions about the game, there is additional excitement. [&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRankv2.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SRDRank&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; gives the Brawlers the advantage over their hosts, but with low certainty - Ed.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;You played Oldham earlier this year and were victorious, how are you feeling about taking on Tibicenas Men's Roller Derby? &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Have you seen them play before or met any of the players during your World Cup experiences?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pudz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nervous but excited at the same time. We've scoured the internet for footage to watch but come up short so are going into this game a little bit blind as to our opponent's style. Unless you count their uploads of the T Rex on skates, if the dinosaur gets rostered we'll be facing a new challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Momo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We trained really hard on the run up to the Oldham game, I think we stepped up drastically from our previous game last year. We went back through the previous game and pin-pointed every weakness and focused heavily on certain aspects that were lacking; we're not perfect yet but the guys really worked hard and for the first time at the Oldham game we had in all sense's of the word: a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tenerife is a complete wild card! None of us know what to expect from the team and I think a lot of the guys are underestimating how hot it's going to be; myself and Pudz have a good idea how hard it's going to be after playing in Canada [at MRDWC] last year. TMRD will have the advantage being used to playing in the heat, and I think we are only playing with 9* so it's going to be seriously tough. Whatever happens we'll do all we can do and have fun knowing we have a holiday after the game as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We haven't seen the roster yet and I'm not sure if anyone played in the World Cup but it's obviously quite possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*GCB will now be playing with 10 skaters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tell me about your fundraising efforts to get the team and crew over to Tenerife &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pudz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five of our Brawlers are doing a sponsored leg wax to help cover the costs of skater insurance and the bus to the game in Tenerife. Whichever Brawler has the most money against their name will be getting a nice pre holiday leg wax. #waxonwaxbrawff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoever has the highest funds against them is going to have an itchy time in the crazy heat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/img_0038-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22170" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/img_0038-1.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/waxonwaxbrawff"&gt;http://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/waxonwaxbrawff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;What sort of special preparation are you doing as a team/individual for playing in such a super warm place?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pudz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team have been doing "jumper scrims" in preparation for the game to try and adjust to the heat. These have been met with sad faces from our peely wally Brawlers but have been good fun and shown off Raffers' fine selection of Christmas Jumpers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also invited some guests to scrim against the Brawler Tenerife roster as a warm up which went very well. Our Brawlers' hard work is paying off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Momo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've been training with jumpers on during scrims to help with heat training and our scrims are generally quite intense, almost "iron man" if you like, so it's good for the endurance, especially since we're playing with 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a scrim with the "Tenerife 9" vs the rest of the Brawlers, some GCRD members, and some Bairn City members last weekend, a good mixed bunch to help us prepare. They were great, totally mixed it up and they didn't take it easy on us! It went well and gave us a few more things to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;How does preparation for an international game differ to preparing for a local game?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pudz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to think about things like jet lag [not to Tenerife though! - Ed], lower roster numbers due to the distance travelled and, most importantly, the bar order; "Tres sidras por favor!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a team we are very excited to represent Scottish roller derby on an international scale, strengthening the roller derby community even further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Momo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preparing for Tenerife seems a lot more labour intensive from an organising point of view. If it wasn't for Nikki, Brawlers' Bench Manager, sorting the entire thing out I think we'd be walking from one end of the island to the other to get to the game. I did my bit as well though: I organised a rainbow of the best beach towels Scotland's ever seen! We're obviously doing our heat training and some of us have been working on our after party stamina to last the entire holiday, I guess maybe some of the guys have been working on their beach bods, not likely but maybe....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've lost a few skaters at the start of this year/ tail end of last year but we've gained some new young blood with loads of potential and honestly the Brawlers are the strongest we've ever been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're looking forward to what we have planned for the rest of 2017 and can't wait to see what 2018 brings!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22169" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/img_0040.jpg" alt="img_0040" width="1024" height="682"&gt; Photo Credit: Len Rizzo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge 'thank you' to Pudz and Momo for taking the time to answer my questions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, for one, am so excited for the first GCB international game and wish the team loads of luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, there's still time to donate and nominate your favourite brawler for a cheeky leg wax! &lt;a href="http://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/waxonwaxbrawff"&gt;http://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/waxonwaxbrawff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Brawlers/Tibicenas bout is in just 10 days - &lt;strong&gt;22 July&lt;/strong&gt;. The Facebook event is: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1910383885902598/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1910383885902598/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>tenerife</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/11/were-all-going-on-a-summer-brawliday/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 08:00:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WFTDA Membership Status for DRG</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/28/wftda-membership-status-for-drg/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you may have heard last week, the Women's Flat Track Derby Association (WFTDA) has extended full membership status to nine graduating leagues after completion of the WFTDA apprenticeship program! The full list of new members can be found in the press release &lt;a href="https://wftda.com/wftda-adds-9-new-members/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leagues announced included members from across the United States, South America and more in line with our reporting: Europe! On the back of four skaters making the Team Scotland squad; Dundee Roller Girls becomes only the third league in Scotland to receive this graduated status!  Interestingly enough, Tenerife Roller Derby, the hosts of the &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/15/tenerife-roller-derby-bringing-the-heat-to-winter-tournaments/" target="_blank"&gt;December tournament &lt;/a&gt;that featured the Dundee side, have also graduated to full WFTDA membership!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are currently&lt;i&gt; (as of March 2017) &lt;/i&gt;399 WFTDA member leagues and 54 leagues in the WFTDA Apprentice program globally. Leagues joining these ranks enjoy benefits including the ability to compete in sanctioned games, discussions with other member leagues and access to learning resources for skaters and officials. Dundee Roller Girls begin their WFTDA membership a Class C member and we caught up with the leagues co chairs, &lt;strong&gt;Laura Liston #07&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Crown Jewels #67&lt;/strong&gt;, for a chance to learn a bit the history of DRG and what the future holds for this up and coming league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="16584,16583" type="circle" columns="2"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Q: Hi guys! So WFTDA full membership, a pretty huge step for a league that was skating in a car park at the back of 2009, eh?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;L: It's huge for us. I still can't quite believe we get to consider ourselves in the ranks of the incredible teams in WFTDA. Everyone has worked really hard over the years to keep our wee league together so this is a lovely reward.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CJ: Ha Ha! Yes a massive leap for us. I think it’s just amazing how we’ve managed to progress, I think most leagues probably started off in a similar fashion, a very much DIY existence. It still is (DIY) today but there is so much more awareness around derby that is does become slightly easier to progress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: So with Dundee Roller Girls forming around 2011, you both have been involved for a long time. How have you seen the league grow in these past few years?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L: For me I think the biggest growth we've seen is when we created our B team and home teams. Giving our newer skaters the opportunity to develop and to get game experience has allowed the whole league to grow - from them getting games to our new officials getting game experience at an appropriate level. So proud of them all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CJ: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;We’ve seen a lot of league members come and go, but there are still a core few that remain. Year on year we’ve continued to build a group of league members that wants to do their best for DRG, whether that’s officiating or skating. I think the drive in people is what pushes the league forward. We have so many committed members that look for the best guest coaches to come to the league, arrange challenging games for us, run the financial side of things and look to push us on to the next level. This is what has allowed the league to grow to where it is now and will continue to do so in future. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;i&gt;What was the deciding factors for you guys to pursue the WFTDA Apprenticeship program? Was it a hard decision for the league to make since it is quite a lot of work that goes into the full program?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L: It was a lot of work in terms of admin but it made sense as the next step for us. Being so isolated in Scotland, we were finding it hard to find leagues of a similar level who would travel to play us. Joining WFTDA has given us more game opportunities and more varied game offers. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CJ: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;I don’t think it was a hard decision to make, it’s something we have aspired to for a long time and again allows us to push the league forward. The deciding factor was probably looking to get us more involvement in international events, to face and learn from some of the best leagues in the world.
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;i&gt;An interesting point to maybe make here is your discontinued presence in British Championships this year.. Did your decision to pursue WFTDA membership affect your attendance to Brit Champs 2017? A close miss to promotion in 2016, and a great game against Swansea held high promise for your league in the following year?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L: The main factor involved in us leaving British Champs was the organisation as a whole. Having to travel so far to each game meant we needed the organisation to be really clear and far in advance, which it wasn't for us. Our B team was also really disadvantaged by our A team's involvement in Champs as it meant their season was quite limited. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CJ: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;I think partly it did affect our decision to leave champs. We needed to try to make sure we were focusing our energies in one direction and for us, as a league on a whole, that was WFTDA.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: We have already seen your league representing internationally with the aforementioned Tenerife Tournament, are we going to see more of the Dundee crew hitting sights outside of the UK?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;L: Well our officials are now travelling all over Europe for games - Spain, Sweden, Finland and Norway recently. The Colliders are also heading to Ireland this year!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CJ: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;Let’s hope so! My dream is to get to Vienna (my favourite city) after that I may retire! It would be great to get further afield but sometimes finances are a limiting factor in that respect.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Q: Do you have any tips for aspiring leagues, either the new leagues blossoming in Scotland or others wishing to gain WFTDA status?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;!-- I have clearly run out of good Questions.. --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;L: To go for it! WFTDA membership isn't related to wins, or scores etc. It's for leagues who want a say in the future of roller derby. The support we had to develop through Apprenticeship from Auld Reekie, Newcastle Roller Girls and our rep from Hellfire Harlots was amazing.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;CJ: I think mainly consult other leagues for advice. We have always been helped immensely by other leagues in Scotland and across the UK and we are always willing to provide advice to other leagues. Decide on what you want your focus to be and aim for it, find out as much as you can about what you want to achieve and ensure you have committed league members willing to put in the work towards it.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>wftda</category><category>wftda apprenticeship</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/28/wftda-membership-status-for-drg/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 10:00:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: A Chat with: Paris Rollergirls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/07/euroclash-interviews-a-chat-with-paris-rollergirls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next up in our series of interviews with the attendees at Newcastle Roller Girls' &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is the second mainland European team, a team tipped for greatness by The Derby Apex... &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.parisrollergirls.com/"&gt;Paris Rollergirls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-15753" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/prg2017.jpg?w=600" alt="PRG2017" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the two top leagues and teams in France, vying with Toulouse for the top spot, Paris Rollergirls had an exceptional 2016, winning the Elite tier of the French National (against Toulouse, by only a few points), travelling to the USA for the first time (at Beach Brawl), and making serious gains in their WFTDA Rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They've also had the time to mark their 7th anniversary with, amongst other things, a stylish rebranding with an iconic Tour Eiffel logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to Paris' Kill Belle about their 2016, their plans for EuroClash, and their seriously exciting schedule for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[soundcloud url="https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/311055810" params="auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true" width="100%" height="450" iframe="true" /]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash will be held from the &lt;strong&gt;25th&lt;/strong&gt; to the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt;, at the Walker Activity Dome, Newcastle. Tickets available from the EuroClash &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, at £&lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt; advance, £&lt;strong&gt;30&lt;/strong&gt; on the door. (Day tickets £15 on the door).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>euroclash</category><category>international derby</category><category>paris rollergirls</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/07/euroclash-interviews-a-chat-with-paris-rollergirls/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 09:51:26 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>