<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about an interview with...)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/an-interview-with.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:34:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Lannthrax Talks to: Wintourope Glasgow edition</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/16/lannthrax-talks-to-wintourope-glasgow-edition/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So if you were at the Glasgow edition of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1717432861812471/"&gt;Wintourope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, you should probably by now, know your Toe Stop Pop from your Zip Zap Zop. If not, then I'm sorry, all I have for you is an interview with the lovely coaches. Scald Eagle and Lady Trample took the time to chat with me and I must admit, I felt like a fan-girl. These guys are two of my favourite skaters to watch and I'm so glad I got this opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13937 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/wintourope.jpg" alt="wintourope" width="960" height="354"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lanna&lt;/strong&gt;- “ How do you guys deal with the fame attribution that comes along with being at the top level within the sport?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scald&lt;/strong&gt;- “First of all, Fame is fleeting. What might be hot now might be day-old news next week. Saying that, I will always do my best regardless of status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The derby fame is something that you just have to deal with; I can still walk into a 7/11 and no one knows who I am, but you wouldn't see Lebron James walk into a 7/11. However, if I walk in to Rollercon, that’s a different story. Sometimes it’s hard to just make it to the bathroom and back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what I've really worked on is to put time aside and do what needs to be done but also make sure I have time to do what I need to do. It's great though: I am more than happy to have those interactions and I love it. It feels just like yesterday for me that I was waiting in line to get stuff signed and having people that I looked up to. I have a lot of patience for it and I love to do it”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trample&lt;/strong&gt;- “ One of the interesting things about, it is there is a level of responsibility, you have to be careful about what you put in the public eye. You are so accessible through social media. However, it also gives you a chance to do things for the community and opportunities to travel and share your knowledge, which I think Isn't really a thing you would see in other sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lanna&lt;/strong&gt;- “ Mental resilience is something that I personally have struggled with, how do you guys switch off that part of your brain and just get the job done?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trample&lt;/strong&gt;- “It’s something that comes with time; I had a really great coach this year and the main thing he would say to me is to back myself, so much so that I actually got a tattoo of it. It’s a nice memento that I can take with me to remind myself that I've worked hard and to trust my instincts, my pack, my offence, defence and my coaches. If your team are putting you on the line, they believe in you. It takes a little bit of self belief: I played some of my hardest games last year and once I got on that line I just had to remind myself that I've done all the training and to just let it all come into motion”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scald&lt;/strong&gt;- “I think that's where I'm at. In gameplay my cognitive part switches off and my instincts take over, I let my muscle memory do its thing. I don't know how often I have to actually tell myself to continue because it’s more like that's what I have to do, it's instinct. When I think about mental fortitude it’s about getting through practice week to week and living through the dynamics of my team at that level. When you're at that level you don't have the choice to just switch to the next team across town. If you want to play at that level I think the hardest part in my opinion is not figuring out how to deal with your opponents but how you can work well with your team mate”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lanna&lt;/strong&gt;- “ What have your highlights of the Winter Tour been so far ?”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scald&lt;/strong&gt;- “ (adopts an awkward Scottish accent) Shcotland! Och aye ye wee lass, We're in the land of Ootlander an' its ma favourite show and a cannae wait to be here. Its gonnae be a great time. (Back to American) I am super excited to be up here, I've been once before and I loved it. In the US we spent a lot of time re-visiting leagues that I had already been to so it was a lot about going and seeing old friends. We spent our time on the south west but I anticipate that next time round we will head along the east. As far as for the Wintourope Tour, my last name is Buschovik, so I’m really excited to go to Poland. I don't know much what it’s going to be like but it’s going to be an experience. The point of life is to experience new things so...”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trample&lt;/strong&gt;- “ I'm super excited to be in Europe because I've never been on this side of the world. I have a little bit of heritage in Scotland so it was cool to come and explore this place a little bit. Everywhere we are going is exciting to me and there's people who I've been talking to online for the past few years who I'm now getting to meet. They are all coming to our ramp camps and people are travelling all over the world to get to the different bootcamps. Chicks in Bowls is at close to 250 Chapters and it’s amazing I get to meet so many of the Chapter admins and members”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lanna&lt;/strong&gt;- “ And finally, What advice would you give to skaters who want to improve their game?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scald&lt;/strong&gt; - “I think that off skates training is really important, mostly from an injury prevention standpoint. You may not like going to the gym, but going to the ER is much less fun. Having strong quads helps you have strong knees and as women we have naturally weak knees so it's imperative that we strengthen the muscles around them so that they can withstand the torque we put them under. Same with ankles, there's so many baby ankle muscles and foot muscles that we need to look after. If you want to be a kick ass skater and be better than the person next to you then you need to start doing some squats with weight and different things like that. At Rose specifically one of the keys to our success, I believe, is that we have a required gym hour 2 hours a week where we all train together in the gym.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trample&lt;/strong&gt;- “ I don't really do off skates, I know, I'm bad. But I have recently been convinced by Scald that I should be hitting the gym especially to do Pre-hab. I rolled my ankle a while back and I'll do the rehab until its better but then I'm straight back on skates, and it’s not good because a few months later I'll roll my ankle again and it’s because I didn't build up the strength that I needed to help the muscles fully recover and be strong enough to stop the injury from happening again. So I am in a position now where I'm going to push myself to do it”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, there you have it. It was an absolute pleasure to interview these lovely ladies and hopefully you all take something away from my questions. Huge thanks to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GlasgowMensRollerDerby/"&gt;GMRD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for hosting a fantastic event and making sure the day was super fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Till next time
Much Love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next WinTourope is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1852698681626181/"&gt;WinTourope Poland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, this weekend (21-22nd Jan), followed by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/227698337655754/"&gt;Netherlands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/381880268819988/"&gt;France&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and finally &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/146844349126661/"&gt;England&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>chicks in bowls</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>training</category><category>wintourope</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/16/lannthrax-talks-to-wintourope-glasgow-edition/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 19:25:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An interview with Lothian Derby Dolls' Captain: Fully Harmed</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/18/an-interview-with-lothian-derby-dolls-captain-fully-harmed/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The third team we've covering in the run up to Auld Reekie Roller Girls' &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/535844416618826/"&gt;ARRGmageddon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Tournament is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/lothianderby/"&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. LDD are, perhaps, the underdogs coming into the tournament in some ways, having lost to Dundee's Bonnie Colliders early this year. However, their roster at that point was somewhat different to their current lineup, so it's really hard to call.
We talked to their Captain, Fully Harmed, to see how Lothian's year has been, and how they're thinking about the upcoming Tournament:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- So, I think it's fair to say that Lothian Derby Dolls have had a mixed year so far; early on you had a few losses against the Bonnie Colliders and Mean City, but more recently you pulled off a win against Ayrshire Roller Derby away... how would you say the league is steering itself?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I would say this year has been very mixed. We started off quite low; I think with LDD it's always very skater dependant, and we lost a few reliable, strong skaters. We've really spent the summer building up our core again. We've got a reliable lot of, I'd say, 15 skaters, but, because of the type of league we are...  you know, it could be chicken pox and, because we're mums, that could be (say) 5 skaters off for a couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We've also had some injuries with some of our players, Poca Loca [LDD ViceCaptain] came back quite strong from an ankle injury, but she's still not 100%, and Fury has a niggling knee injury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;However, I &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; say it's been a really really positive year, because while we've really stepped back from bouting, we've really worked on our skill, to get that more solid; our skills, our communication, our teamwork. Definitely, on taking over as Captain, that's been our focus as a team: it's not about winning or losing in my eyes, (I mean, a win's brilliant) it's about us all having our personal goals, and as a team having a goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We are a little league; we're the smallest of the leagues who will be playing [in ARRGmageddon], by miles. I mean, we've got 30 active skaters just now.  For us to be even putting ourselves forward for the tournament, we've come a long way, this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Ayrshire was a brilliant experience; lovely people, lovely skaters. We were really happy to win, but for us it was more about showing that working on our skills together as a team, and you know, it really proved to us that when you work on your skills and trust each other, it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;So, thats the change from the [bout against the] Bonnie Colliders... when we played them, we weren't really working well as a team, I would say we got downheartened very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;These days,  as a Captain, I'm pushing&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;- "Fine, if we're losing, we're working on Our Goals, all the time, keep strong, .. " So you know, I'm not expecting a win, in a week's time, but I'm expecting us to have our goals and win that way !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- Despite you saying that, LDD are the only team competing at ARRGmageddon who've actually had Tournament experience (from the Battle of Britain tournament in 2013). Quite a few of the skaters from 2013's roster are still around, has their experience helped in preparation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I think it does help. The skaters who were involved in that experience, you know, they've been very honest - that there's negative [factors] to being involved in a tournament - but, we've talked about that, and we're going to try to avoid those issues with people's stamina, and try to keep the positivity going all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I think, compared to [Battle of Britain], there's a lot more positivity, there's a lot more — happiness - I feel positive, regardless of the score, that LDD will&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;come out, and we'll play strongly, we'll work together well, but, you know, we're against big teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;But, I think that previous experience will help us - we've got a lot of players with [general] experience, though. We just keep everything calm, and…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- When the high of the tournament has passed, what's coming up next for LDD?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Well, other than the tournament, we're looking for return matches, with New Town and the Fight Hawks, we're looking at some more new bouts with new teams, which are about our levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The problem with [finding bouts in] Scotland, is you've got Glasgow, ARRG, Granite, Dundee, even the [Bairn City Rollers'] Central Belters are up there, and Fierce Valley,… and then there's us. [Our interest is] trying to play with more teams that are our level, so we can get better scrims, and bouting experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;But, also, we're really working on our Coed. Fear and Lothian were our big piece of work we did this year, with Capital City, and I think training with men has brought a different dynamic to the team. Definitely, it's speeded up our game: we've got less time to stop and think about things on track.
So, Fear and Lothian will be having a bout, we've got a couple of idea of teams, we're just negotiating that at the minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;That's definitely a focus for LDD as well, keeping the Coed going - and really working on our female game, consolidating all the skills we've been working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;So, we're feeling positive. And I think we're the kind of team that, you know, it doesn't matter if we win or lose, but … the thing about Ayrshire was, they're a great team, they think about this the same way as us: you go out and you do the best you can, and you enjoy it - I mean, that's why we all do it&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;- you enjoy yourself, that's sometimes forgot. And, we are a team that really do; we socialise together, we love each other, we support each other, if we're injured,&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;and we do have a lot of kids and they play together too. It sounds a bit mushy, but we're very much in and out of each others' lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;And, it sounds terrible, but if somebody hurts one of my Dolls, I'll do everything I can to support them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;So, very much, we've got a lot of camaraderie between us, and I think we've come along way together, through all the ups and downs for LDD; I'm sure there's more to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We are a wee league I mean, ARRG's got about 60 skaters and you can't… compare them.But actually,  I've skated with some of the girls from the C team, you know, at scrims and things, and they're a lovely bunch, so...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I think LDD's getting to know leagues a bit better, I mean, Dundee are very friendly with us, and Granite too… so it'll be an enjoyable day, we're really looking forward to it.

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The ARRGmageddon Tournament is running on the &lt;strong&gt;26 November&lt;/strong&gt;, at Auld Reekie's usual venue of &lt;strong&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/strong&gt;, as an all-day event starting at &lt;strong&gt;11am&lt;/strong&gt;.. Ticket prices are £8 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2714193"&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, £10 (£6 concessions) on the door, free entry for under 14's.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>arrgmageddon</category><category>articles</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/18/an-interview-with-lothian-derby-dolls-captain-fully-harmed/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 13:40:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An interview with: ASTROs Captain, Princess Die</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/12/an-interview-with-astros-captain-princess-die/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.arrg.co.uk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; have a had a pretty good year to date, and perhaps no better is this expressed than in the fortunes of their new C Team, the Auld Reekie All-Stars Rookies, who've been busily bouting since March this year, and already clocked up two wins.
On the &lt;strong&gt;19th&lt;/strong&gt;, they'll be flying across to Belfast to take on Belfast City Rockets in their first "international" bout, so we thought we'd catch up with ASTROs Captain Princess Die to see how they've managed to do so much so quickly!
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-11272" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/die.jpg?w=400" alt="die" width="500"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;So, you've been in ARRG since before the ASTROs ever existed, and now you're captaining them. Tell us a bit about how being Captain is going, since … March this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die: So, we set up the team in March, and had our first game around June [against Granite City's Fight Hawks].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was captain of the [ARRG B, the Cannon] Belles, and then the Reserves after that (when the Belles changed their name to the Reserves), and I've been Captain for a home seasons team as well, so I've been a Captain for quite a long time, and I'm really proud of that. When the ASTROs were set up, it was a sort of mixed team - it was a team of newer skaters, coupled with some returning skaters - I'd just taken a year off skating to have a baby, so I was returning - and we had some people who were just returning from injury and things. I suppose the two factors - my previous experience, and that I'd returned from a year off skates - meant that I could relate to all levels of experience in the team, and bring a lot as captain, so I was totally honoured to be nominated. To be fair, I was the only one who was nominated, so I didn't have a lot of choice, but I'm still very proud to lead our team!
It's been really good: developing new skaters is something that I love doing; I coach the Fresh Meat classes, or Skate Skills as we call it now, I coach at all levels, but I mostly coach the beginner classes. I really enjoy developing new skaters, so it's been really fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;The ASTROs have had a pretty good innings so far, with victories over Granite City B, and Mean City Women, and a not bad loss against your strongest opponents so far, Dundee's Bonnie Colliders. You must be happy with the track record to date?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die: Yes! We've done really well! We've developed some quite specific tactics, that we've really really worked hard on, and, when we played Mean City away a couple of weeks ago, and we really saw how good our tactics were, and how they worked, that was lovely to see.
Everybody in the team is incredibly dedicated, working towards these tactics, and thankfully they're all really responsive to my ideas, (which sometimes are really bad!). But we go with it, and we work things out, and see what works and what doesn't and it's been really interesting and fun, but we've done very well.
We've also had two closed bouts, which we won both of as well!
So, yeah, we've had a really good run, so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-11253" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/princessdphoto.jpg?w=2048" alt="princessdphoto" width="1024" height="683"&gt; Princess Die, left, facing off against Mean City in the ASTROs' most recent victory. (Photo: Laura MacDonald)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;Of course, your next bout is on the 19th, against Belfast City Rockets, your first "proper" away game, flying across the Irish Sea. How do you feel about the extra challenge of your first international - Flat Track Stats today &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/20657/79213"&gt;predicts&lt;/a&gt; a 50:50 perfect split as to the winner!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die:Oh, really? [laughs] Okay, that's exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erm; we're &lt;em&gt;incredibly&lt;/em&gt; excited. There are just four people on the team who've travelled for away games before, for the kind of away games where you're leaving the country, so it's relatively new for pretty much everyone on the team. So, everyone's really excited that we're going away, first of all.
A lot of people who are on the ASTROs have been members of ARRG and skating for a while, but haven't been on a travel team, so they've been through seeing other teams go on their trips and things, So everyone's very excited about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of the game, we are really really working to nail down our tactics, and we do really think that our strengths lie in our tactical knowledge and our tactical awareness, and how together we are as a team. We have a lot of trust, we do a lot of trust-building skills and exercises and things, and we've really developed this intense trust with each other which I think really works on track. So we're hoping we can bring that with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;Yes, one comment that's often been made of the ASTROs when seeing you for the first time, is that you're very "together" for a C, or even a B team. Sometimes B teams tend to be more 'relaxed', but you're all doing very cohesive activity as soon as you arrive at a venue.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die: Yeah, we do, yeah. I think its just an "ARRG" way of being I think: we practise "zenfully", so we keep ourselves calm and into each other. We don't watch the track, or we try not to, when we're on the bench; we don't watch the play that's happening, we try to focus on what we're gonna do, rather than what's happening right now. We focus on each other, rather than the other team, and you know, that's the kind of way that &lt;em&gt;ARRG&lt;/em&gt; works, right from All-Stars all the way down.
Certainly, in terms of my experience, having played on the B team for a couple of years before I had taken time off and our Bench Coach [Lex Louthor] also a Reserves skater - we were on the Belles and the Reserves together at the B-team level - we've kind of brought that experience down to the C team. Straight from Day 1, we've been like, "we're playing this as seriously as any other travel team". And I think that takes some people that we play by surprise, because, like you say, they tend to be a bit more relaxed at B team level, and so when coming to a C team, they think it's going to be really quite relaxed, and quite easy, and then we just put up a fight, and they're like, "Allright, okay!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;So, we hear that, even after Belfast, there's more excitement in the ASTROs' future?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die: Yeah, we've got a tournament! We're hosting a Scottish tournament on the 26th of November; we've invited .. we've got 2 B teams, and an A team, and the ASTROs playing in the tournament. There's Lothian Derby Dolls, A team, Granite City B team, and Dundee's B team. The four teams are going to play off against each other in short games, in the morning, and then in the afternoon there'll be two full games - one for our 3rd and 4th place playoff , and one for 1st and 2nd place. So, we're very excited about that.
Obviously, we've played Dundee B team this year, and Granite City B team this year, and we won against Granite City, but we lost against Dundee. So, I don't want to call this a grudge match, but we're all really wanting to beat Dundee this time…
A number of us played in the WarriARRGs, which is our ARRG pick-up team, a mixed-ability pickup team, with advanced and less advanced skaters together, and we played also Dundee's B team as the WarriARRGs this year,… and we lost. So we really want to beat Dundee in the tournament! That's our biggest goal at the moment!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can make it to Belfast on the &lt;strong&gt;19th&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/761145590695158/"&gt;bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; will be held at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Queen's+Sport/@54.580861,-5.9318286,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x486108e58874e8db:0x50f3671ebfcba059!8m2!3d54.580861!4d-5.9296346"&gt;Queen's Sport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, with doors opening at &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt;. Tickets &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; on the door, under 12s free.
We'll have details of the tournament on the 26th, as well as more content, closer to the time!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>astros</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/12/an-interview-with-astros-captain-princess-die/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 09:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Interview With... outgoing Team England Coach, Ballistic Whistle!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/10/an-interview-with-outgoing-team-england-coach-ballistic-whistle/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of people were surprised to hear that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamenglandrollerderby/"&gt;Team England Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s Ballistic Whistle announce that he did not intend to reapply for the role in the current round of recruitment. (The applications for the Team England (Women's) coaching and management roles are currently being voted on.) Considering his contributions to Roller Derby, both in the National teams, and also ongoing with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://londonrollergirls.com/"&gt;London Rollergirls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.southerndiscomfort.co.uk/"&gt;Southern Discomfort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, we thought it was a good idea to catch up with him and talk about, well, him.
(This interview is also undertaken in collaboration with the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UK Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, as part of our National Teams series.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/10/an-interview-with-outgoing-team-england-coach-ballistic-whistle/9012365607_0dd177bdf1_k/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-7241"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-7241" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/9012365607_0dd177bdf1_k.jpg?w=700" alt="Ballistic Whistle (London Rollergirls v Rat City) (Photo: Eric Von Flickr)" width="700" height="467"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Ballistic Whistle (London Rollergirls v Rat City) (Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/31756530@N08/9012365607"&gt;Steve Messerer&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Despite the wide range of your involvement in Roller Derby, you're probably best known as the Coach and Bench Manager of London Roller Girls, who pretty much were the vanguard of Europe's entry into the top levels of Roller Derby. Did you feel responsible, in a way, for representing the UK or Europe in the early days of LRG going across to the States (and is it more of a relief that other teams are now increasingly high level)?&lt;/strong&gt;
I don't feel that was ever a specific goal or aim of ours. From a really early stage we had aspirations of travelling to the States to play high level derby. That benchmark over the years has continued to be pushed on and on to test how far we can go. Through our first tour of the States, and the first visit of American teams to our shores it was quite evident just how much support we were receiving from the UK and Europe. Feeling that during our Stateside trips has always been amazing for us and serves as quite an emotional motivator when away from home. If we have had an impact on how enthusiastic other players and teams are for playing the sport then we've definitely achieved one of our aims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Literally everyone we've spoken to before this interview has mentioned specifically that you're a nice guy (and you parodied this in your appearance in the LRG Fort Wayne's World promo videos [which sadly seem to have mostly disappeared from the internet]). Do you think this surprises people?&lt;/strong&gt;
Haha, that's nice of you to say. I guess I try my best not to irk people on purpose, but I definitely have my foibles and personality clashes just like anyone else. I guess what I find most interesting is how people will formulate an idea of you without ever having met you, purely by how they would expect a person in my position to be. I'll often meet someone for the first time and there will be a period of trying to balance out the shockwaves in our interactions as a result of how they expect me to behave. I'd really love to not have to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As well as coaching and bench managing, you also find the time to play on track, with Southern Discomfort (as well as another signing we'll get to next…). How does your time on track contribute to your coaching decisions (and which would you rather be known as: a great coach, or a great skater)?&lt;/strong&gt;
I took some time off during the 2015 season to try and rehabilitate a back injury. It was during this season that there was a major swing towards formation defense. I realised after a number of months that I was lacking empathy for the difficulty our players had working against this formation. Some of the minor adjustments I was asking our players to make, were actually majorly difficult. Getting back into playing has helped me incredibly to understand what is possible and where the difficulties lie in the modern game. I also get the opportunity to jump in with Brawling from time to time, which I find incredibly helpful to understand what it feels like being inside of the on track action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I roll all of these experiences into my coaching; I guess that answers your parenthesised question. I have no doubt that I love coaching more than playing. I feel like seeing my friends achieve amazing things is much more rewarding for me than achieving them myself. The great thing about fighting to see your team-mates reach their goals, is that you generally achieve yours as a result!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And you recently made the roster for the Team Australia (&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/WizardsofAusDerby/"&gt;Wizards of Aus&lt;/a&gt;) who will be competing at the &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; in Calgary. How did you make the decision to represent your birth nation in the World Cup, and how does it feel to be on the team?&lt;/strong&gt;
Um, actually, it's not my birth nation. I was born in Denmark to a Danish father and Belgian mother. I arrived in Australia on my 2nd birthday and remained there until age 25. But, if you were to ask me what I considered my nationality it would be Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the first World Cup, I had the amazing opportunity to participate with so many of my great derby friends for Team England. Being a part of that team was a fantastic experience, but it wasn't until I was selected for the Australia team that I truly understood what the other players on that English team felt during that first World Cup. In hindsight, I felt incredibly guilty for taking that feeling from someone during the first World Cup, and I feel that is the special thing about that event. Playing for your nation is something that can call on something deeper. At all World Cups I have attended, both male and female, hearing the Australian national anthem has been a...tricky...moment for me emotionally. At this next World Cup, I am going to be so happy to be able to belt out the anthem without any mixed feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You've been Team England Coach for two World Cups, and London Roller Girls coach for 5 years. While both positions are top-level coaching positions, are there more differences than might be apparent?&lt;/strong&gt;
Absolutely. There's no substitute for working with the same team week in week out. You can definitely deliver the most effective change in strategy and refine what you do on track on multiple occasions over a shorter period of time. With both teams you are dealing with a group of incredibly talented skaters, but with Team England it was much more of a situation of building cohesion. Nailing down defaults and making sure, as much as possible, everyone is on the same page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the England team, there was the tricky balance of trying not to be just Brawling + friends, but really appreciate that there are different ways to play. World Cups comprise a number of nations from the extreme fledgling derby countries to the most seasoned. We had always set our sights on taking on the most seasoned. Hopefully in coming World Cup cycles, there will be more English players in other teams who have more of that high-level derby play and will be ready to take on the best countries in the world. With limited training sessions, it becomes a lot more sink or swim when put into that intensely hot cauldron of competition, and so it is all about looking for the players who can take that pressure and really excel. Without the experience of that level, it comes so much more down to personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recently, you announced that you would not be applying for the role of Team England Head Coach this time around. Can we talk a bit about your reasons for this, and your feelings about the decision?&lt;/strong&gt;
The 2015 season was one that definitely took a toll on me. Brawling, at the beginning of the season, had set ourselves what we thought was the ultimate goal (incidentally, we have since understood that the Hydra is not the ultimate goal). Having an amazing season and falling short at the critical time definitely hit me with my first proper feeling of derby burnout in the 9 1/2 years I've been in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we've set our sights even higher than the goals we set last year and I understand what that is going to take from me on a personal level. I also feel that this time around, we are blessed with a number of candidates that could really use this as a springboard to get that experience of that new level. I obviously have mixed feelings about it. Watching England at the World Cup is going to be tough as I'll be wanting the best for all my friends on that team, but will have zero input on helping them achieve that. I'll be waving the 3 Lions flag regardless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, what have been the high and low points in your 6 years as TE Head Coach?&lt;/strong&gt;
Again, it's only 5 years really as the lead up to that first World Cup happened in the same year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lows have always been any time we needed to make some kind of cut to the squad, whether that be to the charter that would go to an event or the roster of 14 that would play. I've been tasked with making these decisions countless times during my life as a coach, but it never gets easy telling talented players that they aren't going to have the opportunity, this time, to do what they love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As bad as those moments are, they are eclipsed by the highs, and I feel like one of the biggest highs was our final against the USA at the 2014 World Cup. Prior to the game I had pored over and re-written my pre-game speech so many times I thought I had written the perfect speech. I got in there and saw all of those players looking at me to hear the message I had for them at that point. Prior to a game where getting all of the 1 percenters right mattered. I threw everything I had written out the window and just spoke from the heart. Anyone in that room will be able to tell you that the message was pretty simple. Regardless of its simplicity, I feel like it resonated with the players, and really struck a chord. In spite of the result, it was one of those games where we just felt like we were playing on point, executing our strategies so well. It all felt so streamlined and precise, against potentially the toughest group of individual skaters you could ever face on track. For it to culminate in one of my derby idols - Kamikaze Kitten - taking us over the 100 point mark in the final jam, I couldn't have asked for a better written story. For me, that game illustrated what Roller Derby (and playing team sport for that matter) is truly all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Given your experience in the role, do you have any advice to pass on to your successor as Head Coach?&lt;/strong&gt;
I feel like there are a lot of coaches out there who work with a top down decision making structure. The coach will dictate the direction and decisions the team makes, sometimes opening the floor to the players for input. When working with some of the best players to ever play the sport, it would be remiss of any coach not to leverage that knowledge and experience. Every single player that played for Team England has a wealth of experience, has an incredibly active derby brain. It's so important to keep those brains ticking over and thinking at a high level, rather than trying to stifle them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with both Brawling and England has shown me that when you are dealing with these incredibly talented groups of players, you are just one equally important part of the team, rather than the single decision making point. Having said that, there definitely comes a point whereby the players need to focus on playing and the decisions need to be directed. The closer to game time this is, the more important it becomes for the coach to take responsibility for decision making. So, rather than a top down, triangle type shape, I think of it more of an hourglass decision making shape. The active brains in the team will feed their ideas into the team's leadership or management, and the leadership with all of this great information will compile it and disseminate a directed decision to the team to execute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, coaching a high level national team at a World Cup is something that not many people the world over will ever be able to say they did with their life. It's exhilarating, and the more you put into it, the greater the reward will be. Don't fuck it up!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team england roller derby</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/10/an-interview-with-outgoing-team-england-coach-ballistic-whistle/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 09:16:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An interview with UKRDA Chair Tess Robinson</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/27/an-interview-with-ukrda-chair-tess-robinson/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the National Squads selection processes well underway, under the Observation of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UK Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, we thought it was a good time to catch up with the organisation's Chair, Tess Robinson, to find out more about what they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-7182" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/fb_img_1461766969488.jpg?w=2046" alt="FB_IMG_1461766969488" width="1023" height="1024"&gt; Tess herself. (Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/graemewillettsphotography/"&gt;Graeme Willetts&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I guess we should start by talking a bit about who you are, and what you do with UKRDA.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I'm Tess Robinson, and I skate with the London Roller Girls B, the Brawl Saints, and I am currently the Chair of the UKRDA Board of Directors, and also the Director of Internal Affairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the Directors has a remit in terms of overseeing different committees, so I directly oversee Membership and Grievances, but really all of the directors are such a big team that we're always communicating and collaborating with each other about everything that comes to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it's not so strict in terms of what people oversee, we just work together to make sure everything runs smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After that easy intro question, I'd like to lead with something a bit more philosophically difficult: what is the purpose of UKRDA?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, our mission statement is: "Promoting and Developing the Growth of the Sport in the UK". So, it would be very specific to the UK: we could just say "Growing and Developing the Sport", but it's specific to what we want to achieve in the country. And I think that's very special - because we have such great teams, and because the UK has something different to everyone else (I think that's true of every nation [that they have unique aspects], but I like what we have here).
We've got specific kind of projects that we're working on now, but really, I just want to, this is a really difficult question…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main thing that I would want people to see the UKRDA as is Themselves! After the AGM this year, I started trying to tout this hashtag, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23YouKRDA"&gt;#YouKRDA&lt;/a&gt; , because I feel that a lot of people think that the UKRDA is a certain person, or a certain group of people. Maybe they think that the UKRDA is the Board of Directors, that we should be Doing Something (and we do, we do do lots of stuff), but people need to understand, and if I'm honest, take responsibility for, the fact that every single person whose team is a UKRDA member is a member of the UKRDA, and they have the power to do whatever they want with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people ask us, "What is the UKRDA, what does the UKRDA do; what is the UKRDA doing, why isn't it doing This?", and the simple answer is: because the community isn't doing it.
We [the Directors] wholeheartedly listen to the members, and we just need our members to know that they have the power as individuals, to instigate any changes that they want to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, for you, the democratic and communal nature of Roller Derby is key to how UKRDA works?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely! UKRDA is a league of leagues. (Or, I think a lot of people are trying to move away from "league" as a word: UKRDA is a Team of Teams.) So, we're just one big Community. We oversee and ensure that everything is running as it should, and as we want it, as a community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the things that I think is key to this Role for UKRDA is your relationships with the other bodies that affect Roller Derby in the UK - the WFTDA (on the side of Roller Derby), and the British Roller Sports Federation (on the side of UK Sports). How you do get on with and interact with them?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a really great relationship with both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a great relationship with the WFTDA. Gareth Lowson, who was the previous Chair, and is our Director of External Engagements, did some amazing work building a strong working relationship with the WFTDA. He met personally with [WFTDA Executive Director 2009-2016, Juliana Gonzales] Bloody Mary a number of times, and they had a really good working relationship.
And the WFTDA have always supported us, especially in things that we've done that they haven't. Like: we've just started sanctioning and chartering B-teams; they were supportive of that idea. There was a big B-Team tournament in the USA last year, I think Gareth went to that, or he spoke to Bloody Mary after that, and told her about this multi-team sanctioning that we were at the time trying to vote through, and she thought it was a really great idea.
It makes me really happy to know that someone representing the Directors of the WFTDA is supportive of what we're trying to achieve. She's always helped with UKROC and been supportive of our events.
Obviously, she's just stepped down, and there's soon going to be a new person in her place [new WFTDA Director Cassie Haynes], and we're hoping that we'll be able to forge the same strong bonds that we've had, with her. But, generally, our relationship with WFTDA has always been good because we're always trying to follow in their footsteps, and they always try to support what we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Well, sometimes you're ahead of them - the UKRDA Gender Policy, for example.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah!, we work together and it's you know, very much a relationship!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other side, with BRSF… BRSF is a really interesting kind of link that we have, because that is how we receive recognition from Sport England, which is kind of the key to sporting achievement and recognition in England. As the biggest organisation for sports in the UK (not to downplay what Scotland and Wales have, we've not had as much of a tie with them) in England at least, they recognise Roller Derby as a sport because we have our tie with the BSRF, which is really great for us. And, it's pretty clear, I haven't got definite numbers but I'm 99% sure that, Roller Derby is officially the biggest roller sport in the UK. Out of all of the other disciplines that the BRSF cover - roller hockey, inline hockey, inline speed skating and artistic skating - I'm pretty sure that we have more members than all of the rest of them combined. So it seems ridiculous that the only way we can garner recognition from these big kind-of multi-sport governing bodies, like Sport England, is through BRSF, given our relative sizes.
But! That's our gateway, and BRSF is a really important organisation, not just for us but for all roller sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;In a way, isn't an entity UKRDA what Sport England needs in order to conceptualise how to interact with a sport, though?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completely!
So, we have strong ties again with BRSF; Gareth sits on their board of Directors as our representative, but I feel like Roller Derby is really a pioneer in Roller Sports in that respect. We are far more proactive and we have a bigger membership, and we're more of a go-getter than the other sports. Probably because we have more that we need to achieve, in terms of getting that recognition, but the other sports aren't really fighting for anything. (But we are.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7176" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/fb_img_1461765537634.jpg" alt="FB_IMG_1461765537634" width="800" height="533"&gt; Tess Robinson with London Brawl Saints versus Glasgow Roller Derby (British Champs Tier 1). (Photo: &lt;a href="http://boutday.com"&gt;Dave McAleavy&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, moving to the internal aspects of UKRDA; obviously, UKRDA has some obvious things that it has organised - there've been two UKROC conferences now, and the Tattoo Freeze tournament is something of a long-standing tradition. What else does UKRDA do for the community?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, Tattoo Freeze is something that we put on, or we try to put on, every year. They've now asked us to start paying, to do it; I'm not sure if that means we'll continue it. But…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man, what is other stuff we've done(?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the big kind-of things which I think is a really great achievement is our insurance that our members get. They get just a super insurance deal through our brokers, and it's something that we get a lot - I'm on the info@ukrda.org.uk email account, and by far the most frequent inquiry we get is about insurance and how, especially new teams; a lot of new teams can't get practice space if they're not insured, and they struggle to find people who will insure them in the sport, so one of the biggest achievements we've had is a reasonable and [searches for word] comprehensive enough to cover what we do, so that we can continue to play. So that's something that's really great.
and I'm pretty sure it's the most competitive rate that anyone will get for this sport in the UK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing is just, well, I dunno, we provide a community and we try and make things fair; the National Squads is something that's huge, and a lot of that is going on right now. I think it's very important to have those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;We should say that this is the &lt;em&gt;Women's&lt;/em&gt; National Teams; and that this is a fairness-motivated oversight role, not a controlling role.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, the way it works is that we facilitate the recruitment of the Women's National Teams, the ones who are affiliated and soon to be affiliated, (and there will be more news on that coming up in terms of Men's teams, following the World Cup and things like that).
We facilitate the recruitment, to make it fair - one thing that I've always wondered was, in countries where there's not a national governing body, like the UKRDA, how do they even start? Where do they begin? Who just Decides that they are going to start the national team? I feel that the UK is lucky to have something to kind of do that [in an impartial way] because it's something that's so big and so important for our sport to have National and International recognition.
And then, basically, after Management is recruited, the National Teams go off and do their own thing, and the only position that the UKRDA takes is that things are done fairly, and there's no kind-of-like favouritism, bias; to make sure that if people have problems, they have someone that they can come to; and because the National Squads are affiliated [with UKRDA] they get votes on our policies, because those affect the National Squads as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the National Squads are huge and it's a massive part of what we do, so it's important that we feel that they are run correctly and fairly, so that people can have the best time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;It's important to note that this does not mean that you have to be from a UKRDA member league to apply for National Team Management. The involvement of UKRDA is not intended to restrict skaters from applying!&lt;/strong&gt;
Yeah. Yeah, with Team England Women's parting from their affiliation last time around, I feel like people got certain ideas about why and what happened, and I mean, there were disagreements, there always will be, especially when two partners are working together like that, and Big Names like England and UKRDA, there's always going to be disagreements in things that are done. But I will say that since then, we have made massive changes, we've listened to all of the National Squads and our Members on what they want us to do, what the National Squads want us to do, we've had so many meetings, both in person and over the phone, and we've made a huge effort to conform to how our members want the National Squads setup to be, so that it can be what everyone wants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what they want is: for National Squads to operate as their own entities, but with, a Body in place, so that if something goes wrong, they have that support, which is what we will do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, and that's it really. Absolutely no restriction going on.
[laughs]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This kind of centralised oversight is a model being adopted in other countries, to various extents for the French and German national teams, for example...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm, yeah, and it's always really nice to get questions and requests for support from other countries. Like with Spain: last year, they came under fire from FIRS when they couldn't get training venues for their teams, and they came to us and said, "You guys have obviously created a National association that would deal with this kind of stuff, and we don't have that, and we don't want FIRS to, you know, kill our sport over here, or take it, at least. Will you help us?" And so that was really nice, to have that recognition that we've done something good, and that other people want our support, was a nice realisation to have as a National Governing Body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UKRDA was (possibly) the first Roller Derby national association...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was, yeah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, you guys have more experience at this than everyone else.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, it makes me really proud to think that we were the first ever National Governing Body, for Roller Derby. And so, I think the whole community needs to give itself a pat on the back for making it something that has worked for so long…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's been about 6 years since first AGM...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[surprised]Erm, possibly, I don't…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first AGM was in 2010, so…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, okay, then yeah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/27/an-interview-with-ukrda-chair-tess-robinson/26193888381_1d277a9ef5_k/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-7187"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-7187" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/26193888381_1d277a9ef5_k.jpg?w=700" alt="Tess v Newcastle Roller Girls (Photo: Dave Moore)" width="700" height="926"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Tess v Newcastle Roller Girls' Gin + Sonic (Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/gridiron/albums"&gt;Dave Moore&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, although UKRDA was the first NGB (and some people tend to think of it as an inflexible Institution), 6 years isn't so long that there's not the possibility for change and growth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely! I mean, one thing that I certainly learned, coming into the UKRDA, is that there is an infinite amount of room for change. I have no problem admitting that, before I joined as a member of the board of Directors (I joined in 2015 as Secretary) I was exactly one of those people who was like: "Urg, the UKRDA does nothing, I don't understand what their purpose is, what are they doing for us?". I was 100% one of those people.
And it wasn't until I actually sat down and spoke with Gareth about it at EROC that year that I realised all of the things that I'm now telling you! And so, then and there, I said "I'm in! I'm up for it: how can I help, how can I start changing things?". I came in, and I just said "I want to do: this, this, this", and everyone was like "Great: you go and do that".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is exactly the way that I would be if anyone else came to us with ideas. I think people were surprised at our AGM; at how open we were. I said to people, "You know, what do you want to see? What do you want the UKRDA to do? What do you want us to achieve in 2016?" And people had so many ideas, which is excellent! It's so great to have that! People just need to realise that they can't just give ideas and expect someone else to do them; as much as we need ideas, we need people to follow them through! And we've been incredibly lucky that a lot of those people have stayed on since the AGM to follow a lot of these things through. This first kind of part of the year has been really positive in terms of getting things done and ideas moving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, these ideas, are they secret? Tell us about them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, all of them [are public]. So, a lot of the projects that we're working on are… you don't have to be a Rep or someone with a Post in the UKRDA to work on something, anyone that's part of a UKRDA team [league] can help. I would say anyone outside of the UKRDA can help! We would never put barriers up against people who want to give us their time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things that we're doing is looking into sublimation of our patch onto uniforms. So, we're scoping out suppliers, finding out Pantone numbers, and getting samples in. So, we're going to be contacting a lot of suppliers soon about that.
We are looking into how to incorporate and support invisible illnesses more. So that's anything, any disabilities that are not like, breaking your leg, the stuff that you can't see - anything from mental illness, chronic illness, epilepsy, anything like that. So we've started recruiting people who seem interested, to start putting together policies, guidance and support resources on that kind of thing. which is excellent - a lot of people from the Community on Facebook for Roller Derby mental health have been really supportive and helpful with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A massive one for this year, and I think probably infinitely, for ever, is Coaching Qualifications. Everyone wants to see Coaching Qualifications, so that's something that we're trying to work hard with now. There's so much politics and [so many] complex relationships that we have to work on with Sport England and Sports Coach UK, coaching structures in the BRSF, in order to get that done. So it's expensive, but given that I think it's so important - I'm a real driver of that ambition, because it unlocks funding, and that's so important.
We have a lot of councils who will deny spaces for Roller Derby, or deny funding for Roller Derby, because they don't have qualified coaches. So, I think as soon as we get that, both teams will be able to get funded easier, and also it brings in an income, both to the UKRDA and to people who are Coaches in our community, something which I think is really important.
Obviously, it's the kind of thing which we would charge for: we can't offer things for free when people are going to work so hard. We're going to have coaches writing specifications and curricula, and delivering the courses, and travelling; so it's the kind of thing we'll charge money for, and the kind of thing that the UKDA would make a "profit" from, but only because we would want to give that money back to coaches, for their time, and also fund ourselves so that we can do more.
Obviously, we are a non-profit organisation, but we don't have any way of making money right now. So, I feel like it's important for us to have money, so we can give it to other people! One of my dreams is that one day, the UKRDA will have a steady income, and will be able to offer grants to teams that they can then apply for it - for travel, or uniforms, or hire-kit for fresh meat, venues. That's kind of like one of my ultimate dreams for what I want us to offer as a governing body. We just need to build up first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And you have only been going for 6 years!&lt;/strong&gt;
I know! So ambitious (!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's lots of stuff going on with Officials as well. We're trying to champion this new kind of position, where we will offer, I think - this comes from Rocky, our Director of Officials, so I might get this wrong - we want to develop something along the lines of offering an Officials Observer to watch games, to more usefully fill out Officials Evaluations.
You know, I still compete in the sport, and we always get chucked a handful of eval forms at the end of a game, and you think: I wasn't even watching the officials, I have no idea how to fill this out, so it results in stress for the teams filling it in, and the officials end up with poorly done evaluations; and most of the time people will only say stuff if something went badly, so we really want to offer something more for the officials on that sense
And personally, I'd just like to see more development and support for officials in the UK anyway; I know it exists out there, but I'd love to see more training, and stuff for newer refs, to make their transition into officiating as great as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, that's quite a lot of things(!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, it's a lot of things!. And there's a lot more, as well: we've just gotten Valkyrie on board, as our Director of Gameplay, and she's really doing a lot of work to forge this connection between British Champs and the UKRDA. She really wants that to become more cohesive, so that we can offer better gameplay across everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's the Big Stuff that we're working on; there's a lot of little things from day to day that we join up with, so …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People might think that's a lot of stuff, but I would still welcome 10 times more, if it meant that it made our community happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, I'd like to talk a little about a sore point, perhaps: UKRDA's visibility. You've said earlier that you didn't know what UKRDA did before you joined it. Do you think this is still a problem - that no-body seems to know what UKRDA does?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's definitely a problem: what's the point in having an organisation like ourselves when people don't know about it?
A lot of people from outside the sport that I've talked to about it say "Well, how many members do you have?" I say "we have 63 or 64 members" (maybe, it is 65 now?), and they say "Oh, cool!", but I say, "Well, yeah, but there's also so many more teams in the UK who aren't members…", and they say "WHY? Why would they not be members?" and I think, Well, I dunno(!)
People say "What's your strategy for recruiting those teams?" and I think "I dunno… there's so much more work that we could be doing…"
Especially in regards to communications - all of last year we had a really great Director of PR &amp;amp; Communications, Katy [Gordon] from Auld Reekie Roller Girls, and she did a great, I think two or three years, with UKRDA. She stepped down at the most recent AGM, and we had no-one run for Director of PR, and no-one run for Head of Communications in the first round. We've only just had a couple of people step up and apply to be our Head of Communications. So certainly for the first part of this year, we've had no-one to do our PR - it's just me and the people who are still on the PR Committee, kind of doing bits and bobs now and then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's a massive gap in our organisation. Obviously, I don't really know anything much about it, and hopefully we've now got a new Head of Communications, but it's come at such a crucial time, when we've had all of the National Squads stuff, that it's really left us in not a great situation, with poor turn out for [Squads] Management Applications.
So it's definitely something that we could improve on… I have nothing against admitting that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's just a matter of getting people who want to work with us, and all that kind of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And hopefully your new Head of Communications will be spearheading this.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, definitely!
* &lt;strong&gt;On the topic of National Teams, you yourself are trying out for Team Wales, I hear.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;[This interview occurred just before the Team Wales first round tryouts on 24 April.]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah! I tried out last time, and I got through round 1, and I was really gutted that I couldn't attend Round 2. I was at University and it was the same date as one of my assessments which I definitely couldn't miss, because it was the equivalent amount of credits as my dissertation. It was the kind of thing that was assessed on one day - it was a theatre performance; I did Drama at Uni.
So I was super gutted that that kind of ruled me out completely, so I did feel a bit lost, knowing that… I was a real champion for the Welsh teams that we have; I came from Swansea Roller Derby, and I know a lot of people in the Welsh Roller Derby Community. It was really sad, also exciting, to see so many of my friends, you know, go to the World Cup, I was so supportive of Team Wales - so that was really, like a Challenging Time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But! I've waited, and worked really hard for the past 2 to 3 years, to be able to try out again, and I've graduated from Uni now, so there's nothing, absolutely nothing in my way. I'm really excited, and I absolutely cannot wait for tryouts on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's going to be great to see my friends, it's going to be great to give my all, and see the other people that are trying out. You know it's been 4 years since I played Roller Derby for a Welsh team, and the community and the people there have changed a lot, so I'll be really excited to meet new Welsh skaters, and people from new teams. so, it's just a very exciting time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just can't wait for the whole process to get going, it's going to be great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hopefully you make it, at which point you'll be on 3 important UK Derby entities [London Roller Girls, Team Wales, UKRDA]!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[laughs] Yeah, I'm feeling confident, you know! I play at a high level, and I work really hard: as long as I do my best, that's all that matters and counts .
Obviously, because I am also Chair of UKRDA, and trying out for a National Squad, my permissions have been quashed, so I can't actually see inside any of those files and folders; so, yeah, I'm not allow access to any of that!
Before I try out, I was, as Chair, with the National Squads, if there's ever a tied vote, the Chair is the deciding vote, so I'm now no longer allowed to do that(!). Which is fine: there's a lot of privilege that I've lost, through trying out, but I don't think there's any greater privilege than representing your country, so it's really important to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good luck!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/27/an-interview-with-ukrda-chair-tess-robinson/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 14:29:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Wales Skater: Buccaneer Betty Fear</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/28/team-wales-skater-buccaneer-betty-fear/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing our series of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamwalesrollerderby/"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Interviews, in collaboration with the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UK Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, we present Buccaneer Betty Fear, who skated on the first Team Wales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tryouts are currently open for the next Team Wales, who will compete in the 2017 Roller Derby World Cup. To learn more about the Tryouts, read the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1"&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform"&gt;Application Form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The Application Form also has details of the dates and locations that Tryouts will occur, in &lt;strong&gt;April&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;May&lt;/strong&gt;. If you would like to represent Wales internationally, then sign up to try-out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-6874" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/230c42621.jpg?w=2048" alt="230C4262" width="1024" height="647"&gt; Fear skating in the 2014 World Cup (against New Zealand), on the right. (Courtesy &lt;a href="http://www.girlsofderby.com/"&gt;Sean Murphy&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buccaneer Betty Fear started out in Roller Derby with Severn Roller Torrent in 2011. She remained with Severn, skating and coaching until 2015, when she joined Tiger Bay Brawlers. She was an active member of Tiger Bay during their first and only season in British Champs. She attended the 2014 Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup as a member of Team Wales, playing against Norway, South Africa, New Zealand and Puerto Rico.
Before her retirement from Roller Derby at the end of the last season, she blogged on roller derby and other topics at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://itsahardblocklife.com/author/buccaneerbettyfear/"&gt;It's a Hard Block Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, the obvious first question is at the beginning: why try out for Team Wales?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is so hard to write about why I tried out without relying on cliche. I think it is because it is such a big set of feelings that you run out of words...
Trying out to make a National Squad was not a life experience that I thought I would have. Roller Derby is still at this special, magical time where people who have come to the sport as an adult can have dreams like making a National Squad and have the chance to turn them into reality. If you bring the work and the commitment and the courage to put yourself on the line, you can make it happen. Our sport might not be like that forever (have you seen those juniors??), so grabbing that opportunity now, while we are in this meeting place where hard work can turn you into an elite athlete... was an obvious. At the point of trying out, even the trial felt like a win and an experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell us a bit about the mental game of the tryout process. What did it feel like to go through the tryouts; and wait and then discover you had made it onto the roster?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tryout experience was utterly unlike I expected. I thought it would be this pressurised, lonely experience where everyone was out for themselves. Nope. Within minutes of arrival the skaters trying out were forming bonds with each other. There was a palpable sense of community and support. It was like the larger Roller Derby community, but squeezed into this incredibly intense experience. During drills people were supporting each other and rooting for each other. During scrimmage we were urging each other to jam and to pivot.
Physically and mentally it was one of the toughest experiences I have gone through. The trials were long, demanding and I think they were designed to ensure you were pretty exhausted by the time you scrimmaged. Waiting for the results of the first round of trials was agony, the elation of finding you had made the next round was swiftly followed by the awful realisation you had to do it all again, with more at stake...
Finding out I had made the Squad was an incredibly proud moment. I had spent so long prepping for those trials... I had spent all my money hiring lonely sports halls  at early hours on weekend mornings, I had trained relentlessly in the gym, I'd read pretty much every sports psychology book I could get my hands on. I'd gone all out to make the Squad. Knowing I would wear a Welsh jersey was incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Training for a National Team is a significant additional investment for a skater, on top of their existing league commitments. How did you manage the time needed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the time I was in the Squad, there was no balance in my life. It was Roller Derby, all in. I worked, I played derby and I cross trained. I mumbled 'sorry' to my brilliantly supportive partner as I disappeared every weekend, usually on both days, for League and Squad training. I spent my money on Roller Derby travel, the gym and physio. I missed the wedding of a close friend and countless nights out and weekend adventures.
At some point it stops being about you, and becomes about what you owe the Squad. You know that there were other skaters who would have done anything to have the spot on Squad you have, you owe it to them to go all out. You know that your team mates are missing birthdays and weddings and not seeing their kids in order to train, you owe it to them. And there is always the thought of not letting your Country down. You are going to skate out with a Welsh dragon on your chest, you want to show the World (and the Welsh) that we were serious about this sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the lead up to the World Cup, Wales played several other games, including a kind of home-series (Road To Dallas) against Ireland, Wales and the West Indies. What do you think you and the team gained from these games?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The games we played in the lead-up to the World Cup were an incredibly experience. I think the proliferation of European (and UK-based teams) really lifted the quality of derby that was played at the World Cup. By the time we got there we had played half a dozen games as a National Squad - that makes a huge difference.
Instead of working out kinks in our game at the World Cup, we had a squad who had skated together, understood each other and had developed our game. We also got to learn from the experiences of teams that had skated in the first World Cup. Scotland and Ireland had such strong, experienced Squads. Playing them beforehand gave us a chance to learn and adjust. The West Indies were great to play against as well... they were such a tough, hard-hitting Squad... it totally warmed us up (tenderised us??) for the hard-hitting play we experienced in Dallas.
It also gave us a chance to experience skating as Team Wales and the whole different set of nerves that comes with that. Finally, it meant that more players had the experience of playing for their country. Not everyone made the Squad in Dallas, so some great skaters who didn't get the chance in Dallas still had the incredible experience of skating for their country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representing Wales in Dallas, you played against New Zealand, South Africa, Norway and Puerto Rico. What was your favourite game, and why? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each game was a special and intense experience and created memories that will stay with my forever. South Africa were a great, physical side, having the time of their lives and their spirit was infectious. New Zealand were, well, HUGE! They were formidable and it was brilliant to have the chance to go up against them. Puerto Rico was a joy of a game - the final of the one we played at the World Cup and just a riot.
But my favourite... was Norway. They were skilled, strong and relentless, but we had a moment where Wales came together and realised that everything we had worked for was now and that this was our chance. We went back out on track with a vengeance, lifting our performance. We lost, but that switch in how we were operating on track was special. It was a moment of mental resilience and this incredible sense of skaters going out there for each other. We did each other proud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you planning on trying out for Team Wales again?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've retired now - full of dreams made reality! But to anyone considering it - go.
Try out.
Yes: you.
Imagine being able to say you were at trials for a National Squad... imagine being able to say you made it. Get your butt to training, get to the gym, get watching footage and grab yourself a derby dream. You will get something from any part of the process you go through. Go get it, skater!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We currently don't know much about the 2017 World Cup. If you had a choice, where would you like it to be (and who would you like to face on track?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd love to see it in Europe: the cost for so many teams to travel to North America was prohibitive. I'd love to have it closer to home, and see more European teams able to have all their skaters there and more skaters get the chance to have their moment on track.
Who would I like to see Wales face on track? It's got to be Norway. But this time with a different ending...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team wales</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/28/team-wales-skater-buccaneer-betty-fear/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 13:09:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Wales Manager Dorkmistress</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/24/team-wales-manager-dorkmistress/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, we interviewed the outgoing members of the Team Scotland Management and Coaching Team, in collaboration with the &lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UKRDA&lt;/a&gt;. In an ongoing collaboration with UKRDA, we're happy to present interviews with &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamwalesrollerderby/"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt;' Management and Coaching team, starting with Team Manager: &lt;strong&gt;Dorkmistress&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(You can apply to try out to skate for Team Wales here: &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform&lt;/a&gt; , with a FAQ concerning tryouts here: &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1"&gt;https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1 &lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dorkmistress has had a long and varied time in Roller Derby. Starting in 2011 with the Cardiff Roller Collective, as a skater and announcer, she has since moved to Swansea City Roller Derby (in 2013), and moved into refereeing for both Swansea and the South West Silures in 2014. She was Team Manager for Team Wales Roller Derby for the 2014 Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup, and continues in this role, having been re-elected in the post earlier this year. Her derby CV is extensive, including over 60 games refereed, and 100 announced, over her 5 year period in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full aligncenter" title="wp-1458819373825" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/wp-1458819373825.jpg" alt="image"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In common with other Team Wales roles, you're returning to the role of Manager from the last iteration of the National Team. What led you to decide to continue in the role? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a big decision - I loved the last two years but it's a fairly big commitment. We learnt so much in the last two years, starting the team from scratch and I wanted to make sure that I could see these lessons implemented. I know how I want to do things differently and think that I can do a much better job this time around. Plus, I'm not ready to watch Team Wales on track without being part of it! When I was thinking about how to answer these questions I looked back on the Team Wales Facebook page and seeing the support, encouragement and emotion on there made me remember what an incredible experience and honour it is to be part of Team Wales, and to be part of a team of such amazing people. And I still regularly look at the pictures of the Team Wales supporters gang - those crazy laydees from Neath Port Talbot, the supporters who travelled to Belgium and Dallas with their inflatables and daffodil hats, our own official leader of chants, Rhys Jones. Who wouldn't want to be part of that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managing a National team is quite a complex task, with many things to keep track of (and you've technically managed 2 Nations, what with Team Sealand). What do you think are the most important aspects of the job? (And coping with the workload?) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able and willing to keep all the plates you are spinning in the air is probably the key to success! And you can only achieve that with delegation and lots of communication. I worked with the skaters and other members of the management team to set up committees to cover key areas, like fundraising and events, and each group had an action plan and regular meetings. I did live on Facebook and Google Docs for the year, and ended up missing training a fair bit, but I wanted to make that commitment to make sure Team Wales was in the best place possible in Dallas. I have a busy real life job, but that's given me lots of time management and project planning skills, which were essential. Team Sealand was much easier, I just had to sort out travel and bout contracts ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last time around, a big part of the Management for most National teams was simply raising the funds to make it to Dallas. How did you guys go about managing the process, and finding new ways to get funds?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were really clear that fundraising was the responsibility of everyone in Team Wales, and everyone got involved. We had huge support from leagues from Newcastle to LRG to Severn Roller Torrent to Swansea City Roller Derby, giving us raffle proceeds, holding fundraising events and giving us stall space at their events. We had people donate money, we sold a LOT of t-shirts, we held kare-oke nights, we made loom bands, we had a baby picture competition, we had face painting at our games - literally any way we could get money out of people, we tried. We also decided to hold the fabulous Road to Dallas tournament in Newport in October 2014, hosting Teams Scotland, Ireland and West indies. Fundraising was constant - the challenge was to make it fun and to try and not just ask the same people all the time....same as most leagues face. It will be easier in some ways this time - we have our merch in place and an existing fan base - but harder in a sport where we have more leagues trying to fundraise from the same audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What've you learned from the last time around that you'll be applying this time, to improve Team Wales' management?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you got enough space in this blog? We're starting in a better position - we have a clear identity and design, so we will have t-shirts and merch available sooner and more options for our supporters. Do more on social media - keep everyone updated on our journey towards the World Cup. Delegate more and more completely - easier when you know what you are trying to achieve and know all the details and issues that need to be considered. Get the right partners and sponsors so things are as easy and cheap as possible for us. Play more games - we had 9 months from team selection to the World Cup last time and that wasn't enough - one reason we were keen to kick off the National Squad selection process in the UK. Everyone's going to freak out a bit on this journey - we are all allowed a freakout, just hopefully not at the same time. Sleep more and stop looking at Facebook messages at midnight and then again at 7am. Don't share a room with morning people if you are a night owl - probably the hardest and most important lesson I learnt.....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You've also announced in many places, including at the first Men's World Cup. How would you compare your two World Cup experiences?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very different experiences because they were very different sized events on very different continents. The Men's World Cup memories I have will last me a lifetime. It was my first taste of international roller derby and it was small and perfectly formed - the announcing team was incredible and the size of the schedule and event meant you could keep up with all of the action and see all of the teams and skaters sat next to you. I got to hang out with Team Japan and watch Team Argentina and nearly lost my voice shouting at Team Wales scoring points against Team USA - and those moments were all in the same room, right next to each other. It was the first time I got to introduce the Welsh National Anthem and I can still feel the hairs rising on the back of my neck. I also got to do the in-house announcement for &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; Wales V Australia game and the emotion in the venue at that last jam overwhelmed me so much I cried for 30 minutes at the end of the game - us announcers feed off that crowd emotion and I have never felt anything like it. It was such a personal experience I am not sure anything will ever really be the same as that. I'm desperately proud to have been part of the delivery of that event and I am more than a bit heartbroken that I can't go to Calgary this July - but I know Team Wales will make me and everyone else even prouder than they did that day in Birmingham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blood and Thunder World Cup was just so much bigger. When we arrived at the airport the customs guys said 'you here for the roller derby?'. Thats because they had already seen so many skaters and fans. 30 teams is a lot of people, three tracks in this massive room in a ginormous exhibition centre in America? Much bigger than the Futsal! If I went to the team room (each team had its own room! what?!) it was a good 5 minute walk, which, by the end of the day, felt like 5 miles. We'd gone to the European Roller Derby Tournament in Belgium and shared the underside of the bleachers seating with 7 other National teams and the next thing you knew we had a Team Support person, and a room and all sorts of things to make our time easier. I missed announcing though, you watch games in a different way and I didn't see a lot of other games as I was busy on the merch stall or sorting transport or one of the many other things that went on. And I missed being part of the team that showed you the event and explained what was going on. However, nothing in my life will ever compare to being able to walk out on the biggest Roller Derby stage in the world as part of Team Wales in the Parade of Nations. I can't even now, all this time later, put that experience and feeling into words. It's something I will forever be proud of and proud to have been part of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you were interviewed last time around, you noted that you were most looking forward to Team Wales playing "teams from far off places". In the event, Wales played South Africa, New Zealand, Norway and Puerto Rico, at least three of which probably count! If you could play any teams (announced or not) in the upcoming World Cup, what would they be?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Norway are going down this time ;-) It was almost impossible to watch the game  - seeing the team play out of their skins to claw back to within reaching distance for Norway to pull away just at the end. I'd love to see us play Argentina, they were incredible in Dallas and I think the South American teams are going to go to the next World Cup with a huge step up in skills and strategy. And there will be teams from new places - Iceland, definitely, maybe even Egypt, or Russia [where there are teams, but no established National infrastructure, yet]! We think and talk a lot about European Derby and Derby in North America, but the World Cup is the only place we get to see derby developing as a Global sport, and thats going to be really evident in the next World Cup for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(And if you have a place you'd like the World Cup to be, for any reason…)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would love it to be in Japan as I have always wanted to go there but even pretending I'd have to fundraise for that makes me want to cry! Very boringly I'd like it to be in Europe next - I think that showing as many people as possible international level derby inspires skaters and so would like to see it move around continents to give everyone that experience - watching it on the internet isnt quite the same. So next time Australia or New Zealand. Then South America or Asia or Africa. A true world tour!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team wales</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/24/team-wales-manager-dorkmistress/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 11:38:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Girls: Five Years On</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/10/fierce-valley-roller-girls-five-years-on/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In November 2010, three friends decided to try to set up a local roller derby league, and Fierce Valley Roller Girls was born.  I spoke to the league founders, V for Vienetta, Grizabelta and Kirk Jammett, for their thoughts on the last five years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What prompted you to establish Fierce Valley Roller Girls, and how did you get started?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V:&lt;/strong&gt; I had been following ARRG for a while and was interested in derby then after finaly seeing a bout I took Griz and Kirk through to see ARRG's next one. I quickly realised I wanted to be involved in some way with roller derby in Scoland and started to look into learning to ref.
At this time Scotland only had leagues in Aberdeen, Dundee, Perth, Glasgow and Edinburgh and we joked about starting one in Falkirk, the joke continued on for a couple of weeks where it then started to become more serious and then before we knew it we were looking into equipment, finding out about rules, skating, training and trying to find a hall to put this all together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G:&lt;/strong&gt; Our own laziness! V had convinced Kirk and myself to go along to an ARRG bout, and we were instantly hooked. We spent the entire journey home discussing how we could go about getting involved, but living in Falkirk, our nearest leagues were Edinburgh and Glasgow. I already spent a lot of time out the house with my other hobbies (outwith derby I'm a band geek and hospital radio DJ!) so wasn't keen to add more travelling to my week, and eventually 'if only there was something closer' turned into 'we could make this happen if we try'. It was really the boys' vision – but as a predominately female sport at the time, they thought it a bit inappropriate to approach sports halls on their own to try and bring this amazing women's sport to Forth Valley – which is where my involvement really came in! As the radio station is a small charity, I was fortunate to have the knowledge behind me of how to run not-for-profit organisations (or at least know the principles of how to run one!). We managed to convince Bo'ness Recreation Centre to let us skate around for a bit, and after a meeting in a pub to gather some interest – Fierce Valley Roller Girls was born!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K:&lt;/strong&gt; Marco has been pestering us to go to a - then bout - with him, so we finally took up the chance to go see ARRG play. Then followed a rather excited train journey home about what names we could have, and if we could really create our own league in the falkirk area.
A few weeks went by and I got in contact with Marco again and said that if he was serious about starting it to count me in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What difficulties did the league face in the early days?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; V:&lt;/strong&gt; I would say our main difficulty much like any other derby league at that time was getting a hall to practice in. We went round visiting all of the local sports centres/halls speaking to the managers to no avail, we even looked into other halls in the hope of someone letting us. For a while there was a real fear that we would never be able to get somewhere but thankfully Bo'ness Sports Centre said yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G:&lt;/strong&gt; Getting a hall! So many halls had inappropriate floors, and those that didn't were reluctant to let us skate. Bo'ness used to host roller hockey, so we took a chance with asking them, and thankfully they said yes – but even then only for a trial period. Back then we couldn't afford a full hall either- we had 2/3 of a hall, with a net wheel trap!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K:&lt;/strong&gt; The basics - getting a hall that was happy to let us skate in without damaging the floor. So we gathered as much information about the sport, and the different requirements needed to play the sport and tried every hall we could think of to let us just skate on their floor before we even considered the basics of roller derby and getting others interested. Weeks and weeks of every free moment contacting, and researching halls in the area to either be ignored or told ‘no’. 2 men turning up and saying we’re looking to start an all female sport in the area was confronted with many confused expressions. However we decided to give Bo’Ness Sports centre a stop by one day just to see - even though we’d been advised they’d banned skating in their halls. We gave the centre manager the run down on what we needed, and what our plans were going forward, he was kind enough to give us a tour of the halls available, and then offered us a 6 or 12 week probation to make sure there were no issues. And we never got kicked out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What roles did you play, and how have these changed over time?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; V:&lt;/strong&gt; For the first three years I was quite involved in the running of the league as the vice chair, I was also on a few different committee's including our Sports and Training. As time went on and as I got involved in Men's Derby I took less to do with the running of the league but am still involved in different committees within FVRG and find myself helping to train our new refs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G:&lt;/strong&gt; I think I've done everything and everything haha! Managerial-wise – I held the position of Chairperson for FVRG's first 4 years, which was amazingly rewarding and frustrating all at the same time! I took a step down last year to arrange my wedding, but also because I think you do get to a point where you just start to run out of ideas – you need that different perspective for a while. I'm now one of FVRG's UKRDA reps, which I'm still very much adjusting to – the whole 'big fish small pond' to 'small fish big pond' thing! Front-of-house so to speak, I started off as a skater (it's really odd seeing old pictures of my in my Parma Violents top!) but used to get far too nervous and basically just get jelly legs and spend all my time on the ground... Tried my hand at line-up manager a couple of times, and did a few games as bench coach, but then I settled as a full time NSO. NSOing was just something I started doing so I didn't have to sit on my own while Kirk and V were reffing, so I'm always slightly baffled as to where it's taken me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K:&lt;/strong&gt; Being the people with the crazy notion of starting this we got voted in as Chairperson, Vice Chair, and board member at our first AGM in Weatherspoons in Falkirk that memorable November evening.
With relatively low numbers we took on a lot of other tasks, such as sourcing designers to come up with our branding, then obtaining our first range of merchandise. Where possible we focused on keeping these to local businesses to help the area as well.
While the structure of the league has remained - if not grown - things are generally run in a similar manner, but with more and more experience coming into the league and taking on the different board, and spokesperson positions which are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the league grown over the past five years?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; V:&lt;/strong&gt; FVRG has grown in so many different ways and that is all thanks to its members. We started as a handful of people in half a hall skating once a week to a league filed with skaters, refs, dedicated NSOs and off skate members. We run 4 sessions a week covering all skating levels within the league. Our bouting team is sought after to be played against and has risen sharply up the rankings in the last couple of years and our officials travel all over reffing derby at different levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G:&lt;/strong&gt; We've certainly got a lot more structure – we're run more like a business now than just a group of friends muddling along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K:&lt;/strong&gt; Oh whoa! How has it grown! From 5 people skating in a badminton court in Bo’Ness to 4 regular training sessions spanning all levels of skating, to continually growing our knowledge and numbers in not only skaters but officials. And while we see friends moving on to bigger things, personally and in derby, our little league keeps pulling in the numbers and growing all of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your personal highlights and proudest moments?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; V:&lt;/strong&gt; It has been great to see the league build up from its formation and its members develop in their roles and watching the team grow from their first bout to now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G: It's always hard to single out a particular moment – I'm always proud of what our members achieve, on and off track. What does warm my heart though is when I see the friendships that have been formed through FVRG – people who are now the best of friends, who may never have met if they hadn't taken a chance on coming along to a Fresh Meat session one time. Or the transformation of those who are so quiet when they join, to becoming a confident and assertive individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K:&lt;/strong&gt; Personal highlights? Working with the vast number of amazing officials in Scotland, and somehow moving from just standing up in my skates to being picked to represent Scotland’s officials at the first Men's World Cup in Birmingham. While it’s been a lot of work to get to this stage, it certainly wouldn’t have been possible without everyone who has given me feedback and having the faith in me.
Proudest moments, would be seeing what seemed like a crazy idea one afternoon has become something not only we can be proud of, but everyone in the league who keeps pushing the league forward.
That and seeing referees who I’ve helped train go on to do amazing once let loose on the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You were all involved in the first ever Men's Roller Derby World Cup, as officials and as a skater - how was this experience for you?&lt;/strong&gt;
V: It was such an honour and privilege to play and represent Power of Scotland at the first Men's Roller derby World Cup. Between the training on the run up to and the actual world cup, it is an experience I could never forget as there are so many fond memories. The camaraderie between all the teams/skaters was amazing with everyone helping each other out, I got to meet and skate with/against some amazing people from all over the world and the atmosphere between us all in the team area just bfore the closing ceremony was unforgettable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G:&lt;/strong&gt; Amazing! To get to work with some of the best officials in the world, while seeing some of the best men's skaters in the world – I think I spent the entire time starstruck! I was very much the newbie in my crew (when we introduced ourselves it was lots of 'I'm xxx, Head Ref/HNSO of xxx', it came round to me and I was like 'I'm Griz, and I like to NSO'!!) but I learned so much from them and they looked after me amazingly well, especially during what ended up being a quite challenging time personally for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K:&lt;/strong&gt; So many different emotions happened that weekend. From feeling like the least experienced person in my crew - A lot of high level referees were on my crew. To being given amazing feedback on my refereeing, to then some stressful stuff happening closer to home, to then being picked to work on the last 3 games for my crew. Embarrassment, and a lot of laughter at the support I was getting from back home.
I still look back at that weekend and love all of it.
One of the hardest parts was being part of the crowed during the PoS and America game and staying completely impartial. Also, I missed every single Scottish point - every time I left the track they scored! My crew was up next so I couldn’t hang around and watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What advice would you give to a new league starting out?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; V:&lt;/strong&gt; I think the best advice would be not to rush and take your time. Build up your league and tune those skating skills so you are all ready to play together as a team, it can be tempting to start playing before you are all ready. Also make friends and build bridges with other leagues, you never know how much help they will be able to give you and how much you may need them in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G:&lt;/strong&gt; Be prepared for a lot of hard work! There are a number of reasons why people want to start a new league, but there will always end up being policies that need to be written, meetings to be had – and no matter what you do, you'll never please everyone all of the time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K:&lt;/strong&gt; Take as much advice as you can. It’s hard, it’s stressful, it takes all of your time and hard work, but seeing so many happy faces make it worth it.
You’re going to make mistakes a long the way, and recognising and learning from them will help move the league forward.
Most importantly, have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How would you like to see FVRG develop in the future?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; V:&lt;/strong&gt; I would like to see FVRG keep pushing forward and building their team and experience whilst developing all their upcoming skaters, hopefully long term get a 2nd team and who knows, even join WFTDA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G:&lt;/strong&gt; Well our goal for now is to work towards becoming a WFTDA league – but that has been our goal from the outset and it will take as long as it needs to take. We've spent a lot of work in the past year determining our vision, mission statement and values, and everything we do ties into these, so we're becoming much more aware of how the little things we do tie into the bigger picture. I'm always really proud of our community involvement too, so I'm hoping this will continue! And of course, I just want everyone to enjoy being part of FVRG, no matter what role they play :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K:&lt;/strong&gt; While there are the obvious ones of continuing to climb the rankings in Europe and UKRDA, and also joining WFTDA, just being where the league needs to be at that point in time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/10/fierce-valley-roller-girls-five-years-on/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 09:35:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>From Lucerne with Shoves: Voodoo's international tournament plans!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/12/from-lucerne-with-shoves-voodoos-international-tournament-plans/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While this weekend continues the tradition of being rather busy in roller derby, in Glasgow, something a little epic is being planned. Fresh from the end of the British Championships Tier 4 competition, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Voodoo-Roller-Dollies-571771319549241/"&gt;Voodoo Roller Dollies&lt;/a&gt; are hosting a mini-tournament, with an international bent. Returning from Voodoo's last tournament (only this February!) are Glasgow C, the &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/content/cannie-gingers"&gt;Cannie Gingers&lt;/a&gt;; however, flying in all the way from Lucerne (Luzern), Switzerland, the third team are &lt;a href="http://www.thehellveticats.ch/"&gt;The Hellveticats&lt;/a&gt;, part of the new wave of Swiss and Central European roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/12/from-lucerne-with-shoves-voodoos-international-tournament-plans/12006363_963059253753777_8455008463369869288_n/" rel="attachment wp-att-4938"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4938" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/12006363_963059253753777_8455008463369869288_n.jpg" alt="12006363_963059253753777_8455008463369869288_n" width="614" height="231"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2012, the Hellveticats started with the usual enthusiasm of new leagues, despite, as Referee Lucy Cat Rolls told us "that most of the girls on the team haven't even watched a roller derby game, we did our best to train and build up our league". They've been bouting since late 2013, according to Flat Track Stats, mostly playing the rest of the Swiss and Central European derby community. In fact, the tournament will not just be a new experience for the Scottish teams, as it's the furthest trip that the Hellveticats have made in their history."As we have many members with family or other responsibilities we try to get bouts which are possible to travel within a day trip. But, every now and then, we make a journey with the team - we went to [Prague] in the Czech Republic and to Nice in France. Scotland is within a very good distance by plane so we decided to travel there together, we are thrilled to be invited to this awesome event."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it happens, the fact that the tournament exists at all is actually down to the Hellveticats' enthusiasm for a long distance trip. As Voodoo's Roll-N-Pin told us: "[The Hellveticats] actually contacted us, believe it or not. They got in contact with our very own Titan and from there it progressed. We wanted to make sure that they got as much of a Scottish derby experience as possible, [so we organised the tournament around them]." Not that Voodoo have ever been shy of a tournament, as Pin admitted, "tournaments are always a great way to involve so many people at the same time. To come up against new teams and get to spend even more time in a weekend or day playing against them. I mean, who doesn't love more derby time? It's double, and even triple, the fun at times with tournaments."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Hellveticats are travelling the furthest, it's Glasgow's &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/45330"&gt;Cannie Gingers&lt;/a&gt; who are the most dangerous competitors in the tournament, sitting almost 200 places above &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/38908"&gt;Voodoo&lt;/a&gt;, and 130 above the &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/20691"&gt;Lucerne&lt;/a&gt; team, in Flat Track Stats' European ranking scheme (although our own prediction scheme places the latter somewhat closer in ability to the Glasgow team). Despite the huge challenge they represent, Voodoo are relishing the rematch. "The Canny Gingers are always a fierce opponent and are really the definition of a true challenge, " said Roll N Pin, "but with each bout we play against superior teams, we gain more knowledge , discover more tactics  and get to try out more strategies. It would take a phenomenal achievement on our part to win against them, but for us it's not all about the win. At the end of the day if the other team are walking away with bump and bruises, sore spots and dead arms or legs then we know we have put up a great fight and have made them work for it. It gives us a goal to work towards as well, a comparison to ourselves to see how much we have improved and how we can improve more." And the Cannie Gingers aren't willing to rule out the possibility of a Voodoo win, saying "there are no guarantees in Derby; just look at the Rose/Victorian/Gotham games in the WFTDA Championships. We just want to play our games and take each jam as they come!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow C are also keen to see what Swiss derby has to offer, noting that "one of the great things about roller derby is the opportunities it brings, and it's an honour to play every team we face, for the things we are taught in each game. It will be interesting to see how our styles play against each other; we hope it will also be a fun experience and that [the Hellveticats] have a good Scottish welcome".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of who actually wins, all the teams have the same goals at heart. Roll N Pin "First and foremost, and it may seem cheesy, [our goal] is to have FUN! We want to present an environment to welcome all and make sure that the players and the crowd are having fun. But hey that's not too hard to do when you've got derby, tunes and CAKE!", and Lucy Cat Roll agrees, "I guess the biggest challenge will be understanding the Scottisch dialect and resisting to the urge of drinking whisky before the first whistle ;-) We hope to have fun and to meet many nice derby people and we hope to have you over in Switzerland one day and invite you for a nice tournament, some cheese and a ton of chocolate." The Gingers also, "above all, [] just want to have a nice time! We have some established skaters, and some who will be playing their first game, so it's a nice mix. We work hard at training, and in running our league, so we just want to represent GRD in the best way we can."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voodoo Roller Dollies have a new intake planned for the end of November, and extensive plans for the future. As Pin puts it: "Voodoo's future is looking bright. We have a new intake at the end of this month (as always we are looking to expand) and we have many a teams to play again for return games. We are hoping to get more involved in the derby community and attend more scrims. Maybe even host a few ourselves. One thing is for sure we will always come back hitting harder and pushing ourselves further."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tournament starts from &lt;strong&gt;Midday&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8666126,-4.2505074,17z/data=!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7"&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt; in Glasgow Caledonian University on Saturday &lt;strong&gt;14th November&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event page can be found on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/908423505918913/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, and tickets will be £5 on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as we are aware, the planned schedule of play is:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Doors 12:00&lt;br&gt;
Skate outs 12:20&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
1st game - VRD v GRD - 12:30&lt;br&gt;
2nd game - GRD v Hell - 13:55&lt;br&gt;
3rd game - Hell v VRD - 15:20&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>cannie gingers</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>hellveticats</category><category>international</category><category>interviews</category><category>tournament</category><category>voodoo roller dollies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/12/from-lucerne-with-shoves-voodoos-international-tournament-plans/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 20:42:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fight Hawks at the Trawler: GCRG's B Team speak.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/31/fight-hawks-at-the-trawler-gcrgs-b-team-speak/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coming soon to Edinburgh, &lt;a href="http://lothianderbydolls.com/"&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; will play Aberdeen's second ever derby team, as &lt;a href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/"&gt;Granite City Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; launch their B-squad, the &lt;em&gt;Fight Hawks&lt;/em&gt;. We caught up with Fight Hawks Bench Manager, Pert Hits, to find out a bit more. (Season Tickets for &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/346223992230568/"&gt;the bout on the 12th&lt;/a&gt;, and LDD's two subsequent games, can be obtained from &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/1820858"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City are only the fourth Scottish league to form a B-team (after ARRG, GRD and DRG). How does it feel to be able to launch a second travel team? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels natural.  With the roster sort of set for the Northern Fights, it had left a fair few of our skaters with no games to play, which was a real real shame given the calibre of skaters we are seeing coming through our fresh meat course (a number of whom completed the 3 month course and passed all mins first time!).  As the number increased over the course of the year, it just felt like the right time for it to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you tell us a little about the makeup of the team, and the selection process? Are these all new skaters to GCRG fans?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a look at the sheer number of mins passed skaters we had that were not dedicated to the British Championships and who were game ready.  Various things were looked at, perhaps the more important factors were attendance to training and scrim practice.  The team selection will be quite fluid as time goes on with different players perhaps being selected for each game.  Of the 14 skaters submitted for our first game, only 4 of them will be familiar faces to GCRG fans.  The rest may have been spotted in various "cherry poppers" across Scotland to those with a keen eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GCRG B are named 'The Fight Hawks'. Obviously, this continues the 'Fight' theme with GCRG A 'Northern Fights', but which Night Hawks (the painting, perhaps?) were you inspired by, and what do you hope it says about you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are actually named after a local term for seagulls, which we have in Aberdeen in abundance.  A quick youtube search and you can see why we went with this name; they're brash, brave and persistent.  And we will steal your chips when you're not looking.  But we do pay for Doritos, so please feel free to invite us for game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your first bout is away against Lothian Derby Dolls, down in Edinburgh. How are you preparing for the bout? What result are you hoping for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With British Champs winding down for the Northern Fights, we are in a good position to have our training sessions tailored directly towards the Hawks' needs. As bench and line-up, myself and Krusty have been watching like... hawks... as the girls train and giving feedback to our training committee, who have been very good at taking it into account and getting the right drills we need. We have also been doing "Hawks vs the rest" at scrim practices just to ensure the team meld and we get a good hive mind.
We are heading down to Edinbrugh looking to score more points. Perhaps the more important win, however, is knowing we gave 100% and played well as a team. Even defeats on the score board feel like wins if you know you did your best and worked well as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What're the Hawks' plans for the future? With GCRG A committed to British Champs, will you guys be taking on more eclectic teams?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not entirely certain what the future holds for us. I would certainly be expecting a good jaunt around Scotland in 2016, playing various teams, and with the right amount of fundraising taking our team a little further afield would a dream!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>b-teams</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/31/fight-hawks-at-the-trawler-gcrgs-b-team-speak/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 14:42:49 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>