<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about announcers)</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/announcers.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:54:21 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>An Interview With Elliot Fress</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/27/an-interview-with-elliot-fress/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next up in line in our announcer interviews, Glasgow Roller Derby's Elliot Fress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/img_20131126_0083258.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/img_20131126_0083258.jpg" alt="Photography by Dave McAleavy" width="614" height="408" class="size-full wp-image-3066"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photography by Dave McAleavy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you get started announcing for Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many life-changing events, it involved a photocopier; some office gossip; and a man named Helliverance...  He and I pretend to work in the same building, and one day about three years ago, he cornered me by said copier and asked if it was true that I was previously involved with professional wrestling.  This was true - I'm a former manager/commentator for the Scottish Wrestling Alliance.  As I was comfortable with crowds and microphones, would I be interested in trying my hand at live Roller Derby commentary with him?  A fee was negotiated, and a few weeks later I was at the ARC, making vaguely human noises over the first GRG home teams bout of the season.  From then on, I was never to look forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Announcers all have different styles, how would you describe your style and how has it evolved since you started?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I can call it a style, it's irreverence, with ignorance firmly in mind.  Derby's complex and unique.  Anyone coming to see it fresh is in for a lot of confusion as a lot happens and there's no other sport you can refer to for an easy comparison.  It's important to keep that in mind and try to keep the watching newbie in mind when things happen on track.  "Why?" is as important as "What?" when you're talking about a sending off, or why a team has slowed everything down during a powerjam, for example.  The rest of the time, I just quote dead comedians and joke about skater's names, while I'm sure they're not listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been training as a skater with Glasgow's Mean City Der-boy team for the last six months.  The training and generally spending more time around skaters has given me a lot more material to work with, regarding techniques and tactics; but the bulk of what I do is still aimed at the people struggling to make sense of what they're seeing.  As I told a crowd recently, Derby seldom reveals her charms quickly, or all at once.  It can take a few bouts for someone to learn where they need to be looking, and a commentator needs to be there to help them along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you prepare for bouts and how much work do you have to do on the fly?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more sterile prep is reviewing the rules in the week running up to a bout and trying to get familiar (in a nice way, I mean) with the line-ups before a bout starts.  Just about everything I watch, think or hear goes through a filter to see if it can one day be usable in a Derby context.  If I hear a song lyric a skater's name can be slipped into, then it gets filed away.  While it's underway, a good bout can almost describe itself.  But, if you're faced with a 50-odd minute time-out - you better be able to talk some shite to distract folk from heading for their bus!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skaters have skate heroes, do you have any announcer heroes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the "Bulldog" question, yes?  I've been lucky enough to work with the man and be stunned by his play-by-play commentary.  Knowing the limits of the rhythms of my own speech and my diction, though, it would serve nobody for me to try to emulate him.  I'm happiest working with anyone who can hear what I'm saying more than half the time, and are prepared to have the occasional spot of harmless fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which has been your favourite bout to call and what are you looking forward to calling in the future?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard to pick a favourite bout, but generally any time a scoreline stays close for the bulk of the game makes it easier to stay invested.  For that reason, I look forward to GRD going back up against Berlin and Stockholm after this past season's nail-biters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>announcers</category><category>grd</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/27/an-interview-with-elliot-fress/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 19:29:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Interview With...Sven WillIBeFamous</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/05/an-interview-with-sven-willibefamous/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next in line in our series of announcer interviews, the one and only Sven WillIBeFamous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/sven.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/sven.jpg" alt="Photo by Zero-G Photography" width="538" height="720" class="size-full wp-image-3015"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photo by Zero-G Photography&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you get started announcing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the start of 2010 and myself and fellow Newcastle Rollergirls ref Glen Moreangry had been invited to stay with some friends in Falkirk.  Glen had just started dating Blackjack Belle who was skating with ARRG and it was arranged that we'd go to see London Rockin Rollers versus Glasgow's Irn Bruisers on the Saturday and then Leeds Roller Dolls versus ARRG's Twisted Thistles on the Sunday.  I had heard about Roller Derby but never seen it and so after a bit of googling decided it would be a good place for Glen and I to try out our budding hobby of photography.  The Saturday came and we arrived at the Arc, cameras in hand to try and shoot some of the action.  About 10 minutes into the bout we both realised that we'd forgotten about the photography and were just enthralled by the game.
The next day we went to Meadowbank, again with the cameras but I don't think either of us removed the lens caps.  After the bout we were leaving and Blackjack suggested that I should take up announcing, as I'd recently been dabbling with stand up comedy and that was it. Sven WillIBeFamous was born.  I even came up with the name there and then.  Next thing I know I've been volunteered to announce at Highland Fling, A 2 day tournament in Aberdeen.  I had a few months to learn the rules and even did some NSOing with ARRG.  It was while NSOing that we found out about Newcastle Rollergirls, our home city league!  Highland Fling came around sooner than expected and Helliverance and I spent a weekend trying to fill air time with our meandering banter.  The week after, Glen and I joined Newcastle Rollergirls properly as referees and as we were learning the ropes I was announcing as many bouts as I could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Announcers all have different styles, how would you describe your style and how do you think your experience as a referee has altered it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My style is definitely play by play(PBP) now.  I think when I started I was a mix of colour and PBP but then I had the fortune to work with Bulldog, during a Berlin vs ARRG bout.  I learned a lot that day including the way that a true PBP announcer works, and I started to work on that style. I now alter my style depending on who I'm working with and what works best.
 I think that being a referee definitely helps me as an announcer as I can pick up on whistles and hand signals and of course, I have a very good knowledge of the rules. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you prepare for bouts and how much work do you have to do on the fly?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all depends on which bouts I'm announcing.  If it's 2 teams that I know really well then I normally just make sure I have the postcode for the venue and spare batteries for my microphones... On the day I spend a bit of time getting to know the rosters.  For this I like to watch the skaters warm up and commit their names and numbers and any distinguishing features to memory.  I'll then write out the rosters side by side on a fresh sheet of paper in numeric order, which helps to cement them into my brain(and is also a handy reference for me mid bout). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you find that stream announcing differs from trackside?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stream announcing is the announcing equivalent of taking a car to a private track.  You get to do all the stuff there that you normally aren't allowed to. You have the freedom to discuss tactics, say what you think 1 team is trying to do and you don't have to worry about hyping the crowd.  You still have to be careful what you say though, and I wouldn't say anything about a skater on the stream that I wouldn't also say to their face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skaters have skate heroes, do you have any announcer heroes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're talking announcers/commentators of any sport then I guess I'd have to say Al Michaels from the NFL's Monday Night Football.  I've spent nearly 30 years following the NFL and Al Michaels is definitely one of those voices that has been with the game all that time, and is considered one of the best play by play callers in the game.  I don't know if I could single out any particular heroes in derby announcing but there are a lot of people out there that I look up to and love working with. It sounds cheesy but anyone that is willing to devote their time to learning the sport, the gameplay, the tactics and the teams gets my worship. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What has been your favourite bout to call and what are you looking forward to calling in the future?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to spend 3 days announcing Track Queens in Berlin last November and was paired with L'il Joker. Every bout we called there was amazing and we were lucky enough to call most of the ARRG and GRD bouts.  I can't really pick 1 bout out of the many we did that weekend though, maybe ARRG vs LRG if I was pushed. Most recently it was the last 2 bouts of MERDC 2013.  I called the 3rd place final and saw Tyne and Fear fight tooth and nail with The Inhuman League to take 3rd in Europe and then the Final was something else. Probably the greatest deby crowd I've ever had the pleasure to work with.  Helliverance was announcing with me and was in his element! 
The next bouts I'm looking forward to announcing will be at the Men's Roller Derby World Cup in March, where I'll be co-ordinating the house announcing.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>announcers</category><category>arrg</category><category>interviews</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/05/an-interview-with-sven-willibefamous/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 16:26:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Interview with sMack Daddy</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/10/22/an-interview-with-smackdaddy/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing our series of interviews with Scottish Announcers, we caught up with Granite City's SmackDaddy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/10/received_m_mid_1382451002655_6c2020f76495bf0e16_0.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2980 aligncenter" alt="received_m_mid_1382451002655_6c2020f76495bf0e16_0" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/10/received_m_mid_1382451002655_6c2020f76495bf0e16_0.jpeg" width="533" height="800"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;How did you get started announcing for GCRG?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ha! This was actually quite funny. I had originally got involved with the league as my other half (Krusty) was convinced I’d make a good ref. Unfortunately, injuries etc. kept me off skates for a while so, since they had lost their normal announcer and I had a bit of a history as a presenter on the radio, they asked me to step in. It was a home bout (their first in over a year due to issues with the venue) and I was honoured to do it. Needless to say I was MAJORLY nervous but I just ploughed ahead with it. One of the GCRG skaters (Zomboobies) was injured so she joined me on the mic to help with the play by play stuff. It was awesome and I got a lot of great feedback from refs, skaters and fans. J&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Announcers all have different styles, how would you describe your style and how has it evolved since you started?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My style is very simple. I’m loud and clear! I’ve taken a lot of the stuff I learnt from doing podcasts and radio shows and carried it across to announcing bouts. Get rid of the accent as much as possible, throw your voice and have fun with it! I firmly believe that you have to have a lot of inflection in your voice. Get hyper with awesome plays, go crazy during timeouts and be serious when you have to. Simples! ;) In regards to how my style has evolved, by attending more bouts and watching ALLLLLL the footage I can online, my play by play has improved a lot. I’ve started to develop little catchphrases and I have become a lot more natural meaning my sense of humour tends to shine through a bit more too. Although if you ask the girls up here, they’d tell you that’s not necessarily a good thing…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;How do you prepare for bouts and how much work do you have to do on the fly?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try and be as prepared as possible. I study the rosters as soon as I get them, I contact the leagues taking part in the bout and see if there is anything specific they want me to talk about (birthdays, sponsor messages etc.) and I make sure I have the skaters' names perfected! God help me, there is nothing worse than getting a skaters' name wrong! They WILL kill you! Problem is, 90% of what announcers do is on the fly as you are talking about the match going on in front of you and obviously you can’t plan any of that! Sometimes, it’s the off the cuff stuff that gets the best reaction from the crowds. Whenever there is a decent break in play, I have been known to wander into the crowd and pick out some of the best signs and talk to people about them on the mic! It’s great fun and it gets people interacting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Skaters have skate heroes, do you have any announcer heroes?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hell…yes! Jim Ross, the greatest announcer in the history of the WWE. I have idolised that man since I was knee high to a grasshopper! His delivery, his flair and his attention to detail is phenomenal. He spent a lot of his time working alongside the younger talent in WWE so in addition to honing his mic skills, he was learning about the stars of the future! This was invaluable as often he would be announcing their matches so he knew their history which gave him loads to talk about during the lull periods in live events! I was gutted to miss out on seeing him when he came to Scotland recently. L&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;When you watch sports in your free time, do you find yourself doing your own commentary?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emmmm…kind of! I don’t so much commentate as I do shout and scream! I’m a nightmare for screaming “what are you doing??! You totally shouldn’t have done that! You should have done X-Y-Z!” I do have a little bit of an inner monologue though. I talk to myself a lot throughout the day. I find it helps me concentrate and remember what I’m doing. I have to make sure I don’t do that when I’m announcing derby bouts because I will probably mutter something incoherent and/or ridiculous! And yes, by inner monologue, I do mean that essentially…I talk out loud to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Which has been your favourite bout to call and what are you looking forward to calling in the future?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final of Quad Nations a few months ago in Swansea. It’s my favourite for one reason…GCRG won the whole thing! Although as well as being my favourite, it is also my worst because I was so proud of the girls yet I had to remain completely impartial the whole time. It actually got to the point where I just went quiet because if I didn’t, I was going to explode! At the end, I broke down in tears…while talking on the mic! Not ashamed to admit, I bawled my eyes out! I’d also say MRD vs. GCRG because I got to work with a fellow wrestling fan, Captain Malice! We bounced off each other fantastically and had an awesome chemistry. It was the first time we met, yet everything we did just sounded so natural. Loved it. What do I look forward to calling in the future? Well, I applied to announce the Men’s World Cup next year but to be fair, I’m probably not experienced enough for that yet. I would love to do it and have total faith in my own ability, but there are loads of other awesome people who have applied so I don’t envy those who have to make the final decision!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>announcers</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/10/22/an-interview-with-smackdaddy/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 16:08:09 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>