<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about annoucements)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/annoucements.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Big Blether 2: Mean City host the return of the Scottish Derby community meetup.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/06/big-blether-2-mean-city-host-the-return-of-the-scottish-derby-community-meetup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, the Scottish Roller Derby Community made a bit of history, by finally getting together in one place for a &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/18/the-big-blether-scotland-together/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big Blether&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This wasn't just a disorganised chat, of course: this was the first ever Roller Derby Conference for Scottish derby, on the model of the European "EROC". On the 7th of October 2017, the vast majority of active Scottish leagues were represented by pairs of delegates [and all but one of those who couldn't make it sent statements by proxy], actively engaged in process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-24409 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/screen-shot-2017-09-13-at-16-17-08.png" alt="Screen Shot 2017-09-13 at 16.17.08" width="335" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the first Big Blether was the brainchild of Auld Reekie Roller Girls' Crazylegs and Skinner, and Glasgow Roller Derby's Head Referee, Candy Moho, it was also agreed that future convocations would pass the torch onto other leagues around the country, spreading the democratic work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as it goes, the first volunteers to do the hard thing of repeating previous success were Glasgow's All-Gender league, Mean City Roller Derby. Very slightly more than a year later, their iteration of the conference, Big Blether 2, is coming to central Glasgow on the 20th October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principal task of a repeat convention is more nuanced than that of a first meeting. The first Big Blether did great things in generating conversation; in spreading knowledge [we personally enjoyed the group discussion elements, and how well they were orchestrated] and sharing problems. &lt;em&gt;More importantly&lt;/em&gt;, it generated actions - foci for future progress and development, mutually agreed by all those present. (It also gained Scottish derby a little bit of publicity, via an article in Five On Five magazine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second Big Blether will have the equally hard task of looking at those actions, a year later, and seeing what has been done, what has not; correcting course, potentially, or pushing forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it might do us well to look at what actions the first Big Blether produced, across the multiple sessions it held (these were scheduled as pairs of parallel sessions, run as facilitated group discussions):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby Oversight&lt;/strong&gt; spread some useful information (and quashed some misapprehensions) about the existing governance structures in Roller Derby. The action produced was to develop a "&lt;strong&gt;Scottish Derby Lobbying Group&lt;/strong&gt;" to provide a unified voice for the Scottish community in representing our needs and desires to larger entities.
We followed up on this, and believe that at least some work was done towards this aim, but as yet there is no formal group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Game Scheduling&lt;/strong&gt; produced some frank discussion between leagues about competition for resources; the low ratio of leagues to halls and fans (as well as to officials), the network effects which mean that smaller leagues can be accidentally outcompeted by older, more established clubs, and so on. The actions for this session were to more strongly adopt the shared &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby Schedule&lt;/strong&gt; for scheduling bouts and events (this common document is hosted on Google Docs, and made available via links in the Scottish Derby Facebook group) and to consider &lt;strong&gt;Sharing Fixtures with Other Leagues&lt;/strong&gt;.
We've seen use of the Schedule increase significantly since the first Big Blether, and there have been a number of "shared fixtures", so we think these actions have been broadly successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Officiating&lt;/strong&gt; involved some extensive discussions about the widespread issues of officials recruitment and training (and respect within leagues). The action for this session was to promote more central training and learning opportunities for Officials (on and off skates) - a &lt;strong&gt;Ref School&lt;/strong&gt; to be run by Glasgow Roller Derby - and for leagues to work towards giving their officials a more "cohesive identity" to form around and generally &lt;strong&gt;treat them as first class citizens&lt;/strong&gt; of the sport.
The Glasgow Roller Derby Ref School has run a few sessions (and Dundee have continued to run their own series of Officiating bootcamps, extant before Big Blether); and the branding of several league's officials as their own "teams" seems to represent a start of the second action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Access to Scottish Derby&lt;/strong&gt; revolved around the perennial issues of costs, access to halls and training certifications; as well as problems with providing kit, and burnout in "highly active" members of the community; and the less discussed issues with cultural homogeneity in derby. This session produced a lot of "personal actions" for leagues to &lt;strong&gt;Share More Resources&lt;/strong&gt;, and investigate community Volunteering Schemes.
It's difficult to measure how well this has been progressed without hearing from all the leagues - so this will be a point of discussion in October!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting as a whole also produced actions to produce and maintain a &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby Ranking&lt;/strong&gt;, which would enable a &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby National Tournament&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Scottish League or Championships&lt;/strong&gt;.
These have progressed very slightly (there's an initial Scottish Derby Ranking derived from Flat Track Stats Europe ratings), but on the meat of the matter - an organised competitive structure - there's a lot of work to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The second ever Big Blether will give those actioned a chance to report on their progress, as well as discussing any new topics which have developed in the past 12 months - since that year has seen three World Cups, a changing structure in other International Gameplay, and at least one new style of Roller Derby, we’re sure that there will be lots to talk about.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2nd Big Blether will be hosted on the 20th October 2018, in &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/bsRwxpsb6Do"&gt;Glasgow Quakers Meeting House, Elmbank Crescent, Glasgow. G2 4PS&lt;/a&gt;. Final timings to be decided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams can register representatives (as can independents) here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSf5LLsKjK3egYsLrcJNX8vWnnoRV5DRErii42kKAsANWbbP-w/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSf5LLsKjK3egYsLrcJNX8vWnnoRV5DRErii42kKAsANWbbP-w/viewform&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;REGISTRATION CLOSES 1 OCTOBER.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can contribute to the discussion topics on offer, and shape the schedule, via this form here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeiKb3UVcj1mKjVAeZmUVUY5krWkziPGH7HKCR4OQirmRKATQ/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeiKb3UVcj1mKjVAeZmUVUY5krWkziPGH7HKCR4OQirmRKATQ/viewform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>communication</category><category>in the news</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>officials</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>team scotland</category><category>the big blether</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/06/big-blether-2-mean-city-host-the-return-of-the-scottish-derby-community-meetup/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 10:00:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2018 Seasons beginnings for DRG!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/28/2018-seasons-beginnings-for-drg/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a late start due to the very wonderful &lt;em&gt;Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/em&gt; earlier this year in Manchester (!), Dundee Roller Girls are hosting their Season Opener on &lt;strong&gt;15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of April 2018&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;D.I.S.C. in Dundee&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boasting an action packed day for both DRG's A and B team, doors open at &lt;strong&gt;12:30&lt;/strong&gt; with tickets on the day at &lt;strong&gt;£6.&lt;/strong&gt; You can look forward to &lt;em&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/em&gt;' Fear Maidens facing off against the Bonnie Colliders at 1pm, with &lt;em&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/em&gt;' All Star Reserves taking the track against the Silvery Tayzers at 3pm!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a new season of games, come new captains! So we thought we would have a wee chat with both teams' captains to see how the season is shaping up. First up is ALLY-J and Tiny Tearaway captaining the Bonnie Colliders!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="26529,26530" type="circle" columns="2"]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table style="width:100%;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Questions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;ALLY-J&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;Tiny Tearaway&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;931&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Position&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Jammer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Jammer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Derby Hero&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Hubs &amp;amp; Mayhem&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Lady Trample and Mayhem&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Motto&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Lets do dis"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Nothing is impossible, the word itself says "I'm possible""&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How long have you been skating?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I’ve been quad skating with DRG since March 2016, so 2 years now (time flies!) but used to inline skate from the age of 10!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I have been skating 6 years this coming May (scary) and I have been with DRG for 2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;What does this season hold for the Colliders?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We've had the opportunity of playing in Copenhagen, Newcastle and in our home town, and this season we're going to build as a whole Team! We totally found our feet working with each other, and we are looking at focusing on attendance, positivity and building our knowledge of the game!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Yes its going to be very exciting for the Colliders. We have some fantastic games lined up already and a strong team full of skaters determined to be the best.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;As a B team, what challenges to you face?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Finding our way of working together as a team. Fitting in our newest skaters and helping them gain lots more skills and understanding of the game.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We are all part of a very supportive league so the challenges I see aren’t limited to us as a team. We face the same challenges as the A team; attendance, working together well and pushing ourselves to the best of our abilities.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How does the league, as a whole, carve space for the B team?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;As a league, our A and B team train together, which is an amazing opportunity. We are constantly learning from each other, talking over drills and skills; with us skating alongside folk from Team Scotland, really being able to learn from the best is our greatest asset.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;B team, A team who? We're a league that trains together. Skaters for both teams, crossovers and new skaters. We all do the same drills and are expected to put the same amount of hard work and effort into every one from the newer skaters to those who were on Team Scotland.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;And if you could set goals for yourself and for the team this season?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;My personal goal is to work on my jammer skills and tactical knowledge. I want to work well for the team and push myself this season! For the Colliders: to focus on ourselves as a team. Although we are all building our personal skills, I really want everyone to bring positivity and sportsmanship to the Colliders.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Our B team has played and flourished with smaller numbers the past season. It would be great to see us play with higher numbers. This would give us the chance to have a solid jammer rotation and walls that are to be reckoned with. To be part of that jammer rotation is my goal for this season.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Second up is the captains of the Silvery Tayzers, Seaton and Bosies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="26532,26531" type="circle" columns="2"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table style="width:100%;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Questions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;Seaton&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;Bosies&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;102&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;37&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Position&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Pivot/ Offence&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Blocker&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Derby Hero&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Serelson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Kid Block&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Motto&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Shitemare"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"SITFU"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How long have you been skating?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;6 years, started and stayed with DRG since then.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Skating for six years, initially with GCRD and have been with DRG for almost 2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;What does this season hold for the Tayzers?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I'll probably cry and give dramatic speeches alot. Hoping that as a league we'll be able to continue to perform like we did last season but also move passed that, honing in our skill set. The Tayzers have always performed under a "get the job done, nae fancy shit" mentality and I want to continue that while progressing within the WFTDA rankings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We are continuing to evolve the skills, tactics and endurance that we've developed last season. Which will set us in good stead for the exciting and tough games we have lined up for this year.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;As an A team skater, how do you stay ontop of your game&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I hydrate and then spew it up if I go too fast.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Pepsi Max, avocados and hummus. And cross training.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How has becoming a WFTDA league changed your priorities and training?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I think it gives us clear global equivalents to try to compete against, which we haven't really had before. It's good to be able to feel super involved with the development of the sport as a whole, as well as having access to more teams.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;It allows us to skate against teams of a similar calibre at national and international level, as well as competing in tournaments! This emphasises the need for a strong mental game, the ability to work as a tight unit and to continue to function when the fatigue sets in!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;And if you could set a goal for yourself and your team?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Finish a game without a spew or a cry, working on my mental game is a constant priority as well as my on track skills. As a team, I just want to end every game as a happy wee unit proud of what we have just done.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;My personal goal is the same as it was when I first started skating, which is to get lower! As a team if we can continue to work together, support each other on and off track and leave each game with a sense of achievement, then that's a job well done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26534" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/fbimage-01-1.png" alt="FBImage-01 (1)" width="6035" height="8534"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15th April 2018&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; Dundee DISC&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/908750512641504/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Event Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; 12:30-5pm&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; £6 on the door&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>interviews</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/28/2018-seasons-beginnings-for-drg/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 09:00:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mean City Roller Derby: Relaunch 2017</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/17/mean-city-roller-derby-relaunch-2017/</link><dc:creator>meancityrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-19258" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/received_10158754925150594.jpeg?w=300" alt="received_10158754925150594" width="300" height="300"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;Roller derby is a very DIY sport, so people at different levels will always be looking to achieve different goals within the sport. For some, their purpose is to advance as far as their body will allow. For others, it’s a great way to get out a couple of nights per week and let off some steam in a fun, friendly environment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby fall somewhere in the middle, as we're made up of a wide variety of different people and personalities – we have actors, students, scientists and even a Thai masseur! It's our members that make our league special. Although we have lives outside of derby, we'll always be there for each other, both on and off the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we're looking to continue to build upon progress we've made as a league and as a group of friends. Next Saturday&lt;strong&gt;, 20th May 2017&lt;/strong&gt;, will be our first bout of the year and we are hoping to capitalise on the hard work we've put into our training. Not only that, we are rebranding and will be debuting our new logo and team tops for the first time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logo really captures the good humour of the league and the spirit of Glasgow, Mean City's home and stomping ground.  We don't want to give too much away until game day, but we can say the logo is indeed still purple! This has been a long time in the making, but we can proudly say it looks fantastic. A big thank you to our Design Team and to Roller Derby City for our awesome new uniforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are facing tough opposition. Our ladies' team are playing the Granite City Fight Hawks from Aberdeen. We played them up north in &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85548"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and were narrowly defeated, so we will be looking to make the most of the home advantage! Our co-ed/open team will then be playing the Portsmouth Scurvy Wenches who are travelling up to Glasgow for the bout. They are more unknown to us, so should make exciting opponents. We also hear they like a good after party, as do we!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-19259" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/received_10158754874915594.jpeg?w=300" alt="received_10158754874915594" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The action starts at &lt;strong&gt;12pm&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662012,-4.2516905,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8661982!4d-4.2494965"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARC: Health &amp;amp; Fitness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Glasgow Caledonian University, Cowcaddens Road, Glasgow, G4 0BA. Entry is &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; per person/under 14s free,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets available from the Facebook event page here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1288036437909237/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1288036437909237/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>annoucements</category><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>pictures</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/17/mean-city-roller-derby-relaunch-2017/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 14:08:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Power of Scotland, under new Management</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/14/power-of-scotland-under-new-management/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;(Scotland's National Men's Roller Derby Team) Management and Coaching Team elections are complete, and there's some new faces, and some returning ones, in the mix; as well as a few new positions. The new team will be managing Power of Scotland as they prepare for the 2018 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;Men's World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're going to give you a rundown of the Positions and their holders:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Team Manager - Nikki Morris&lt;/h3&gt;
Returning to the role of Team Manager from the 2016 squad, Nikki is also a member of the MRDWC Committee, playing a strong role in progressing the International game itself.
When she's not involved with the International game, Nikki is a manager of Granite City Brawlers, Aberdeen's open Roller Derby league.
&lt;h3&gt;Bench Coach - Laura "Milky" Liston&lt;/h3&gt;
Milky is also returning from coaching PoS to the World Cup in Calgary this year. Now something like a quadruple threat, as referee, coach, blocker and jammer, she's also on the (Women's) Team Scotland Training Team, and is still one of Dundee Roller Girls' top skaters. She also has the distinction of having Bench Coached Madrid's Mad Riders at Men's European Cup 2016, despite not speaking Spanish.
Milky is a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdXySN7hUTbQGCepCzq5ifeS5qK9dglaRXZxchv0kymMGuzUg/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1"&gt;Talk Derby To Me Listener Awards Nominee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the Hero of the Year category.
&lt;h3&gt;LUM Coach/Line Up Manager - "McDonagh"&lt;/h3&gt;
McDonagh, or Owl,  was a rostered skater for Power of Scotland's 2016 World Cup run, and has stepped up as Assistant Coach for Barcelona. When not on the National Team, Owl skates for Nottingham Roller Derby's Super Smash Brollers (British Champs T2 Men's), and coaches Nottingham Roller Derby's Women's A team (British Champs T3 West).
&lt;h3&gt;Support Coaches - rEd Baron, Phoenix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;em&gt;These two new positions were added this time around, to provide additional coaching support.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;rEd Baron was on the roster for the 2016 World Cup in Calgary, as well as for the original 2014 team that played in Birmingham. When he's not on the National Team, he skates for and coaches at Bairn City Rollers (the Skelpies debuting in British Champs T3 North Men's this year), and has provided support for many other teams, including Team Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phoenix is currently a member of Glasgow Men's Roller Derby (British Champs T3 North) [MRDA's rules are very gender accepting], having transferred from Glasgow Roller Derby, where she was a rostered A-team skater, this year. She has extensive coaching experience from her time in GRD, and is also a member of the Team Scotland Training Squad.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Head Official - Mags Payne&lt;/h3&gt;
Returning from last time, Mags Payne will be providing her experience and contacts to the National Team, arranging officials for their practices and any bouts along the way, as well as keeping them in line. When she's not providing her knowledge to PoS, Mags referees for Auld Reekie Roller Girls, and also contributes to the WFTDA Rules committee. We recently talked to Mags about her refereeing, so you can read more &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/12/an-interview-with-mags-payne/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
Mags is a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdXySN7hUTbQGCepCzq5ifeS5qK9dglaRXZxchv0kymMGuzUg/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1"&gt;Talk Derby To Me Listener Awards Nominee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the Referee category, and Tournament Head Referee for ARRGmageddon, which is a Nominee in the Event category.
&lt;h3&gt;Team Sports Therapist - Goldginger&lt;/h3&gt;
Also returning from last time,  Goldginger is a fully trained professional Sports and Remedial Massage Therapist, and accompanied the team to Calgary to provide post-game therapy, as well as fundraising with her skills in the build up to the trip. When she's not doing sports therapy, she also skates for Dundee Roller Girls' A team, and is on the Team Scotland Training Squad.
Goldginger is a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdXySN7hUTbQGCepCzq5ifeS5qK9dglaRXZxchv0kymMGuzUg/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1"&gt;Talk Derby To Me Listener Awards Nominee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the Breakout Star category.
&lt;h3&gt;Team Photographer - Laura MacDonald&lt;/h3&gt;
Our final position, and another returnee. Laura was Team Photographer at the Calgary World Cup; when she's not photographing for the National Team she's an independent Roller Derby Photographer, mostly covering the Central Belt of Scotland (Fierce Valley Roller Girls, Bairn City Rollers, but also Mean City Roller Derby, Ayrshire Roller Derby, Lothian Derby Dolls, Dundee Roller Girls and others).
Laura is a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdXySN7hUTbQGCepCzq5ifeS5qK9dglaRXZxchv0kymMGuzUg/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1"&gt;Talk Derby To Me Listener Awards Nominee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the Photographer category.
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to tryout to skate in the Men's National Team, supported by the above, there are two training dates: &lt;strong&gt;14 Jan 2017&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1133482293431082/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1133482293431082/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] and &lt;strong&gt;29 Jan 2017&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1805159703057798/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1805159703057798/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] both in Grangemouth. The signup form for both is here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfsZy7UMC8AvVZIQJBRIGNolr1q8LBMTuPTEB919fkMCk7mhA/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfsZy7UMC8AvVZIQJBRIGNolr1q8LBMTuPTEB919fkMCk7mhA/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>power of scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/14/power-of-scotland-under-new-management/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 19:40:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Are you ready for a skating spooktacular?</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/19/are-you-ready-for-a-skating-spooktacular/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9817" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/fb-hallowmean-a.jpg" alt="fb-hallowmean-a" width="3545" height="1305"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tricks or treats? Why choose when you can have both – and a whole lot more – at Mean City’s closing home game of the year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow’s only coed league will be hosting a devilish double dunt of derby delights on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 29 October&lt;/strong&gt; at the Dear Mean Place – aka the &lt;strong&gt;ARC Sportscentre in Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hallowe'en is when things go bump in the night - &lt;strong&gt;HallowMean&lt;/strong&gt; is when things go bump on the track and there are trick and treats for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, the &lt;strong&gt;Mean City ladies&lt;/strong&gt; – fresh from a gallus bout against Granite’s Fight Hawks and looking to maintain their forward momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Meanies have been reaping the benefits of a greater emphasis on tactics, fitness and skills – with fresh recruits bolstering the settled squad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their opponents on 29 October will be the out-of-this-world &lt;strong&gt;ASTROs (Auld Reekie All Star Rookies)&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s going to be a stern test of the Mean City ladies’ resolve, as well as a showcase for some of Scotland’s finest up and coming skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second game will see &lt;strong&gt;Mean City's coed team&lt;/strong&gt; ghosting to the track to take on &lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers' Belter Skelpers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tis the season to be fearful and while there’s no fear among the Mean City ranks, there will be some trepidation given the excellent form the Belter Skelpers have been in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bairn City Rollers’ coed team recently played a mix of Aberdeen and Dundee skaters – the Brawler Buddies – and really brought their A game, winning with a well-oiled performance combining offence, defence and excellent tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City’s coed team may lack the experience of their opponents, but they have spirit, guts and tenacity in abundance and will match them skate for skate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City President Elaine Hunter – aka Roller Dobby - said: “We can’t wait to round off our home season in style with a spook-tacular thriller for all the family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Trick or treat – why choose when you can have both? There will be skating, fun, cakes and cracking tunes – what else are Saturdays made for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Tickets are just &lt;b&gt;£4&lt;/b&gt; in advance – that’s just £2 per game – or &lt;b&gt;£5&lt;/b&gt; on the door. It’s a bargain and you’ll be supporting grassroots sport at the same time. Under-14s get in free.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean City presents HallowMean - Saturday 29 October 2016 - doors open at the ARC Sportscentre at noon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;For more information on the event – &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/312912055752880/"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;For tickets – &lt;a href="http://www.meancityrollerderby.com/tickets.php"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>coed</category><category>in the news</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/19/are-you-ready-for-a-skating-spooktacular/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 15:36:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team England Training Roster announced!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/04/team-england-training-roster-announced/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Down south, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamenglandrollerderby/"&gt;Team England&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; have been hard at work with a massive set of tryouts over the last 2 months. After two initial tryouts in August, one in the North of England (hosted by Rainy City Roller Derby, the highest WFTDA ranked league north of London), and one in the South (hosted by London Rollergirls themselves), the initial talented few still had to face the final second-round tryout session in Birmingham, hosted by Central City Rollergirls. UKRDA Observers were, of course, present at each tryout to ensure fairness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Team England Manager illbilly, along with multiple selection teams chosen for their expertise in the Regions have deliberated and come to their final conclusions for the Training Roster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected, the roster draws strongly from the highest ranked UKRDA member teams: London Rollergirls provide 14 members, and Rainy City Roller Derby an impressive 7, with Middlesbrough Milk Rollers, Newcastle Roller Girls, Bristol Roller Derby, Liverpool Roller Birds, London Rockin' Rollers, Central City Rollergirls, and (across from the 'States) Charm City Roller Girls all helping to fill out the roster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official England Photographer Jason Ruffell captured images of the tryouts &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamenglandrollerderby/photos/?tab=album&amp;amp;album_id=1117984021615161"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamenglandrollerderby/photos/?tab=album&amp;amp;album_id=1161561447257418"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In full, the  Team England Training Roster is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-9153 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/england.jpg" alt="england" width="480" height="339"&gt; Image by:Sam Bishop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex Valentine &lt;strong&gt;666&lt;/strong&gt; Rainy City Roller Derby
Alex Wilde &lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; Rainy City Roller Derby
Becky Ruckus &lt;strong&gt;105&lt;/strong&gt; Liverpool Roller Birds&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;
Carley McAdam &lt;strong&gt;369&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Delta Strike &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Bristol Roller Derby
Ella Storey &lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; Middlesbrough Milk Rollers
Fay Roberts &lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt; Rainy City Roller Derby
Fayetal Blonde &lt;strong&gt;38&lt;/strong&gt; Rainy City Roller Derby
Fisher &lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; Rainy City Roller Derby
Florence the Machine &lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Gaz &lt;strong&gt;8008&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
GG Hardy &lt;strong&gt;308&lt;/strong&gt; Charm City Roller Girls
Ho Chee &lt;strong&gt;1971&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Jack Attack &lt;strong&gt;101&lt;/strong&gt; London Rockin' Rollers
Just Jess &lt;strong&gt;129&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Katie Hellvetica Black &lt;strong&gt;84&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Kid Block &lt;strong&gt;40&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Kristen Lee &lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Lexi Lightspeed &lt;strong&gt;55&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Lucy &lt;strong&gt;314&lt;/strong&gt; Newcastle Roller Girls
Menace &lt;strong&gt;6955&lt;/strong&gt; Rainy City Roller Derby
Missy Rascal &lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; Rainy City Roller Derby
Onyeka Igwe &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Philly &lt;strong&gt;419&lt;/strong&gt; Rainy City Roller Derby
Rammit &lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; London Rockin' Rollers
Rogue Runner &lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Shaolynn Scarlett &lt;strong&gt;888&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Stefanie Mainey &lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Terri Sudron &lt;strong&gt;86&lt;/strong&gt; Middlesbrough Milk Rollers
Trisha Smackanawa &lt;strong&gt;42&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Woo &lt;strong&gt;19&lt;/strong&gt; Central City Rollergirls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>team england roller derby</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/04/team-england-training-roster-announced/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 18:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UK's first Coaching Summit: Derby Stance</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/03/uks-first-coaching-summit-derby-stance/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back when we&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/27/an-interview-with-ukrda-chair-tess-robinson/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; interviewed&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;UKRDA Internal Chair, Tess Robinson, one of the ongoing projects she mentioned was to support Coaching, via certifications and other events.
Well, in combination with Coaching outfit &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/derbystance-1/"&gt;Rule 56&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Female-Coaching-Network-900335303354547/"&gt;Female Coaching Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, part of this is coming to pass: in &lt;strong&gt;November 19th&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;20th&lt;/strong&gt;, the UK's first "Coaching Summit" will be held, in &lt;strong&gt;Leeds&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/536421803211316/"&gt;"Derby Stance"&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;will be a two day event, with sessions available to see on the website, and including aspects across the community, including Junior Derby Coaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A host of guest speakers and presenters will be there, of who more in a bit, but this is also seen as being an opportunity for Roller Derby Coaches across the UK to get together to influence the future of coaching, the certification process and any other developments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To support this, Rule 56 have managed to get coaches from some of the top teams in the UK: Auld Reekie's own Stef Skinner, London Rollergirls/Team England and Double Threat Skates' Kirsten "Kitty Decapitate" Lee, ex Team England/current Wizards of Aus/Southern Discomfort Ballistic Whistle (who we &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/10/an-interview-with-outgoing-team-england-coach-ballistic-whistle/"&gt;interviewed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; not long ago) and many more. But, more than this, they've also managed to get Texas Rollergirls' own Smarty Pants (Nadia Kean) to come across to provide her own sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smarty is a very experienced coach, both in Roller Derby and other sports; she runs Get Smarty Coaching to provide coaching services across the USA and worldwide, as well as skating for Texas. She's also working on a book on coaching!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were lucky enough to get the chance to talk to her about her experience in coaching, roller derby and a lot of other topics. You can hear the interview, in a first for us at the blog, here (forgive the initial uming from yours truly, this is a new thing for us):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[soundcloud url="https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/285835975" params="auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true" width="100%" height="450" iframe="true" /]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you're inspired by that, get booking your tickets for Derby Stance, if you haven't already!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>annoucements</category><category>coaches</category><category>interviews</category><category>rule56</category><category>smarty pants</category><category>texas rollergirls</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/03/uks-first-coaching-summit-derby-stance/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 19:07:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BCR Central Belters vs Furness Firecrackers</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/09/12/bcr-central-belters-vs-furness-firecrackers/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elusive Sunday Afternoon Derby is back this weekend (18th of September) as Bairn City's Central Belters take on Furness Firecrackers at Grangemouth Sports Complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second time these teams have faced each other on track. The first encounter dating way back to July 2013,  when it was Furness who skated to victory taking the win that day by a large margin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We haven't seen much of the Belters on track this year but they have gotten two games so far under their belt for 2016. Those coming against Belfast City (home) and North Cheshire (away) and in both cases they have emerged victorious.  Since May of last year, the Belters have only lost one out of the five games they have played, which has seen them climb up the European rankings to 180th where they currently stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With it being over three years since these teams last played each other much has changed for both in that time, but there is only one way to see out how much and if the Belters will take the win this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors are at 14:15, &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/bcr-central-belters-v-furness-firecrackers-tickets-27243993518?utm-medium=discovery&amp;amp;utm-campaign=social&amp;amp;utm-content=attendeeshare&amp;amp;aff=escb&amp;amp;utm-source=cp&amp;amp;utm-term=listing"&gt;tickets can be purchased online in advance here&lt;/a&gt; or at the door on game day. For further information visit the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1676911969301646/"&gt;facebook event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/bcr-central-belters-v-furness-firecrackers-tickets-27243993518?utm-medium=discovery&amp;amp;utm-campaign=social&amp;amp;utm-content=attendeeshare&amp;amp;aff=escb&amp;amp;utm-source=cp&amp;amp;utm-term=listing"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8884" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/09/bcr-furness.jpg" alt="Central Belters vs Furness" width="669" height="351"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bcr</category><category>central belters</category><category>furness firecrackers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/09/12/bcr-central-belters-vs-furness-firecrackers/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 12:17:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Science v Magic: Twice in one month!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/09/science-v-magic-twice-in-one-month/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've previously mentioned that Glasgow Roller Derby are hosting an exhibition double header on the 20th of the this month, featuring a Science v Fantasy themed B-feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if you like the idea of pitting SF against F, then you don't even have to wait that long, as Glasgow's only Coed league, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby/"&gt;Mean City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, are holding their own &lt;em&gt;coed&lt;/em&gt; extravaganza this weekend (&lt;strong&gt;13th August, 2pm&lt;/strong&gt;) as the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1807206382885256/"&gt;Wizards take on Gallifrey's finest Timelords.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;This is an opportunity to see both established MCRD skaters, as well as their newest up-and-coming skaters in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-8598" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/08/13653353_836734026463019_2149065422421141685_o.jpg?w=2048" alt="13653353_836734026463019_2149065422421141685_o" width="1024" height="724"&gt; Just one of four (4!) posters that Mean City produced for the event!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event will be at Mean City's usual venue, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662153,-4.2519236,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8662153!4d-4.2497349"&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Glasgow, with afterparty at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Rufus+T+Firefly/@55.8635334,-4.2600056,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48884420befd257d:0xff9a66f3090f61a0!8m2!3d55.8635594!4d-4.257813"&gt;Rufus T Firefly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. (Links above link to maps.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advance warning also: the following week (&lt;strong&gt;2oth August&lt;/strong&gt;) features a bit of a clash. As well as the aforementioned &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/550878811750965/"&gt;Soy Division v Vagine Regime/Science v Fantasy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; double header in &lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;, there will also be a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/972951379480637/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls / Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; joint double header in &lt;strong&gt;Grangemouth&lt;/strong&gt;! As the second bout in the schedule features the long anticipated rematch of Bairn City's Skelpies against Tyne and Fear B (the Inglorious B**stards), it seems that both events have unmissable second fixtures...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's &lt;em&gt;possible&lt;/em&gt;, based on the preliminary timings, to just about see the first bout in Glasgow, and then rush across Scotland by car to get to Grangemouth in time for both bouts, but we're not sure we'd risk it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The approximate timings are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First bout (&lt;strong&gt;Science v Fantasy&lt;/strong&gt;) at Glasgow, skateouts start &lt;strong&gt;13:05&lt;/strong&gt; (implies end around &lt;strong&gt;14:30&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second bout (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/SoyDivisionDerby/?fref=ts"&gt;Soy Division&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;/&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GayRobots/?fref=ts"&gt;Vagine Regime&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt; ends &lt;strong&gt;17:10?&lt;/strong&gt; (which implies a &lt;strong&gt;15:45&lt;/strong&gt; start, or earlier depending on slack?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First bout at Grangemouth (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://fvrg.co.uk"&gt;FVRG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; intraleague) starts &lt;strong&gt;15:30&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second bout (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers/?fref=ts"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;' Skelpies v &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/tyneandfear/?fref=ts"&gt;Tyne and Fear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; B) starts &lt;strong&gt;17:20&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes around 40 minutes to get from the centre of Glasgow to the centre of Grangemouth, so it should, hypothetically, be possible to see all of the mixed bout at Glasgow, jump in a car, and arrive &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; 20 minutes before the first game starts in Grangemouth. Assuming that derby runs to time, which is, of course, not something we can ever rely on, and that our guesses about the timings are correct... ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>annoucements</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>soy division</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>vagine regime uk</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/09/science-v-magic-twice-in-one-month/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 11:15:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Girls - Wanna Join?</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/22/fierce-valley-roller-girls-wanna-join/</link><dc:creator>alibonanza</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="" title="11908592_1042693805742471_2412030954146539060_o" src="http://i1.wp.com/www.fvrg.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/11908592_1042693805742471_2412030954146539060_o.jpg?resize=530%2C355" alt="11908592_1042693805742471_2412030954146539060_o" width="222" height="149"&gt;&lt;img class="" title="11888546_1042693869075798_8615470236872184543_o" src="http://i1.wp.com/www.fvrg.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/11888546_1042693869075798_8615470236872184543_o.jpg?resize=262%2C176" alt="11888546_1042693869075798_8615470236872184543_o" width="221" height="149"&gt;&lt;img class="" title="FVRG Taster Sessions" src="http://i1.wp.com/www.fvrg.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/11875044_1042689072409611_6975712594037629319_o.jpg?resize=262%2C175" alt="FVRG Taster Sessions" width="222" height="148"&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;7th August&lt;/strong&gt;, FVRG will be hosting a roller derby taster in &lt;strong&gt;Grangemouth Sports Complex&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;from 11.30 - 13.30.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Fierce Valley Roller Girls is a not-for-profit women's roller derby league within the Forth Valley area. Whilst our competitive team is women-only, we welcome all genders to be referee or non-skating members. Our training sessions and our home games are held in Grangemouth Sports Complex.
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in joining Fierce Valley Roller Girls and are aged 18 or over, please complete our Registration Form &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/join-fvrg/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Signing up as a competitive skater or as a referee?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
If you would like to register as either a skater or a referee, the taster session will give you the opportunity to learn the basics of skating (and stopping!) safely. You will be buddied up with an experienced skater who will share their wisdom - and their equipment - with you. Please bring your own mouth guard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the taster session, we will welcome you into a dedicated roller derby training programme for beginners, tailor-made and led by FVRG coaches. On completion of the beginners training, you will also attend the intermediate training, where your roller derby 'minimum skills' will be assessed. Beginner-training is held on Sunday mornings; intermediate-training is held on Wednesday nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competitive skaters will then move into the advanced training programme and have the opportunity to try out for our travel team. Advanced-training is held on Friday nights; team-training is held on Tuesday nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon completion of their intermediate training, referees will branch off into the referee training programme. It's common for referees to gain their basic training in our intermediate sessions, and then move onto officiating drills in the advanced and team sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Signing up as a non-skating member?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Not everyone in at FVRG skates, believe it or not. If you want to be part of the roller derby community but don't wish to compete of officiate, then you can join us a Non Skating Member. We're always looking for 'Non Skating Officials' (NSOs); artwork designers; photographers; bloggers - the list goes on. All we ask is that you attend at least one of our 'scrims' (internal games) per month to keep you integrated with the league and to learn the rules of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We hope to see you there !&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>#wearefierce</category><category>annoucements</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>fvrg</category><category>join roller derby</category><category>taster session</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/22/fierce-valley-roller-girls-wanna-join/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 08:57:35 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>