<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about announcements)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/announcements.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>UKRDA Elections Update: your new Directors!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/26/ukrda-elections-update-your-new-directors/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a democratic organisation, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://ukrda.org.uk/"&gt;UK Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; undergoes a yearly AGM, in which vacancies for its Directorships can be filled by vote within the member leagues. The most recent AGM was held this month, 5th of June, and resulted in a particularly large number of changes to the Directorships, due to retirements and the filling of previously empty posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're giving you a quick overview of the current Directorships and their holders, to help you get to know your organisation.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26918" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/ukrdadirectors2018.jpg" alt="UKRDADirectors2018" width="960" height="720"&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Halo Jones - Secretary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halo Jones remains in the position of Secretary for UKRDA from before the AGM. Outside of UKRDA, she is well known in the world of NSOing around the Oxford area (especially for &lt;a href="https://www.oxfordwheelsofgory.co.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oxford Wheels of Gory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), and beyond. A nominee for the Talk Derby To Me NSO Listener Awards in 2017 and 2016, she has officiated at multiple high level events, including the 2017 MRDA Championships, and both the Roller Derby World Cup and the Men's Roller Derby World Cup 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maw Deuce - Director for Internal Communication&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maw Deuce continues in her role as Director for Internal Communication from the last elections. The longest term member of the UKRDA family, Maw previously served as the UKRDA National Squads chair, responsible for interactions with and support of the affiliated national teams, and has held additional roles before then.
Outside of UKRDA, Maw is a member of &lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and a referee and official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rollin Rat - Director for Officials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rollin Rat continues as a Director from before the AGM, moving from the position of Director of Policy &amp;amp; Strategy to Director of Officials. Outside of UKRDA, he is a Referee for &lt;a href="https://centralcityrollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Birmingham, and has refereed at many high level events, including the Roller Derby World Cup 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stat Man - Director for Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stat Man has a long history in Roller Derby, as both an Announcer and an Official. As well as starting one of the first attempts to rate and rank European teams, he was one of the individuals responsible for establishing the ongoing &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;s, of which he remains the Chair of the Organising Committee. He may also have been involved in the short-lived attempt to have a roller derby team based in Sealand. He has also continued to announce at high level events, including both World Cups this year.
Stat Man has also previously served as Executive Director of Sanctioning and Games for the MRDA (2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smacktivist - Director for Communications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smacktivist is new to the Director of Communications role. She hails from &lt;a href="http://rollerbillies.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cambridge Rollerbillies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where she's currently Line Up Manager for their B-Team, the Punt Rockers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dorkmistress - Director for External Engagement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dorkmistress has a very strong history in Roller Derby, as both an Announcer and an Official. She has previously Managed several iterations of Team Wales Roller Derby, as well as announcing for &lt;a href="http://www.swanseacityrollerderby.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swansea City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and announcing and officiating for &lt;a href="http://www.sws.pizza/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;South Wales Silures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; she's also been seen announcing across a gamut of high level events, including the most recent Men's Roller Derby World Cup, and Newcastle Roller Girls' EuroClash tournament.
As well as UKRDA External Engagement, she currently holds the position of &lt;a href="http://www.rollerderbynationscommittee.org/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roller Derby Nations Committee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Regional Representative for Northern Europe, representing all the World Cup Nations from that region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buckfast - Head of Tech&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buckfast is new to the role of Head of Tech (which is not a Directoral role, and has been semi-empty since the last AGM). He's relatively new to Roller Derby - having recently begun Bench Coaching at &lt;a href="https://www.yorkminxters.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>agm</category><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>in the news</category><category>news</category><category>ukrda</category><category>ukrda directors</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/26/ukrda-elections-update-your-new-directors/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 11:22:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Big Blether: Scotland Together</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/18/the-big-blether-scotland-together/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's often been commented that Scotland has seen some of the more dramatic growth (and changes) in Roller Derby, with respect to its population. Since the first league started in Glasgow in 2007, Roller Derby has spread across the Nation - but not always uniformly, or consistently. Whilst there's certainly a lot of Roller Derby in Scotland now - with 19 leagues in existence (by one count) now - communication and organisation across the community has not always been as good as it could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;October 7th&lt;/strong&gt;, in Edinburgh's Charteris Centre, three people aim to change this. Auld Reekie Roller Girls' Crazylegs and (Steph) Skinner, and Glasgow Roller Derby's head referee Candy Moho, are organising what they hope will be the first of a regular series of gatherings of the Scottish Roller Derby Community in one place and one time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-24409 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/screen-shot-2017-09-13-at-16-17-08.png" alt="Screen Shot 2017-09-13 at 16.17.08" width="335" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Big Blether&lt;/em&gt;, as it's now known, aims to bring together all of the extant leagues and clubs in Scotland, as well as others in the sport, in order to share and discuss the future and present of the sport. Every active league in Scotland has been invited to the event as part of the organisation process,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to two-thirds of the Organisers - thrice Team Scotland skater,  founding Roller Derby Nations Committee rep, and founding Auld Reekie Roller Girls member, &lt;em&gt;Crazylegs&lt;/em&gt;; and long-standing Glasgow Roller Derby Head Referee and organiser of the Scottish Roller Derby Events Spreadsheet, &lt;em&gt;Candy Moho&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crazylegs was inspired to kickstart this idea at the last European Rollerderby Organisational Conference, as she told us. "I guess for me the inspiration came from EROC - I love attending that event, and I guess the more I go to events like that and attend sessions, and deliver talks,  I kind of think, we've got such a compact community in Scotland - and I don't think we take advantage of it enough.
Our league [ARRG] gets so much out of events like EROC in terms of knowledge and new ideas to refresh you. It's so much easier for us to get together in Scotland - the leagues in Australia might find it harder to all meet up, for example - but we're so close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chatted to Candy at the end of EROC, and she mentioned that she'd been thinking of something similar, so it was in my mind from then."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candy, meanwhile, had a slightly different perspective. "My main focus was the Officials side, off of the back of a project I'd done for the Open Uni. And also being in the Event Organising Group, the Interleague Liasion group, a lot of the issues there - it just seemed it would be easier to get people in the same room to talk to each other!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;One of the things I am planning to do at The Big Blether is to present the findings from my OU project, which focussed on Scottish Derby Officials - I've not had a chance to pass on the results of that to the community, and I thought this is the perfect forum to do it, and make the results public after. That took in feedback from Officials as well as skaters from leagues. A lot of the stuff from that is still very relevant, and it's relevant to UK officials as well."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Unlike EROC's speaker-centered sessions, The Big Blether is intended to foster a less hierarchical approach - each topic will have a "facilitator" to moderate, but will emphasise communication and discussion between peers, not a top-down dissemination of from on-high.&lt;/p&gt;
Topics on the agenda currently cover the spectrum of community concerns and interests, from best practice in Training, through the creation of better links for interleague support and with local communities, and how to move the sport on in terms of recognition on both local and National/International scales; however, in keeping with the design of the event, there are no topics which are out of bounds if attendees wish to discuss them.
&lt;p&gt;Speaking to the organisers, again, they each have their own favourite areas from the menu presented. For Crazylegs, a key topic is governance and organisation, on all scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We want to cover topics like League Governance - so: the legalities of how you set up a league, how you structure a league, what works for different leagues, of different sizes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I guess leading on from that you'd look at&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt; sports &lt;/span&gt;governance - as in governing bodies, as in the national teams, UKRDA, WFTDA [MRDA], just I think maybe putting a bit of information out there for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I think there's a lot of myths out there concerning the various bodies - but we also need to talk about what Scotland itself needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I know Stef's driving force for this comes from her job, she's a community sports officer, and she's been has been doing a lot of research around the growth of sport, how we can better use Sport Scotland, and have better links with them for funding and support. We were also discussing working on having clear pathways, to show people how they can get to where they want to go - if that's high level competition, or having fun - from where they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;And I think training as well - what support setups different leagues need, if we feel that there needs to be more information out there about training and structures, and how to set things up from beginning to getting wherever your league or team wants to go."&lt;/p&gt;
Candy, with her other hat on, is most concerned with another topic. "On the Events side: getting a Scottish Tournament (doing another "Highland Fling", perhaps) but also the topic of if we need to look into a League structure - as they have in Germany  and France. I think you tend to find that when you have that kind of structure, and people working well together, then you also drive the sport, and the level of competition as well. "
&lt;p&gt;But, most of all, the event is about everyone meeting up and building the community links that can make Scottish Derby stronger together. As Crazylegs notes, "having a relaxed chat to people that you don't know, but you've heard of their leagues - if you get that kind of face-to-face conversation with people you've only interacted with on social media, then you make better connections, and everyone learns something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The venue's amazing, it's close to town, we'll get some nice stuff going on in the breaks to build connections - and we'll be providing a delicious lunch!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Charteris Centre can be found &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Greyfriars+Charteris+Centre/@55.9455414,-3.1817633,19.53z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x104319695d91d9d9!8m2!3d55.9456793!4d-3.1812937"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here on Google Maps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
Sign up for leagues (who are already contacted) is for the &lt;strong&gt;23rd September&lt;/strong&gt;, with potential for other slots for non-league attendees after the initial numbers are known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All questions can be sent to the event organisers at &lt;a href="mailto:scottishderbyevent@gmail.com"&gt;scottishderbyevent@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial shortlist of topics is:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Training: Creation of clear pathways and sharing best practice&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sport recognition (Leagues, National/International Governing Bodies and National Teams)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Club governance; sharing best practices / resources / contacts, league support.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Scottish Events Scheduling: game scheduling, events, opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Partnership working, local communities&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Officiating: recruitment and retention, development pathways, national association&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Volunteering (development, pathways, recruitment, training)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
The organisers would like to thank Auld Reekie Roller Girls for funding both the event, and travel subsidies for the more distant leagues.&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>news</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>the big blether</category><category>training</category><category>upcoming events</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/18/the-big-blether-scotland-together/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 07:09:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow ready to rock as British Champs T3 goes down to the wire</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/06/glasgow-ready-to-rock-as-british-champs-t3-goes-down-to-the-wire/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't stop believing&lt;/strong&gt; - that's the tune blasting out at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GlasgowMensRollerDerby/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; HQ where the Irn Brn are plotting a derby escape act which would make Houdini hop the apex with delight.
&lt;p&gt;This Saturday, GMRD play host to the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/133440747209468/?acontext=%7B%22ref%22%3A%222%22%2C%22ref_dashboard_filter%22%3A%22upcoming%22%2C%22action_history%22%3A%22%5B%7B%5C%22surface%5C%22%3A%5C%22dashboard%5C%22%2C%5C%22mechanism%5C%22%3A%5C%22main_list%5C%22%2C%5C%22extra_data%5C%22%3A%5B%5D%7D%5D%22%7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;final fixtures in the British Championships' Men's Tier 3 - Regional North group&lt;/a&gt; (at Glasgow's ARC Sports Centre).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD will be taking on their Celtic cousins, Men Behaving Derby (MBD), while Bairn City Rollers' Skelpies will be setting blasters to stun against Teesside Skate Invaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a decidedly Scottish-type twist, only a specific combination of results can now see GMRD qualify for the play-offs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the uninitiated, here's the short story:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April, GMRD travelled to Dublin to play the Skate Invaders, winning by 234 points to 167. GMRD were later denuded of victory due to an eligibility malfunction, with the score becoming 200-0 in favour of the Invaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD's next game against the Skelpies was then forfeited by the Falkirk team due to lack of numbers - a 200-0 win in favour of GMRD - leaving the table looking like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-20255 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/brd-table.jpg" alt="BRD table" width="1014" height="650"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, GMRD need to beat MBD on Saturday - that's a pre-requisite if GMRD want a play-off place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regardless of what flavour that victory lollipop is, the Irn Brn need to be sucking on it by Saturday evening.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Skelpies win against the Invaders then victory of any variety will be enough for the Glasgow mob.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if the Invaders win &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; GMRD win then the three top teams will be tied on six points and it goes down to scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD would need to have a better points differential than MBD to qualify for the play-offs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't worry about crunching the numbers, SRD Blog has done it for you - &lt;strong&gt;GMRD need to beat MBD by over 123 points to be certain of a play-off place.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That isn't going to be any kind of easy as MBD have already beaten both the Skelpies and the Skate Invaders this season, the latter with just 6 players!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's why Hugs &amp;amp; Kisses - GMRD's President - is sounding the rallying horn to the Irn Brn faithful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We need everyone in the West of Scotland and beyond to come out and support Saturday's double-header," he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-20254" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/18768309_10209728094985432_4231219290125343973_o.jpg" alt="18768309_10209728094985432_4231219290125343973_o" width="1600" height="1067"&gt; The Irn Brn - photo by Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"This is an amazing first for our city - a British Champs men's game at the home of Glasgow derby, the ARC sportscentre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"You are going to see two gallus games of roller derby, with the fate of three teams hanging in the balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Come out and support the Irn Brn as we attempt the great escape. We're confident we can put on a great show - don't stop believing, ken?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* Doors open at the ARC sportscentre, Glasgow, on Saturday (10 June) at 11.30am. Tickets cost £7. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/133440747209468/?acontext=%7B%22ref%22%3A%222%22%2C%22ref_dashboard_filter%22%3A%22upcoming%22%2C%22action_history%22%3A%22%5B%7B%5C%22surface%5C%22%3A%5C%22dashboard%5C%22%2C%5C%22mechanism%5C%22%3A%5C%22main_list%5C%22%2C%5C%22extra_data%5C%22%3A%5B%5D%7D%5D%22%7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Click here for more information.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teeside Skate Invaders vs Bairn City Skelpies - first whistle at 11:45&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby vs Men Behaving Derby - first whistle at 2pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>men behaving derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>teeside skate invaders</category><category>the skelpies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/06/glasgow-ready-to-rock-as-british-champs-t3-goes-down-to-the-wire/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 16:02:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mean City Roller Derby: Relaunch 2017</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/17/mean-city-roller-derby-relaunch-2017/</link><dc:creator>meancityrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-19258" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/received_10158754925150594.jpeg?w=300" alt="received_10158754925150594" width="300" height="300"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;Roller derby is a very DIY sport, so people at different levels will always be looking to achieve different goals within the sport. For some, their purpose is to advance as far as their body will allow. For others, it’s a great way to get out a couple of nights per week and let off some steam in a fun, friendly environment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby fall somewhere in the middle, as we're made up of a wide variety of different people and personalities – we have actors, students, scientists and even a Thai masseur! It's our members that make our league special. Although we have lives outside of derby, we'll always be there for each other, both on and off the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we're looking to continue to build upon progress we've made as a league and as a group of friends. Next Saturday&lt;strong&gt;, 20th May 2017&lt;/strong&gt;, will be our first bout of the year and we are hoping to capitalise on the hard work we've put into our training. Not only that, we are rebranding and will be debuting our new logo and team tops for the first time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logo really captures the good humour of the league and the spirit of Glasgow, Mean City's home and stomping ground.  We don't want to give too much away until game day, but we can say the logo is indeed still purple! This has been a long time in the making, but we can proudly say it looks fantastic. A big thank you to our Design Team and to Roller Derby City for our awesome new uniforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are facing tough opposition. Our ladies' team are playing the Granite City Fight Hawks from Aberdeen. We played them up north in &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85548"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and were narrowly defeated, so we will be looking to make the most of the home advantage! Our co-ed/open team will then be playing the Portsmouth Scurvy Wenches who are travelling up to Glasgow for the bout. They are more unknown to us, so should make exciting opponents. We also hear they like a good after party, as do we!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-19259" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/received_10158754874915594.jpeg?w=300" alt="received_10158754874915594" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The action starts at &lt;strong&gt;12pm&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662012,-4.2516905,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8661982!4d-4.2494965"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARC: Health &amp;amp; Fitness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Glasgow Caledonian University, Cowcaddens Road, Glasgow, G4 0BA. Entry is &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; per person/under 14s free,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets available from the Facebook event page here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1288036437909237/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1288036437909237/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>annoucements</category><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>pictures</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/17/mean-city-roller-derby-relaunch-2017/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 14:08:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Power of Scotland, under new Management</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/14/power-of-scotland-under-new-management/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;(Scotland's National Men's Roller Derby Team) Management and Coaching Team elections are complete, and there's some new faces, and some returning ones, in the mix; as well as a few new positions. The new team will be managing Power of Scotland as they prepare for the 2018 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;Men's World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're going to give you a rundown of the Positions and their holders:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Team Manager - Nikki Morris&lt;/h3&gt;
Returning to the role of Team Manager from the 2016 squad, Nikki is also a member of the MRDWC Committee, playing a strong role in progressing the International game itself.
When she's not involved with the International game, Nikki is a manager of Granite City Brawlers, Aberdeen's open Roller Derby league.
&lt;h3&gt;Bench Coach - Laura "Milky" Liston&lt;/h3&gt;
Milky is also returning from coaching PoS to the World Cup in Calgary this year. Now something like a quadruple threat, as referee, coach, blocker and jammer, she's also on the (Women's) Team Scotland Training Team, and is still one of Dundee Roller Girls' top skaters. She also has the distinction of having Bench Coached Madrid's Mad Riders at Men's European Cup 2016, despite not speaking Spanish.
Milky is a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdXySN7hUTbQGCepCzq5ifeS5qK9dglaRXZxchv0kymMGuzUg/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1"&gt;Talk Derby To Me Listener Awards Nominee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the Hero of the Year category.
&lt;h3&gt;LUM Coach/Line Up Manager - "McDonagh"&lt;/h3&gt;
McDonagh, or Owl,  was a rostered skater for Power of Scotland's 2016 World Cup run, and has stepped up as Assistant Coach for Barcelona. When not on the National Team, Owl skates for Nottingham Roller Derby's Super Smash Brollers (British Champs T2 Men's), and coaches Nottingham Roller Derby's Women's A team (British Champs T3 West).
&lt;h3&gt;Support Coaches - rEd Baron, Phoenix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;em&gt;These two new positions were added this time around, to provide additional coaching support.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;rEd Baron was on the roster for the 2016 World Cup in Calgary, as well as for the original 2014 team that played in Birmingham. When he's not on the National Team, he skates for and coaches at Bairn City Rollers (the Skelpies debuting in British Champs T3 North Men's this year), and has provided support for many other teams, including Team Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phoenix is currently a member of Glasgow Men's Roller Derby (British Champs T3 North) [MRDA's rules are very gender accepting], having transferred from Glasgow Roller Derby, where she was a rostered A-team skater, this year. She has extensive coaching experience from her time in GRD, and is also a member of the Team Scotland Training Squad.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Head Official - Mags Payne&lt;/h3&gt;
Returning from last time, Mags Payne will be providing her experience and contacts to the National Team, arranging officials for their practices and any bouts along the way, as well as keeping them in line. When she's not providing her knowledge to PoS, Mags referees for Auld Reekie Roller Girls, and also contributes to the WFTDA Rules committee. We recently talked to Mags about her refereeing, so you can read more &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/12/an-interview-with-mags-payne/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
Mags is a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdXySN7hUTbQGCepCzq5ifeS5qK9dglaRXZxchv0kymMGuzUg/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1"&gt;Talk Derby To Me Listener Awards Nominee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the Referee category, and Tournament Head Referee for ARRGmageddon, which is a Nominee in the Event category.
&lt;h3&gt;Team Sports Therapist - Goldginger&lt;/h3&gt;
Also returning from last time,  Goldginger is a fully trained professional Sports and Remedial Massage Therapist, and accompanied the team to Calgary to provide post-game therapy, as well as fundraising with her skills in the build up to the trip. When she's not doing sports therapy, she also skates for Dundee Roller Girls' A team, and is on the Team Scotland Training Squad.
Goldginger is a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdXySN7hUTbQGCepCzq5ifeS5qK9dglaRXZxchv0kymMGuzUg/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1"&gt;Talk Derby To Me Listener Awards Nominee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the Breakout Star category.
&lt;h3&gt;Team Photographer - Laura MacDonald&lt;/h3&gt;
Our final position, and another returnee. Laura was Team Photographer at the Calgary World Cup; when she's not photographing for the National Team she's an independent Roller Derby Photographer, mostly covering the Central Belt of Scotland (Fierce Valley Roller Girls, Bairn City Rollers, but also Mean City Roller Derby, Ayrshire Roller Derby, Lothian Derby Dolls, Dundee Roller Girls and others).
Laura is a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdXySN7hUTbQGCepCzq5ifeS5qK9dglaRXZxchv0kymMGuzUg/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1"&gt;Talk Derby To Me Listener Awards Nominee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the Photographer category.
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to tryout to skate in the Men's National Team, supported by the above, there are two training dates: &lt;strong&gt;14 Jan 2017&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1133482293431082/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1133482293431082/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] and &lt;strong&gt;29 Jan 2017&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1805159703057798/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1805159703057798/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] both in Grangemouth. The signup form for both is here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfsZy7UMC8AvVZIQJBRIGNolr1q8LBMTuPTEB919fkMCk7mhA/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfsZy7UMC8AvVZIQJBRIGNolr1q8LBMTuPTEB919fkMCk7mhA/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>power of scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/14/power-of-scotland-under-new-management/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 19:40:44 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>