<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about arrgmageddon)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/arrgmageddon.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Granite City's Hawks flock to the ARRGmageddon</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/21/granite-citys-hawks-flock-to-the-arrgmageddon/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the run up to Auld Reekie Roller Girls' first B-level tournament, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/535844416618826/"&gt;ARRGmageddon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the team travelling the furthest by far will be Aberdeen's Fight Hawks, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.granitecityrollerderby.co.uk/"&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s B team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hawks have played two of their three competitors this year, with very similar losses against Auld Reekie's ASTROs (in Edinburgh) and Dundee's Bonnie Colliders (at home in Aberdeen). They finished off their year so far with a win against Mean City Roller Derby's women's team (also by a very similar ratio, but in their favour!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We managed to catch new Fight Hawks Captain, Phanny, for a quick chat about their year, and ARRGmageddon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, how would you say the Fight Hawks year has been so far? Is there anything you'll be building on or focussing on as Captain?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's quite a tough question! The Hawks have, we have had a good year - we've definitely come on leaps and bounds from where we started - we're a stronger team, and we work better together. I (just) think we're quite gelled, and we like to have fun, we like to have a nice time;  we're not all about win win win, but when we do, its nice. And then we do enjoy a... sometimes we come off a loss and we're feeling pretty happy as well, because we've done our best as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Given your location, having to travel long distances together to get to bouts must help with the gelling?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah... Bus time is an opportunity to maybe speak to people that you wouldn't normally speak to, and then on the way back, from any tournament or games, it's a Party Bus, so a chance to drink with your teammates on the way up the road (laughs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARRGmageddon will be the first tournament that the Hawks have played in, do you have any plans for how to approach it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've had discussions about who's going on when, what's the best way to work this, not tiring out players before you get to the hour long game. I think, definitely going in for fun for the short games, and then really focus on the hour long game as the "big one".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's next for the Fight Hawks?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christmas Party! [laughs] As a team, we'll have a short break over the Christmas period - we'll be back on it around Janurary, and I believe... we're into games again in February!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARRGmageddon is this weekend - the &lt;strong&gt;26th November&lt;/strong&gt; - starting at &lt;strong&gt;11am&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Meadowbank+Sports+Centre/@55.9559777,-3.1579275,16.15z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x4887b86eb150070f:0x6955a8c9b9a10cc5!8m2!3d55.956619!4d-3.1563086"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Tickets  &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2714193"&gt;£8 online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, £10 (£6 concessions) on the door, free entry for under 14's, with a discounted rate for those just turning up for the final full-length bouts (from 4pm)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrgmageddon</category><category>articles</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>interviews</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/21/granite-citys-hawks-flock-to-the-arrgmageddon/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 08:33:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An interview with Lothian Derby Dolls' Captain: Fully Harmed</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/18/an-interview-with-lothian-derby-dolls-captain-fully-harmed/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The third team we've covering in the run up to Auld Reekie Roller Girls' &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/535844416618826/"&gt;ARRGmageddon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Tournament is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/lothianderby/"&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. LDD are, perhaps, the underdogs coming into the tournament in some ways, having lost to Dundee's Bonnie Colliders early this year. However, their roster at that point was somewhat different to their current lineup, so it's really hard to call.
We talked to their Captain, Fully Harmed, to see how Lothian's year has been, and how they're thinking about the upcoming Tournament:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- So, I think it's fair to say that Lothian Derby Dolls have had a mixed year so far; early on you had a few losses against the Bonnie Colliders and Mean City, but more recently you pulled off a win against Ayrshire Roller Derby away... how would you say the league is steering itself?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I would say this year has been very mixed. We started off quite low; I think with LDD it's always very skater dependant, and we lost a few reliable, strong skaters. We've really spent the summer building up our core again. We've got a reliable lot of, I'd say, 15 skaters, but, because of the type of league we are...  you know, it could be chicken pox and, because we're mums, that could be (say) 5 skaters off for a couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We've also had some injuries with some of our players, Poca Loca [LDD ViceCaptain] came back quite strong from an ankle injury, but she's still not 100%, and Fury has a niggling knee injury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;However, I &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; say it's been a really really positive year, because while we've really stepped back from bouting, we've really worked on our skill, to get that more solid; our skills, our communication, our teamwork. Definitely, on taking over as Captain, that's been our focus as a team: it's not about winning or losing in my eyes, (I mean, a win's brilliant) it's about us all having our personal goals, and as a team having a goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We are a little league; we're the smallest of the leagues who will be playing [in ARRGmageddon], by miles. I mean, we've got 30 active skaters just now.  For us to be even putting ourselves forward for the tournament, we've come a long way, this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Ayrshire was a brilliant experience; lovely people, lovely skaters. We were really happy to win, but for us it was more about showing that working on our skills together as a team, and you know, it really proved to us that when you work on your skills and trust each other, it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;So, thats the change from the [bout against the] Bonnie Colliders... when we played them, we weren't really working well as a team, I would say we got downheartened very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;These days,  as a Captain, I'm pushing&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;- "Fine, if we're losing, we're working on Our Goals, all the time, keep strong, .. " So you know, I'm not expecting a win, in a week's time, but I'm expecting us to have our goals and win that way !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- Despite you saying that, LDD are the only team competing at ARRGmageddon who've actually had Tournament experience (from the Battle of Britain tournament in 2013). Quite a few of the skaters from 2013's roster are still around, has their experience helped in preparation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I think it does help. The skaters who were involved in that experience, you know, they've been very honest - that there's negative [factors] to being involved in a tournament - but, we've talked about that, and we're going to try to avoid those issues with people's stamina, and try to keep the positivity going all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I think, compared to [Battle of Britain], there's a lot more positivity, there's a lot more — happiness - I feel positive, regardless of the score, that LDD will&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;come out, and we'll play strongly, we'll work together well, but, you know, we're against big teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;But, I think that previous experience will help us - we've got a lot of players with [general] experience, though. We just keep everything calm, and…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- When the high of the tournament has passed, what's coming up next for LDD?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Well, other than the tournament, we're looking for return matches, with New Town and the Fight Hawks, we're looking at some more new bouts with new teams, which are about our levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The problem with [finding bouts in] Scotland, is you've got Glasgow, ARRG, Granite, Dundee, even the [Bairn City Rollers'] Central Belters are up there, and Fierce Valley,… and then there's us. [Our interest is] trying to play with more teams that are our level, so we can get better scrims, and bouting experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;But, also, we're really working on our Coed. Fear and Lothian were our big piece of work we did this year, with Capital City, and I think training with men has brought a different dynamic to the team. Definitely, it's speeded up our game: we've got less time to stop and think about things on track.
So, Fear and Lothian will be having a bout, we've got a couple of idea of teams, we're just negotiating that at the minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;That's definitely a focus for LDD as well, keeping the Coed going - and really working on our female game, consolidating all the skills we've been working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;So, we're feeling positive. And I think we're the kind of team that, you know, it doesn't matter if we win or lose, but … the thing about Ayrshire was, they're a great team, they think about this the same way as us: you go out and you do the best you can, and you enjoy it - I mean, that's why we all do it&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;- you enjoy yourself, that's sometimes forgot. And, we are a team that really do; we socialise together, we love each other, we support each other, if we're injured,&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;and we do have a lot of kids and they play together too. It sounds a bit mushy, but we're very much in and out of each others' lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;And, it sounds terrible, but if somebody hurts one of my Dolls, I'll do everything I can to support them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;So, very much, we've got a lot of camaraderie between us, and I think we've come along way together, through all the ups and downs for LDD; I'm sure there's more to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We are a wee league I mean, ARRG's got about 60 skaters and you can't… compare them.But actually,  I've skated with some of the girls from the C team, you know, at scrims and things, and they're a lovely bunch, so...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I think LDD's getting to know leagues a bit better, I mean, Dundee are very friendly with us, and Granite too… so it'll be an enjoyable day, we're really looking forward to it.

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The ARRGmageddon Tournament is running on the &lt;strong&gt;26 November&lt;/strong&gt;, at Auld Reekie's usual venue of &lt;strong&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/strong&gt;, as an all-day event starting at &lt;strong&gt;11am&lt;/strong&gt;.. Ticket prices are £8 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2714193"&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, £10 (£6 concessions) on the door, free entry for under 14's.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>arrgmageddon</category><category>articles</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/18/an-interview-with-lothian-derby-dolls-captain-fully-harmed/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 13:40:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A chat with... Bonnie Colliders Captains Khilleesi and G-Wrecks</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/16/a-chat-with-bonnie-colliders-captains-khilleesi-and-g-wrecks/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So... Dundee's B Team, the Bonnie Colliders, have had a pretty exciting year to date, which is about to get only more exciting with their first appearance in tournament - Auld Reekie's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/535844416618826/"&gt;ARRGmageddon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the weekend of the &lt;strong&gt;26th November&lt;/strong&gt;.
We had a chat with Bonnie Colliders Co-Captains Khilleesi and G-Wrecks about the upcoming challenge - and also Dundee A's upcoming trip to Tenerife in December (as both skaters are also on the A roster).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be able to listen along here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[soundcloud url="https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/293033096" params="auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true" width="100%" height="450" iframe="true" /]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>arrgmageddon</category><category>articles</category><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby tenerife</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/16/a-chat-with-bonnie-colliders-captains-khilleesi-and-g-wrecks/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 11:51:59 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>