<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about auld reekie roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/auld-reekie-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Derby: The Story behind the Rebrand (A guest post)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/02/auld-reekie-roller-derby-the-story-behind-the-rebrand-a-guest-post/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those of you who pay attention might remember that, way back in April, Auld Reekie Roller Girls were shortlisted for the People's Projects funding, with one of their goals being to rebrand to a more inclusive name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie certainly haven't forgotten, and with the launch of their new identity today, we've given them the spotlight to talk about their reasoning and process leading to this launch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Why Rebrand?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We’re not the first league to do this, and I’m pretty sure we won’t be the last, but we’re finally (the vote was a while ago!), officially, publicly rebranding from ‘Auld Reekie Roller Girls’ (ARRG) to Auld Reekie Roller Derby (ARRD). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; The reasons behind the change are simple - our members wanted a name to reflect our diverse membership and support our ethos around equality and inclusion. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;All Star skater and Equalities Team member Mallory Powers shared thoughts on the rebrand: 'We believe in the power of sport to change lives - roller derby can help improve physical and mental wellbeing, boost self-esteem and give people a sense of belonging - and we want more people to have the opportunity to experience this for themselves. By rebranding, and through promotion and outreach, we hope that more people will see a place for themselves in Auld Reekie Roller Derby.'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;From now on, we’d like to be referred to as &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie&lt;/strong&gt;, and our acronym is &lt;strong&gt;ARRD&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The choosing of the name was surprisingly painless, a simple discussion and almost unanimous vote, and as summed up by skater, Lady Scrapnell, ‘It's a win for inclusivity, equality and humanity, but it's a sad loss for punnage’.  &lt;em&gt;[SRD's note: we can think of plenty of "ARRD" puns, so we're not sure this is the case.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Anyone who’s been through this process will know that organising a wholesale change of name, logo and brand takes a lot of work on top of keeping a Roller Derby League running smoothly. With around 120 members, 3 travel teams and a host of new recruits, it’s also not cheap to rebrand!  Thanks to some amazing support from the community who voted for our pitch to access National Lottery 'People’s Project' funding this year, we were awarded a runners up prize of £5,000 and finally had the money, people resource and time to get things organised. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Through the exposure with the campaign, we were contacted by a local designer Emily Horgan who loved the values and ethos of our league and generously offered her services for free! So began the process to really look at our values, our aspirations and our vision and to get ideas from our members to build some concepts. 'If you're going to rebrand; why not go the whole hog and design a whole new look', we thought.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Building Concepts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Our league members sent in all of their thoughts and ideas about the look and feel of the logo, team shirts, design concepts, branding and we gathered up some keywords to focus us:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-27691" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/screen-shot-2018-10-31-at-22-44-19.png?w=300" alt="ARRD Word Cloud" width="300" height="260"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Revealing the New Look!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-27692 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/screen-shot-2018-10-31-at-22-44-36.png?w=250" alt="ARRDLogo1" width="250" height="300"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The main logo - it’s super adaptable; we wanted to be able to pull it apart to create recognisable mini marks (some are already in evidence on our current Taster Day advertising - sneaky sneak preview!)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The three entities represent our community (the three travel teams, and the three different paths you can take to become a skater, official and volunteers).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The look and feel really reflects the galaxy vibe we’ve been using on our game poster designs for the last couple of years, and sits really well with our travel team names - the All Stars, All Star Reserves and ASTROs. We also loved the idea of unexplored territory, taking bold steps and reaching for the stars.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27693" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/screen-shot-2018-10-31-at-22-45-02.png?w=1024" alt="ARRDLogo2" width="1024" height="293"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Font Version - we love the boldness of this, it’s simple and recognisable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27694" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/screen-shot-2018-10-31-at-22-45-27.png?w=1024" alt="ARRDLogo mini marks" width="1024" height="579"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We dramatically revealed the new logo, with awkward tabletop drum rolls and much build up at the league AGM in September and never has anyone been as nervous, excited and shaky knee’d as the rebrand team on that day!  Thankfully everyone has been enthusiastic (apart from newborn baby Scrapnell who burst into tears at the moment of revelation - we’ll take that as tears of joy) and we cannot wait to see our new team shirts, due to be ready for the 2019 season.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Astro Bench Coach Jodie tells us, '&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Now we have a look and branding that represents the professionalism and fun we live on a daily basis as a league.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;It represents us, and the element of fun which is vital to keep our motivation high. It’s a strong and professional branding. It’s revolutionising our approach to our image and the message we send out to potential team members, officials and audience. It’s fit for purpose in terms of bringing us together as one unit ready to take on the world.'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;What happens next?  We’re holding an exciting 5 team &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/595819127499790/"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tournament&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;on November 17th with 3 teams coming from mainland Europe to play our All Stars and ASTROs in a giant celebration of our new league branding - what better way to celebrate than by playing roller derby?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We’d like to take this opportunity to say a huge thanks to our designer pal Emily Horgan for creating such a wonderful look and feel to our new branding, and we can’t wait to get our hands on the amazing new look Auld Reekie merchandise.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie are also moving their website URL, and updating their Facebook page in concert with the rebrand.
You can find them at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://auldreekierollerderby.com/"&gt;http://auldreekierollerderby.com/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;from now on, and on Facebook at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/auldreekierollerderby/https://www.facebook.com/pg/auldreekierollerderby/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/pg/auldreekierollerderby/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;(their other social media links, and email addresses have also migrated as you would expect)&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie's first event under their new branding and name is in just two weeks, as they face international competitors in &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/595819127499790/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Close Encounters of the ARRD Kind&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;! This mighty quadruple header sees ARRD A and C facing teams from Helsinki, Lille and Vienna to end the year on a high!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARRD's new brand was designed by Emily Horgan, who you can find on instagram at: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/emilynorarose/"&gt;https://www.instagram.com/emilynorarose/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller derby</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>rebranding</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/02/auld-reekie-roller-derby-the-story-behind-the-rebrand-a-guest-post/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 11:48:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie's 10th Anniversary Rebrand - with your help!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/25/auld-reekies-10-anniversary-rebrand-with-your-help/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has been part of Roller Derby for a moderate time will have noticed the increasing trend for rebrands amongst the older leagues. When the Roller Derby revival was in its initial phase, many of the first leagues named themselves "Roller Girls" - almost certainly resonating with the post-90s echoes of "girl power" (and the RiotGirl punk movement, which played into initial conceptions of how Roller Derby culture would work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-26653 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/peoplesprojectweb.png" alt="PeoplesProjectweb" width="607" height="431"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a more modern era, as Roller Derby becomes ever more inclusive; both naturally (accepting more people means accepting more viewpoints), and intentionally (WFTDA's gender policy explicitly spelling out the inclusion of all kinds of women, as well as gender-expansive and non-binary people), that phrasing becomes increasingly uncomfortable for many leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; were the second ever league to exist in Scotland, founded 10 years ago, back in 2008. After a long process of discussion, the league made the (near-unanimous) decision to move to the gender-neutral formulation in 2017... but were immediately hit by the disruption of their main venue for their entire existence, &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/memories-of-meadowbank/"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, preparing to close at the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Auld Reekie Roller Derby rebrand is still moving ahead, in their symbolically significant decennial year; but, as with Central City Roller Derby [who were Rollergirls only a month ago], the rate at which a complete rebrand can happen is limited by realities of funding.
Changing a name - and informing WFTDA and UKRDA that you're doing so - is fairly easy. Changing your logo, and extending that to your website, uniforms, banners, merchandise and so forth, is much harder, and costs significantly to complete. Without their main venue, and with no really equivalent alternatives available in the medium term, Auld Reekie's revenue streams are lower than they otherwise would have been, and so they've had to seek additional sources of funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one reason why Auld Reekie are applying for funding from "The People's Projects". This website is one of the ways in which the public can influence the distribution of National Lottery funds, in order to support locally deserving projects. Auld Reekie are asking for £21.7k - some of which will go towards the rebranding costs above. (This is actually the smallest requested amount of funding out of all the projects in their region.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As importantly, however, the rest of the money will go towards improving accessibility and inclusion in Auld Reekie in other ways. As much as "Auld Reekie Roller Derby" is a statement of inclusion, acts are as important as words. Whilst Auld Reekie already work hard to provide an inclusive culture in terms of gender, there are other barriers in the sport that can be addressed.
Anyone starting out in Roller Derby will know just how very expensive it is to acquire even the minimum set of kit, and these costs act as a different kind of exclusionary filter for the sport. So, the league also plan to spend funds on doubling their provision for loaner kits for potential new skaters, lowering the financial barriers to becoming involved in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie have already passed the shortlisting phase for People's Project funding for their region, and simply need enough votes relative to the 4 other shortlisted projects in order to achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voting is open on The People's Project Funding for Auld Reekie's project until the 30th (next Monday). You can vote by simply following this link: &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.thepeoplesprojects.org.uk/projects/view/rebrand-recruitment-and-celebration"&gt;https://www.thepeoplesprojects.org.uk/projects/view/rebrand-recruitment-and-celebration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[We hope to also bring you a follow-up article on the new Auld Reekie Roller Derby brand, later in the year!]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller derby</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>in the news</category><category>lottery funding</category><category>rebranding</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/25/auld-reekies-10-anniversary-rebrand-with-your-help/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 15:36:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>