<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about auldreekierollergirls)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/auldreekierollergirls.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>June 11th's Packed Scottish Derby Schedule...</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The weekend of the 11th is another extravaganza for high level Scottish Roller Derby, with both Auld Reekie Roller Girls and Glasgow Roller Derby engaged in multiple bouts across the weekend, and Fierce Valley playing away in the continuing British Champs Tier 3 North fixtures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Glasgow and Fierce Valley playing away, the Scottish home games are happening at Auld Reekie's traditional venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Meadowbank+Sports+Centre/@55.956622,-3.1585026,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4887b86eb150070f:0x6955a8c9b9a10cc5!8m2!3d55.956619!4d-3.1563086"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, doors open at &lt;strong&gt;2:20pm Saturday 11th&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-7441" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13235130_10156950736565224_2994993262049877442_o.jpg?w=1024" alt="13235130_10156950736565224_2994993262049877442_o" width="1024" height="385"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heading up &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/350352705088707/"&gt;the double-header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Auld Reekie's All-Stars are taking on Kallio Rolling Rainbow, one of Finland's finest teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After their usual impressive performance at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-big-o-2016-schedule-timezones/"&gt;The Big O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Oregon, Auld Reekie are riding high, ready for another challenge - Kallio are slightly higher ranked than they are (FlatTrackStats &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/79684/rankings"&gt;predicts a win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the Finns, albeit with some uncertainty). This will be a WFTDA Sanctioned bout and contribute to both teams' rankings, so it will be an especially hard-fought contest, as both teams will want to reach Division 1 (or remain in Division 2) of the WFTDA Rankings in order to qualify for Playoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other bout is no less exciting in its own way, marking the debut of ARRG's new 'C'-team, the 'All-Star Rookies'&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/#sup"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as they take on Granite City Roller Girls B, the Fight Hawks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, with a team debut, it's hard to make predictions as to the result of the bout; this will be a contest between Auld Reekie's new skater training and the experience gained by the Fight Hawks over the last year. (Having seen some of ARRG's rookies in "rising stars" bouts in the last few months, however, there's some very impressive performers there...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets on the door will be £8 (just £4 per bout), or £5 online via &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2553305"&gt;BrownPaperTickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Concessions tickets will be just £6 on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Glasgow Roller Derby are apparently the stars of the show down in Oldham, as Rainy City Roller Derby are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://rainycityrollerderby.com/event/euro-weekender/"&gt;hosting a weekend of derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, in which Glasgow feature in 3 out of 4 bouts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a Scotland versus Wales playoff, Glasgow's A team, the Irn Bruisers, will be taking on Tiger Bay Brawlers' A; and their B team, the Maiden Grrders will also be facing off against TBB's B-Bombs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FlatTrackStats predicts an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/7953/7929"&gt;incredibly closely-matched bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; between the A-teams (the result depends on which team you give "home-team advantage" to). The B-teams are almost as close in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/10262/11067"&gt;FTS's predictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, although it looks like their stats very narrowly favour the Welsh team (albeit by only a few percent). With only one exception, match-ups between GRD and TBB have been hard-fought, high-level affairs, so we do anticipate some great derby here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Rainy City Roller Derby are scheduled against simply "Glasgow Roller Derby", which we might guess is the A team... Last time they faced each other, Glasgow came out with a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/59869"&gt;convincing win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;; but Glasgow's significant team changes this year have FTS &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/10262/11067"&gt;predicting a win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the home team this time around. Glasgow will have to pull out something special to keep the win record on their side...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the rankings of Tiger Bay Brawlers A, and Rainy City Roller Derby, these bouts also fill in a chunk of the higher-level UK matchups missing from British Champs this year. With the results from these games, we'll be publishing an "extended" BC Tier 1 ranking, extrapolating where some of the teams not competing in T1 might have ended up, this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[On the Sunday, Kallio Roller Derby are also featuring in this derby weekend, so presumably there's some exciting train travel in Kallio's Sunday morning schedule...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://britishchamps.com"&gt;British Champs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, after an extended period &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/17/british-champs-at-dundee/"&gt;hosted in Scotland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the Tier 3 North fixtures continue in the North of England, with Hallam Hellcats hosting a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/587023974805101/"&gt;double-header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of bouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7445" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13267947_1010255862421996_6895825634478283487_n.jpg" alt="13267947_1010255862421996_6895825634478283487_n" width="530" height="750"&gt; Hallam's bout poster was also available as a limited edition physical print! (Design by Ed Syder) &lt;a href="http://edsyder.tumblr.com/"&gt;http://edsyder.tumblr.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hosts will be taking on Preston Roller Girls, while Scotland will be represented by Fierce Valley Roller Girls taking on Manchester Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FVRG will be hard pressed to defeat currently unbeaten Manchester, but a loss will keep them at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/womens-tables-2016/"&gt;bottom of the table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and in danger of relegation. Meanwhile, Hallam and Preston will be fighting it out to avoid the second-from-bottom spot in the table - there's not much to call between them, but FTS believes that home-team advantage gives the hosts &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/25963/8972"&gt;a slight edge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="sup"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;the Auld Reekie current team naming scheme is a bit confusing - the A team are simply "All-Stars", whilst the B team append "Reserves" and the C team "Rookies". This makes it a bit hard to unambiguously form acronyms for the two, but we're working on this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>auldreekierollergirls</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>fvrg</category><category>gcrd</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>hallam hellcats roller derby</category><category>kallio rolling rainbow</category><category>manchester roller derby</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 11:04:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>InARRGuration</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/18/inarrguration/</link><dc:creator>jennifergelignite</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/nazgul.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4856" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/nazgul.jpg?w=225" alt="Nazgul" width="225" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AULD Reekie Roller Girls’ InARRGuration bout for the league’s newest competitive skaters and guests was a victory for all.
A close-run game saw Green Eggs and SLAM! Leading with 123 points to Team Nazgul’s 99 at half-time.
But the second half saw the Nazguls race back to score 223 to 184 for a stonking win.
Team Nazgul Captain Powerhouse said the pre-game secret weapon was team brownies.
She said: “We prepared by having a meeting over drinks in the Auld Hoose to discuss rules, default tactics, any worries or issues.
“Then we had many more chats on our Facebook group - I think this helped our guest skaters a lot, and helped them feel part of the team.
“On the day, the wonderful vice-captain, Radge of Honour made amazing brownies, and I made (equally as amazing, but less tasty) posters.
“These had some simple focuses for the bench (keep positive, calm and zen) and on track (have fun, communicate and stay together).
“There was also a pink elephant, amongst other beautiful artwork, which really got the point across.”
Green Eggs and Slam Captain Hex said fizz helped the green team bond.
She said: “We had loads of chat on Facebook and then we all met up at vice captain Dead Metal's house for a meeting where we talked rules and strategy and watched derby on the telly.
“We may also have drunk some fizzy drinks...”
Hoose and Hex both admitted in the thrill of the game they barely checked the score.
Hex said: “I wasn’t actually really looking at the score.
“I noticed we were in the lead at half time and yeah! It felt good!
“I felt like we were doing really well and the score reflected that.”
Hoose said: “Once both teams settled into the game, I felt we were well matched and I was having so much fun, I barely looked at the scoreboard!
“Our bench coach, the inimitable Collie, used our team time outs really wisely, when we were able to take a breath, refocus and get back out on track raring to go.
“I think the gap in points spurred us on, and the green team really forced us to bring our top game - they were incredibly strong, aggressive with some fantastic offence.”
Hex said the turning point was half-time, when four Green players fouled out.
She said: “Oh dear, I think the turning point was our penalties.
“Everyone was giving their all and sadly it was maybe a bit too much!
“Players started to foul out and the bench was getting shorter as people were tiring.
“Team Black were also totally amazing!!!”
The second half was where Hoose felt the team came into their own because of their focus.
She said: “There were a few jams in a row where more than one green player was in the bin.
“The black team managed to keep their cool, keep low, slow and strong (SO PROUD), and take total advantage of this.
“Our fantastic line up manager, Gerry, noticed this and put on some really smart line ups, with fast jammers.
“Once we pulled away, it was going to be difficult to catch us, and added to that, there were a few foul outs on the green side - that's always going to be exhausting!
“The boost of focus carried over into the rest of the game, raised the quality of derby, and the rest is history.”
After the game, both teams headed to the pub.
Hoose said there were many sweaty hugs and lots of beer to celebrate everyone’s hard work.
She said: “It was such a great experience, and I think everyone learned a huge amount.
“I'm incredibly proud of both teams, and so grateful to ARRG, and all the officials and volunteers on the day!
“It didn't matter who won or lost. As clichéd as it sounds, we all won - every single person now has the experience of a well matched, well played game under their belt. That's invaluable.
“We all developed skills, and tried things we never thought we could do - we are now better skaters, and have a bunch of new friends to talk derby with!
Hex agreed derby love was the order of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said: “There were lots of hugs and lots of derby love! It was great how close you get in a couple of hours!
“Then not so healthy food and drink with greens, blacks, refs, nsos -- all the best people you could hope to hang out with!
“There were incredible vibes - how much all the skaters put their heart and souls into it and what an amazing team we created having never met half of the skaters before, how much hard work the organisers had put into it, all the refs, nsos, announcers, audience - everyone involved! I just felt spoiled rotten to be a part of it all! best day EVA!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auldreekierollergirls</category><category>bout reports</category><category>image</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/18/inarrguration/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 17:30:32 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>