<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about auld reekie roller girls)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/auld-reekie-roller-girls.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 08:59:33 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Derby: The Story behind the Rebrand (A guest post)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/02/auld-reekie-roller-derby-the-story-behind-the-rebrand-a-guest-post/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those of you who pay attention might remember that, way back in April, Auld Reekie Roller Girls were shortlisted for the People's Projects funding, with one of their goals being to rebrand to a more inclusive name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie certainly haven't forgotten, and with the launch of their new identity today, we've given them the spotlight to talk about their reasoning and process leading to this launch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Why Rebrand?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We’re not the first league to do this, and I’m pretty sure we won’t be the last, but we’re finally (the vote was a while ago!), officially, publicly rebranding from ‘Auld Reekie Roller Girls’ (ARRG) to Auld Reekie Roller Derby (ARRD). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; The reasons behind the change are simple - our members wanted a name to reflect our diverse membership and support our ethos around equality and inclusion. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;All Star skater and Equalities Team member Mallory Powers shared thoughts on the rebrand: 'We believe in the power of sport to change lives - roller derby can help improve physical and mental wellbeing, boost self-esteem and give people a sense of belonging - and we want more people to have the opportunity to experience this for themselves. By rebranding, and through promotion and outreach, we hope that more people will see a place for themselves in Auld Reekie Roller Derby.'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;From now on, we’d like to be referred to as &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie&lt;/strong&gt;, and our acronym is &lt;strong&gt;ARRD&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The choosing of the name was surprisingly painless, a simple discussion and almost unanimous vote, and as summed up by skater, Lady Scrapnell, ‘It's a win for inclusivity, equality and humanity, but it's a sad loss for punnage’.  &lt;em&gt;[SRD's note: we can think of plenty of "ARRD" puns, so we're not sure this is the case.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Anyone who’s been through this process will know that organising a wholesale change of name, logo and brand takes a lot of work on top of keeping a Roller Derby League running smoothly. With around 120 members, 3 travel teams and a host of new recruits, it’s also not cheap to rebrand!  Thanks to some amazing support from the community who voted for our pitch to access National Lottery 'People’s Project' funding this year, we were awarded a runners up prize of £5,000 and finally had the money, people resource and time to get things organised. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Through the exposure with the campaign, we were contacted by a local designer Emily Horgan who loved the values and ethos of our league and generously offered her services for free! So began the process to really look at our values, our aspirations and our vision and to get ideas from our members to build some concepts. 'If you're going to rebrand; why not go the whole hog and design a whole new look', we thought.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Building Concepts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Our league members sent in all of their thoughts and ideas about the look and feel of the logo, team shirts, design concepts, branding and we gathered up some keywords to focus us:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-27691" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/screen-shot-2018-10-31-at-22-44-19.png?w=300" alt="ARRD Word Cloud" width="300" height="260"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Revealing the New Look!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-27692 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/screen-shot-2018-10-31-at-22-44-36.png?w=250" alt="ARRDLogo1" width="250" height="300"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The main logo - it’s super adaptable; we wanted to be able to pull it apart to create recognisable mini marks (some are already in evidence on our current Taster Day advertising - sneaky sneak preview!)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The three entities represent our community (the three travel teams, and the three different paths you can take to become a skater, official and volunteers).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The look and feel really reflects the galaxy vibe we’ve been using on our game poster designs for the last couple of years, and sits really well with our travel team names - the All Stars, All Star Reserves and ASTROs. We also loved the idea of unexplored territory, taking bold steps and reaching for the stars.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27693" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/screen-shot-2018-10-31-at-22-45-02.png?w=1024" alt="ARRDLogo2" width="1024" height="293"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Font Version - we love the boldness of this, it’s simple and recognisable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27694" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/screen-shot-2018-10-31-at-22-45-27.png?w=1024" alt="ARRDLogo mini marks" width="1024" height="579"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We dramatically revealed the new logo, with awkward tabletop drum rolls and much build up at the league AGM in September and never has anyone been as nervous, excited and shaky knee’d as the rebrand team on that day!  Thankfully everyone has been enthusiastic (apart from newborn baby Scrapnell who burst into tears at the moment of revelation - we’ll take that as tears of joy) and we cannot wait to see our new team shirts, due to be ready for the 2019 season.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Astro Bench Coach Jodie tells us, '&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Now we have a look and branding that represents the professionalism and fun we live on a daily basis as a league.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;It represents us, and the element of fun which is vital to keep our motivation high. It’s a strong and professional branding. It’s revolutionising our approach to our image and the message we send out to potential team members, officials and audience. It’s fit for purpose in terms of bringing us together as one unit ready to take on the world.'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;What happens next?  We’re holding an exciting 5 team &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/595819127499790/"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tournament&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;on November 17th with 3 teams coming from mainland Europe to play our All Stars and ASTROs in a giant celebration of our new league branding - what better way to celebrate than by playing roller derby?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We’d like to take this opportunity to say a huge thanks to our designer pal Emily Horgan for creating such a wonderful look and feel to our new branding, and we can’t wait to get our hands on the amazing new look Auld Reekie merchandise.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie are also moving their website URL, and updating their Facebook page in concert with the rebrand.
You can find them at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://auldreekierollerderby.com/"&gt;http://auldreekierollerderby.com/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;from now on, and on Facebook at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/auldreekierollerderby/https://www.facebook.com/pg/auldreekierollerderby/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/pg/auldreekierollerderby/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;(their other social media links, and email addresses have also migrated as you would expect)&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie's first event under their new branding and name is in just two weeks, as they face international competitors in &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/595819127499790/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Close Encounters of the ARRD Kind&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;! This mighty quadruple header sees ARRD A and C facing teams from Helsinki, Lille and Vienna to end the year on a high!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARRD's new brand was designed by Emily Horgan, who you can find on instagram at: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/emilynorarose/"&gt;https://www.instagram.com/emilynorarose/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller derby</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>rebranding</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/02/auld-reekie-roller-derby-the-story-behind-the-rebrand-a-guest-post/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 11:48:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash 2018: Newcastle Roller Girls' tournament expands beyond the "Euro".</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/26/euroclash-2018-newcastle-roller-girls-tournament-expands-beyond-the-euro/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Readers of the blog will remember our coverage of Newcastle Roller Girls' first European Tournament, &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/365884340424845/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, back in 2017. Newcastle's first WFTDA Recognised Tournament brought together teams across Europe for some high level action, and prefigured performances as far ahead as WFTDA Playoffs; as well as presenting a sneak peak at two of the National teams (Scotland and Ireland) as they worked towards the 3rd Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the ridiculously tournament-filled start of this year has delayed us, we're also going to be bringing you as much coverage as we can of the return of EuroClash this year... although, given one of the attendees this time, the tournament has already outgrown its name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this initial article, we're just going to introduce you to the competitors, and their current placements in the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst 2018's edition is slightly smaller than 2017's - 9 attendees (6 returning from last time), rather than 11 - their geographic distribution is &lt;em&gt;substantially&lt;/em&gt; wider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning from 2017's inaugural event are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls (hosts)
Auld Reekie Roller Girls (soon to &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/25/auld-reekies-10-anniversary-rebrand-with-your-help/"&gt;rebrand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; to Auld Reekie Roller Derby) [Edinburgh]
Central City Roller Derby (competed last year as Central City Rollergirls) [Birmingham]
Dublin Roller Derby
Middlesbrough Roller Derby (EuroClash2017 was their first fixture after rebranding)
Tiger Bay Brawlers [Cardiff]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joining them to make up the full nine are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames
Dock City Roller Derby [Gothenburg]
Steel City Roller Derby [Pittsburgh]!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-26639" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/euroclash2018.png?w=2048" alt="EuroClash2018" width="1024" height="768"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, EuroClash served as the first step for several of the attending teams' campaigns to get into WFTDA Playoffs - Auld Reekie, Bear City, Paris and Dublin all gaining valuable ranking points from their attendance, as all bouts are WFTDA Sanctioned games.
Whilst EuroClash itself is not arranged to provide a final ranking, or a tournament cup, we did analyse the tournament itself &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Our analysis was good enough to predict the results of Paris Rollergirls' subsequent two games against other attendees, so it's probably as good as any other attempt at rating the teams...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since last year, the returning teams have played a lot of Roller Derby, with varying stories; so we can expect some changes in the matchups this time around. [We're using the FTS "WFTDA" ratings here, as not all the teams can be rated with the usually-more-accurate Europe ratings.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the time of writing, the attending EuroClash 2018 teams span a 41 position zone within FTS's rankings - but a fairly closely rated one. (FTS's built in predictor tool expects only a 2:1 score ratio between the highest rated - Dublin - and lowest rated - Auld Reekie - teams if they played today.) We've also included, in parenthesis, the WFTDA Official ratings and rankings for the teams - despite the different ordering, the "range" in strengths is about the same for WFTDA's own ratings, perhaps slightly larger.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="3" rowspan="1"&gt;FTS "WFTDA" Ratings 23 April 2018 (WFTDA Rating 31 March)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rank&lt;/strong&gt; (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Rating (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;53&lt;/strong&gt; (46)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7775/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;745.2 (391.51)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;62&lt;/strong&gt; (65)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/29732/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dock City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;732.4 (318.9)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;63&lt;/strong&gt; (68)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7948/rankings/wftda"&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;729.4 (307.57)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;70&lt;/strong&gt; (94)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7763/rankings/wftda"&gt;Central City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;713.3 (242.58)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;83&lt;/strong&gt; (62)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7949/rankings/wftda"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;691.7 (323.67)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;86&lt;/strong&gt; (95)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/3417/rankings/wftda"&gt;Steel City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;683.0 (241.15)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;88&lt;/strong&gt; (88)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7736/rankings/wftda"&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;682.2 (259.63)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;93&lt;/strong&gt; (85)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7953/rankings/wftda"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;676.0 (262.62)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;94&lt;/strong&gt; (87)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/5912/rankings/wftda"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;674.9 (259.86)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
Auld Reekie and Middlesbrough both suffered ratings reductions against 2x4 Roller Derby during the latter's Jan-Feb tour of Europe, where the Argentine team outperformed expectations against almost &lt;i&gt;everyone&lt;/i&gt;. The jury is out as to how much of this is due to 2x4's general under-ranking, and how much is due to over-ranking of the teams they played - in general, we'd expect better-than-ranking performances from both teams at EuroClash.
Middlesbrough could potentially surprise the current #1 seeds, Dublin; the gap between their WFTDA ratings is entirely due to that loss to the under-ranked 2x4, and their European rating, by comparison, places them above the Irish team (and only just below Paris)!
Similarly, Auld Reekie's European rating places them in the middle of the field, rather than at the bottom, although their trajectory is in the same direction - however, some of this is due to their bout against Leeds Roller Derby, who are almost certainly under-ranked at this point in the year.
&lt;p&gt;Hosts Newcastle have also had difficult bouts, against EuroClash 2017 returnees Central City Roller Derby - given CCR's stronger-than-previous performance against other recent opponents, we consider this to be more of a reflection on CCR than Newcastle - and Leeds Roller Derby (who, again, are simply improving themselves, as they knit together as a team after their first year). We suspect Newcastle are somewhat underranked due to their choice of opponents, and as the hosts they'll be wanting to show that at EuroClash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remaining steady, Tiger Bay Brawlers have still had a pretty good year - and even their recent loss to Central City is not a bad sign, as their performance was near identical to that at EuroClash 2017; if CCR show signs of being back on the up, then this is actually good for the Cardiff team too. The recent transfer of Kid Block back to TBB from London can only improve their strength further - we expect strong performances from the team, beyond what their current rating implies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dublin Roller Derby have also had a pretty good 2017, continuing their upward trend in the FTS European ratings, and remaining steady in the WFTDA rating. Their current placement at the top of EuroClash 2018's rankings seems solid, barring improvements from Dock City, or Middlesbrough. This could all change this weekend, however, as Dublin play some competitive sanctioned games over in the USA at Southern Discomfort 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also remaining steady for the past year, Steel City Roller Derby - after losing around 100 rating points in 2016, the team had a very stable 2017, sticking around the 680-690 rating they still reside at entering EuroClash. A return to their 2016 high would make them easily the strongest team in the tournament, but we suspect their middle-table ranking is more likely, especially given the effects of trans-Atlantic travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gothenburg's second league, Dock City Rollers, continued their generally upwards climb over 2017 (and 2016), and show no particular signs of stopping this progress in WFTDA bouts. They're one of two teams which could challenge expected #1, Dublin if they play against them. Looking at the more plentiful data in the European FTS rankings, they've suffered a "correction" to their ranking as a result of their performance in last year's Swedish national tournament, but their trend is still upward - if we believe the European values, however, they'll be better matched against Auld Reekie than Dublin's finest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representing Birmingham, we have both Birmingham Blitz Dames and Central City Roller Derby, and both seeing upwards movement in the rankings over the past year - Central City in the past month or two, and BBD earlier in 2017 - although the more detailed European ratings show signs of a correction in the Blitz Dames rating at the start of this year, albeit again against the probably-underranked Leeds Roller Derby.  We'll see if the Blitz Dames still have more rating gains to come in the WFTDA rating, as they play in the 2018 K Town Shakedown this weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be back with some more articles, and a guide to the schedule when its published, closer to the event...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash 2018&lt;/a&gt; will be hosted at the &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/6NHQpKxP5Em"&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; on the &lt;b&gt;19th&lt;/b&gt; and&lt;b&gt; 20th May&lt;/b&gt; 2018 - less than a month away! Tickets are on sale, for &lt;b&gt;£30&lt;/b&gt; in advance (£35 on the door), or at a limited special group discount price of&lt;b&gt; £100 for 4&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>birmingham blitz dames</category><category>central city roller derby</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>dock city rollers</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>euroclash</category><category>middlesbrough roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>steel city roller derby</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/26/euroclash-2018-newcastle-roller-girls-tournament-expands-beyond-the-euro/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 13:04:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie's 10th Anniversary Rebrand - with your help!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/25/auld-reekies-10-anniversary-rebrand-with-your-help/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has been part of Roller Derby for a moderate time will have noticed the increasing trend for rebrands amongst the older leagues. When the Roller Derby revival was in its initial phase, many of the first leagues named themselves "Roller Girls" - almost certainly resonating with the post-90s echoes of "girl power" (and the RiotGirl punk movement, which played into initial conceptions of how Roller Derby culture would work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-26653 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/peoplesprojectweb.png" alt="PeoplesProjectweb" width="607" height="431"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a more modern era, as Roller Derby becomes ever more inclusive; both naturally (accepting more people means accepting more viewpoints), and intentionally (WFTDA's gender policy explicitly spelling out the inclusion of all kinds of women, as well as gender-expansive and non-binary people), that phrasing becomes increasingly uncomfortable for many leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; were the second ever league to exist in Scotland, founded 10 years ago, back in 2008. After a long process of discussion, the league made the (near-unanimous) decision to move to the gender-neutral formulation in 2017... but were immediately hit by the disruption of their main venue for their entire existence, &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/memories-of-meadowbank/"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, preparing to close at the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Auld Reekie Roller Derby rebrand is still moving ahead, in their symbolically significant decennial year; but, as with Central City Roller Derby [who were Rollergirls only a month ago], the rate at which a complete rebrand can happen is limited by realities of funding.
Changing a name - and informing WFTDA and UKRDA that you're doing so - is fairly easy. Changing your logo, and extending that to your website, uniforms, banners, merchandise and so forth, is much harder, and costs significantly to complete. Without their main venue, and with no really equivalent alternatives available in the medium term, Auld Reekie's revenue streams are lower than they otherwise would have been, and so they've had to seek additional sources of funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one reason why Auld Reekie are applying for funding from "The People's Projects". This website is one of the ways in which the public can influence the distribution of National Lottery funds, in order to support locally deserving projects. Auld Reekie are asking for £21.7k - some of which will go towards the rebranding costs above. (This is actually the smallest requested amount of funding out of all the projects in their region.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As importantly, however, the rest of the money will go towards improving accessibility and inclusion in Auld Reekie in other ways. As much as "Auld Reekie Roller Derby" is a statement of inclusion, acts are as important as words. Whilst Auld Reekie already work hard to provide an inclusive culture in terms of gender, there are other barriers in the sport that can be addressed.
Anyone starting out in Roller Derby will know just how very expensive it is to acquire even the minimum set of kit, and these costs act as a different kind of exclusionary filter for the sport. So, the league also plan to spend funds on doubling their provision for loaner kits for potential new skaters, lowering the financial barriers to becoming involved in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie have already passed the shortlisting phase for People's Project funding for their region, and simply need enough votes relative to the 4 other shortlisted projects in order to achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voting is open on The People's Project Funding for Auld Reekie's project until the 30th (next Monday). You can vote by simply following this link: &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.thepeoplesprojects.org.uk/projects/view/rebrand-recruitment-and-celebration"&gt;https://www.thepeoplesprojects.org.uk/projects/view/rebrand-recruitment-and-celebration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[We hope to also bring you a follow-up article on the new Auld Reekie Roller Derby brand, later in the year!]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller derby</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>in the news</category><category>lottery funding</category><category>rebranding</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/25/auld-reekies-10-anniversary-rebrand-with-your-help/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 15:36:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2018 Seasons beginnings for DRG!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/28/2018-seasons-beginnings-for-drg/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a late start due to the very wonderful &lt;em&gt;Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/em&gt; earlier this year in Manchester (!), Dundee Roller Girls are hosting their Season Opener on &lt;strong&gt;15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of April 2018&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;D.I.S.C. in Dundee&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boasting an action packed day for both DRG's A and B team, doors open at &lt;strong&gt;12:30&lt;/strong&gt; with tickets on the day at &lt;strong&gt;£6.&lt;/strong&gt; You can look forward to &lt;em&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/em&gt;' Fear Maidens facing off against the Bonnie Colliders at 1pm, with &lt;em&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/em&gt;' All Star Reserves taking the track against the Silvery Tayzers at 3pm!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a new season of games, come new captains! So we thought we would have a wee chat with both teams' captains to see how the season is shaping up. First up is ALLY-J and Tiny Tearaway captaining the Bonnie Colliders!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="26529,26530" type="circle" columns="2"]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table style="width:100%;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Questions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;ALLY-J&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;Tiny Tearaway&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;931&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Position&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Jammer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Jammer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Derby Hero&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Hubs &amp;amp; Mayhem&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Lady Trample and Mayhem&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Motto&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Lets do dis"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Nothing is impossible, the word itself says "I'm possible""&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How long have you been skating?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I’ve been quad skating with DRG since March 2016, so 2 years now (time flies!) but used to inline skate from the age of 10!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I have been skating 6 years this coming May (scary) and I have been with DRG for 2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;What does this season hold for the Colliders?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We've had the opportunity of playing in Copenhagen, Newcastle and in our home town, and this season we're going to build as a whole Team! We totally found our feet working with each other, and we are looking at focusing on attendance, positivity and building our knowledge of the game!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Yes its going to be very exciting for the Colliders. We have some fantastic games lined up already and a strong team full of skaters determined to be the best.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;As a B team, what challenges to you face?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Finding our way of working together as a team. Fitting in our newest skaters and helping them gain lots more skills and understanding of the game.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We are all part of a very supportive league so the challenges I see aren’t limited to us as a team. We face the same challenges as the A team; attendance, working together well and pushing ourselves to the best of our abilities.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How does the league, as a whole, carve space for the B team?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;As a league, our A and B team train together, which is an amazing opportunity. We are constantly learning from each other, talking over drills and skills; with us skating alongside folk from Team Scotland, really being able to learn from the best is our greatest asset.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;B team, A team who? We're a league that trains together. Skaters for both teams, crossovers and new skaters. We all do the same drills and are expected to put the same amount of hard work and effort into every one from the newer skaters to those who were on Team Scotland.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;And if you could set goals for yourself and for the team this season?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;My personal goal is to work on my jammer skills and tactical knowledge. I want to work well for the team and push myself this season! For the Colliders: to focus on ourselves as a team. Although we are all building our personal skills, I really want everyone to bring positivity and sportsmanship to the Colliders.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Our B team has played and flourished with smaller numbers the past season. It would be great to see us play with higher numbers. This would give us the chance to have a solid jammer rotation and walls that are to be reckoned with. To be part of that jammer rotation is my goal for this season.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Second up is the captains of the Silvery Tayzers, Seaton and Bosies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="26532,26531" type="circle" columns="2"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table style="width:100%;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Questions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;Seaton&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;Bosies&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;102&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;37&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Position&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Pivot/ Offence&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Blocker&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Derby Hero&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Serelson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Kid Block&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Motto&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Shitemare"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"SITFU"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How long have you been skating?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;6 years, started and stayed with DRG since then.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Skating for six years, initially with GCRD and have been with DRG for almost 2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;What does this season hold for the Tayzers?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I'll probably cry and give dramatic speeches alot. Hoping that as a league we'll be able to continue to perform like we did last season but also move passed that, honing in our skill set. The Tayzers have always performed under a "get the job done, nae fancy shit" mentality and I want to continue that while progressing within the WFTDA rankings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We are continuing to evolve the skills, tactics and endurance that we've developed last season. Which will set us in good stead for the exciting and tough games we have lined up for this year.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;As an A team skater, how do you stay ontop of your game&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I hydrate and then spew it up if I go too fast.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Pepsi Max, avocados and hummus. And cross training.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How has becoming a WFTDA league changed your priorities and training?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I think it gives us clear global equivalents to try to compete against, which we haven't really had before. It's good to be able to feel super involved with the development of the sport as a whole, as well as having access to more teams.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;It allows us to skate against teams of a similar calibre at national and international level, as well as competing in tournaments! This emphasises the need for a strong mental game, the ability to work as a tight unit and to continue to function when the fatigue sets in!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;And if you could set a goal for yourself and your team?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Finish a game without a spew or a cry, working on my mental game is a constant priority as well as my on track skills. As a team, I just want to end every game as a happy wee unit proud of what we have just done.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;My personal goal is the same as it was when I first started skating, which is to get lower! As a team if we can continue to work together, support each other on and off track and leave each game with a sense of achievement, then that's a job well done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26534" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/fbimage-01-1.png" alt="FBImage-01 (1)" width="6035" height="8534"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15th April 2018&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; Dundee DISC&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/908750512641504/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Event Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; 12:30-5pm&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; £6 on the door&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>interviews</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/28/2018-seasons-beginnings-for-drg/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 09:00:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs North Update 23 March:York Minxters, Whippin Hinnies and more</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/22/british-champs-north-update-23-marchyork-minxters-whippin-hinnies-and-more/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our second update on the Northern Tiers of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/"&gt;British Champs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. We're aiming to do approximately monthly updates on the Tier 1, Tier 2 North, Tier 3 North and Tier 4 North, partly through the lens of specific teams in each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the last update, the &lt;strong&gt;Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; saw our advertised bout between&lt;strong&gt; Leeds Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; and Tiger Bay Brawlers end in an impressive win for the Cardiff team (294:44). Performance stats show that at least some of this seems to have been "first game" syndrome for LeedsRD, who significantly improved their performance in the second period (scoring 70%  of their points in period 2, as well as taking less penalties). If they perform at their period 2 level, or continue to improve, they'll be a significant force in the Tier in future games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Tier 2 North&lt;/strong&gt; has seen another round of bouts, with our tracked team, Newcastle Roller Girls' &lt;strong&gt;Whippin Hinnies&lt;/strong&gt; facing the formidable Rainy City Tender Hooligans, with the Hooligans taking the win, 348:62. This is a approaching half the score ratio than Rainy B managed against Wirral, which looks promising for the Hinnies' next bout in the tier. Looking at the stats (not published yet), this was a tough game for the Hinnie's jammers, with only Ania Marx achieving lead jammer status against Rainy's exceptional blocking. Hosts Wirral also played, losing to Manchester Roller Derby with the score 101:248.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; saw our tracked team &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; win a pretty closely contended game against Halifax Bruising Banditas - finishing 130:117. The stats show particularly strong jamming performances by GCRD's Lizzie Rascal (75% Lead Jams!), Team Scotland's Udder Mayhem, and Kami-Tazzy; blocking-wise, high VTARs are with Crimson Chaos, Team Scotland's Rock'N Riot, and Pert Hits.
North Wales convincingly defeated hosts Furness Firecrackers in the other bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first &lt;strong&gt;Tier 4 North&lt;/strong&gt; bouts saw tier-champions favourites Mansfield crush Durham City Rolling Angels 398:38, and the second Durham team, Durham Roller Derby, lose to Grimsby Grim Reavers 198:110.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tier 4 North is coming around again for another set of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1002205086551977/"&gt;bouts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; this weekend, and features the &lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt;' first ever bout in British Champs (as well as hosts Mansfield versus Durham). In honour of the occasion, we caught up with their Captain, Gem O'Cide to see how they're feeling:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, let's start by talking about last year, which was a big year for the Minxters. After several years of just playing a few bouts, 2016 saw the team play 7 over the season, with some pretty challenging opponents. What lead to this surge in activity, and has it been a good thing for the team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016 was a year of practice, practice and more practice. We had a lot of changes in the team and a lot of up and coming skaters joining the rostered team- this meant our dynamics changed and we needed to learn how to play together. We very much wanted to take the "Win or Learn" approach and felt some real time game play - working as we would on game day- would be best to learn this. Everyone loves scrimming and it helped us grow confidence and learn how each other work, where our strengths lie and what we needed to improve on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After missing the first two years of British Champs, you're entering this year for the first time. Why now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to get started on the Champs journey! We've had a massive new skater intake and great retention and it would be awesome to get the ball rolling and have something yearly to aim for! Something to show everyone what we are working towards...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You're entering into the tournament in Tier 4 North. Flat Track Stats and us agree that you're pretty much in the middle of the Tier in terms of expected performance - but there's a lot of unknowns, as you've only played one of your competitors before (Grimsby's Grim Reavers). How are you preparing for the tournament&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off shout out to Reavers. We love those guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are playing and training to our strengths. We've had some great input from Rule 56, as well as other guest coaches who have analysed our play. This had helped massively in preparing by knowing what we focus on from A-team players and what direction to take our training in. This has given us concrete goals and really solidified our skills and tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your first bout in Champs looks like being a tough one - Wakey Wheeled Cats are one of the strongest teams in this Tier! What are your aims for this particular game?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Wakey game, we are going into a tough one! But this is a great challenge to practice what we have learnt, and are continuing to learn, in training. For me as Captain, all I ever want to see for my team is that they are working hard as a team and putting our training into practice. We go into and leave this as a team who wins or learns!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As well as British Champs itself, what other plans and events do York Minxters have in store for 2017?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have lots of fun things planned for our newer skaters after Champs - they have helped out with NSO roles and August will be and time of fun and folly for everyone! After Champs we will be having a bit of fun for the team, then looking at some more challenges to prepare for 2018!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upcoming bouts in other tiers are:
&lt;strong&gt;Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; - our tracked team, Leed Roller Derby, host a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/288187818265184/"&gt;massive triple header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;April 8th&lt;/strong&gt;, where they will play Bristol Roller Derby, London Brawl Saints will play Tiger Bay, and newly-rebranded Middlesbrough Roller Derby will take on Birmingham Blitz Dames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next &lt;strong&gt;Tier 2&lt;/strong&gt; bouts are on &lt;strong&gt;22nd April&lt;/strong&gt;, where Newcastle host a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1886091588294805/"&gt;double header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, with the Whippin Hinnies playing Manchester Roller Derby (which should be their closest bout yet), and Liverpool Roller Birds bouting Wirral Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tier 3&lt;/strong&gt; also plays next on &lt;strong&gt;22nd April&lt;/strong&gt;, with Aberdeen the venue, as hosts Granite City Roller Derby play the other Scottish team in the tier, Auld Reekie Roller Girls' Reserves; and Furness Firecrackers playing Halifax Bruising Banditas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>whippin hinnies</category><category>york minxters</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/22/british-champs-north-update-23-marchyork-minxters-whippin-hinnies-and-more/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 10:50:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: Auld Reekie Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/10/euroclash-interviews-auld-reekie-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a bonus for this week, we're returning to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for one more interview before the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we're talking to&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk"&gt; Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The second oldest league in Scotland, ARRG have been active on the European stage almost as long as they've been competing - and their trip to the USA last year was their third. Whilst they qualified for WFTDA Division 2 Playoffs in 2016, the team declined the invitation for a host of good reasons - unfortunately, given the changes in competitive divisions in 2017, it will be harder work to make it a second year running.
Last year, Auld Reekie's All-Stars competed against Dublin and Newcastle out of the other EuroClash attendees - with a win against the former, and mixed results (a win and a loss) against the latter.
Team Scotland Roller Derby, who will also be competing at EuroClash, have 6 Auld Reekie skaters on their roster of 20, so they will also be represented in the bout between Ireland and Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13740 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/arrg-logo.png" alt="arrg-logo" width="200" height="89"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie's Sharlotte Patterson (also a Team Scotland Rostered skater) talked to us about the team's past and future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The ARRG All-Stars had a pretty good 2016 - starting off with a couple of wins against two other EuroClash attendees, Dublin and Newcastle.What was the high point of the year for you?&lt;/strong&gt;
Oh my goodness where to start? It was a fantastic year for us. We really played well together as a team. It’s hard to pick just one point in the year, there were so many good times for ARRG and myself. I think that I am just proud to a part of this wonderful team and play with very talented people. Everyone works hard at fostering togetherness and making us all feel like part of a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You then went across the Atlantic to compete in the Big O 2016, a return to the tournament from 2014. Despite facing even tougher opponents than the last time, we think you held up pretty well and reached the playoffs selection point with a high enough ranking to be invited to D2, which you declined. Overall, how was the transatlantic experience - does it ever get "normal" to travel across to the USA? And do you think you'll be keeping up the tradition, now that more WFTDA things are being scheduled on this side of the Atlantic?&lt;/strong&gt;
The Big O was an incredible experience and it was my first time visiting the USA. It was a really good environment and the organisers of the tournament were super welcoming. It was a great chance for the team to bond being together for a long period of time away from home.
I’m not sure you could ever say that it be ‘normal’ to travel such a huge distance to play roller derby - an amazing experience, yes! One that I will always remember as my first far flung trip away and my first tournament. The team were really strong and we came out with some very good results which helped us move up the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to say anything further on tradition about going over but it is really exciting that there are more WFTDA things being scheduled this side of the Atlantic; this will mean more opportunities for European teams as cost is always something that will impact teams on going far away for games. I can’t wait to see how this progresses and watch/play in all the high level derby that is out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coming up this weekend, though, you're still giving yourselves the tough challenges, playing current-hot-stuff league in the UK, Rainy City Roller Derby! How did that come about, and how are you feeling about challenging the WFTDA #26 team?&lt;/strong&gt;
This was a game arranged last year, and we have travelled down to scrimmage Rainy on a few occasions over the last year. They are a lovely team to play against and it has provided us with some valuable extra training.
This weekend is going to be an incredibly challenging game but one we can absolutely rise to the challenge of. We have been training hard and have had extra team training sessions this year, not just for this game but for our upcoming season. I know that the All Stars will go down and will always give their absolute best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At EuroClash, Auld Reekie will be playing Middlesbrough Milk Rollers, Bear City Roller Derby and Leeds Roller Derby. How are you feeling about the three bouts, and are there any specific plans you're making for them?&lt;/strong&gt;
Really excited. The last time we played against Middlesbrough Milk was back in 2015 for British Champs and it all came down to the last jam. I still replay that in my head at times because I was the jammer for Auld Reekie during the last jam and it was nerve-racking. Bear City and Auld Reekie have played each other a few times in the past and remained fairly close in the rankings. This will be our first time playing the new merged Leeds team. All three games are going to bring their own challenges, but we have been training as hard as we always do and really nailing our tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you're not on skates, are there any teams, or matchups, which you're particularly looking forward to seeing?&lt;/strong&gt;
There’s so many amazing teams taking part in Euro Clash that it’s too hard to pick. I’m really excited to watch all the other teams because each game is going to be as exciting as the next! It’s so good to see such high level teams have the chance to play in a European tournament and hopefully this is the start of many many more to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EuroClash also features a rematch between Team Ireland and Team Scotland. Last time, Ireland had had a single training session, and Scotland had a selection from the training team - this time you both have more experience of playing together, and Scotland has selected its final 20. (Congratulations on being a member!) How did it feel to be selected for the team - and how are you feeling about the rematch with Ireland?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, I am so proud to have been selected as one of the final 20 to play for my country. It’s an honour and I can’t wait to get stuck in. To be able to go to the World Cup to play and watch some of the best skaters in the world is going to be an unforgettable experience. I’m excited about the rematch with Ireland, it’s going be a challenging game as well as a great training opportunity for Team Scotland; we now have our final 20 selected and will be settled into our specific roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After EuroClash, what's next for ARRG's All-Stars? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The All Stars have a trip coming up to play Kallio and Paris at the end of April, and we will also be playing Newcastle again on 27 May. Our league has been pretty busy since the start of the year and our C team the ASTROs have a game against Bairn City on the 25 March and our B team the Reserves will be taking part in their first British Champs game on 22 April. It’s a really exciting time to part of ARRG and we have many more games coming up for all three of our teams over the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash is held between the &lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt;th and &lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt;th &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt;, by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at the Walker Activity Dome. Tickets available at the EuroClash website: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets"&gt;https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the door.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>euroclash</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>team scotland</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/10/euroclash-interviews-auld-reekie-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 12:23:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Champions in Reserve: Auld Reekie B start off a busy year.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/09/champions-in-reserve-auld-reekie-b-start-off-a-busy-year/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While it's usually the A teams for a league which get most of the action, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.arrg.co.uk"&gt;Auld Reekie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; B, the All-Star Reserves, are setting themselves up for a very exciting 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as becoming only the joint-second B team to compete in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/"&gt;British Champs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (along with Newcastle B, the Whippin' Hinnies, and following London Rollergirls B last year), they're also taking Auld Reekie's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1623816624593204/"&gt;second bout of the year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; this weekend, against Central City Rollergirls B, the Slay Belles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14708 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/02/asrvccrsb.jpg" alt="asrvccrsb" width="851" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught up with Pukeahontas, ASR Co-Captain, for a quick chat about the team's past and future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The All-Star Reserves had a fairly busy year last year - even managing some international derby against Dresden. What was your highpoint of 2016?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016 was a mixed bag for me personally, I was off skates for the first 6 months of the year with a knee injury. But then to come back and skate in three amazing games against Batter C, Newcastle Whippin Hinnies and Granite City Northern Fights was incredible. My high point would have to be the Newcastle game, I felt this game was where we really came together as a team on track, we found our rhythm in the second half and I was gutted when I realised it was the last jam. Then we got to watch our pals in the All Stars skate an amazing game, have great chat with the lovely Newcastle skaters in the pub, and a hilarious coach trip back to Edinburgh. For me that day was what being part of ARRG is all about - playing a hard game of derby, and having a great time with great people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first bout of the year is against Central City B… whose A team will be at &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/12/euroclash-2017-the-teams/"&gt;EuroClash &lt;/a&gt;with ARRG A. Does this add a bit of symbolism to your bout… and how are you preparing for it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it does add a bit of symbolism, and I actually just think it’s really cool that we have this great level of play in the UK that leagues are well matched like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve been training hard, and drilling our tactics on repeat. We want to make sure that we are working as a unit on track, and that all the skaters on the roster trust each other. We don’t know too much about Central City B, we are preparing for a hard game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Reserves are also one of two Scottish teams in Tier 3 North of British Champs this year. What are your aims for the tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a team meeting about our plans for the year recently, and when we were discussing our goals and how the team might be a completely different line up before we play our games in August; one skater said that, no matter what might change, our goal should be that we feel like team, that everyone is welcomed and trusted. I’d love to support and encourage that environment as captain over the course of the tournament, and I guess winning our tier would be pretty great too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, the All-Star Reserves will be hosting the Slay Belles at Meadowbank Stadium, Edinburgh. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;2.2opm &lt;/strong&gt;on Saturday &lt;strong&gt;11th Feb&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catering provided by Bonnie Burritos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; online, or &lt;strong&gt;£8&lt;/strong&gt; on the door, or £6 for concessions, or free for under 14s. (online sales at: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2860993"&gt;http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2860993&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all star reserves</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/09/champions-in-reserve-auld-reekie-b-start-off-a-busy-year/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 11:14:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The North Sea and the Stars: Auld Reekie 's and Newcastle's C Teams.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/24/the-north-sea-and-the-stars-auld-reekie-s-and-newcastles-c-teams/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;28&lt;/strong&gt;th of &lt;strong&gt;January&lt;/strong&gt; sees the first full Roller Derby bout of the year in Scotland, and it's looking like being a great match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; have had a long tradition of playing &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; over the years - both their A teams and their B teams have taken on multiple rematches, and both wins and losses (in the case of the All Stars versus Canny Belters, both in the last year!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was inevitable, then, with both leagues launching their C teams in 2016, that it wouldn't be long before they ended up playing each other!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14116" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/astrosvnc1.jpeg" alt="astrosvnc1" width="1300" height="861"&gt; The ASTROs on track in 2016...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie's ASTROs have had a very busy first year, as we covered a month or two back in an interview with their captain [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/12/an-interview-with-astros-captain-princess-die/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;], playing 4 stand-alone bouts (including one over in Belfast), and also a mini-tournament at the end of the year (which they won). Playing at home, as well, the advantages all look like being on their side...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASTROs Captain Princess Die told us, "We are very excited to be back after our incredible win at the ARRGmageddon tournament. It was 8 weeks ago, but we've had our winter break so we're all working intensively to get ourselves game ready! We’ve lost a couple of players since our last game but the newly refreshed team who will face Newcastle are fiercely solid and determined. We are as strong as ever and ready to show Newcastle what we've got and continue ASTRO’s winning form into 2017."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Newcastle's North Cs have had a more sedate opening season, with just two bouts in the last year - a loss against Spa Town, and a win against York Minxters (putting the North Cs somewhere around "high British Champs T4" level). That said, despite the experience differential, Newcastle C have a particular incentive to do well here, as their Captain, McSlay, explained :
"We're very excited to be kicking Newcastle Roller Girls' 2017 season off against our good friends at ARRG. The Whippin' Hinnies (B) and Canny Belters (A) took a double win at home to end our 2016 season and the North Cs are looking to continue that winning streak in our first away game."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, winning isn't everything, and the real point of this event is for both ARRG and Newcastle to find a new excuse to travel to play each other! (With both of their B teams in British Champs this year, we might expect more C team bouts in the future, as well...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event page for this bout is here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/250628665359800/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/250628665359800/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tickets&lt;/strong&gt; are available for £&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2792585"&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, £&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; (£6 concessions) on the door, free entry for under 14’s
Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;14:20&lt;/strong&gt; at ARRG's usual venue of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Meadowbank+Sports+Centre/@55.956619,-3.1584973,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4887b86eb150070f:0x6955a8c9b9a10cc5!8m2!3d55.956619!4d-3.1563086"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium, Edinburgh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/24/the-north-sea-and-the-stars-auld-reekie-s-and-newcastles-c-teams/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 10:52:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash 2017 - The Teams</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/12/euroclash-2017-the-teams/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;When Newcastle Roller Girls announced their intent to host a women's derby equivalent of the Men's European Cup (hosted by their sibling league, Tyne and Fear), there was understandable excitement... but the hosts have been remarkably secretive about the leagues involved, with the only hints being that the attendees were amongst the best teams in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Now, finally, the roster of competitors is announced, so we've made this quick guide to the teams (and will have individual features later on). EuroClash will be March 25th to 26th, at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Walker+Activity+Dome/@54.968707,-1.558266,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487e7068944e76d1:0xe1a6394d9f25325!8m2!3d54.968707!4d-1.556072"&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Newcastle. Tickets available &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.org.uk/buy-tickets/euroclash-2017"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-13774" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/euroclash.jpg" alt="euroclash" width="851" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, who are the teams competing in the first ever &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/365884340424845/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13711 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/newcastlerg_1.png" alt="newcastlerg_1" width="122" height="250"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Starting with the hosts, we have &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;. British Championships 2016 Premier Tier Winners, and currently ranked 76th by WFTDA (13th in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/europe"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and 13th by &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;*), the Canny Belters have had a strong 2016 - competing in the USA for the first time, at Beach Brawl in Florida (losing only to the mighty Rainy City) almost immediately after taking that British Championships win. In fact, the Belters have only lost to two teams in the last year - Rainy City and Edinburgh's Auld Reekie (who they also defeated in a rematch). As the hosts, home team advantage will also help their performance, and it would be a mistake to underestimate their chances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13716 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/leedsrollerderby-09.jpg" alt="leedsrollerderby-09" width="200" height="200"&gt;Staying within the UK, &lt;strong&gt;Leeds Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; are "technically" a new league, formed by merger of Hot Wheel Roller Derby and Leeds Roller Dolls at the end of 2016. Leeds Roller Dolls were ranked 65th by WFTDA, and their European Rankings were 23rd FTS, 22 SRD Rank; whilst Hot Wheel had Euro rankings of 31 and 25 respectively. We &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/19/by-their-powers-combined-they-are-leeds-roller-derby/"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on their merger at the time, and are excited to see what the combined pool of talent can accomplish in a single roster. Leeds Roller Dolls had their second trip to the USA in 2016, performing significantly above expectations; after placing solidly in the middle of the Champs Premier Tier rankings. Hot Wheel, by contrast, played their first European tournament in 2016, attending A Skate Odyssey, where they met surpassed expectations (beating their seeding by 4 places); they also managed to come second-from-top in British Champs Tier 2, clearly on the up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13765 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/mmr1.jpg" alt="mmr" width="222" height="200"&gt;Middlesbrough Milk Rollers&lt;/strong&gt; are possibly the highest ranked English team attending Euro Clash, with an impressive 56th position on the WFTDA rankings (9th in Europe by FTS, and 4th by SRD Rank)! MMR declined to participate in British Champs in 2016, but had an absolutely impressive year of competition, defeating almost all comers (including Connecticut and New Jersey) despite playing away for each and every bout. The only team to defeat them was London B, the Brawl Saints, which is not a bad record at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13730 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/central-city.png" alt="central-city" width="200" height="200"&gt;Central City Rollergirls&lt;/strong&gt; are the 83rd WFTDA ranked team (16th in Europe by SRD, and 20th by FTS), and one of the first Roller Derby leagues in the UK, representing Birmingham. CCR are the second team in this list to have spent their 2016 breaking into the USA via Beach Brawl, where they won more than they lost. They also defeated London B earlier on in the year, still a rare accomplishment for a UK team. The Birmingham team had quite a quiet year by comparison with the hectic adventures of some of the others in this list, and will have a lot of energy for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13735 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tigerbay.jpg" alt="tigerbay" width="200" height="183"&gt;Moving outside England, Wales' &lt;strong&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/strong&gt; are the best that their country has, ranked 75th by WFTDA (14th FTS, 12th SRD Rank in Europe). Declining to compete in British Champs in 2016, TBB instead competed against a wide range of European opponents, defeating London B, but narrowly failing against the mighty Rainy City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;After a lull in 2015, the general feeling is that Cardiff's all-stars have regained their best performance and are ready to go further in 2017; they're also a strong component of the current, and very strong, Welsh National Team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13740 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/arrg-logo.png" alt="arrg-logo" width="200" height="89"&gt;And representing the northern part of the UK, Edinburgh's &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; are the strongest team in Scotland, placing 60th in WFTDA (16th FTS, 20th SRD Rank in Europe). Auld Reekie made some waves last year by declining the offer to compete in WFTDA Playoffs, using the time to work more on their own performance - and they also declined British Champs 2016 as well. They did spend some time in the USA earlier in the year, competing at The Big O 2016, but had perhaps a more impressive start to 2016 where they defeated both our hosts Newcastle and Ireland's finest, Dublin. They'll be wanting to recapture that energy for the start of 2017... and will have a boost from their significant presence in the Team Scotland training squad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;For our remaining teams, we have to head outside the UK, so by distance, we first have...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13744 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/drd-logo.png" alt="drd-logo" width="200" height="213"&gt;...&lt;strong&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;, ranked 86th by WFTDA (but 11th in Europe by FTS and SRD Rank). Dublin have had a very exciting 2016, playing their first bouts in the USA at (yes!) Beach Brawl and winning against everyone except Newcastle Roller Girls! This performance didn't slow them down at all, as they also had one of the busiest schedules of 2016 as well, playing 15 bouts over the year, 10 of them away! With strong representation in Team Ireland, the Dublin team is definitely a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13749 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/paris.png" alt="paris" width="200" height="200"&gt;Moving a little further into Europe, &lt;strong&gt;Paris Rollergirls&lt;/strong&gt; are one of the two most exciting teams in France, ranked 71st by WFTDA, but 8th (or 9th) in Europe by FTS (SRD Rank). Hotly tipped for greatness in 2017 by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://thederbyapex.com/trending-french-roller-derby-56c5e691b036"&gt;The Derby Apex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the potential strength of Paris is also reflected in the performance of the French National Team, which they are a significant contributor to - Equipe de France is yet to lose a game with their current roster! Paris also burst onto the USA scene in 2016 at... (you've guessed it!) Beach Brawl, losing only the single bout. Much of the rest of their busy 2016 schedule was consumed by the French Nationale Elite Tier, which they topped, winning each and every bout in the 2015/6 season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13756 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/bcrd-bear-city-roller-derby_0.png" alt="bcrd-bear-city-roller-derby_0" width="200" height="200"&gt;From Berlin, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;Bear City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; are also one of the older teams in Europe, established back in 2008 . Ranked 50th by WFTDA (and 12th in Europe by FTS, 14th by SRD Rank), the Berlin Bombshells are the only team in this competition to have competed in WFTDA (Division 2) Playoffs in 2016, placing a strong 5th out of the 10 competitors, and defeating 4th seed Cincinnati on the way. In fact, Bear City spent more time competing in the USA than anywhere else in 2016, as the majority of their remaining bouts were at the Midwest BrewHaHa, with only two bouts in Europe (against Kallio Rolling Rainbow and Glasgow Roller Derby). Whilst Bear City the league also won the German Nationals (the Bundesliga), we believe this was strictly an exhibition team which differed from BCRD's normal A roster...
EuroClash sees the Bombshells return to Europe to take on the other rising stars of the continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;But that's not all, as we also have the excitement of a National Teams bout as well!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13777 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/ireland.jpg" alt="ireland" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13779 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/scotland.png" alt="scotland" width="200" height="200"&gt;Teams &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; met at the Road to TBC in Cardiff this November, with the Irish taking the win... but neither team had finalised their roster at that point. This rematch is taking place after final selections for Team Scotland [their selection bout is February 11th], and the Scots will be keen to show what they can do with the team that will be heading to the World Cup in Manchester. Meanwhile, Team Ireland were exceptionally green at the Road to TBC, and they will be that much more experienced as a squad by March...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We will be posting interviews with each of the teams competing at EuroClash over the next few weeks, to get into more depth about each of the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;* European rankings on SRD Rank computed from the set of all Women's Travel Teams in Europe known to the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bear city roller derby</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>euroclash</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>middlesbrough milk rollers</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>paris rollergirls</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/12/euroclash-2017-the-teams/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 19:15:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs Schedule 2017</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/03/british-champs-schedule-2017/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, by now you're probably aware that the British Championships 2017 schedule is out (it's hosted here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/2017-british-roller-derby-champs-fixtures/"&gt;http://www.britishchamps.com/2017-british-roller-derby-champs-fixtures/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in a big, searchable, list).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the list is pretty long, we thought we'd pull out some key dates for you (and also tip our hand a bit as to teams and divisions we'll be focussing a little more on - Talk Derby To Me will be continuing their excellent overall Champs coverage this year for those who want to cover the whole thing):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; kicks off on the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Feb&lt;/strong&gt;ruary, with a double header featuring Tiger Bay Brawlers against newly-merged Leeds Roller Derby, and Birmingham Blitz Dames against Bristol Roller Derby hosted by TBB in Cardiff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; also begins a few weeks later in Wales, as South West Silures host the Crash Test Brummies on the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, by then, most of the other Tiers will have had their first bouts, with the whole British Champs schedule starting on the &lt;strong&gt;4th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Feb&lt;/strong&gt;ruary, as the &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 2&lt;/strong&gt; begins with Barrow Infernos hosting Southern Discomfort B (the first B team in the Men's tiers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friends of the blog, &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;, see their B-team, the Whippin' Hinnies, compete for the first time in &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 2 North&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch, in a battle of the B-teams against Rainy City Roller Derby's formidable Tender Hooligans; hosted by Wirral Roller Derby, this is also somewhat Manchester area themed, as the second bout of the fixture is hosts versus Manchester Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you'll have to wait until April to see some &lt;em&gt;Scottish Women&lt;/em&gt;'s action in the Champs, as &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; host a &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; double header on the &lt;strong&gt;22nd&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Apr&lt;/strong&gt;il. &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;' Reserves are travelling up to Aberdeen to take on the hosts, whilst Furness Firecrackers and Halifax Bruising Banditas will be coming up to play each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scottish Men&lt;/em&gt;'s Derby also has its first showing in Champs that month, as Men Behaving Derby host a &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; fixture on the &lt;strong&gt;16th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Apr&lt;/strong&gt;il; pitting &lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt;' Skelpies against the hosts, followed by Teeside Skate Invaders facing off against &lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, whilst the &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 4&lt;/strong&gt; North starts its series a few weeks earlier, we'll be following friends of the blog (and some of our first interviewees!) &lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt; - their first bout is on the &lt;strong&gt;25th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch against Wakey Wheeled Cats, in Mansfield; the second bout is hosts against Durham Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>york minxters</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/03/british-champs-schedule-2017/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 09:44:56 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>