<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about ayrshire roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/ayrshire-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Fair City Rollers: Rising</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/20/fair-city-rollers-rising/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Sunday is the only time you'll see Perth's local roller derby league, Fair City Rollers, on track at home this year, due to the popularity of their excellent local venue, Bell's Sport Centre. As a result, for those following the team, it's an opportunity not to be missed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-26879" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/fcr_map-layered.png?w=1024" alt="FCR_map-layered" width="1024" height="948"&gt; Fair City, and the leagues combining to face them as "Scotland's Rising Stars"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fear Maidens, Fair City's travel team, will be facing a mixed exhibition team drawing newer skaters from Ayrshire Roller Derby, Bairn City Rollers' Central Belters, Dundee Roller Derby, Granite City Roller Derby, Lothian Roller Derby and Mean City Roller Derby. Coming together as "Scotland's Rising Stars", these skaters represent some of the best new talent in Scottish roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fear Maidens have played one previous bout this year, losing away to Dundee's B team, the Bonnie Colliders, back in &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/8969"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Due to way Flat Track Stats' rating changes are applied (always equally, but oppositely, to both teams), this has almost certainly underrated the Perth team at present, due to both Dundee teams' considerable strength gains year on year. Whilst this game against an exhibition team will not compensate in the ratings, we're confident of a strong showing from Perth's only roller derby team at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City's Invader Zoom told us, "We are so excited to be playing at home again and can't wait for the people of Perth to see some of our new recruits in action. Our last home game was a nail biter that had the audience on the edge of their seats all game, and we are sure this game will be just as thrilling with a challenge team of skaters from 6 different Scottish leagues!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as Roller Derby action on track, there will be the usual collection of stalls, including an opportunity to support the charity &lt;a href="http://www.clicsargent.org.uk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CLIC Sargent in Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, raising money to help Young Lives versus Cancer. Fair City Rollers will be participating in CLIC Sargent's Rainbow Assault assault course event in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City Rollers' "&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1869400046436599/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pack to the Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;" is at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/Sty37VvYGx92"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bell's Sports Centre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Perth, on the &lt;strong&gt;24th June&lt;/strong&gt;, 2018. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>fear maidens</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/20/fair-city-rollers-rising/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 13:36:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Doonhame Roller Derby show collaboration is the way to victory.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/10/03/doonhame-roller-derby-show-collaboration-is-the-way-to-victory/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst one of the prevailing narratives in Roller Derby is that the sport is the "fastest growing female sport in the world", it's worth noting that even when this was unarguably true, growth is always unevenly distributed. In order to keep growing, a league needs enough skaters to form good bouting team, in order to get those games which build visibility and retain ambitious players. If you're a smaller team, this can be challenging!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-24847" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/10/doonhameunicorn.jpg?w=596" alt="Doonhameunicorn" width="298" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dumfriesshire's Doonhame Roller Derby have found that collaborating with other leagues is a profitable way to enable more derby, more of the time, and help grow both themselves and their collaborators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more long-term collaboration is with fellow-West-of-Scotland league, Ayrshire Roller Derby - the resulting "Doonshire" train together and have even played a closed bout, with perhaps more fixtures in the future. Doonhame's Suze MacBruise told us, "Ayrshire Roller Derby are in a very similar situation to us: they had a big shake up when they lost their regular training hall, moving them to actually training in Kilmarnock rather than Ayr. We find that, with smaller towns like ourselves and Ayrshire, that we almost get up to full team numbers, and then when the slightest thing happens we're pushed back to training again."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it's another collaboration which is providing a bigger event, as Doonhame are joining forces with Durham City Rolling Angels to take over Newcastle's &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Walker+Activity+Dome/@54.9687347,-1.5582393,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487e7068944e76d1:0xe1a6394d9f25325!8m2!3d54.9687316!4d-1.5560506"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for a special Triple Header event for Halloween.
Whilst Durham might not be the obvious collaboration, Suze told us "we also have always got on really well with DCRA, and myself and [Durham's] Clairely Psycho hatched this plan to get a game together... we got far too excited and now it has turned out to be this marvellous Halloween event, focusing on players stuck in the 'twilight zone', who've played too many games for a cherry popper, but are not quite confident enough to play advanced."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as an opening Cherry Popper bout, the remaining bouts will both be previously-unseen collaborations:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Doonhame and Durham forming the "Doom Angels" to take on an exhibition team of low/intermediate skaters&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Newcastle's Tyne and Fear joining with Teeside Skate Invaders (as the "Tyne Invaders") to take on an advanced, open/coed exhibition team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Durham and Doonhame's Halloween Triple Scrim is on Saturday&lt;strong&gt; October 28th&lt;/strong&gt; , with tickets for skaters who wish to play in any of the games available from EventBrite (&lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/halloween-triple-header-scrim-tickets-37317907867?aff=efbeventtix"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;link&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The same link also allows spectators to get a ticket to see all the lovely games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event is also in need of lovely NSOs and Referees in order to support all three bouts: if anyone is interested in joining the Officiating team, they should &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/805242299645606/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;look here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event Facebook page is: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/111674759544178/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/111674759544178/&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;for updates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>doonhame roller derby</category><category>durham rolling angels</category><category>teeside skate invaders</category><category>tyne and fear</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/10/03/doonhame-roller-derby-show-collaboration-is-the-way-to-victory/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 18:56:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City's Sparkling Year peaks with Glasgow rematch.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/23/granite-citys-sparkling-year-peaks-with-glasgow-rematch/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Granite City Roller Derby's rebranding (from Roller &lt;em&gt;Girls&lt;/em&gt;) at the end of last year obviously prefigured some kind of Pokémon style evolution to a new level of performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year has been an exceptional one for the league to date. A-team, the Northern Fights, absolutely demolished their Division in British Champs, taking the top spot after convincing wins against fellow Tier 4 North members Spa Town, Halifax Bruising Banditas and Blackpool Roller Derby League, and earning promotion into Tier 3 North next season. They've gotten 3 skaters into the Team Scotland 2016 Training Team. And their B-Team, the Fight Hawks, have embarked on a second successful year of bouts, working their way up the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Granite City are trying to top things off with a double header at home on &lt;strong&gt;27 August&lt;/strong&gt;, placing the Northern Fights against Glasgow Roller Derby's tough B-team, the Maiden Grrders; whilst the Fight Hawks take on a mixed team of great skaters from Doonhame Roller Derby, Ayrshire Roller Derby and Mean City Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught up with GCRD's &lt;strong&gt;Krusty&lt;/strong&gt;, the Northern Fights' Co-Captain (and Team Scotland Training team member) Udder Mayhem (&lt;strong&gt;Christine&lt;/strong&gt;), and Fight Hawks' Co-Captain and Northern Fights Bench Manager Pert Hits (&lt;strong&gt;Sam&lt;/strong&gt;) to see how the league feels about their year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8850" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/08/13925480_10155196192769012_6950054464319126321_o.jpg" alt="13925480_10155196192769012_6950054464319126321_o" width="1448" height="2048"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Obviously, 2015 was not a good year for Granite City at Champs, ending with your relegation to Tier 4 from Tier 3. This season, however, you've really stepped into gear, convincingly topping the table for promotion back up into T3! Did you make this a conscious aim for the year, and what changes did you make to help it happen?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christine:&lt;/strong&gt; 2015 was a challenge for us. We lost some experienced skaters, but we also gained new ones, however, we hadn’t quite gelled into the team we knew we could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disappointment at the beginning of 2015 forced us to refocus our tactics and to adopt the use of specific line-ups. To facilitate this, the Fights organized extra “team time” dedicated training sessions, which was funded through the skaters own fundraising efforts (e.g. boot sales, personal fundraising etc.). We were very determined to be the awesome team we knew we could be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn’t win all of our games, but we started to perform much better against higher ranked teams, and finished British Champs 2015 with a convincing win against Halifax Bruising Banditas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 2016, fortnightly team-focused sessions have continued as part of our structured training, and are now funded by the league for both the Fights and the Hawks. We recognised the importance of training as a team, especially as GCRD continues to grow. We’ve gelled really well this year as a result, and this is reflected in our performance in Tier 4. We hold regular team meetings to revisit our goals, and are planning for a more successful time in Tier 3 in 2017. Bring it on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam:&lt;/strong&gt; The regular team training has certainly helped the team bond and act as an effective unit. These sessions also allowed the 2016 Bench staff (myself and Krusty) to really focus on the team, feedback what was working and direct the team to further their game, the game they want to play. It has been really pleasing to see the team numbers grow, allowing them to move away from specific line-ups and into a direction where they know each other and their play and it doesn’t matter who they are lined up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GCRD have also had a good year in National terms, with 3 skaters (including two of your highest rated jammers in Champs) making it through to the Team Scotland Training Squad selection. I think last time you had 4, but it's also true that less GCRD skaters tried out this time. How do feel about your skaters making the training team (and the training team itself having skaters from so many leagues)?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christine:&lt;/strong&gt; As one of selected skaters, I am obviously delighted that I managed to make it through to the training squad, along with the brilliant Rock’N Riot and Jo Mamma. All three of us are also coaches, and we are keen to soak up as much as we can and bring it back to GCRD training sessions, so that the skills we learn can be passed on to benefit the rest of the league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer the other question, I am personally thrilled to see so many talented skaters from a variety of leagues! It will keep things interesting as every league is different, and we can all learn new and awesome things from each other. We had our first session a couple of days ago, and it was a fantastic and positive experience. I asked the question “how many hours did you drive to get here?” many times that day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam:&lt;/strong&gt; Echoing Christine, we are very proud of our skaters being selected for the Team Scotland training squad. Each year we have had good representation at Team Scotland try outs and then onto Team Scotland itself. Seeing such a variety of leagues represented on the training team is so reassuring that the sport in our wee country is really progressing and skaters really advancing. Some exceptional high-level derby being played across the country!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This upcoming bout against Glasgow's Maiden Grrders is your first non-Champs bout this year. This is something of a delayed rematch - the last time Granite City faced the Maidens was in 2013, where Glasgow took a convincing win. How are you feeling about this time around?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christine:&lt;/strong&gt; We look forward to welcoming the Maidens to Aberdeen, and are excited for the challenge! A lot has changed since 2013 and it will be a very different experience for both teams involved. For instance, when the Fights last played the Grrders, I was more focused on passing my minimum skills! We’ve been working very hard the past few months, and this will be a good test for us as we approach Tier 3 again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam:&lt;/strong&gt; The best test for us! The team are really looking forward to this challenge, aiming for all the hard work to pay off and give the Grrders a run for their money. I think the skaters involved, from both teams, have changed so much since 2013 it will be really fun game both to be part of, but to watch too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the Northern Fights busy with British Champs, GCRD B have had most of the flexibility in their fixtures. You’ve taken on both Dundee B (the Bonnie Colliders) at home, and more recently, Auld Reekies ASTROs away. Are the Fights jealous of your free schedule, and what’s next for the Hawks?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christine:&lt;/strong&gt; I guess I am a little bit jealous, but pinning down games has been somewhat of a challenge for both the Fights and the Hawks, especially in the first half of the year. A lot of work has been done behind the scenes to try and remedy it, however, there were home game slots for both May and July that I couldn’t find a team for the Fights to play against, and July’s date was completely cancelled in the end. Now we are approaching autumn, and Champs is finishing for most teams by this point, we are finding it much easier. We have one more home game against Sheffield Steel Roller Girls in October, and are playing ARRG’s All Star Reserves in November, which should keep the Fights busy! It should also challenge us, and help us to prepare for Tier 3 next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam:&lt;/strong&gt; If they are they’ve certainly not voiced it… but I guess travelling (half) the length of Britain once a month for 3 or 4 months keeps you busy and focused. They are certainly excited about the few home games we have planned for the later half of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hawks have a few games in the pipeline, a couple more double header home games and an away game too. As a team, we are still evolving and finding our game but as time is moving on we are gelling better as team too. As Co-Captain, I’m excited for the skaters to get more games under the belt and get the opportunities to play and show-case their hard work. I am also really looking forward to training with our freshly minimum passed skaters and helping build them up to game time! Some very exciting skaters are on the up through not only our minimum course, but our Intermediate training group too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first time for the Fight Hawks taking on a mixed team of skaters from across Scotland. How do you plan for that, and how are you feeling about taking on some of the rising stars from Ayrshire and Doonhame?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam:&lt;/strong&gt; Our plan is probably similar to if we were preparing for any other league team; play &lt;em&gt;OUR&lt;/em&gt; game. Training alongside the Northern Fights, and scrimming against them as teams, has really helped us focus on our weaknesses and up our skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are really looking forward to taking on Ayrshire and Doonhame! As noted previously, I am always super impressed and excited by the calibre of roller derby coming out of every league and I expect these two leagues to be no exception. I hope we are a suitable warm up for Ayrshire before their first home bout on September 10th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, personally, having spent the first few Hawks games as their Bench due to injury, I am so super excited! I was with the Hawks standing on the side-lines during their game with Mean City, and really look forward to playing against some of the Mean City ladies in this game too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We believe that this bout is also raising funds for some great charities, can you tell us a bit about this?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Krusty: &lt;/strong&gt;At every home game we host, we try to give some exposure to local charities within Aberdeen and surrounding areas. We have supported local charities at every home game and managed to raise substantial amounts of pennies on our cake stall, our home bakes are kindly donated by skaters, friends and family. We are overwhelmed by the donations we receive and the generosity of our supporters (and officials!) that purchase our fine home bakes. Sales from our cake stall on the 27&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; August will be donated to &lt;strong&gt;Befriend a Child&lt;/strong&gt;, they are Aberdeen's only 1:1 befriending service for vulnerable children and young people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also decided for this game that we would like to ‘borrow’ an idea we saw Sheffield Steel Rollergirls post up, holding a bra amnesty in support for &lt;strong&gt;‘Smalls for All’&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s something my work is doing too and it’s a fantastic idea! We are looking for brand new pants and new or worn bras that still have good wear in them. It’s an easy thing to organise but it will be greatly received by Smalls for All who is a charity which helps women and children in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone has any great suggestions for our next charity appeal, come speak to us at the game on Saturday!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City's Double Header is at their usual venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Beach+Leisure+Centre/@57.155602,-2.082094,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48840e4028217933:0x30c6b9176815da5b!8m2!3d57.155602!4d-2.0799"&gt;Aberdeen Beach Leisure Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;August 27th&lt;/strong&gt;. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;12:30pm&lt;/strong&gt;, for the first whistle at 1:10pm. Tickets are just &lt;strong&gt;£4&lt;/strong&gt; on the door. The Facebook event page is here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1717081471898842/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1717081471898842/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/23/granite-citys-sparkling-year-peaks-with-glasgow-rematch/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 18:31:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ayshire Roller Derby hit the Track, Full Throttle</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/16/ayshire-roller-derby-hit-the-track/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Someone at Ayrshire Roller Derby is clearly a fan of old Lucasarts adventure games. The league's long-awaited debut bout, hosted at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Magnum+Leisure+Centre/@55.60667,-4.685244,15z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0xaa425516c021b7f4!8m2!3d55.60667!4d-4.685244"&gt;Magnum Leisure Centre, Irvine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, is titled simply "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/300853163602927/"&gt;Day of the Tentacle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;", not just a reference to ARD's Kraken/Octopus mascot, but also the name of Lucasarts' famous sequel to their original hit, Maniac Mansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/300853163602927/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8739" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/08/13901351_1024883397619520_1178475040826834661_n.jpg" alt="13901351_1024883397619520_1178475040826834661_n" width="768" height="318"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike the game, we expect that ARD have few plans for world domination or toilet-based timetravel, and instead will be concentrating on the challenge of taking on Lothian Derby Dolls for their first public bout as a team. It's something that Scotland's west-most league have been working on for months, with many of their skaters immediately signing up for multiple cherry poppers (or "rookie bouts" as the more serious in roller derby seem to be calling them) as soon as they've passed mins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it all builds to this, the &lt;strong&gt;10th September&lt;/strong&gt; in Irvine, when they come together as a team for the first time in public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most visible skaters the aforementioned games has been Poison Petal, who's probably bent the rules on how much experience you can gain and still count as a rookie over the last 9 months. She was also happy to talk to us (and take some comments from others on the team) on this occasion:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;"We have been on an awesome adventure since the team was first formed until now. There's been highs and lows and many hall changes, but we are finally just about there! Our first bout will take place on the 10th of September against Lothian Derby Dolls. Now the hard work begins all over again. We've navigated our way through mins and now we have even more skills, strategies and tactics to learn. There is a very excited buzz around the team at the moment with everyone pushing themselves in order to merit their green jersey and gain a place on that first team. I asked a few of the team about how they felt about the game coming up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Barty Ouch, one of our newest mins passed players, said  «[I'm] nervous, excited, slightly terrified; but can't wait to hopefully make the roster and get out there with my team, and show that all our hard work has paid off and what ARD is all about. It'll be a fantastic day for everyone playing or not and this is really just the beginning for us.»&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Super Sal agreed,  «I'm terrified, and excited all at the same time. I'm also proud of the team (and myself) for getting to this point! It's taken a while. For me anyway!»&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;R2 DeckYou «I'm looking forward to taking the first step with ARD into the derbyverse. This will be the first time that I can play with a full team of the girls I've laughed and cried with for the last 10 months.»"&lt;/p&gt;
Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;11:30&lt;/strong&gt;, for a probable start around midday. There's no online tickets available at the time of writing, so you'll have to get them on the door...&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/16/ayshire-roller-derby-hit-the-track/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 12:09:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Skaters on track for New Town Cherry Popper</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/09/new-skaters-on-track-for-new-town-cherry-popper/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;March 19th&lt;/strong&gt; sees the Livingston area's &lt;strong&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; host a one of roller derby's traditions - a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1048868645164481/"&gt;cherry popper bout&lt;/a&gt;, showcasing new skaters from a mix of leagues. The bout will be held in New Town's current bouting venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/DSZTrnU8cYo"&gt;Blackburn Community Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6395" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/412387_204493976333497_2093997456_o.jpg?w=600" alt="412387_204493976333497_2093997456_o" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skaters from Auld Reekie Roller Girls, Bairn City Rollers, Lothian Derby Dolls, Doonhame Derby Dolls, Ayrshire Roller Derby, Fair City Rollers and Preston Roller Girls will join host New Town's own new skaters on track in two exhibition teams: The Morello Mashers (skating in hot pink) and the Women of Mass Destruction (skating in sapphire).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an ideal opportunity to see the potential of new roller derby skaters as they play their first bout in public. It's particularly exciting to see skaters from some of Scotland's leagues who are not publicly bouting yet, as this is a preview of perhaps what we might expect from Ayrshire, Doonhame and Fair City when they enter public bouts as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a slightly later game than we normally have in Scotland, with doors opening at &lt;strong&gt;4:45pm&lt;/strong&gt;, for a 5:15pm start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are available online from &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2521813"&gt;brownpapertickets&lt;/a&gt; for just &lt;strong&gt;£4&lt;/strong&gt;. Under 14s are free. Tickets will also be available on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>cherry poppers</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/09/new-skaters-on-track-for-new-town-cherry-popper/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 21:19:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Upcoming Events Roundup!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/13/upcoming-events-roundup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scottish Roller Derby is just starting to emerge from its traditional month of hibernation, and there's already a lot of derby events scheduled for the next few weeks. To get you started on your next year of Derby, we've collected them together in one place for you with handy links!
We’ve already covered most of the derby recruitment events &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/03/start-derby-in-the-new-year/"&gt;in a previous post&lt;/a&gt;, so here we present mostly bouts and fundraising. We should note, however, a few addenda to the fresh meat article:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Firstly, &lt;strong&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; have completely filled up their attendance list for their fresh meat, and are now closed for additional skaters until their next recruitment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Secondly, just missing out on our article, &lt;strong&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; also have a recruitment event scheduled for &lt;strong&gt;Tuesday 26th January&lt;/strong&gt;, starting at &lt;strong&gt;7pm&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;Magnum Leisure Centre, Irvine&lt;/strong&gt;. There is some kit available, but you are advised to contact ahead of time &lt;a href="mailto:ayshirerollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;ayshirerollerderby@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/strong&gt; also announced recruitment very recently, with a session planned for &lt;strong&gt;31st January&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Musselburgh Sport Centre&lt;/strong&gt;, starting at &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt;. You are advised to contact &lt;a href="mailto:newskaters@lothianderbydolls.com"&gt;newskaters@lothianderbydolls.com&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The Scottish Derby bout calendar starts on the &lt;strong&gt;30th of January&lt;/strong&gt;, with 3 bouts occurring:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; A and B are taking on Vagine Regime UK in a double-header hosted in the Lagoon Centre, Paisley. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/440385519419560/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/440385519419560/&lt;/a&gt; There's also the second annual GRD Drag Party planned after this event, for which details &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/156611594708195/"&gt;go here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Over in Edinburgh, &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; are also holding their first bout of the year, with the Reserves taking on Roller Derby Dresden. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/918798478210693/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/918798478210693/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Meanwhile, down in Newcastle, Men's National Team &lt;strong&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; are taking on Tyne and Fear B as part of a double header with Newcastle Roller Girls. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1829763710583763/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1829763710583763/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The action doesn't stop the week after, as the &lt;strong&gt;6th of February&lt;/strong&gt; sees:
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; host a 12-team Charity Sur5al tournament at The Peak, Stirling. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/908140529265523/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/908140529265523/&lt;/a&gt; There's also an &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1507929376179373/"&gt;afterparty event&lt;/a&gt; for the tournament, which is sure to be well attended!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Also on the 6th, Power of Scotland have a fundraiser up in Aberdeen, as &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Brawlermen&lt;/strong&gt; host a Quiz Night in Sinatra's Bar. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1711963732359161/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1711963732359161/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The &lt;strong&gt;13th of February&lt;/strong&gt; continues to be lucky for derby enthusiasts, as we have another two events to choose from:
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;In Edinburgh, &lt;strong&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/strong&gt; take on Dundee Roller Girls' Bonnie Colliders at the Jack Kane Centre, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1537726313212932/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1537726313212932/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Meanwhile, playing away at Eston Leisure Centre,Middlesborough, &lt;strong&gt;Mean City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; take on Teesside Skate Invaders in a double header hosted by Middlesborough Milk Rollers. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/370810093043423/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/370810093043423/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/13/upcoming-events-roundup/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 20:54:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-bouting Leagues Roundup of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/30/non-bouting-leagues-roundup-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year has seen another uptick in the number of new leagues in Scotland, with both &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HelginRollerDerby"&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/WeeCRD"&gt;Wee County Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; joining the ranks of &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/InvernessCityRollerDerby/"&gt;Inverness City&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/FairCityRollers/"&gt;Fair City&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Ayrshire-Roller-Derby-Official-618921518215712/"&gt;Ayrshire&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DoonhameDerbyDolls"&gt;Doonhame Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; as leagues making the journey towards their first public bout. As traditional, we're covering all of these leagues together in a Review of the Year, as usually bouts are a big part of what the bouting leagues cover about in their own articles. Since we have so many non-bouting leagues this year, however, we're splitting this article over several pages for readability - click the links at the bottom of each page to move between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every league forms its own relationships with the wider derby community when starting out, but some of our non-bouting leagues have developed particularly close ties.
Inverness City Roller Derby were very happy that Helgin Roller Derby started up nearby in Elgin, and the two have been combining resources:
"Helgin are fantastic and are growing so fast.
We try to go through as often as possible to coach them and help them with anything they may need help with and they often come through to us for a session and with such a big turn out at these sessions it boosts team morale."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5376" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/pudz.jpg" alt="PuDz" width="960" height="540"&gt; Power of Scotland's PudZ, selfie with combined Inverness and Helgin skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helgin are equally happy with the relationship, as they benefit from ICRD's experience and numbers. "All of our skaters rave about Nat from ICRD’s sessions for days afterwards – she really works us hard and we learn a lot! […] We’re looking to link up with ICRD at least once a month in 2016, so that we can all get a bit more contact and pack skills practice – something that can prove difficult if you’ve got a session with low numbers."
Of course, Helgin have also been keeping up their connections with the team to the East of them, and Granite City have been as supportive as they were at Helgin's founding, even donating kit and support for their fresh meat sessions. The Brawlermen also donated Power of Scotland's PudZ for a training session, "Our session with PudZ from Power of Scotland was brilliant – it was our first proper session where we got to practice game tactics and we learned so much!", which also included ICRD, "we had PudZ from POS run a session on walls and pack work which was also tremendously good fun."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, at the south end of the country, Dumfries' Doonhame Derby Dolls made the fortuitious discovery of nearby Carlisle's &lt;a href="http://www.bordercityrollers.com/"&gt;Border City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;, who are newly founded this year. The two leagues have quickly become quite attached, as Doonhame noted: "We only recently discovered that Carlisle had a team on the go through Facebook, one of our girls is from the area and she never even knew haha! This is now the closest team to us! We got in touch and done our own first ever guest coaching with 3 of our girls travelling down to their training night and they couldn't have been more welcoming, they're a great bunch of guys as we expected and they were so pleased to learn and understand where to go from where they'd got to. Georgie and Chloe Holmes helped start is up and have done well starting from scratch. We have kept in touch and they have been along to support us at games in Newcastle and Glasgow, making wee banners and being total fangirls which is amazing (it's usually us fangirling others!). "
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h6&gt;RECRUITMENT AND TRAINING&lt;/h6&gt;
All of the non-bouting leagues have been focussing on the three most important things for any newer league: recruiting skaters, training them to pass mins, and raising money to support all of this.
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, &lt;em&gt;Helgin&lt;/em&gt; held several successful fresh meats this year, recruiting 19 since we &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/23/helgin-roller-derby-scotlands-northernmost-league/"&gt;interviewed them last&lt;/a&gt;, and have also gained some transfers from other leagues "We’ve gained another few regular skaters, including some skaters formerly of Granite City Roller Derby, New Town Roller Girls and Belfast City Rockets, and we’ve now got enough people training on a regular basis to be looking to put a team together". They also have a tremendously organised public training plan, as anyone can see from the regular updates on their Facebook page, "This started back when we were chopping and changing venues a lot, as we were still trying to find permanent training locations, and we needed to keep people informed of where the sessions were. Many people commented that they liked knowing what was coming up, so we just kept it going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We like to be organised, and have a progressive training plan so that we can see the development of our Fresh Meat – sometimes sessions go to plan, sometimes you’ve got an odd number of people there and the ‘paired work’ session plan goes out the window! Slowly but surely we’re working it all out, and we hope to get our next batch of Fresh Meat minimum skills passed much quicker."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They've also been doing quite well at fundraising, having entered multiple grant shortlists, and also "doing rather well with community fundraising, and held another successful pub quiz at the end of August, keeping us afloat for a bit, and we’re looking to put on another at the end of January or beginning of February, to boost funds for 2016."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inverness&lt;/em&gt;, being one of the more established leagues in this article, has been growing a little more slowly, "We've had a few intakes but the struggle to find new members in Inverness is ongoing, we've lowered the age limit to 16 to try grow the team a little, we've got a few new(ish) faces and everyone is coming on leaps and bounds, and we should fingers crossed have them all mins passed just after the new year."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perth's&lt;em&gt; Fair City Rollers&lt;/em&gt; have had an interesting year, given that we reported last year that they were aiming to bout in 2015. Instead, this year has been one of introspection and consolidation. "Over the past year we've redefined ourselves as a team; who we are, what we do and where we're headed.  Our direction has become more bout focused and we've started to work towards becoming an actual bouting team again.
Over the past year we've worked on aligning focus and skills, and recruitment.  We're currently about halfway through our training programme of the new skaters we recruited in September, and are aiming to bout in 2016"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-5372" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/11880588_901492176606579_4883872526247151434_n.jpg?w=300" alt="11880588_901492176606579_4883872526247151434_n" width="300" height="300"&gt; The Wee-County Golden Gauntlet logo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clackmannanshire's &lt;em&gt;Wee Country Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt; have been attempting to retain the momentum from their initial launch (which we interviewed them about &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/29/a-wee-chat-with-wee-county-roller-derby/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), partly by launching their distinctive gauntlet logo,
We really wanted our logo to describe the fight we have for derby, and our community spirit rolled into one. Its our take on the clackmannshire logo of the gauntlet, with 'Look Aboot Ye' as a tag line. It works as a double meaning, having to be aware at all times who and what is around you on track.
There was a real buzz around the team in the beginning, it was great: lots of attention and press coverage. We had a strong initial recruitment and kept a steady flow of interest, with word of mouth travelling fast. It has been a challenge to form a solid basis for the team, but we have a great foundation of members now. Its been a tough year, of trial and error and lots of personal growth. We were overwhelmed by the support and commitment of the members we do have, as they get stuck in and really help to make our team a family.
Looking at how far we've come and comparing it to how far we have to go to allow us to have our debut bout is quite a step, but were confident that we have the determination and the strong mind set to make it happen."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5381" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/11050639_820246781416517_7188774811881300574_n.jpg" alt="11050639_820246781416517_7188774811881300574_n" width="540" height="960"&gt; Coach Graeme Gow keeping a watchful eye on the paceline at Ayrshire Roller Derby (Credit: Sally Wilkes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt;, meanwhile, have enough mins-passed skaters that they're starting to attend scrims and the like. "ARD have had an excellent year. We were joined by coach Graham Gow of Power of Scotland and Mean City fame. Our team may be small at the moment but it is growing all the time! Our mins passed players are regularly participating in open scrims and learning all they can. We would really like to thank all  the local teams that have helped and supported us this last few months." In addition, ARD have been at a whole host of fundraising and publicity-related engagements, including a stall at their local Christmas Fair. They've also had enthusiastic spectating presence at many bouts this year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, to the south, &lt;em&gt;Doonhame&lt;/em&gt; have been growing strong,
"Recruitment was a challenge to start, with maybe 6-10 people showing up at the start of the year, we then took a break from 'Fresh Meat' open nights and 're-evaluated our training / introduction methods. We then went on to having 2 of our most successful openers in Sept and October with a full house (of 30odd) both nights, and around half of that number dedicating and joining the team! Its the keeping them excited and committed that's the harder bit. We try to encourage everyone to the best of their ability and push those wishing to be pushed, but at a pace that's comfortable with them. We have been very lucky to be able to have a lot of amazing players come along and guest coach for us. To be able to have such a high profile skater like Stefanie Mainey come and guest at our bootcamp in May 2015 was amazing! She was brilliant  and really put us through our paces on the track and giving us some great insights! We love learning new stuff and stretching our mindsets."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5368" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/received_10153711888193956.jpeg" alt="received_10153711888193956" width="600" height="339"&gt; Doonhame's 7 cherry popping skaters at Bristol Roller Derby's event. (Credit: Andy Jardine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Ayrshire, Doonhame have a strong core of mins-passed skaters now, but they've been seeking out public cherry-popper bouts as well as scrims. Most notably, they even managed to appear on film in their first ever appearance (at Bristol Roller Derby's Summer Double Header): "There was 7 of us that popped our cherries in Bristol. It wasn't just any normal cherry popper though, we were filmed by the BBC 'See, hear' programme to promote the abilitly to skate with deaf / hoh players. What a rush! It was so nerve racking, exciting and hundreds of miles away from home, but we did it!
After we got the taste, we actively started to look for cherry poppers, charity games, closed scrimms, anything to let us get out there to play. Its really difficult, frustrating, when you have a handful of players passed skills, gagging to play, but not enough players yet for a full team! Which leads to all of these brilliant events opening up their doors to us, where you learn just how special roller derby is. This has meant us travelling to Edinburgh, Dundee and Newcastle for scrimms and bouts to join other teams. The friendships and camaraderie throughout playing with other teams would be the highlight of travelling, and of course gaining the experience and playing along side some awesome derby gals. "
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h6&gt;PLANS FOR NEXT YEAR&lt;/h6&gt;
We asked each of the leagues about their plans for next year, and it looks like most of them have the same aim in mind: getting on track for their first public bout!
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doonhame&lt;/em&gt;: "All in all I think 2016 is going to be amazing for DDD as we are pushing our girls hard to try and bag a full team line up to finally play as a proper DDD full team. Until then though the girls that have passed will be playing in mixed scrim and bouts when they can and it's great we're always thought of to take part. 2016 will just be Onwards and upwards for DDD. Watch this space!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ayrshire&lt;/em&gt;: "We reckon we will be putting a team together at the beginning of next year and we REALLY cant wait to get stuck into playing!
I feel like it will be next year's [update] that has all the exciting stuff in it!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fair City&lt;/em&gt;: "[We] are hoping to pop our collective team cherry at the start of March 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, within the year of the restructure, we'll be back on track and competing against other teams.  Exciting times for the FCR!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wee County&lt;/em&gt;: "For next year we're hitting training and promotion head on, really pushing ourselves to the limits i know we can achieve. New and improved training programmes will be put in place to fully structurise the fresh meat members, also one for the more advanced skaters.
Were looking to get into the community in a big way, and doing our bit for local charities.
Our goal for 2016 is to integrate roller derby into the Wee County in a big way, so as always, look aboot ye."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Helgin&lt;/em&gt;: "Well, fingers crossed, we get all of our current skaters mins passed in early 2016, and then we’re going on the road to join some boot camps and open scrims to get a bit more experience in game play.  This, along with regular training with ICRD will hopefully have us bout-ready by the end of the year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re planning to hold three more Fresh Meat intakes – probably around February, May and September to keep our skater numbers up, and probably a similar number of fundraisers to keep us going financially. We’re also hoping to get our Business Plan finished over the Festive period (since our training venues are closed and we can’t skate :() and will be able to widen the net of the funds we can apply to, so that we can get scrim vests, more hire kit, more people first aid trained, and even cover our hall hire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve also been in discussions with Moray Sports Centre (a new state-of-the-art sports centre planned to be built on the southern boundary of Elgin) and things are looking hopeful that we may well have a new home in the future – one large enough to host bouts!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inverness&lt;/em&gt;: "We are looking forward to 2016 and having a team ready to start playing after all these years, we will be frequenting Dundee's open scrims with everyone learning to nso's for a couple of turns and then scrimming when mins passed, also we will have a regular session every month with Helgin to keep building on pack skills and game play.  Fingers crossed that later in 2016 Icrd will hit the track as a team!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all goes to the plans above, it's quite possible that next year, there will be no non-bouting leagues roundup, as there'd only be one or two leagues left to cover in it! As always, it's an exciting time with the growth of Scottish derby, and 2016 might see the next big wave of leagues entering the bouting world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>review of the year</category><category>wee county roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/30/non-bouting-leagues-roundup-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 12:29:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-bouting Leagues: Round up of 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/01/11/non-bouting-leagues-round-up-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While we've covered the majority of the bouting leagues in Scotland in our Round-ups of 2014, we cannot and should not forget those leagues who did not bout in the last year, either because they are still growing towards that exciting first bout, or for other reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught up with &lt;a href="http://www.invernessrollerderby.com/"&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.faircityrollers.com/"&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ayrshire-Roller-Derby-Official/618921518215712"&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; to get their perspective on the past year. Doonhame Derby Dolls have also been having an exciting year, and their experience in trying to start up a second junior derby league in Scotland &lt;a title="The Future of Derby: Junior Roller Derby, Part Two" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/10/the-future-of-derby-junior-roller-derby-part-two/"&gt;has been covered here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby, having started as a Women's Derby League in late 2013, caused some surprise by announcing their intent to change to a Co-Ed league structure in mid 2014 (becoming Scotland's second Co-ed league, although not the second bouting Co-ed, with Mean City's change to Co-ed more recently). Ayrshire's Nicola Manley had this to say about their year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby has had a good year in 2014. We have restructured the management at ARD and have a very dedicated team. We have recently enjoyed success with some fundraising and as a result will be able to provide some kit so new recruits can come and try out skating. We have been working hard on our training schedule to find one that works for us and provides plenty of variety.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our change to a CoEd league was perhaps a little soon and not without its own problems....namely lack of male interest also, some women were uncomfortable with idea so we need to think carefully about this in the New Year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have a number of skaters ready to take their minimum requirement skills test shortly, so we plan to be putting a team together in the spring. We are extremely grateful to our friends in other local leagues for all of their support and have had guest skaters come and help us out from time to time, which has been greatly appreciated!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the northernmost league in Scotland, Inverness City Roller Derby (ex Nasty Nessies) have also gone Co-ed, as well as continuing to strengthen and develop the league as a whole. Speaking for the league, Bee-Yatch said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2014 was a busy year for ICRD and our greatest news of the year was securing a permanent venue, we are now in Hilton Community Centre on Monday and Wednesday evenings. Having secured this venue means we can now actively recruit again for ICRD and have just started advertising for our next intake which starts in February.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt; At the moment ICRD have a mixed bunch of skaters and are working on getting all of the team MINS passed, some skaters are already MINS passed and are on hand to help the newer skaters and encourage/motivate them to keep going and be awesome!  Last year we brought the age for training down to 16 as we had interest from younger skaters wanting to become involved  in the team. As we don’t currently have a junior league (we’re working on it though!) we decided to lower the age to 16, on a strict no contact basis until skaters become 18.  This has had a positive effect on the team and along with being co-ed we are keen to promote Roller Derby as an inclusive sport open to all regardless of age, gender or ability.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt; ICRD launched our new website this year as well to reflect our new name, logo and colours. The site is easy to navigate and over the coming months will have information from skater profiles to taster sessions for those interested in strapping on a pair of skates and joining up! The website can be found at &lt;a href="http://www.invernessrollerderby.com/" target="_blank"&gt;www.invernessrollerderby.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all of the non-bouting leagues in this round-up, Fair City Rollers will be leaving most quickly - they caused some excitement on being announced as one of the teams at Voodoo-hosted Highland Rampage tournament in February, marking their return to bouting status after some time rebuilding. Lauren Kettles, Fair City's PR rep had this to say about their preparations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;At the beginning of this year, we were mainly focused on getting our existing skaters through the last of their minimum skills, so it may have seemed like we were less visible for a while. However, after a couple of Fresh Meat intakes  and increasing our numbers again, we started to contact other leagues. I've been out and about getting some experience in various NSO positions in Dundee, Glasgow and Forth Valley. I then took on responsibility for interleague liaison and continue to keep the league up to date with information on scrims, bouts and other training opportunities. All other leagues we've had contact with have been really helpful, welcoming us back with invites to open scrims and opportunities to train with guest coaches. It's important for us to be strongly engaged with the wider derby community, particularly as we build our team towards bouting again. It's been really valuable to us all to be able to keep in contact with other leagues over the year, as any derby related learning is beneficial whether it's on or off skates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Looking towards our inaugural bout, we've been working hard, getting our intermediate skaters through their mins and training up September's newbie intake. We've also been scrimming with other local leagues at open opportunities and getting some valuable NSO experience too. Guest coaching has also been beneficial, with trainers from across Scotland putting us through our paces. Highland Rampage will be a great opportunity to get back into bouting and also begin to establish Fair City Rollers as part of the derby community again. Some of the other leagues taking part have already been helpful to us with scrim invites etc, and we look forward to joining them on track for real.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All three leagues also have Plans for 2015, with all three focussing on recruitment and expansion into the new year. Fair City have already held their first Fresh Meat of the year, last Monday, while Inverness will be holding theirs in February. Ayrshire are simply open to new recruits on a permanent basis, and encourage everyone to contact them via their Facebook page. With Fair City gaining a 2014 Communities grant from the Big Lottery Fund, enabling them to double their training sessions per week, and Inverness City skating in a charity bout and also planning bootcamps for March, it will be an exciting year for all three leagues in 2015!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 in review</category><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>interviews</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/01/11/non-bouting-leagues-round-up-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 12:03:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Review 2014: Non-bouting Leagues Roundup</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/09/derby-review-2014-non-bouting-leagues-roundup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While many of our Scottish leagues have held bouts in the past year, that doesn't make the newer, or relaunching, members of the Scottish Roller Derby community any less important. New leagues are an important part of the derby community, spreading skating to places that it hasn't been before. So, let's spend a little time catching up on what the non-bouting leagues have been doing in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013, Scotland continued to gain new leagues at an impressive pace. Leaving aside Voodoo Roller Dollies (who will be covered in a different article), women's derby leagues sprouted up in Dumfries and Galloway, and in Ayrshire. As is traditional, both the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Doonhame-Derby-Dolls/161632670699789"&gt;Doonhame Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ayrshirerollerderby"&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; were founded by women who wanted to skate, but found themselves too far from the existing leagues to join one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/doonhameandfriends1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3255" alt="Doonhameandfriends1" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/doonhameandfriends1.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="408"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Doonhame Derby Dolls, and friends from GRD and Mean City Roller Derby (Sourced from DDD Facebook page.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;The Dolls have been particularly successful, as skater Claire Warner noted "Our first meet saw 50+ in attendance and that number has grown since (with over 70 paid up members now on the books)!"
As with any new league, that success was supported by the wider derby community, as Claire told us "Our first night was led by Jodie from Glasgow Roller Derby (the woman who had inspired [founders] Debz and Grace) and Cat, a Windsor Rollergirl who luckily for us had just moved to the area, and who has been coaching us ever since. We have had other guest skaters joining in and sharing their skills too, Bruisedog from Mean City, and Turbolinz from GRD came for a visit, Tessington World of Adventures from Granite City Roller Girls and Hazzard from LRG have all dropped in to share their skills, knowledge and love of derby with us, the freshest of fresh meat."&lt;/p&gt;
Doonhame have been exceptionally organised in themselves, as well. In the last four months, they've managed to set up their league branding and management structure, gain sponsorshop, and also garner a huge amount of local media attention, including a spot on ITV Borders News. They've even managed to hold two RollerDisco fundraisers, the funds from which they are planning on using to subsidise costs for skaters on low incomes.
From all of that, you would not be wrong in guessing that their plans for 2014 are.. expansive.
"There is sooo much more planned for this year too (we have just been away on a Dolls development planning weekend)!", Said Claire, "Not only do we plan to gain affiliation, sponsorships/funding to improve access opportunities for other local women, we aim to hold our own local bootcamp to help us work towards passing minimum skills, put on a demonstration bout and hopefully be scrimmaging by the end of the year. In addition to all this we are also looking to take part in local charity fundraisers, spreading the Derby Love and helping those in need in our local community. we will also be running roller disco's on a regular basis throughout the year and hopefully we are about to start organising our own junior derby league!!"
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/ayrshire2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3257" alt="Ayrshire Roller Derby's earliest skaters." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/ayrshire2.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="411"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Ayrshire Roller Derby's earliest skaters. (Sourced from ARD Facebook page)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Dolls were inspired by one Glasgow Roller Derby skater, Ayrshire Roller Derby was inspired by another. As Lorna McIlvanney told us: "We wanted to start up an Ayrshire league but thought it would be difficult and never had the time to do it. Then at Rollerstop, we spotted Sylk from GRD and approached her to see if she might be able to help us set up. She said she would give advice and help with training as and when. [...] We have had massive amounts of help from Sylk, along with various Mean City skaters. We have been invited to scrim with other leagues (once we are mins passed) and have had messages of support and offers of help from many, which has been awesome."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARD have exciting plans for 2014, as well, as Lorna explained, "We are planning on getting to as many bouts as possible and getting involved where we can e.g. as NSO's etc. Our sights are set on passing mins shortly. We have fundraising plans and recruitment drives coming up. Then, scrims for experience and hopefully we'll be ready for our very first bout. We hope to one day base ourselves in the three Ayrshire (North, East, South) and maybe have our home teams structured that way. That's further down the line obviously, but it nice to have goals."
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;⁂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;As well as the brand-new leagues of 2013, leagues founded from 2012 and earlier still continued to develop over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
In Glasgow, the &lt;a href="http://deadlydivasrollerderby.webs.com/"&gt;Deadly Divas&lt;/a&gt; experienced a hiatus for various personal reasons. A spiritual-successor league, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/renfrewshirerockinrollers"&gt;Renfrewshire Rockin' Rollers&lt;/a&gt;, also appeared, with similar stated aims, but is also currently static. RRR Co-founder, Juggs Knock'her said "At the moment due to a lot going on in our personal lives things are on hold. We plan to have a fairly relaxed approach to skating, as well as training to WFTDA rules and Renegade. We are looking to recruit both women and men. Basically derby is about fun and we hope to keep it that way."
With the Deadly Divas also hinting that they might be waking up, it remains to be seen what happens in the space of second-leagues in Glasgow.
&lt;p&gt;Moving northwards, the resurgence of Perth's &lt;a href="http://www.faircityrollers.com/"&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; continued apace in the past year. League chair Pistol Panties was excited about their continued growth, "Initially, we were holding open sessions and just trying to build our numbers up, with the rec sessions, and we have achieved that. We had a big fresh meat intake in August, funded by a local charity geared towards increasing attendance at women's sports, which was a great success and we had a great response from everyone. That really was a stroke of genius, because it allowed us to invite all Scottish leagues along to an open scrimmage, which not only meant we got to see our friends, but it allowed the girls to get a real flavour of what Roller Derby is really about. We now have good numbers of regular attendees, and a team of (very nearly) mins passed skaters."
The league even managed to one-up most of the rest of Scotland, organising a guest coaching session from Steel City Rollergirls' Shrinking Violet in June. "We worked on basic skills, which was really useful even for the more experienced skaters, we all wanted longer with her, so we did a bit of off-skates afterwards too!".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City are now holding regular fresh meat sessions, with the last one being on the 27th of January, and regular training sessions are up to 3 hours a week. "We feel excited about this year," said Pistol, "and to be in a position to be thinking about getting back to competing in the near future. Basically, the only way is up!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/icrdlogo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-3250 " alt="Inverness City Roller Derby's new, striking, logo." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/icrdlogo.jpg?w=614" width="368" height="362"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Inverness City Roller Derby's new, striking, logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inverness' Nasty Nessies Roller Girls underwent a few changes over 2013, not least a change of name and branding. The newly styled "&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/InvernessCityRollerDerby"&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;" will retain the "Nasty Nessies" name and logo for their travel team. While ICRD has not yet bouted, their skaters continue to make appearances in exhibition and cherry popper bouts hosted by other leagues, and travel to open scrims in the rest of Scotland. They've also been working on an interesting outreach project, as Scarlett O'Horror told us: "We've just completed a collaboration with &lt;a href="http://www.fixers.org.uk/"&gt;Fixers&lt;/a&gt; - a group that helps promote community participation and challenge stereotypes. We made a film with them, featuring our own lovely skaters, which will be premièred in Inverness - very exciting!"
2014 looks like being the year for roller derby in Inverness, however, "We have a lot planned for this year! We will hopefully move into a new training venue this year, and have a few more mixed bouts lined up, including participating in a bout in April, which is really exciting for us. Some very lucky members are also off to Texas to watch the World Cup in December - picking up tips and training ideas, no doubt! And t-shirts. Always t-shirts."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, at the northernmost point of Scotland, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ShetlandRollerDerby"&gt;Shetland Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; has continued to hold both derby and open skate sessions throughout the year. Men and women are welcome, and the Open skates in particular have been popular.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;⁂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;As you can see, it's been an eventful year with the growing leagues of Scotland, and 2014 promises to be even more interesting!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>deadly divas roller derby</category><category>derby review 2014</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>renfrewshire rockin' rollers</category><category>shetland roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/09/derby-review-2014-non-bouting-leagues-roundup/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 15:22:11 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>