<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about bairn city rollers)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/bairn-city-rollers.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:04 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>BCR Host the final game day of Champs Tier 2 North</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/bcr_host_final_game_day_bct2nm/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/bairncityrollers"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; started off their 2019 and their champs campaign in the best way possible (you can read more about that here) . Their two wins in their first two Champs games saw them sit third in their group with six points despite having played one less game than the two teams above them, who had played three each. Their next two games came against those two teams: first they took on North Wales Mens and then T&amp;amp;F: Inglorious B*Stars. Both opponents took the wins in very hard fought games ending their 2019 Champs season 1st and 2nd in the group, 2 weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="British Champs Tier 2 M N leaderboard, showing the current state of play, including BCR at the middle of the table." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/MRDAside2-2019.png"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst those two teams have finished their champs season, the other teams in the group still have one more game and each team still has everything to play for. The last game day of Tier 2 North takes place on Scottish ground, with BCR hosting this fantastic battle at Grangemouth Sports Complex on the 29th of June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This double header could not have been set up more perfectly for the final set of games, as each match is a decider and will see the teams involved fighting for their final position against their opponent. Hosts BCR will be taking on The Inhuman League, with the winner of that game finishing 3rd in the group and the loser coming 4th. Whilst the other game will see Knights of Oldham play Teesside Skate Invaders, with the loser unfortunately ending up with the wooden spoon for the tier, and facing potential relegation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both games are shaping up to be quite a close battle as by their results so far each are evenly matched. So every team will be pulling out all the stops to get that final win in this years champs competition to finish above their opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors are at 1.15pm and tickets are only £5 on the door, find out more and keep up to date on the Facebook event page &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/2402082363156371/"&gt;https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/2402082363156371/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Flyer for the final fixtuer in British Champs Tier 2 M N; 29th June, 2019 at Grangemouth Sports Complex." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/BCR-flyer.png"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>british championships</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/bcr_host_final_game_day_bct2nm/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 11:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Positive Start to 2019 for BCR</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/05/a_positive_start_to_2019_for_bcr/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018 was a mixed year for Bairn City Rollers. Whilst some members of the league were busy;
the league not as much. Although BCR had members involved in the Men’s Roller Derby World Cup
covering Power of Scotland, Wales and Italy squads (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/27/bairn-city-rollers-central-scotlands-international-derby-league/"&gt;read more about that here&lt;/a&gt;), each of their
three teams at BCR (Women’s, OTA &amp;amp; Men’s) only managed 1 game each in the whole year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many other leagues up and down the country, BCR saw quite a few members retire from Derby
after years of involvement and even a couple move on to other leagues. With numbers shrinking,
BCR looked towards recruitment and, after a positive meeting with GMRD, the two leagues decided to
pool resources and started sharing one training session a week. This helped both leagues save
on hall costs, whilst at the same time helping with numbers at training, allowing them to run better
and more complex drills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During those difficult times BCR were always looking forward and, with 2019 in mind, they decided
to enter into &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.britishchamps.com/"&gt;British Champs&lt;/a&gt; for the second time, having previously competed in 2017. Unlike their previous
entry to Champs as the Skelpies, this time around BCR decided to enter the OTA team. Again
they find themselves in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.britishchamps.com/league-tables/t2m/north/"&gt;MRDA-Tier 2 North&lt;/a&gt;, but this time as the only OTA team in the tier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, BCR have already played their first two of five games in Champs. On February 9th they
travelled down to Manchester to take on Knights of Oldham at the Thunderdome. After an early rise
for most of the team to travel down they took the win, 209 to 108.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to April 20th and
again they were on the road down South, but this time to Middlesbrough to take on Teesside Skate Invaders
(TSI). The last time BCR were in Champs, as the Skelpies, their last game of the tier was against TSI, where
BCR lost by 20 points. This time around however BCR’s OTA took the win, 180 to 136.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bairn City Rollers OTA Roster [Photo: Bairn City Rollers]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/05/bcr-article-group1.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bairn City Rollers OTA Roster [Photo: Bairn City Rollers]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next week, they will be road tripping to Newcastle to play current tier #1, North Wales Roller Derby Men's. Then, in June,
they have a trip away to Wales to play Newcastle's Tyne and Fear B, before their final game of Champs at the end of June.
BCR will be hosting the final game day of the tier in a double header at Grangemouth on June 29th where they
will skate against The Inhuman League.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With two wins in Champs so far, BCR OTA sit third in their group with six points despite
having played one less game than the teams second and first (thanks to an unbroken set of wins).
Those two wins have led to a significant increase in BCR's &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/coed/coed_europe"&gt;Flat Track Stats Global&lt;/a&gt; ranking. BCR OTA are now ranked 3rd in Europe and 20th overall of all OTA teams
on Flat Track Stats (FTS calls this selection "Co-Ed" still).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="British Champs Tier-2 MN Results Table (as of 3 May 2019) [Copyright: British Championships]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/05/bc_t2mn_3May2019.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;British Champs Tier-2 MN Results Table (as of 3 May 2019) [Copyright: British Championships]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst their wins in Champs have been a great start for their OTA team, BCR’s Central Belters have also
started their year in winning ways. They have already gotten their first game of the year out of the way taking the win over
GRD’s Maiden Grrders, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/108318"&gt;179 to 149&lt;/a&gt;. That means they have been unbeaten in seven consecutive games, stretching
back to November 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They're also starting to see their numbers increase from their recruitment drive, with new skaters and
along with some transfers arriving as well. Along with those new faces, some old ones have reappeared as some retired
skaters from other leagues have decided to pull their skates back on and have choose BCR to do just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bairn City Rollers [Photo: Bairn City Rollers]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/05/bcr-article-group2.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bairn City Rollers [Photo: Bairn City Rollers]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news doesn’t stop there: Bairn City Rollers have seen their skaters making it onto both Wales' and Power of Scotland's training
squads for the Men’s Roller Derby World Cup 2020. There is also the possibility of a BCR member appearing on the Team Italy squad, with
tryouts still taking place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With more games penned for the rest of 2019 for their Women’s and OTA team, this year is starting to look like a good one for
BCR and its members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their first home game of the season will be BCR’s final Champs game on the 29th of June: for more
information head over to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2402082363156371/"&gt;event page here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>british championships</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/05/a_positive_start_to_2019_for_bcr/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fair City Rollers: Rising</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/20/fair-city-rollers-rising/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Sunday is the only time you'll see Perth's local roller derby league, Fair City Rollers, on track at home this year, due to the popularity of their excellent local venue, Bell's Sport Centre. As a result, for those following the team, it's an opportunity not to be missed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-26879" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/fcr_map-layered.png?w=1024" alt="FCR_map-layered" width="1024" height="948"&gt; Fair City, and the leagues combining to face them as "Scotland's Rising Stars"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fear Maidens, Fair City's travel team, will be facing a mixed exhibition team drawing newer skaters from Ayrshire Roller Derby, Bairn City Rollers' Central Belters, Dundee Roller Derby, Granite City Roller Derby, Lothian Roller Derby and Mean City Roller Derby. Coming together as "Scotland's Rising Stars", these skaters represent some of the best new talent in Scottish roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fear Maidens have played one previous bout this year, losing away to Dundee's B team, the Bonnie Colliders, back in &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/8969"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Due to way Flat Track Stats' rating changes are applied (always equally, but oppositely, to both teams), this has almost certainly underrated the Perth team at present, due to both Dundee teams' considerable strength gains year on year. Whilst this game against an exhibition team will not compensate in the ratings, we're confident of a strong showing from Perth's only roller derby team at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City's Invader Zoom told us, "We are so excited to be playing at home again and can't wait for the people of Perth to see some of our new recruits in action. Our last home game was a nail biter that had the audience on the edge of their seats all game, and we are sure this game will be just as thrilling with a challenge team of skaters from 6 different Scottish leagues!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as Roller Derby action on track, there will be the usual collection of stalls, including an opportunity to support the charity &lt;a href="http://www.clicsargent.org.uk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CLIC Sargent in Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, raising money to help Young Lives versus Cancer. Fair City Rollers will be participating in CLIC Sargent's Rainbow Assault assault course event in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City Rollers' "&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1869400046436599/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pack to the Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;" is at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/Sty37VvYGx92"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bell's Sports Centre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Perth, on the &lt;strong&gt;24th June&lt;/strong&gt;, 2018. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>fear maidens</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/20/fair-city-rollers-rising/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 13:36:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bairn City Rollers: Central Scotland's International Derby League</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/27/bairn-city-rollers-central-scotlands-international-derby-league/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2018 it seems Derby World cups are like busses, you wait so long for one to arrive and another appears just after it. February saw the Womens Roller Derby World Cup blow everyone away and now, thankfully, we are past its comedown. But it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; time to get ready for the Men’s Roller Derby World Cup, which kicks off on the 5th of April in Barcelona. This is the third MRDWC; the first was held in England back in 2014, and the second was two years ago in Canada. Back at the first World Cup in 2014, 15 nations battled it out, that tally rose to 21 in Canada, and this year at Barcelona there will be 24 nations represented, with even more set to join in at the next MRDWC after this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland/"&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/a&gt; has featured at every MRDWC so far with its roster comprised of skaters from all over Scotland, as well as some from South of the border. From the first MRDWC to the current POS lineup going to Barcelona, &lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers/"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; has had its skaters featured in each of the squads. BCR's Gibb is one of only three skaters in the current PoS roster who have been present on all three of Power of Scotland’s final World Cup squads to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-26515 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/20180321_204818.jpg?w=700" alt="Power of Scotland and Bairn City Skater Gibb #5" width="700" height="351"&gt; Power of Scotland and Bairn City Skater Gibb #5 (Credit: Andy Mo Photography)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the first World Cup &lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers/"&gt;BCR&lt;/a&gt;’s current or past skaters accounted for over quarter of the POS squad. At the last MRDWC in 2016, six current or past BCR skaters made it onto the training squad, of which four made it into the final squad that traveled to Canada. This time around, partially thanks to injuries and retirements, they have two skaters who made the training squad and both will be at Barcelona with Power of Scotland. One will be skating (Gibb) and the other now as part of the staff (rEd Baron).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BCR are proud that they have skaters once again involved with of Power of Scotland at this World Cup. They are also very proud of their skaters' (past and present) achievements representing and playing for Power of Scotland since its inception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-26514 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/20180321_204752.jpg?w=700" alt="Power of Scotland and Bairn City skater Red Baron" width="700" height="352"&gt; Power of Scotland and Bairn City skater rEd Baron (Credit: Andy Mo Photography)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst we are used to seeing some faces from outside of Scotland in POS squads, we are not used to seeing our male skaters in Scotland appearing elsewhere on other National teams. That was until now! At this MRDWC there will be a couple of skaters that play and train in Scotland who will be representing nations other than Scotland, and both hail from Bairn City Rollers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers/"&gt;BCR&lt;/a&gt; are incredibly honoured and proud to say that in their ranks they have skaters who will be representing not one, not even two, but three different nations at Barcelona. On the track at the tournament along with Gibb representing Power of Scotland they will have Oliver lining up for &lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/WalesMensRollerDerby/"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt; and Vezzani for &lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/mensrollerderbyteamitaly/"&gt;Team Italy&lt;/a&gt;.
If you follow Men’s Derby in Scotland Oliver and Vezzani’s faces will be familiar but perhaps their names not-so-much: they have opted, like many, to play under their real surnames. Normally you would see Oliver playing under his derby name of Basha ROO, and Vezzani as Despicable V.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-26512 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/20180321_204624.jpg?w=700" alt="Team Italy and Bairn City skater Vezzani (Despicable V)" width="700" height="352"&gt; Team Italy and Bairn City skater Vezzani (Despicable V)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Oliver and Vezzani in their past have represented Power of Scotland (both made the 2016 training squad), with Vezzani representing POS at the first MRDWC. Both have now decided that, going forward, they wish to represent other nations instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-26513 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/20180321_204726.jpg?w=700" alt="Team Wales and Bairn City skater Oliver (Basha ROO)" width="700" height="352"&gt; Team Wales and Bairn City skater Oliver (Basha ROO)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking to Oliver about why he decided to try out for Wales he said:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;My mum's side of the family are all from Wales and are passionately Welsh, even my Gran who was originally from Birmingham, so it was a bit of a no brainer to play for Team Wales when I got the chance. The last World Cup, I couldn't commit to traveling down to Wales for training regularly and flying to Canada, financially and work wise. Thankfully this time round I was in a position to be able to.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Vezzani has a similar story for Italy:
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;At the first MRDWC there was no Team Italy, currently in Italy there are really no Men’s teams/leagues. They do have the Woodgang, which is a team made up of skaters from all over Italy and a few other places. A little like how we had the Jakey Bites here in Scotland. When I tried out for POS for the 2016 World Cup there was no Team Italy, they only appeared very late in the day after I had already made the POS training squad.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;When I didn’t make the final 20, quite a few people said to me about trying out for Italy instead. But because I had already made one countries training squad for that world cup I decided against it. Although when I watched and cheered on Italy at the World Cup I realised then, I really wished I had. At that point I decided that if I was going to try out for any Nation going forward it was going to be Italy.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
We also asked both how friends, family and team mates reacted when they found out that they would be representing Wales or Italy.
&lt;p&gt;Oliver:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;My Family have been really supportive about me playing in the World Cup for Wales, so much so that they are coming to Barcelona to come and watch. My mum's gone full Welsh fan-girl so expect lots of daffodils and dragons, lol. My team mates are pleased for me as well although a few wished I had picked Power of Scotland instead.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Vezzani:
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;When it came to trying out last year, I had told a couple of people that I had wanted to but never told anyone when I was actually going to do it. It was only when I played my first game for Italy in November last year (at the Road to Barcelona tournament in Holland) that everyone found out I had tried that also included 99% of BCR as I had managed to keep it a secret. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The response from friends and teammates has been fantastic and everyone has been really supportive. My dad is really proud and happy that I will be representing Italy and my sister seems to be the most excited by it all, even more than me. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
We all know that at the previous MRDWCs, Scotland’s fans have become well known for their support, sheer volume, and chanting for not only for Scotland but other Nations they take a liking to.
Seeing as both Oliver and Vezzani are Scotland-based skaters, they will be hoping that they will get some support from the Scottish fans when they take to the track in Barcelona. Here at SRD, we do hope that the Scottish fans at Barcelona and back home will be celebrating and cheering on both of these skaters, and the Welsh and Italian teams.. at least, when they are not playing against Power of Scotland!&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bcr</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc</category><category>mrdwc 2018</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>team italy mens</category><category>team wales mens</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/27/bairn-city-rollers-central-scotlands-international-derby-league/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 10:09:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Roller Derby Is Back in Grangemouth in 2018</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/02/14/roller-derby-is-back-in-grangemouth-in-2018/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9205" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/bcr-banner.jpg" alt="bcr-banner" width="851" height="315"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby in 2018 has well and truly started after the Christmas break as we have just witnessed the Womens World cup in Manchester recently and still have the Men's world cup to look forward to in April. But this month sees the return of derby in Scotland, with the first games of 2018 taking place thanks to Bairn City Rollers. As they will be kicking of their 2018 by hosting a double header in Grangemouth Sports Complex on Saturday the 24th of February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a double header with a Geordie feel to is as BCR's Skelpies take on Tyne and Fears &lt;span class="_4n-j _fbReactionComponent__eventDetailsContentTags fsl"&gt;Inglorious B&lt;em&gt;Stars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for the first game of the day followed after there is an &lt;span class="_4n-j _fbReactionComponent__eventDetailsContentTags fsl"&gt;All Gender game made up of skaters from Newcastle.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="_4n-j _fbReactionComponent__eventDetailsContentTags fsl"&gt;The Skelpies and the BStars have faced off against each other three times to date, with the B*Stars taking the win each time, can the Skelpies take the win this time? Be sure to come along to find out.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="_4n-j _fbReactionComponent__eventDetailsContentTags fsl"&gt;Doors open 1.30pm and tickets are priced at £5 on the door. If you would like to know more &lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/587963344880848/"&gt;visit the facebook event page here&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bcr</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mens roller derby scotland</category><category>skelpies</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>tyne &amp; fear</category><category>tyne and fear</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/02/14/roller-derby-is-back-in-grangemouth-in-2018/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 11:15:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>DRG's Bonnie Colliders Battle Bairn!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/18/drgs-bonnie-colliders-battle-bairn/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller girls' are hosting their second home game this season as a single header! On the &lt;strong&gt;22nd of July &lt;/strong&gt;at the &lt;strong&gt;D.I.S.C.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Dundee&lt;/strong&gt;, the Bonnie Colliders are taking on Bairn City (&amp;amp; pals!) which looks to be a mighty match! With doors opening at &lt;strong&gt;12:30 &lt;/strong&gt;and first whistle coming in at &lt;strong&gt;1pm,&lt;/strong&gt; it's gonna be a short and sweet single header. Differing from DRG's usual doubles hitters,  these two familiar sides will most certainly make the trip worth while!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-22412 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/19621172_1505774156154661_5391157900722134871_o.jpg" alt="Photo Courtesy: Laura MacDonald" width="520" height="736"&gt;
We thought we would catch up with the Bonnie Colliders Co Captains for 2017, &lt;strong&gt;Breezy Does It #289&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;HullabaLou #17&lt;/strong&gt;, to learn a bit more about leading and shaping a B team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="22420,22421" type="circle" columns="2"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q1: How has the season gone so far for you guys? You've have a few games already and you seem to come out strong both sides.
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breezy:  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;This season has been amazing so far, we've played those two games and won both, which is super exciting! The team is really starting to gel together and we are getting better every time we play. We've had a few newer skaters join us and they are coming on great and are fitting in well with the team.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HullabaLou: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's just been so epic this season, I am so so proud of everyone! To see our wee team taking the skills that we drill together every week at training and scrims, and put them into practice during games is fantastic – whether it’s fancy new toe stop spins, some super controlled one-one blocking or crushing offense; the commitment and effort from every person on the team is something that I respect hugely and do not take for granted as a Captain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q2: And so the Colliders have played a Bairn side a few times, with the most recent in 2015 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/71209" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;[FTS]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;. How does that change your look on this match-up?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I was off on maternity for all of 2015 so unfortunately wasn't part of the team on that one but I was there for the previous year and it was such a tough game! Bairn have continued to grow so much since then, really we're looking at them as a brand new opponent. Which for a lot of our Colliders this season - they will be!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The 2015 game&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; was one of the firsts for quite a few of us who had just been rostered for the B team, and was definitely quite an experience for us haha! Bairn are so lovely and we genuinely can’t wait to play them again, but will definitely be needing as many of our Collidoscopes (our loyal fans) to support us as possible!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q3: How do you guys approach a game when you are captaining, what goes through your mind?
&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;B:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I approach all games in a similar manner, nervous anticipation! The difference as a Co-Captain is that I like to check in with all the skaters to find out how they're feeling, as Lou and I want each skater to enjoy themselves and feel comfortable on game day. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ll we want as Captains is to ensure our team has an absolute blast on game day, I just want to help them smash their goals and whip out those hard-practiced skills! Colliders are definitely all about soaking up the sheer enjoyment of simply playing roller derby together! To quote our wonderful co-chair Milky “It’s just a made-up game on roller skates” and so I try to focus on that…we are from Fundee after all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q4: With the Silvery Tayzers (Dundee's A team) getting quite a lot of focus now with the league being full WFTDA members, do you feel that adds more pressure for you guys, or is it the opposite and you loose some track time as a B team?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DRG train as a league, first and foremost. We all skate together. We have skaters who've just passed their minimum skills alongside our Team Scotland skaters. It is a huge benefit to all our skaters as we work together to push each other on in every aspect. As a team, the Colliders do get lots of track time together to work as a unit, and practice our tactics and skills, but training alongside the Silvery Tayzers really pushes us out of our comfort zones and helps us develop further. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DRG definitely think of ourselves as a league rather than 2 teams – we train together, scrim together and thoroughly support each other; the success of the Tayzers and their sweeeeet wftda ranking (266th!)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;[16/07/2017 FTS]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; has only boosted our league spirit. And likewise when the Colliders smash it, the mad support from the rest of the league is just unparalleled. Personally, that’s one of the things I love most about DRG: Our wonderful bouting committee have always placed an equal importance on getting games for both Colliders and Tayzers….so short answer – no, we never lose track time!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q5: With that in mind, what do you guys aim for, for yourselves and your team? It must be hard to maintain such a close-knit team, with skaters moving on to the A team or with the new intake coming up.
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; My aim is to work alongside all of our current skaters and those moving up from the new skater programme to encourage them to practice in the hopes that our team can grow stronger. As for keeping the team close knit, I think that comes from our training atmosphere. Lou and I are very open in terms of communication and encourage skaters to bring any issues to us in the hopes that everyone feels driven but not pushed, as being a Collider is always about having the best experience possible and taking away as much as you can from both training, scrimmage and game days!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I think that as a team we definitely drive ourselves forward and regardless of experience-level our training committee has always worked us hard to constantly improve our play. Being a B team, the roster is a lot more dynamic; newer skaters come up, more experienced skaters move to the A team, and it changes a lot. We do actively focus on learning how each other blocks/jams so can we gel on track but because we all train together, even when a skater does reach a certain level experience and makes that tough decision to bout exclusively with the A team, it doesn’t really feel like we’ve lost them because we'll be drilling/scrimming with them the week after anyways. Saying that we did have a very emotional locker-room-team-cry after a speech from last season’s stepping down Captains… but I think that just goes to show how much we bond as a team…or perhaps how emotionally unstable a bunch of us are…possibly both.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out more about the upcoming game (&lt;strong&gt;Saturday 22nd July&lt;/strong&gt;) Check out the facebook event page here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/146108915947622/?acontext=%7B%22source%22%3A5%2C%22page_id_source%22%3A133126163419474%2C%22action_history%22%3A%5B%7B%22surface%22%3A%22page%22%2C%22mechanism%22%3A%22main_list%22%2C%22extra_data%22%3A%22%7B%5C%22page_id%5C%22%3A133126163419474%2C%5C%22tour_id%5C%22%3Anull%7D%22%7D%5D%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Colliders vs Bairn and pals!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open: &lt;strong&gt;12:30
&lt;/strong&gt;Tickets: &lt;strong&gt;£5 (on the door)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>captains</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/18/drgs-bonnie-colliders-battle-bairn/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 08:30:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs Schedule 2017</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/03/british-champs-schedule-2017/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, by now you're probably aware that the British Championships 2017 schedule is out (it's hosted here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/2017-british-roller-derby-champs-fixtures/"&gt;http://www.britishchamps.com/2017-british-roller-derby-champs-fixtures/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in a big, searchable, list).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the list is pretty long, we thought we'd pull out some key dates for you (and also tip our hand a bit as to teams and divisions we'll be focussing a little more on - Talk Derby To Me will be continuing their excellent overall Champs coverage this year for those who want to cover the whole thing):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; kicks off on the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Feb&lt;/strong&gt;ruary, with a double header featuring Tiger Bay Brawlers against newly-merged Leeds Roller Derby, and Birmingham Blitz Dames against Bristol Roller Derby hosted by TBB in Cardiff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; also begins a few weeks later in Wales, as South West Silures host the Crash Test Brummies on the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, by then, most of the other Tiers will have had their first bouts, with the whole British Champs schedule starting on the &lt;strong&gt;4th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Feb&lt;/strong&gt;ruary, as the &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 2&lt;/strong&gt; begins with Barrow Infernos hosting Southern Discomfort B (the first B team in the Men's tiers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friends of the blog, &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;, see their B-team, the Whippin' Hinnies, compete for the first time in &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 2 North&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch, in a battle of the B-teams against Rainy City Roller Derby's formidable Tender Hooligans; hosted by Wirral Roller Derby, this is also somewhat Manchester area themed, as the second bout of the fixture is hosts versus Manchester Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you'll have to wait until April to see some &lt;em&gt;Scottish Women&lt;/em&gt;'s action in the Champs, as &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; host a &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; double header on the &lt;strong&gt;22nd&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Apr&lt;/strong&gt;il. &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;' Reserves are travelling up to Aberdeen to take on the hosts, whilst Furness Firecrackers and Halifax Bruising Banditas will be coming up to play each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scottish Men&lt;/em&gt;'s Derby also has its first showing in Champs that month, as Men Behaving Derby host a &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; fixture on the &lt;strong&gt;16th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Apr&lt;/strong&gt;il; pitting &lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt;' Skelpies against the hosts, followed by Teeside Skate Invaders facing off against &lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, whilst the &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 4&lt;/strong&gt; North starts its series a few weeks earlier, we'll be following friends of the blog (and some of our first interviewees!) &lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt; - their first bout is on the &lt;strong&gt;25th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch against Wakey Wheeled Cats, in Mansfield; the second bout is hosts against Durham Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>york minxters</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/03/british-champs-schedule-2017/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 09:44:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bairn City Central Belters Captain and Vice Interview</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/12/bairn-city-belters-captain-and-vice-interview-2016/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2016 has been a successful year for Bairn City Rollers (BCR) Central Belters, with them winning all of the games they played, this has built up a winning streak of 4 games going back to November 2015. Since May of 2015 they have only lost 1 out of the six games they have played. This has seen them climb the rankings during 2016  from 353rd at the start of the year,  to137th where they currently sit. As it is the end of the year, the belters recently voted in their new Captain and Vice for 2017 so I took the opportunity to ask their exiting captain and vice a few questions about their year in charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain:&lt;/strong&gt; Macfarlane 606 #Mac
&lt;strong&gt;Vice Captain:&lt;/strong&gt; JaneSaw Massacre 254 #JM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-12497 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/belters-w2.jpg?w=700" alt="Captain and vice on the offence" width="700" height="560"&gt; Picture courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;After a mixed 2015 (5 games: 2 wins 3 losses), did you set yourselves any goals for the team?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mac:&lt;/b&gt; At the time, the 2015 season was our most successful season to date. Our main goal was for the team to capitalise on our success and hopefully better it in 2016.
&lt;b&gt;JM:&lt;/b&gt; Losing does get boring after a while so we really just set out to win through determination, hard work and commitment to training week in and week out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This year you played three games, two less than last year. Was this a specific choice you made?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mac:&lt;/b&gt; It wasn’t a conscious decision, we did have more games lined up at the beginning of the year but they were cancelled due to reasons out with our control. But I think it has worked out really well for us as we had a few new skaters join our team.
&lt;b&gt;JM:&lt;/b&gt; A benefit of being part of a Co-ed League is the opportunity to play in the Co-ed bouts as well. Our league is very flexible, quite a few of our skaters Guest elsewhere, and join in with other League training sessions, it means that those who want to bout more can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Although the Belters played less games, 2016 was a fantastic year as you won all of your games. Did you think at the beginning of the year that was a possibility?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mac:&lt;/b&gt; I had a feeling we would capitalise on our success at the end of the 2015 but I really didn’t think we would have the season that we did! We lost a few skaters at the beginning of the year, which meant our roster was reduced but we seemed to have made our small roster work to our advantage!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The first two games of 2016 saw you win both by quite a margin (405pts and 248pts), was the differential a big surprise to you after the games?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;JM:&lt;/b&gt; Yes, our rankings were so low compared to the other teams that solely going by the predictor it looked like we would be facing an uphill battle.
&lt;b&gt;Mac:&lt;/b&gt; It was a surprise to me. Against Belfast City Rockets I expected us to do well but with them a good few places above us in Flat Track Stats rankings before we played I hoped maybe we'd have a chance of taking the win. North Cheshire Victory Rollers were similarly ranked to us so I expected a really close game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;During 216 you have never had a full roster and usually play with 9 or 10. Some teams struggle playing with that amount of players, why do you think this hasn't been the case with the Belters this year?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mac:&lt;/b&gt; Playing short is always difficult but we have managed to make it work for us this year.
&lt;b&gt;JM:&lt;/b&gt; We work well under pressure, a smaller roster means more track time even though its tiring!
&lt;b&gt;Mac:&lt;/b&gt; We all have set roles in the team now, rather than having lots of skaters cover a couple of positions. We have been lucky to have a line-up manager that knows the team really well, which means each line is as strong as it possibly can be.
&lt;b&gt;JM:&lt;/b&gt; I think having less players on game day helps to keep us focussed and play cleanly as you can’t afford foul outs because you are playing so short. Everyone has their job to do and we trust each other to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Your roster is largely the same as it was the last year and a half with the exception of a few skaters who have left. Do you think this has been of benefit to you?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;JM:&lt;/b&gt; It's always sad to say goodbye to skaters who’ve been part of the team and league no matter for how short or long a period of time.
&lt;b&gt;Mac:&lt;/b&gt; We have found what works best for the team and we have became a lot more focused in training and what we want out of games. We also have a strong team bond, with all team members not just the core group of skaters.
&lt;b&gt;JM:&lt;/b&gt; We have set roles in the team, which has made a huge difference.  Knowing how people skate, what they like and don’t, learning set “plays”, spending time with each other, all helps, we laugh a lot, I love that.
&lt;b&gt;Mac:&lt;/b&gt; Having a strong core of skaters has been a benefit to the team. Knowing each other's strengths and weaknesses makes sure we support each other on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-12498 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/belters-team.jpg?w=700" alt="Team shot" width="700" height="394"&gt; Picture courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;You have had a few new skaters this year who have integrated well into your team so much so you would be forgiven for not realising it was their first games. Why do you think that is?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;JM:&lt;/b&gt; I think a lot of this has to go back to the individuals, they are totally committed to the training programme and wanted to bout, so they made it happen for themselves.
&lt;b&gt;Mac:&lt;/b&gt; Our new skaters have managed to find their role within the team very quickly. I feel this is down to working together lots at training and making sure each new skater feels like a welcome addition to the team.
&lt;b&gt;JM:&lt;/b&gt; Also with having such a small New Skater intake our skaters got a lot of attention, one to one training and scrimmed lots before their first games.
&lt;b&gt;Mac:&lt;/b&gt; We have more skaters due to come through in the near future so hopefully our high standard continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Have any of your new skaters stood out and impressed you this year?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mac:&lt;/b&gt; All the new skaters have impressed me in so many different ways! Their attitude towards training has been excellent. They came into the team in a time of change and really stepped up to the challenge! After both of RonaCoaster and Volcanic Ash’s first games I have had people say how impressed they are that these two new skaters are playing at such a high level so early on in their derby career.
&lt;b&gt;JM:&lt;/b&gt; They all have, we had two skaters come through BCR’s New Skater Programme and one Transfer Skater.  We’re very fortunate to have them, they’re awesome!  Quality over quantity all the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-12496 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/belters-w1.jpg?w=700" alt="in action" width="700" height="467"&gt; Picture courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Over the last 2 years we have slowly seen a change in the Belters playing style, what would you attribute this to and has it helped with your game results?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mac: &lt;/b&gt;Having consistency in the leadership and coaching has helped shape our playing style. We decided to focus on using a few simple yet effective tactics which has allowed us to really up our game, this has allowed our newer skaters to get up to speed relatively quickly as well.
&lt;b&gt;JM:&lt;/b&gt; I think that quite a few of our League members also Referee/NSO on a regular basis throughout Scotland and further afield really helps us with rules and game play. We’re also very lucky to benefit from skilled coaches, most of whom skate or have skated for Power of Scotland Mens Roller Derby.
&lt;b&gt;Mac:&lt;/b&gt; We are also very lucky that we have the opportunity to practice our tactics against the Skelpies at each training session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Since 2015 your ranking has been on the move up but really jumped in 2016 thanks to your 4 game unbeaten run going back to November 2015. Do you think that the team can continue this on in 2017?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mac:&lt;/b&gt; I am very hopeful our success will continue into 2017. We have voted in an excellent captain and vice for the new season who will make sure we work hard! We will just need to keep the hard work at training and organise as many scrims as we possibly can to ensure we have lots of time to practice as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Finally throughout your time as Captain and vice what what has been your fondest memory and moments that stand out over the last year in charge?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;JM:&lt;/b&gt; We changed our logo and colours throughout the year to tie in with the Skelpies and main League colours.  That felt like a fresh start and I think that's what the Belters needed.
&lt;b&gt;Mac:&lt;/b&gt; My fondest memory is just seeing how much the team has improved. Everyone has upped their game and we all have the same goals for the team.
&lt;b&gt;JM:&lt;/b&gt; I’ve loved all of 2016!  I joined S&amp;amp;T and started coaching on Monday nights endurance and skills based training, that was interesting, especially when I brought the rugby tackle bags to training!
&lt;b&gt;Mac:&lt;/b&gt; My favourite game this year was our last one against the Furness Firecrakers. It was our biggest challenge and we fought right to the end and we came out on top.
&lt;b&gt;JM:&lt;/b&gt; The Furness game was a particular highlight for me what with all the lead changes throughout the game. That really was a fight to the finish with both teams leaving everything on the track.  That was also the first game I got to play in with my sister (Volcanic Ash) and her cherry popper!  So that game will always be special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-12499" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/belters-group.jpg?w=700" alt="Team shot" width="700" height="525"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking over from Macfarlane and JaneSaw Massacre as Captain and Vice for the Central Belters in 2017 will be Wheely Wonka as Captain and Cuckoo Cadoo as Vice Captain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2016</category><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bcr</category><category>belters</category><category>captain</category><category>central belters</category><category>cuckoo cadoo</category><category>janesaw massacre</category><category>macfarlane</category><category>vice</category><category>wheely wonka</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/12/bairn-city-belters-captain-and-vice-interview-2016/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 17:36:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Are you ready for a skating spooktacular?</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/19/are-you-ready-for-a-skating-spooktacular/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9817" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/fb-hallowmean-a.jpg" alt="fb-hallowmean-a" width="3545" height="1305"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tricks or treats? Why choose when you can have both – and a whole lot more – at Mean City’s closing home game of the year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow’s only coed league will be hosting a devilish double dunt of derby delights on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 29 October&lt;/strong&gt; at the Dear Mean Place – aka the &lt;strong&gt;ARC Sportscentre in Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hallowe'en is when things go bump in the night - &lt;strong&gt;HallowMean&lt;/strong&gt; is when things go bump on the track and there are trick and treats for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, the &lt;strong&gt;Mean City ladies&lt;/strong&gt; – fresh from a gallus bout against Granite’s Fight Hawks and looking to maintain their forward momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Meanies have been reaping the benefits of a greater emphasis on tactics, fitness and skills – with fresh recruits bolstering the settled squad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their opponents on 29 October will be the out-of-this-world &lt;strong&gt;ASTROs (Auld Reekie All Star Rookies)&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s going to be a stern test of the Mean City ladies’ resolve, as well as a showcase for some of Scotland’s finest up and coming skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second game will see &lt;strong&gt;Mean City's coed team&lt;/strong&gt; ghosting to the track to take on &lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers' Belter Skelpers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tis the season to be fearful and while there’s no fear among the Mean City ranks, there will be some trepidation given the excellent form the Belter Skelpers have been in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bairn City Rollers’ coed team recently played a mix of Aberdeen and Dundee skaters – the Brawler Buddies – and really brought their A game, winning with a well-oiled performance combining offence, defence and excellent tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City’s coed team may lack the experience of their opponents, but they have spirit, guts and tenacity in abundance and will match them skate for skate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City President Elaine Hunter – aka Roller Dobby - said: “We can’t wait to round off our home season in style with a spook-tacular thriller for all the family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Trick or treat – why choose when you can have both? There will be skating, fun, cakes and cracking tunes – what else are Saturdays made for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Tickets are just &lt;b&gt;£4&lt;/b&gt; in advance – that’s just £2 per game – or &lt;b&gt;£5&lt;/b&gt; on the door. It’s a bargain and you’ll be supporting grassroots sport at the same time. Under-14s get in free.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean City presents HallowMean - Saturday 29 October 2016 - doors open at the ARC Sportscentre at noon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;For more information on the event – &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/312912055752880/"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;For tickets – &lt;a href="http://www.meancityrollerderby.com/tickets.php"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>coed</category><category>in the news</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/19/are-you-ready-for-a-skating-spooktacular/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 15:36:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bairn City's co-ed bout to celebrate their 4th birthday</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/05/bairn-citys-co-ed-bout-to-celebrate-their-4th-birthday/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bairn City Rollers became Scotland's first co-ed league back in 2012. Now as they approach their 4th birthday they are kicking of celebrations and ending their 2016 season in the best way they could, a co-ed game. Their opponents will be the Brawler Buddies, who are made up of skaters from &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/granitecitybrawlers/"&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GraniteCityRollerDerby/"&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/dundeerollergirls/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In change from the norm, there will be no advanced ticket sales for this event. Instead in celebration of their 4th birthday BCR are inviting spectators to pay what they want on the day. That's right, &lt;span class="_4n-j fsl"&gt;just turn up on the game and pay whatever you like.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game will take place at Grangemouth Sports Complex on Saturday the 15th of October, doors will be open from 2.15pm and first whistle will be at 2.40pm, for more information &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/527945357409228/"&gt;visit the event page here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/527945357409228/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-9205" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/bcr-banner.jpg?w=700" alt="bcr-banner" width="700" height="259"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bcr</category><category>central belters</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>grangemouth</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>skelpies</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/05/bairn-citys-co-ed-bout-to-celebrate-their-4th-birthday/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 19:38:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>