<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about bangkok roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/bangkok-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 11:56:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Derby without Borders: One year catchup</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/derby-without-borders-one-year-catchup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, we brought you an &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/05/derby-without-borders-an-interview-with-founder-mae-dae/"&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Mae Dae, to talk about their fantastic project, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://derbywithoutborders.org/"&gt;Derby Without Borders&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, less than a year later, the project has gone from strength to strength, helping more leagues in more countries across the world, in more ways. With so much happening, it is past time to write an update on events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby Without Borders was founded in 2017, as a project initially intended to help leagues in places where it was cost-prohibitive to get kit and other basic resources (sometimes because roller skating just wasn’t a thing in that country, often also because the cost of items was just much higher than the average wage allowed). The idea was, and still is, that donor leagues or individuals could donate “lightly used” or even new, kit to DwB, and the project would distribute items to leagues in need worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="All the places Derby without Borders has provided help to teams, so far. (Black: kit donations achieved, Blue: “start up” support, Green: advice and translation, Yellow: coaching bootcamps (and other additional support), Red: pending kit donation.)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/DwB2019.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;All the places Derby without Borders has provided help to teams, so far. (Black: kit donations achieved, Blue: “start up” support, Green: advice and translation, Yellow: coaching bootcamps (and other additional support), Red: pending kit donation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we talked to Mae back in 2018, DwB had already successfully helped Sailor City Rollers (Buenos Aires, Argentina), Golden City Roller Derby (Johannesburg, South Africa) and the Cairollers (Cairo, Egypt) with donation packs. They’ve also collected for Roller Derby Beirut (Beirut, Lebanon) (in collaboration with Quad Skate Shop), but have had difficulties getting the kit into Lebanon. Since then, they’ve also been able to support Bangkok Roller Derby (Bangkok, Thailand), Toxic Lima Roller Derby (Lima, Peru), Kyoto Roller Derby (Kyoto, Japan), and Roller Derby Beijing (Beijing, China)…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…but Derby without Borders have also been extending their goals in order to help Roller Derby in other ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, DwB is no longer just Mae Dae: since the last time we spoke, DwB has recruited a second body in the UK, in the form of Rosie Peacock (who has also set up a third donation collection point in the UK). They’ve been providing much needed support, Mae admitting “Rosie has been absolutely pivotal and an amazing addition to the team - I don’t think DwB would have gotten this far without their commitment to the project”.
The project has also grown an Advisory Board, positioned to steer the project in the right directions. In recruiting for the board, Mae tells us that they “reached out specifically to have Skaters of Colour on the board: they’re on the board to help steer the project in the direction it wants to be heading, which means engaging with intersectional, inclusionary and anti-oppressive practices.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rosie and Mae were both representing the cause at this year’s European Rollerderby Organisational Conference (EROC 2019) in Berlin with a stall, and a session on “Removing barriers to accessibility in roller derby”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“It was great to be able to talk with the theme of diversity and inclusivity, and how it relates to DwB, because it really is at the foundation of all of the work that we’re doing - this idea that we need to take down barriers to access in order to make this a more inclusive sport,”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;said Mae. In addition, every time DwB has a stall somewhere, more people learn about the project, and offer to support it. At EROC, one of the attending leagues offered to host a collection at their next bout, and to raise funds for the project.
That said, DwB and EROC in some senses were looking in different directions whilst supporting the same ethos. EROC is, intentionally, focused on improving Roller Derby within Europe; whilst Derby without Borders is inherently about looking outside, and working on how to support Roller Derby in other places, building in inclusivity and adapting culture to support other regions from the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- comment
Add images --&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Mae Dae on the Derby without Borders stall at EROC 2019 (Image copyright: Michael Wittig / Bear City Roller Derby)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/MaeDae-EROC.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Mae Dae on the Derby without Borders stall at EROC 2019 (Image copyright: Michael Wittig / Bear City Roller Derby)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that spirit, then, EROC was also the last event that Mae attended before leaving Europe themself. With Rosie positioned in the UK, Mae has courageously moved to Bangkok, Thailand, allowing them to be physically closer to one big region that would benefit significantly from DwB’s support – South East Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“Moving to Bangkok to help develop SE Asian roller derby has definitely been huge, and really pivotal.” Mae told us,  “I’m really understanding the needs of the region a lot better than I did before - and just how different the scale of roller derby is in all of Asia!”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since being closer to the action, they’ve launched an initiative to provide “consultation” services to newer leagues, giving them support and advice from the ground up (not just on how to start up a league, but also on developing local cultural competency). The first beneficiary of this is the first ever Roller Derby team in Bali: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/hotlavarollers/"&gt;Hot Lava Rollers&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with many of DwB’s new initiatives, this started with a conversation, as Mae relates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“Someone who used to skate with Crime [City Rollers] - Glitter Punch - reached out to me; she’d heard about the project, from Hanna P, and she said ‘I live in Bali now, and I’m so sad that there’s no Roller Derby. I really kinda want to make a team, and I was wondering if you could help me’”.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present, Hot Lava Rollers are just two people, and one set of kit (Glitter’s), and the team is just starting to recruit and look for spaces and other resources. Meanwhile, Mae is actively providing mentorship, on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“I’m trying to get them all the other resources that they would need, so helping them develop everything from bylaws, policies, through to making a logo, getting them social media, just… everything.”
“We’re trying to focus on consistent communication - we talk once a week, even if it’s just a 20 minute check-in. I think also it will be a learning experience in how to help support someone in starting a league without being there - I’m in Bangkok and it’s not far, only an hour’s time difference - but still, not being physically there to put in the work in the same way that I would / am with Bangkok [is a challenge].”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst advice and support is very important, when it comes to developing Derby-specific skills, there’s nothing better than a good coach. So, DwB has also been using its connections to organise specific Coaching Bootcamps in those regions involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 27th April, DwB and Bangkok Roller Derby are co-hosting a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2104905746467908/"&gt;bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; run by Canberra Roller Derby League (and Team Korea)’s ShortStop; on the 12 October, Atlanta Rollergirls (and Team USA)’s Baller Shot Caller will be running a DwB &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/781786125525096/"&gt;organised bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; in Bali! A future Bootcamp is also planned for Cairo (to be hosted by the Cairollers, with Zipblock and Freight Train), but dates and funding are still in progress on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Hot Lava Rollers founders, Rustamia Primanisa and Glitter Punch, after their first meeting with Mae [Thanks to Hot Lava Rollers &amp;amp; DwB]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/HotLavaRollers.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Hot Lava Rollers founders, Rustamia Primanisa and Glitter Punch, after their first meeting with Mae [Thanks to Hot Lava Rollers &amp;amp; DwB]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to run a bootcamp in Bali, in particular, came as a pleasant surprise even to Mae themself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“When Baller [Shot Caller] had reached out to me to ask what she could help the project with, I said, ‘well, here’s all the places I could use help with coaching’, and I let her pick.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
And she said, ‘If I have to choose one, I would say Bali. It seems more secluded, and they probably have less resources’!&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“I said, ‘it’s just two people - there’s the potential you could be teaching 5 people minimum skills’.
Baller was completely okay with that, as the gain in awareness, and value in increased representation was worth it. We did choose a date later in the year to give time for recruitment, though.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having already organised their first DwB bootcamp with Hong Kong Roller Derby (coached by Rosie Peacock and Optimus Grime of Glasgow Men’s Roller Derby), Mae is confident, however, that both bootcamps will have significant regional attendance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“The fact that we had 3 girls from the UAE travel all the way to HK just so they could attend a bootcamp and play a game , just goes to show you how isolated people are - but also how hungry they are for it. What I’m discovering about SE Asian roller derby, and Middle Eastern roller derby. is that when these things happen people will come from across the region to attend and come together.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Bali, though, the bootcamp in Bangkok will also be significant for another reason, being the first time that Bangkok Roller Derby will field a full team to compete. The bootcamp will see two games - the usual Pan-Asian Spring Rollers v Pan-Asian Spring Rollers setup, followed by the history-making Bangkok versus Hong Kong bout!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bout flyer for the next DwB bootcamp, hosted by Bangkok Roller Derby. [Image: Bangkok Roller Derby, photo by Teddy Tse]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/DwB-Bangkok-flyer.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bout flyer for the next DwB bootcamp, hosted by Bangkok Roller Derby. [Image: Bangkok Roller Derby, photo by Teddy Tse]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mae has also been active in providing resources and accessibility in other ways: at present, Roller Derby resources are overwhelmingly available in English (with Spanish probably the next largest). Whilst the WFTDA rules have a translation to the second most widely read language in the world (Chinese), there’s almost no availability in Hindi (the 3rd) and Arabic (the 6th – and 3rd most read as a second language) – and the most spoken Slavic language in the world, Russian, has a similar lack of support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DwB has projects underway to translate resources into under-represented languages to increase accessibility – in the case of Arabic, with the support of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/UAERollerDerby/"&gt;UAE Roller Derby All-Stars&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.cairollers.com/"&gt;Cairollers&lt;/a&gt;. (We’ll be catching up with the Cairollers shortly in another article, as they also have exciting news.) Russian translations of the Short Track Roller Derby ruleset have already been produced, thanks to efforts from the White Night Furies, and Abu Dhabi Roller Derby’s Spinky, as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, Mae dreams of having a “database of different resources for leagues, in all the languages; so if a league needs a framework for a code of conduct in Spanish, they can just go to the database and find something to base it on”. That’s for the future, however: the current effort is focused on getting basic rules and coaching resources translated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as translation, another issue, especially for countries with more filtered access to the Internet, can simply be access to resources at all. In China, for example, common hosts for Roller Derby resources like YouTube, Google Drive, Facebook, Twitter, Twitch, Medium and WordPress are all either permanently or irregularly blocked. Derby Without Borders is actively working with the Chinese Roller Derby community to provide access to the resources that the community needs, using hosts which are acceptable to the Chinese government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Derby without Borders continues to pursue its original goal of providing kit for skaters, as well. One of the first things that Mae noticed at Bangkok was that many of the skaters had inflexible, heavy mouthguards designed for Muay Thai. As theytold us, this isn’t really ideal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“you can’t really speak when you’re wearing them, and can barely breathe in them. So I just emailed SISU and said ‘hey, can you like just give us 20 mouthguards’ and they were like ‘yeah, sure, and just shipped them over’.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as SISU, other derby-related businesses - Steaks, Riedell, and Bont - have shown interest in supporting the project, especially as it has gained more visibility in the community. (Bont-sponsored skater Shortshop has managed to provide a set of wheels as a “prize” at her bootcamp in Bangkok, for example.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bangkok Roller Derby with SISU donated mouthguards, thanks to DwB [Image: Derby without Borders]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/Bangkok-SISU.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby with SISU donated mouthguards, thanks to DwB [Image: Derby without Borders]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this additional activity, however, is only sustainable if Derby without Borders continues to grow itself. Mae is currently working towards a new model for the organisation: regional “chapters” which can help to organise and manage the effort which DwB brings. (The Asia chapter will almost certainly be the first to be established, with recruitment happening now.)
The project is already growing fast enough to need this right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“One thing that I’m learning is understanding my own bandwidth and capability - how much I can do as one person.” Mae told us “Particularly, at this point, I’m doing all of this work because I want to do it - there’s no funding. Understanding my own bandwidth has been important because I’ve had two people reach out to me who were interested in doing the same thing in India, and whilst I absolutely want to help someone start a league in India, I think I might need to focus on one at a time, for now. I think with them I’m going to have to take a step back.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team India Roller Derby have since agreed to help support these potential seeds of Roller Derby, in collaboration with DwB, but the project still needs more people - and leagues - to join in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One Derby without Borders initiative which has been active for the start is the idea of “Sibling Leagues”: an opportunity for established leagues to pair up with specific leagues elsewhere in the world to offer them support. This support could be in terms of equipment donations, as the scheme was originally formulated with Texas collecting kit to donate directly to the Cairollers. However, as DwB evolves, it could equally be provided as knowledge exchange, guidance, and political and social support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“I would love to see that kind of Sibling league relationship develop with more leagues.” Mae told us, “instead of needing to come through DwB [to give support], it could be more like a mentorship: one league can mentor another league, and develop all their resources between the two of them. That’s what’s going to make it more sustainable in the long run [and] that’s the point of the project, creating these things for the sake of sustainability.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Quito, Ecuador’s Forajidas Roller Derby, post-recruitment in January. (Photo: Forajidas Roller Derby)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/Forajidas_roller_derby.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Quito, Ecuador’s Forajidas Roller Derby, post-recruitment in January. (Photo: Forajidas Roller Derby)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst we’ve mostly focused on activities in Asia in this update, that should not imply that DwB is not working for other regions as well. Mae told us that they have been in contact with Forajidas Roller Derby, who are currently trying to (re)establish the only league in Ecuador (in Quito, the capital).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the Forajidas have a GoFundMe ( &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gofundme.com/help-bring-roller-derby-to-ecuador"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/help-bring-roller-derby-to-ecuador&lt;/a&gt; ), they also need guidance and support in forming their league. Mae is actively looking for either a Sibling League, or a coach, or both, who can help to support the new team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, as well as helping to nurture and advise new and developing leagues, DwB is also working to support Roller Derby in other ways. Derby Without Borders can host crowdfunders for such leagues to allow them to raise funds more easily: at present, they’re hosting a GoFundMe to support Buenos Aires’ 2×4 Roller Derby on their current international travel requirements. (You can donate here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gofundme.com/2x4-international-tour-2019"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/2x4-international-tour-2019&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby without Borders is open to assisting any league or team who need their support: regardless of if that’s in SE Asia where Mae is currently focused, or in Latin America, the Middle East, Eastern Europe or Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you, or your league, or your company, want to support Derby without Borders in any way mentioned in this article (or another way you can think of), we encourage you to join in. Derby without Borders can only get better as it gets bigger - and it can only get bigger with more of the community pitching in to support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can support DwB via their Donation page [ &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://derbywithoutborders.org/donate"&gt;https://derbywithoutborders.org/donate&lt;/a&gt; ] and by buying their merch (which also lets you raise awareness of the project by wearing it everywhere) [ &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://derbywithoutborders.org/merchandise"&gt;https://derbywithoutborders.org/merchandise&lt;/a&gt; ]. Mae Dae and DwB central can be contacted by email at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:maedae@skatingoutofbounds.com"&gt;maedae@skatingoutofbounds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2x4 roller derby</category><category>argentina</category><category>bali</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>bootcamps</category><category>cairollers</category><category>china</category><category>crowdfunding</category><category>derby without borders</category><category>dubai roller derby</category><category>ecuador</category><category>egypt</category><category>forajidas roller derby</category><category>hot lava rollers</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>russia</category><category>thailand</category><category>uae roller derby all-stars</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/derby-without-borders-one-year-catchup/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 11:17:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Guest Post: Roller Derby — Bangkok Style!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/22/guest-post-roller-derby-bangkok-style/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In another guest post, we're bringing you a report on Bangkok Roller Derby's recent bout against Pan-Asian travel team, the Spring Rollers, by Mouth Almighty; Mouth recently moved to Bangkok (after being deeply involved in UK derby), and this was her first experience of the East-Asian implementation of the sport. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, 2 weeks ago I moved from the UK to Bangkok as part of a change of employment. As a former skater with Wolverhampton Honor Rollers and  a former director of UKRDA (United Kingdom Roller Derby Association) back in Britain, I was eager to see what Roller Derby in Bangkok had to offer. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As luck would have it, within my first week of moving to Thailand, Bangkok Roller Derby were hosting an event: "Monsoon Mayhem".&lt;br&gt; So, at 7pm on Saturday 17th of November, I had my very first taste of Roller Derby, Bangkok-style. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Most Roller Derby bouts or events in the UK tend to be set in the morning or mid afternoon, in a local leisure centre or school (or whatever venue a team can manage to find that is big enough to host a game and is willing to allow teams to actually skate).&lt;br&gt;Here, Bangkok Roller Derby have the luxury of an actual Roller Dome and an evening start time (I can see why, as it had been 34°C most of the day, with a huge rainstorm in the afternoon, so the humidity factor meant that it was still about 30 degrees at 7pm). &lt;br&gt;These factors put together surely helped bring what was very close to a capacity crowd to this event, something that I fear very few Roller Derby teams in the UK have the joy of seeing at their events. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby versus Pan-Asian Spring Rollers&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:heading --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27781} --&gt;

&lt;figure class="wp-block-image"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/11/bangkok-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-27781"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/gjsheehan"&gt;Gareth Sheehan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gameplay itself was fast paced and aggressive, not violent, simply aggressive, passionate gameplay. The  girls on track seemed to truly enjoy the fun, frantic pace of the game, as did the people watching it.&lt;br&gt;An injury early on in the first half bought to my attention that first aid here in Bangkok is not at the same level as bouts in the UK. (However, this was a friendly game). A single first-aider dealt with the injured player before she was eventually taken off the track in a wheelchair (temporary, I’m sure!) to rapturous applause from both players and spectators.&lt;br&gt;The game continued at a fast pace, with fast jams but with relatively low scoring from both teams; some heavy blocks and hits but thankfully no more injuries.&lt;br&gt;The second half continued at the same frantic pace, some very fast jammers up against some skilled blocking on both teams. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Noticeable differences between UK and Bangkok Roller Derby included less referees and NSOs (this may have been due to lack of volunteers perhaps &lt;em&gt;[something which affects Roller Derby everywhere - Ed])&lt;/em&gt; but as Bangkok Roller Derby grows, and as roller derby in Asia grows in general, this will surely stop being the case. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27782} --&gt;

&lt;figure class="wp-block-image"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/11/bangkok-2.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-27782"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/gjsheehan"&gt;Gareth Sheehan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Announcing was minimal, but with a team made up of English, American, Canadian, French &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Thai players, and with a truly multicultural audience watching, perhaps announcing would have simply been lost in translation... &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also no music playing during the game, something that as a follower of UK roller derby I have become used to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing Bangkok Roller Derby did that is not the norm in UK (although is becoming more common for the big tournaments) is half time entertainment: three inline skaters (one in a dinosaur costume) dancing and doing tricks, followed by throwing cuddly toys out into the crowd, which the audience loved. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; The game finished and it was evident that the players on track, the spectators and everyone involved had enjoyed a great evening of roller derby&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:separator --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator"&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:separator --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby can be found here: &lt;a href="https://bangkokrollerderby.weebly.com/"&gt;https://bangkokrollerderby.weebly.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Their opponents, the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers, are a travel team composed of members of Beijing Roller Derby, Shanghai Roller Derby, Hong Kong Roller Derby and Bangkok Roller Derby (but are open to other Asian teams). They can be found here: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Pan-Asian-Spring-Rollers-448887468791803/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/Pan-Asian-Spring-Rollers-448887468791803/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>bout reports</category><category>guest posts</category><category>international derby</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/22/guest-post-roller-derby-bangkok-style/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 14:04:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>East Asian Derby's new Spring (Rollers)!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/07/east-asian-derbys-new-spring-rollers/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Spring is the time when new growth happens, how appropriate it is that East Asian Roller Derby is just now bursting into life and catalysed by the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-14040 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/pan-asian.jpg" alt="pan-asian" width="223" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Readers may remember our coverage of Japan's second-ever Roller Derby Tournament, the&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, in Okinawa earlier this year. The &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/08/the-tomodachi-cup-teams-pan-asian-spring-rollers/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pan-Asian Spring Rollers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; were one of two "exhibition" teams founded to attend - comprising of skaters from Beijing Roller Derby, Shanghai Roller Derby, Hong Kong Roller Derby (the three Chinese leagues), and Bangkok Roller Derby for Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally, the plan was for them to simply exist for the one tournament - a chance for those 4 leagues to share costs and make a more competitive roster together - but the Spring Rollers have quickly become something more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only a few weeks ago, Shanghai Roller Derby held their first ever public game, enabled by the existence of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers as a team to play against them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a few weeks' time, Hong Kong Roller Derby also hold their first public game, ever, once again enabled by the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pan-Asian Spring Rollers are represented by reps from each of their source teams, and we spoke to their Hong Kong Rep, Willow Whips (who also Captained PASR at Tomodachi), and their Bangkok Rep, Jean Claude van Slam about the new aims of PASR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JC:"We all got on amazingly well [at the Tomodachi Derby Tournament], some of us meeting for the first time just hours before our first game. I think we all felt sad to depart afterwards partly for the awesome experience but also as new found friends.
It was after I chatted with members of Okinawa Roller Derby that the idea came to try and maintain the PASRs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beijing and Bangkok had talked before about the importance of maintaining the relationship between our teams as the key to growing this sport in Asia and so this seemed like the perfect opportunity to harness that enthusiasm and drive this new partnership into something long standing."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WW: "We have been working on a set of regulations and things like that, so the aim is that each team will try and host one event (a training session or a scrim) per year. Bangkok is planning on hosting a boot camp and scrimmage at the beginning of October, which will be open to anyone affiliated with Pan-Asian Roller Derby"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JC: For BRD, it's given members a new motivation for the sport, knowing that all that effort each week of learning and practicing drills has a chance to be put into real action, in addition to attracting new people to our team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the issues for BRD being out further than the rest, is the travel costs. However, one of PASRs conditions for being a team member is to host at least one event per year so this should make for plenty of opportunities to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope that this will also help us to build recognition of the sport in Thailand and encourage more people to join. Just having those opportunities that has already made such a difference [to the team]"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WW: "The [long term] aim is to head back to Japan next year for the [next Japanese] tournament, now that we have played together a few times we will hopefully be even more badass!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JC:"I hope that with the extended reach out to lone players in parts of Asia who don't currently have a home team, the PASR team might encourage new leagues to start in other Asian countries. That's yet to be seen but fingers crossed!!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Willow: "If any teams want to join they just have to be in the region and put forward one representative from the team. If any individual skaters are in the area they are also welcome to sign up and train and play with us!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next fixture in this new East Asian derby calendar is against Hong Kong Roller Derby on the 17th June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-20178" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/hkrd.jpg?w=300" alt="HKRD" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Roller Derby, which started out when founder Buffy SlayHers moved to Hong Kong from the USA in 2013, was inspired by an article listing "Top 5 Reasons HK Needs a Roller Derby Team" after realising that her new destination had no derby at all. As Buffy put it, "So I decided the best way to start was to "recruit " my friend, and roommate at the time, Glenda by having a roomie night and watching, yes, you guessed it, 'Whip It!' Now, before you start hating, and as cliche as it I, I think all of us love 'Whip It!' whether we have accepted the facts or not."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team has had a bumpy ride - despite a huge amount of effort, the original Hong Kong Roller Derby collapsed in 2014, "I'm sure you all know the common difficulties many, if not all derby players face, but being in HK, made it that much harder. From difficulty in securing practice venues, to people moving away, and misunderstandings, our team fell apart and remained that way for over a year and a half."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reformed now, for another go since 2016, the new Hong Kong Roller Derby has managed to grow to a healthy 19 skaters!  Buffy has drawn the following lesson from the two experiences: "It still seems like a dream, but [HKRD] is finally happening and has opened my eyes to why we had failed before. It all comes down to the people and the passion. Without community and support, we are nothing. But now our team is a family, and we realize we won't always agree but we will always have each others' backs and remember that in the end, we all want the same thing."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HKRD's A Team, the Yau Ma Titties, have put a huge amount of effort into organising this first bout (thanks to the previous derby experience of their founder, it's been easier than it might have been).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow the event here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1240708282693458/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1240708282693458/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to join the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers as another Asian team, you can find their Facebook page here: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Pan-Asian-Spring-Rollers-448887468791803/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/Pan-Asian-Spring-Rollers-448887468791803/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  which also links to all of their member leagues, including Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>hong kong roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/07/east-asian-derbys-new-spring-rollers/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 08:37:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tomodachi Derby Tournament - The Teams</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, the Asia-Pacific Region saw its first ever Roller Derby Tournament, hosted in Okinawa. Whilst the Japan Open was a huge success, the host leagues were keen to hold another one, with even more direct control from the leagues and skaters themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14076 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tomodachi.png" alt="tomodachi" width="400" height="400"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is the result - another two day tournament, now hosted by the new Japan Derby Tournament Committee, a collective of the involved Japanese leagues. As with the previous Tournament, the Tomodachi also serves a practical benefit to all the teams involved, giving somewhat geographically isolated teams a chance to play those from other areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be bringing you more info with interviews with the attending leagues in the run up to the event on the &lt;strong&gt;24th&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt;, (at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/%E6%B2%96%E7%B8%84%E7%9C%8C%E7%B7%8F%E5%90%88%E9%81%8B%E5%8B%95%E5%85%AC%E5%9C%92/@26.3099785,127.8141462,15.5z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x76c4ab9c228dd0cb!8m2!3d26.3107468!4d127.8213143"&gt;Okinawa Comprehensive Sport Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), but we're starting (as with EuroClash) with an overview of the competitors... (a timetable is available on our technical annex, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/tomodachi2017.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;WFTDA-Sanctioned Division&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14022" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/pacificrollerderby.png" alt="pacificrollerderby" width="200" height="200"&gt;Pacific Roller Derby&lt;/h3&gt;
Pacific Roller Derby are one of the oldest of the cluster of Hawaiian teams, dating from 2008, and a member of WFTDA since 2009! Due to the geographical factor, they mostly play the other Islands teams, especially at the yearly "Battle of the Islands" tournament. Based in the Islands' Capital, Honolulu, Pacific are currently 305th in the WFTDA Rankings (344th by FTS), partly, we suspect, simply due to not having had much opportunity to play non-Hawaiian teams. The Tomodachi will be their first fixtures against non-HI leagues since 2014!
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14024" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/fairbanks_rollergirls.png" alt="fairbanks_rollergirls" width="200" height="240"&gt;Fairbanks Rollergirls&lt;/h3&gt;
Hailing from their namesake in Alaska, Fairbanks Rollergirls are another member of the "Alaskan Derby" set alongside last year's Japan Open competitors, Juneau (who memorably attended with only 6 skaters!). A WFTDA member since 2011, the league has hosted the Alaskan "United We Roll" tournament for the last two years. We rate them at 1137th out of all teams (male and female, A and B) in the World which can be rated, whilst FTS places them 331st out of all WFTDA teams (a much smaller set).
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14034" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/devil_dog_300.png" alt="devil_dog_300" width="200" height="199"&gt;Devil Dog Derby Dames&lt;/h3&gt;
Local Okinawan Derby league, Devil Dog Derby Dames, (868th SRDRank), were a competitor at the Japan Open last year, although failed to defeat the non-Japanese teams in the WFTDA Division. (Their Home Team, competing in the Unsanctioned Division, defeated exhibition team Nippon Senbatsu.) The year before that, DDDD managed a win over fellow Okinawa league Kokeshi, which they'll be looking to repeat this time.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14036" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/kokeshi.png" alt="kokeshi" width="200" height="200"&gt;Kokeshi Roller Dolls&lt;/h3&gt;
The first league in Okinawa, Kokeshi Roller Dolls, (700th SRD Rank) were hosts of the Japan Open last year, as well as organising hosting for the Tomodachi Tournament as part of the Japan Roller Derby Tournament Committee. At the Japan Open, they took a win over Alaska's Juneau Roller Derby; we will see if they managed to repeat the feat against Fairbanks this time around.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14028" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tokyo.jpg" alt="tokyo" width="200" height="200"&gt;Tokyo Roller Girls&lt;/h3&gt;
The first league in "mainland" Japan, Tokyo Roller Girls, (745th SRD Rank) faired as well as the Devil Dog Derby Dames at the last tournament. However, they've had a busy home season since then, with all three of their home teams bouting each other, and recruitment has been strong. (TRG skaters have also been behind much of the activity of Women's Roller Derby Japan, the governing body for the Japanese Women's National Team, including their impressively active outreach in the last year.)
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Men's Division&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14032" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/grd_logo_cmyk.png" alt="grd_logo_cmyk" width="200" height="102"&gt;Glenmore Reservoir Dogs&lt;/h3&gt;
Hailing from Calgary, Canada, Glenmore Reservoir Dogs (Chinook City Men's Roller Derby) are the 17th ranked MRDA team in the world (65th SRD Rank), and are the men's component of Chinook City Roller Derby. Perhaps most recently known on the international stage as hosts of the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup, the league as a whole also regularly host the annual "Flat Track Fever" (women's derby) tournament. Last year, the Reservoir Dogs themselves competed at the Mayday Mayhem (Colorado) and the O-Town Throwdown (Ontario), taking second place at the former.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14038" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/japan-logo-232x300.jpg" alt="japan-logo-232x300" width="193" height="250"&gt;NinJapan Rollers&lt;/h3&gt;
The Japanese Men's National Team, and still the only Men's league in Japan, NinJapan Rollers have fairly frequently competed against the other Japanese teams (especially Tokyo), but have rarely had the chance to play non-National teams from other locations. In the 2016 MRDWC, NinJapan placed 17th, although their performance was very close to that of Puerto Rico, one place above them. The NinJapan Rollers have also (partly due to necessity) actively promoted Roller Derby throughout Japan, and have a comprehensive "off-season" training and recruitment system to build up their pool of skaters.
&lt;h2&gt;Unsanctioned Division&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14026" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/yokosuka.png" alt="yokosuka" width="200" height="189"&gt;Yokosuka Sushi Rollers&lt;/h3&gt;
A Tokyo Roller Girls "Home Team", this is the Sushi Rollers' first appearance as a travel team, let alone their first tournament. Based in and around United States Fleet Activities Yokosuka naval base, the Sushi Rollers were the founding team of Tokyo Roller Girls, and remain one of the strongest in intraleague contests. It remains to be seen how they will fare in their first bouts away from Honshu.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14040" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/pan-asian.jpg" alt="pan-asian" width="223" height="200"&gt;Pan-Asian Spring Rollers&lt;/h3&gt;
The Pan-Asian Spring Rollers are a collaboration between the other (non-Japanese) East Asian Roller Derby leagues, with members from Beijing Roller Derby, Shanghai Roller Girls, Hong Kong Roller Derby and Bangkok Roller Derby. Several of these leagues participated in the first ever Roller Derby bout in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; last year (hosted by Beijing), and so collaboration to attend the Tomodachi seems natural.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14030" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/teamwrdj-sm.jpg" alt="teamwrdj-sm" width="250" height="154"&gt;Team WRDJ&lt;/h3&gt;
Team "Women's Roller Derby Japan" is a the open-subscription exhibition team, run by the committee for . It comprises skaters from the Neon Roller Monsters (Tokyo Roller Girls' Japanese-nationals-team), Tokyo Three Rollers (Tokyo's Open-To-All/Coed Team), Kokeshi Roller Dolls, Devil Dog Derby Dames, and a single skater from Hawaii's Echo City Knockouts (of Kailua-Kona).&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>beijing roller derby</category><category>devil dog derby dames</category><category>fairbanks rollergirls</category><category>glenmore reservoir dogs</category><category>hong kong roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>kokeshi roller dolls</category><category>ninjapan rollers</category><category>pacific roller derby</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><category>shang-hai rollers</category><category>tokyo roller girls</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>women's roller derby japan</category><category>yokosuka sushi rollers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 08:05:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Beijing Roller Derby and UN break ground in China: Derby for equality with HeForShe Derby Invitational</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you thought that the Japan Open was the only exciting thing happening in Asia with Roller Derby, you were wrong.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="vertical-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/13/the-future-of-derby-china/brdlogo/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-4793"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4793 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/brdlogo.jpg?w=300" alt="BRDLogo" width="300" height="216"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="vertical-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/screen-shot-2016-03-31-at-08-37-09/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-6898"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-6898 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/screen-shot-2016-03-31-at-08-37-09.png?w=223" alt="HeForShe" width="223" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.beijingrollerderby.com/"&gt;Beijing Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; have been working on a project in collaboration with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.unwomen.org/"&gt;United Nations Women&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (the UN Entity responsible for Gender Equality and Empowerment of Women), and today they have announced it publicly.
&lt;p&gt;The "&lt;strong&gt;International HeForShe Roller Derby Invitational&lt;/strong&gt;" will be a co-ed tournament, featuring skaters from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://shanghairollerderby.tumblr.com/"&gt;Shanghai Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://bangkokrollerderby.weebly.com/"&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; as well as the hosts Beijing. Hosted in &lt;strong&gt;Ditan Olympic Park&lt;/strong&gt;, Beijing, from &lt;strong&gt;7pm&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;3rd of May&lt;/strong&gt;, the event will be the first ever Roller Derby tournament of any kind in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The event was first a dream to bring a team to Beijing so we could finally hold a bout or a scrimmage. Our teammate Sustainable Devilment saw something bigger. With the new domestic violence law in China and the HeforShe campaign, she felt derby was a great way to show a sport that encourages women empowerment" said Bejing Roller Derby's Jessica Jabbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event is being described as a 'scrimmage' and an 'informal tournament', which we take to mean that it is not being undertaken for ranking purposes. In fact, the purpose of this event is more serious than sporting rankings; as part of the UN Women's HeForShe campaign, the aim is to show solidarity between all sexes with women across the globe, by the symbolic means of a full-contact sport where women are the dominant force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby's Jean-Claude Von Slamme spoke to us about the event, saying:
"Our team is really excited to be a part of this event as it will be our first chance to meet with other roller derby teams and play a full game together. For some of our skaters it will be the first time they have ever played on a full sized track (ours is a little small) so the experience will be hugely beneficial to not only individual development but also in inspiring a new motivation and enthusiasm in our team by giving them a real taste of Roller Derby as a professional sport and as a worldwide community. We're extremely grateful to Beijing Roller Derby and UN Women for giving us this opportunity and working so hard to get us all there. They have been so supportive and I hope we can show our appreciation when we arrive by making this a really memorable event for everyone involved."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a draw from a high level Roller Derby perspective here, too: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gothamgirlsrollerderby.com/"&gt;Gotham Girls Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s &lt;em&gt;Sexy Slaydie&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Miss Tea Maven&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nyshockexchange.com/"&gt;New York Shock Exchange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s &lt;em&gt;Willverine,&lt;/em&gt; will be attending, providing a training bootcamp ahead of the tournament event itself! From Beijing Roller Derby's perspective, this is also a great opportunity to further increase the visibility of Roller Derby in China, an aim which they have been pursuing with some success over the past 3 years. (The topic of the promotion of Roller Derby in such contexts is something which is also close to this Blog's interests, and we will be following up on this with an article later in the year.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gotham's Miss Tea Maven was keen to emphasise the wider importance of the event's context. "Gender Equality is incredibly important for me.  As a self identified cis-gendered straight female, every single person should be able to self identify how they would like to.  I feel like parts of the world are taking great strides in moving forward with movements like 'HeForShe'  but there is still a lot of work to be done.  The recent North Carolina transgender bill is a very saddening example of this.  We as human beings need to support our fellow human beings, and make sure that rights are equal for everyone no matter how you identify or what your birth certificate says.  It shouldn't matter - you are a human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am beyond excited to help support this cause through my favorite medium - roller derby - and being able to go to China is just an amazing experience... I can't wait for the event to start!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the UN Women's HeForShe Campaign, go here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://heforshe.org"&gt;heforshe.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can watch the tournament itself live at: &lt;a href="http://lady.163.com/special/sense/heforshe2016.html"&gt;http://lady.163.com/special/sense/heforshe2016.html &lt;/a&gt;7:00pm Beijing time (&lt;strong&gt;midday&lt;/strong&gt;, UK time - although, actually, the bout is currently just being introduced at 1pm UK time...)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>beijing roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>shang-hai rollers</category><category>un</category><category>un women</category><category>united nations</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 07:26:47 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>