<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about bear city roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/bear-city-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:34:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>EROC 2019: The return of Europe's community conference.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/03/eroc-2019-the-return-of-europes-community-conference/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst it skipped a year in 2018, due to the potential conflict with the Roller Derby World Cup, one of the most important events in European Roller Derby is returning for 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2063064350378242/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;European Roller Derby Organizational Conference&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will be 10 years old at the time of its next edition, running from January 31st through February 3rd 2019, in its usual host city of Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2009, EROC has provided a place for the entire European derby community to come together to share experience, build contacts, and plan the future. It's been an invaluable starting point for several of the European National Governing Bodies, as well as helping to seed derby future across the continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/?attachment_id=27817#main" rel="attachment wp-att-27817"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27817" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/eroc2019.jpg?w=700" alt="" width="700" height="700"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular hosts, &lt;strong&gt;Bear City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;, have extended the conference to an additional day for the first time ever, providing two days of Workshops (Thursday + Friday) and two days of Sessions (the weekend) to bring together Europe's Roller Derby community in discussion and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst EROC has always existed to help build the European community, this year has a particular focus on "Inclusivity", with several sessions and workshops specifically covering aspects of that area. (Those that do not explicitly cover the topic will still interact with it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there will be a lot of sessions and workshops to cover: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8 workshops&lt;/strong&gt; (longer, more interactive topics) of which the titles and conveners of 6 have been released:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Bout preparation: Footage Analysis, Data and Statistics (Michael Watson)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Retention &amp;amp; Growth - your league, our sport (Crazylegs)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Roller Derby Coaching Qualification (Hydra (Rule56))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Inclusive Practice and Accessibility (Feminist Killjoy)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Your League’s Brand - Does it say what you want? (Crazylegs)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Breaking down walls - how to work with conflict management (Maurine Filip)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20 sessions&lt;/strong&gt; (shorter, more directed topics) of which the titles of 9 have been released:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Group Dynamics and Conflict Management (Pernilla Hellan and Lisa Plüschke)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Just another brick in the wall? What we need to know about the individual to create a good fit (Maurine Filip)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The Evaporating History of Roller Derby: fighting the Ephemerality of Digital Media (Sam Skipsey)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Inclusive Practice and Accessibility (Feminist Killjoy)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;False Economies: Is our DIY Approach holding back our sport? (Hydra (Rule56))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Junior Derby (Barney Trubble)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;How Skateboarders dealt with FIRS, best practices for WFTDA and FIRS (Shiran Habekost)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Is it in the walls? How organisational structures affect behaviour (Maurine Filip)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The first WFTDA Continental Cup Feedback Experience and best Practices (Birmingham Blitz Dames)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other unconfirmed topics previously mentioned as appearing include (unless we've missed a few covered above):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whipping your finances into inclusive shape&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low level harassment, aggression, consent, bystanders behaviour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Officiating crew selection process. Sexism and discrimination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open divisions and all-gender roller derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long lasting officiating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, that's still not all, as in addition, special sessions will be held, including a Round Table meeting with NGBs / National Teams and Governing Bodies, A League Fair (including space to sell merch and advertise your league), a 2 day WFTDA Officiating Clinic (weekend)...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and the requisite on-skates events, including the "EROC All-Stars Scrimmage" on Saturday afternoon/evening, and Chicks in Bowls Berlin beginners' bowls and ramps sessions on Sunday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the inclusive focus, &lt;strong&gt;Group Discounts&lt;/strong&gt; for multiple-tickets are available for consortia of smaller leagues banding together to share costs (meaning that, for example, if you and three other leagues can each only afford to send a single delegate each, you can pay together for 4, and get the same benefits as a single league sending 4 delegates); &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; all of those leagues are less than 3 years old, have less than 20 members, and are EROC first timers. If your league does not qualify, there are also a &lt;strong&gt;limited number of "Soliprice" (free, host-subsidised)&lt;/strong&gt; tickets available, to delegates with a strong case for why inclusion is particularly important to them (and/or how they will bring EROC experience back to their league).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; encourage leagues from newer areas to send a delegate, if they are able: EROC is only as good as the breadth of experience and viewpoints at it, and some of the most valuable opinions are from some of the newest places with derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registration is available via the following link: &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScUDoNk7cHaAqDsFIa1vjdCeHBwPjnlVjl-bvRRLhYz3Im_tg/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScUDoNk7cHaAqDsFIa1vjdCeHBwPjnlVjl-bvRRLhYz3Im_tg/viewform&lt;/a&gt; with Early Bird discounts lasting until the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with the additional on-skates activities available with an additional submission here:  &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfLPe5crURLG9pbhqL3bLoR1xvPRzhshloOmRXTS-ZaVVHOiw/viewform?fbclid=IwAR039VtJfOwx3aQs2xrbQXlF6DbtTbJekb4uePbsULouqX1iG2MreXW9l04" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfLPe5crURLG9pbhqL3bLoR1xvPRzhshloOmRXTS-ZaVVHOiw/viewform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2019</category><category>articles</category><category>bear city roller derby</category><category>coaching</category><category>eroc</category><category>european derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>rdwc</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/03/eroc-2019-the-return-of-europes-community-conference/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 11:14:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: Bear City Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/21/euroclash-interviews-bear-city-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Newcastle Roller Girls' first international tournament, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, fast approaches, we're keeping to our schedule to bring you more interviews with the attending teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we're covering one of the two competitors from mainland Europe, Berlin's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://bearcityrollerderby.com/en"&gt;Bear City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bear City have had a long history in European Roller Derby, founded back in 2008 (as Berlin Bombshells) as one of the first two teams in Germany, they also played the first bout in Germany against Stuttgart Valley Rollergirlz back in 2009, and attended the first ever European international tournament, Roll Britannia, the same year. Joining WFTDA as an apprentice league in 2010 (trailblazing in Europe once again, as they would when gaining full WFTDA membership in 2012, first in mainland Europe), they also founded the EROC European organisational conference at that time. It's fair to say that the league has probably done more than most to promote and develop the sport in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More recently, Bear City Roller Derby have divided their time between their regular attendance at the WFTDA Division 2 Playoffs [which the recent changes to the format may break this year] and participation in the German National Tournament, the Bundesliga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13756 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/bcrd-bear-city-roller-derby_0.png" alt="bcrd-bear-city-roller-derby_0" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bear City Captain Peanut Butter Panic and Co-Captain FoXy Führer answered some questions for us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bear City has been one of the few European teams to represent at the WFTDA Division 2 Playoffs consistently for 3 years in a row now. You even managed to improve on your seeding in 2016, taking 5th place from 8th seed. How did it feel to be representing Europe on this stage, and how do you prepare for something like this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a great honor to be able to take the stage, and help show how competitive European derby has become. Granted, there are many other high-level leagues also representing Europe in D1, but to be able to be part of those leagues showing that strong and competitive play is not only in North America, really makes us proud and fuels our fire to continue pushing the level of our play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We prepared for this by really analyzing our previous games in the season and focusing on 2 or 3 things that we needed to improve on. For example, in Midwest BrewHaHa we identified that our offense needed a lot of work, so we made sure to focus on offense during our training and scrimmage times: offense starts, offense on power jams, offense on a scoring pass, etc. Even if we weren't always successful, we kept trying different ways to be more effective and help lighten the load for our jammers. Some ideas stuck, and became integral parts of our toolboxes, some ideas still need to be refined before we can use them, and some just didn't work at all. The important thing for us was to keep trying and refining our plays. We also ramped up our trainings, with some additional training times and increased intensity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In fact, Bear City spent more time in the USA than in Europe in 2016, with four more bouts at the Midwest BrewHaHa as well. There's obviously significant costs to the increased investment in play with USA teams, what do you feel are the main benefits, other than Ranking?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our league decided many years ago, that we wanted to play on the highest level we possibly can, whether it's nationally or internationally. With that in mind, we set up our league structure to support this goal, and even though at times players were not able to afford the costs, it was really important for us to find ways to finance the trips without leaving them behind. For that, and this is one of the biggest benefits, we've created a really close and motivated league, who always supports each other. Besides the A – Team, our B - Team, C – Team, Officals, and all members work together behind the scenes to reach this goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also the additional team bonding that comes from this kind of trip. We typically fly out a few days before the trip to help adjust to the time change and jet lag, and in the time we have fun activities to help us get to know the city better, and to keep us moving before game time. We've done bus tours, boat tours, escape rooms, each of which impart a piece of the city onto us and really allow us use the time to come together as more than only a group of individuals that play the same sport. We also see the cities that may not be the typical choices when planning a trip to the US, some of which we probably would have never visited otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whilst your attendance of at the Bundesliga is with an exhibition team (not your A team), you still managed to top the rankings in the German Nationals. Why did you choose to enter a different roster to the "standard" A team, and how do you feel about the increased number of National tournaments in Europe?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the Bundesliga and the „Ranking“ season at the same time, can make it difficult to coordinate our season plan. As we schedule our season plan, we need to always have in mind that the majority of the Bundesliga games will be after September, due to the sanctioned season running from about March - August. Naturally, we always want to bring our strongest game to the Bundesliga, and we felt that these games are a great opportunity for our league to give back to Germany and the leagues here. Due to the increased intensity our A Team sees during the season, we decided to mix our A and B teams for the Bundesliga to give those players a chance to excel where they may not have been able to during our regular season games. In the Bundesliga games, we also take the time to try new tactics, player rotations, formations, and really step out of our comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly, the increase of National Tournaments in Europe is very exciting and opens new opportunities for new team matchups to happen. Additional national tournaments in Europe mean that more teams will be able to play each other closer to home, we will see new matchups, and really get a feel for how strong various teams actually are. Presently, teams, us included, decide to go to the USA for a tournament or tour in order to play teams closer to their ranking; however, with the increase in tournaments in Europe, that play comes closer, and perhaps we will even see more US teams traveling to Europe for tournament play. Thank you to all the teams who have worked hard to organize and host these tournaments which give us the opportunity to play. We even have WFTDA D1 Playoffs in Sweden! It is a milestone that all of us have been working toward for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On EuroClash - you'll be playing the hosts Newcastle, Auld Reekie and Middlesbrough in your fixtures. Of these, we don't think you've played Newcastle or Middlesbrough before - Auld Reekie / Berlin bouts have been a more regular fixture, and one which seems to go either way! How are you feeling about (and preparing for) these games?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie has always been one of our favorite opponents! Both of our leagues were founded in 2008 and since then we have a very good and friendly relationship. We are very similar in relation to our structures, visions, and gameplay. They are always good hosts, fair opponents, and a tough team to play against. So everytime we meet on track, it feels like meeting a really good old friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we have never played Middlesbrough before, we've kept an eye on them and have seen their hard work they put in during 2016. They went to the US, played different teams there, and won every single game. Middlesbrough is definitely going to be a tough opponent for us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, never underestimate the hosting league! Hosting leagues seems always exhausted, stressed out, there is a lot of going on – organizing a big tournament like that is not always fun and a big challenge for the whole league. However, it is also a good opportunity to grow together as a league and forces are released from which you thought they were not there. Newcastle has the home field advantage here, and will be on fire!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For us, it is always an exciting challenge to play teams we have never played before. We are using our resources to make sure we are up to date with how the teams are playing and what their rosters look like. Footage is always a great resource to utilize, which allows us to see what strategies teams are using and how we can effectively shut those strategies down. Playing three games in two days is tough, both physically and mentally, even with previous tournament experience. Which means that part of our training also includes effective mental training, so we can continue to push forward and always bring our strongest game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, in the time between your two fixtures, which teams are you most looking forward to watching?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering that all of the teams are ranked closely, I feel that none of the games should be missed! It'll be hard not to watch the games until the last minute, when we need to prepare for our own games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, we are definitely excited to see Paris play, since we will be playing them the next weekend. It will be a nice preview to what we can expect in our game against them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash will be held from the &lt;strong&gt;25th&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt; at Newcastle Roller Girls' regular venue, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Walker+Activity+Dome/@54.9687101,-1.558266,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487e7068944e76d1:0xe1a6394d9f25325!8m2!3d54.968707!4d-1.556072"&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Tickets and other information at the official website: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;http://www.euro-clash.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bear city roller derby</category><category>euroclash</category><category>interviews</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/21/euroclash-interviews-bear-city-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 10:19:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash 2017 - The Teams</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/12/euroclash-2017-the-teams/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;When Newcastle Roller Girls announced their intent to host a women's derby equivalent of the Men's European Cup (hosted by their sibling league, Tyne and Fear), there was understandable excitement... but the hosts have been remarkably secretive about the leagues involved, with the only hints being that the attendees were amongst the best teams in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Now, finally, the roster of competitors is announced, so we've made this quick guide to the teams (and will have individual features later on). EuroClash will be March 25th to 26th, at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Walker+Activity+Dome/@54.968707,-1.558266,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487e7068944e76d1:0xe1a6394d9f25325!8m2!3d54.968707!4d-1.556072"&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Newcastle. Tickets available &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.org.uk/buy-tickets/euroclash-2017"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-13774" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/euroclash.jpg" alt="euroclash" width="851" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, who are the teams competing in the first ever &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/365884340424845/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13711 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/newcastlerg_1.png" alt="newcastlerg_1" width="122" height="250"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Starting with the hosts, we have &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;. British Championships 2016 Premier Tier Winners, and currently ranked 76th by WFTDA (13th in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/europe"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and 13th by &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;*), the Canny Belters have had a strong 2016 - competing in the USA for the first time, at Beach Brawl in Florida (losing only to the mighty Rainy City) almost immediately after taking that British Championships win. In fact, the Belters have only lost to two teams in the last year - Rainy City and Edinburgh's Auld Reekie (who they also defeated in a rematch). As the hosts, home team advantage will also help their performance, and it would be a mistake to underestimate their chances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13716 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/leedsrollerderby-09.jpg" alt="leedsrollerderby-09" width="200" height="200"&gt;Staying within the UK, &lt;strong&gt;Leeds Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; are "technically" a new league, formed by merger of Hot Wheel Roller Derby and Leeds Roller Dolls at the end of 2016. Leeds Roller Dolls were ranked 65th by WFTDA, and their European Rankings were 23rd FTS, 22 SRD Rank; whilst Hot Wheel had Euro rankings of 31 and 25 respectively. We &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/19/by-their-powers-combined-they-are-leeds-roller-derby/"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on their merger at the time, and are excited to see what the combined pool of talent can accomplish in a single roster. Leeds Roller Dolls had their second trip to the USA in 2016, performing significantly above expectations; after placing solidly in the middle of the Champs Premier Tier rankings. Hot Wheel, by contrast, played their first European tournament in 2016, attending A Skate Odyssey, where they met surpassed expectations (beating their seeding by 4 places); they also managed to come second-from-top in British Champs Tier 2, clearly on the up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13765 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/mmr1.jpg" alt="mmr" width="222" height="200"&gt;Middlesbrough Milk Rollers&lt;/strong&gt; are possibly the highest ranked English team attending Euro Clash, with an impressive 56th position on the WFTDA rankings (9th in Europe by FTS, and 4th by SRD Rank)! MMR declined to participate in British Champs in 2016, but had an absolutely impressive year of competition, defeating almost all comers (including Connecticut and New Jersey) despite playing away for each and every bout. The only team to defeat them was London B, the Brawl Saints, which is not a bad record at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13730 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/central-city.png" alt="central-city" width="200" height="200"&gt;Central City Rollergirls&lt;/strong&gt; are the 83rd WFTDA ranked team (16th in Europe by SRD, and 20th by FTS), and one of the first Roller Derby leagues in the UK, representing Birmingham. CCR are the second team in this list to have spent their 2016 breaking into the USA via Beach Brawl, where they won more than they lost. They also defeated London B earlier on in the year, still a rare accomplishment for a UK team. The Birmingham team had quite a quiet year by comparison with the hectic adventures of some of the others in this list, and will have a lot of energy for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13735 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tigerbay.jpg" alt="tigerbay" width="200" height="183"&gt;Moving outside England, Wales' &lt;strong&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/strong&gt; are the best that their country has, ranked 75th by WFTDA (14th FTS, 12th SRD Rank in Europe). Declining to compete in British Champs in 2016, TBB instead competed against a wide range of European opponents, defeating London B, but narrowly failing against the mighty Rainy City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;After a lull in 2015, the general feeling is that Cardiff's all-stars have regained their best performance and are ready to go further in 2017; they're also a strong component of the current, and very strong, Welsh National Team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13740 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/arrg-logo.png" alt="arrg-logo" width="200" height="89"&gt;And representing the northern part of the UK, Edinburgh's &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; are the strongest team in Scotland, placing 60th in WFTDA (16th FTS, 20th SRD Rank in Europe). Auld Reekie made some waves last year by declining the offer to compete in WFTDA Playoffs, using the time to work more on their own performance - and they also declined British Champs 2016 as well. They did spend some time in the USA earlier in the year, competing at The Big O 2016, but had perhaps a more impressive start to 2016 where they defeated both our hosts Newcastle and Ireland's finest, Dublin. They'll be wanting to recapture that energy for the start of 2017... and will have a boost from their significant presence in the Team Scotland training squad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;For our remaining teams, we have to head outside the UK, so by distance, we first have...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13744 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/drd-logo.png" alt="drd-logo" width="200" height="213"&gt;...&lt;strong&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;, ranked 86th by WFTDA (but 11th in Europe by FTS and SRD Rank). Dublin have had a very exciting 2016, playing their first bouts in the USA at (yes!) Beach Brawl and winning against everyone except Newcastle Roller Girls! This performance didn't slow them down at all, as they also had one of the busiest schedules of 2016 as well, playing 15 bouts over the year, 10 of them away! With strong representation in Team Ireland, the Dublin team is definitely a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13749 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/paris.png" alt="paris" width="200" height="200"&gt;Moving a little further into Europe, &lt;strong&gt;Paris Rollergirls&lt;/strong&gt; are one of the two most exciting teams in France, ranked 71st by WFTDA, but 8th (or 9th) in Europe by FTS (SRD Rank). Hotly tipped for greatness in 2017 by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://thederbyapex.com/trending-french-roller-derby-56c5e691b036"&gt;The Derby Apex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the potential strength of Paris is also reflected in the performance of the French National Team, which they are a significant contributor to - Equipe de France is yet to lose a game with their current roster! Paris also burst onto the USA scene in 2016 at... (you've guessed it!) Beach Brawl, losing only the single bout. Much of the rest of their busy 2016 schedule was consumed by the French Nationale Elite Tier, which they topped, winning each and every bout in the 2015/6 season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13756 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/bcrd-bear-city-roller-derby_0.png" alt="bcrd-bear-city-roller-derby_0" width="200" height="200"&gt;From Berlin, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;Bear City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; are also one of the older teams in Europe, established back in 2008 . Ranked 50th by WFTDA (and 12th in Europe by FTS, 14th by SRD Rank), the Berlin Bombshells are the only team in this competition to have competed in WFTDA (Division 2) Playoffs in 2016, placing a strong 5th out of the 10 competitors, and defeating 4th seed Cincinnati on the way. In fact, Bear City spent more time competing in the USA than anywhere else in 2016, as the majority of their remaining bouts were at the Midwest BrewHaHa, with only two bouts in Europe (against Kallio Rolling Rainbow and Glasgow Roller Derby). Whilst Bear City the league also won the German Nationals (the Bundesliga), we believe this was strictly an exhibition team which differed from BCRD's normal A roster...
EuroClash sees the Bombshells return to Europe to take on the other rising stars of the continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;But that's not all, as we also have the excitement of a National Teams bout as well!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13777 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/ireland.jpg" alt="ireland" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13779 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/scotland.png" alt="scotland" width="200" height="200"&gt;Teams &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; met at the Road to TBC in Cardiff this November, with the Irish taking the win... but neither team had finalised their roster at that point. This rematch is taking place after final selections for Team Scotland [their selection bout is February 11th], and the Scots will be keen to show what they can do with the team that will be heading to the World Cup in Manchester. Meanwhile, Team Ireland were exceptionally green at the Road to TBC, and they will be that much more experienced as a squad by March...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We will be posting interviews with each of the teams competing at EuroClash over the next few weeks, to get into more depth about each of the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;* European rankings on SRD Rank computed from the set of all Women's Travel Teams in Europe known to the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bear city roller derby</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>euroclash</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>middlesbrough milk rollers</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>paris rollergirls</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/12/euroclash-2017-the-teams/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 19:15:31 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>