<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about beijing roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/beijing-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:03 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Beijing's Dragon Bootcamp - the start of an annual tradition!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/rollerderby-bei-2019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby in China, and Asia in general (outside of Japan) has always been a widely dispersed community, with initiatives like the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers helping to tie the region together, and share resources sustainably. However, there've been relatively few big "all-day all-round" bootcamps in the region, and, in particular, little for the officiating side of the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it was particularly exciting to hear that &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://beijingrollerderby.weebly.com/"&gt;Beijing Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; was hosting a 1-day multi-discipline bootcamp over the Dragon Boat Festival Weekend (8 June) this year. Skaters from all three Chinese-region leagues - Beijing, Shanghai and Hong Kong - were present, for the all day event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Flyer logo for the Beijing Dragon Bootcamp event." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/07/Beijingbootcamplogo.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to a few of the attendees for feedback on the event, which included everything from Skate maintenance and "what is Roller Derby", all the way through drills, communication skills, and a final modified-&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://rollaskateclub.com/short-track-roller-derby-resources/"&gt;Short Track&lt;/a&gt; rules scrimmage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read on for more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/rollerderby-bei-2019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (5 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>beijing roller derby</category><category>bootcamp</category><category>chinese roller derby</category><category>officiating</category><category>roller derby</category><category>short track roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/rollerderby-bei-2019/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 09:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tomodachi Derby Tournament - The Teams</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, the Asia-Pacific Region saw its first ever Roller Derby Tournament, hosted in Okinawa. Whilst the Japan Open was a huge success, the host leagues were keen to hold another one, with even more direct control from the leagues and skaters themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14076 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tomodachi.png" alt="tomodachi" width="400" height="400"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is the result - another two day tournament, now hosted by the new Japan Derby Tournament Committee, a collective of the involved Japanese leagues. As with the previous Tournament, the Tomodachi also serves a practical benefit to all the teams involved, giving somewhat geographically isolated teams a chance to play those from other areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be bringing you more info with interviews with the attending leagues in the run up to the event on the &lt;strong&gt;24th&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt;, (at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/%E6%B2%96%E7%B8%84%E7%9C%8C%E7%B7%8F%E5%90%88%E9%81%8B%E5%8B%95%E5%85%AC%E5%9C%92/@26.3099785,127.8141462,15.5z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x76c4ab9c228dd0cb!8m2!3d26.3107468!4d127.8213143"&gt;Okinawa Comprehensive Sport Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), but we're starting (as with EuroClash) with an overview of the competitors... (a timetable is available on our technical annex, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/tomodachi2017.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;WFTDA-Sanctioned Division&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14022" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/pacificrollerderby.png" alt="pacificrollerderby" width="200" height="200"&gt;Pacific Roller Derby&lt;/h3&gt;
Pacific Roller Derby are one of the oldest of the cluster of Hawaiian teams, dating from 2008, and a member of WFTDA since 2009! Due to the geographical factor, they mostly play the other Islands teams, especially at the yearly "Battle of the Islands" tournament. Based in the Islands' Capital, Honolulu, Pacific are currently 305th in the WFTDA Rankings (344th by FTS), partly, we suspect, simply due to not having had much opportunity to play non-Hawaiian teams. The Tomodachi will be their first fixtures against non-HI leagues since 2014!
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14024" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/fairbanks_rollergirls.png" alt="fairbanks_rollergirls" width="200" height="240"&gt;Fairbanks Rollergirls&lt;/h3&gt;
Hailing from their namesake in Alaska, Fairbanks Rollergirls are another member of the "Alaskan Derby" set alongside last year's Japan Open competitors, Juneau (who memorably attended with only 6 skaters!). A WFTDA member since 2011, the league has hosted the Alaskan "United We Roll" tournament for the last two years. We rate them at 1137th out of all teams (male and female, A and B) in the World which can be rated, whilst FTS places them 331st out of all WFTDA teams (a much smaller set).
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14034" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/devil_dog_300.png" alt="devil_dog_300" width="200" height="199"&gt;Devil Dog Derby Dames&lt;/h3&gt;
Local Okinawan Derby league, Devil Dog Derby Dames, (868th SRDRank), were a competitor at the Japan Open last year, although failed to defeat the non-Japanese teams in the WFTDA Division. (Their Home Team, competing in the Unsanctioned Division, defeated exhibition team Nippon Senbatsu.) The year before that, DDDD managed a win over fellow Okinawa league Kokeshi, which they'll be looking to repeat this time.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14036" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/kokeshi.png" alt="kokeshi" width="200" height="200"&gt;Kokeshi Roller Dolls&lt;/h3&gt;
The first league in Okinawa, Kokeshi Roller Dolls, (700th SRD Rank) were hosts of the Japan Open last year, as well as organising hosting for the Tomodachi Tournament as part of the Japan Roller Derby Tournament Committee. At the Japan Open, they took a win over Alaska's Juneau Roller Derby; we will see if they managed to repeat the feat against Fairbanks this time around.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14028" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tokyo.jpg" alt="tokyo" width="200" height="200"&gt;Tokyo Roller Girls&lt;/h3&gt;
The first league in "mainland" Japan, Tokyo Roller Girls, (745th SRD Rank) faired as well as the Devil Dog Derby Dames at the last tournament. However, they've had a busy home season since then, with all three of their home teams bouting each other, and recruitment has been strong. (TRG skaters have also been behind much of the activity of Women's Roller Derby Japan, the governing body for the Japanese Women's National Team, including their impressively active outreach in the last year.)
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Men's Division&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14032" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/grd_logo_cmyk.png" alt="grd_logo_cmyk" width="200" height="102"&gt;Glenmore Reservoir Dogs&lt;/h3&gt;
Hailing from Calgary, Canada, Glenmore Reservoir Dogs (Chinook City Men's Roller Derby) are the 17th ranked MRDA team in the world (65th SRD Rank), and are the men's component of Chinook City Roller Derby. Perhaps most recently known on the international stage as hosts of the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup, the league as a whole also regularly host the annual "Flat Track Fever" (women's derby) tournament. Last year, the Reservoir Dogs themselves competed at the Mayday Mayhem (Colorado) and the O-Town Throwdown (Ontario), taking second place at the former.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14038" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/japan-logo-232x300.jpg" alt="japan-logo-232x300" width="193" height="250"&gt;NinJapan Rollers&lt;/h3&gt;
The Japanese Men's National Team, and still the only Men's league in Japan, NinJapan Rollers have fairly frequently competed against the other Japanese teams (especially Tokyo), but have rarely had the chance to play non-National teams from other locations. In the 2016 MRDWC, NinJapan placed 17th, although their performance was very close to that of Puerto Rico, one place above them. The NinJapan Rollers have also (partly due to necessity) actively promoted Roller Derby throughout Japan, and have a comprehensive "off-season" training and recruitment system to build up their pool of skaters.
&lt;h2&gt;Unsanctioned Division&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14026" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/yokosuka.png" alt="yokosuka" width="200" height="189"&gt;Yokosuka Sushi Rollers&lt;/h3&gt;
A Tokyo Roller Girls "Home Team", this is the Sushi Rollers' first appearance as a travel team, let alone their first tournament. Based in and around United States Fleet Activities Yokosuka naval base, the Sushi Rollers were the founding team of Tokyo Roller Girls, and remain one of the strongest in intraleague contests. It remains to be seen how they will fare in their first bouts away from Honshu.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14040" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/pan-asian.jpg" alt="pan-asian" width="223" height="200"&gt;Pan-Asian Spring Rollers&lt;/h3&gt;
The Pan-Asian Spring Rollers are a collaboration between the other (non-Japanese) East Asian Roller Derby leagues, with members from Beijing Roller Derby, Shanghai Roller Girls, Hong Kong Roller Derby and Bangkok Roller Derby. Several of these leagues participated in the first ever Roller Derby bout in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; last year (hosted by Beijing), and so collaboration to attend the Tomodachi seems natural.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14030" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/teamwrdj-sm.jpg" alt="teamwrdj-sm" width="250" height="154"&gt;Team WRDJ&lt;/h3&gt;
Team "Women's Roller Derby Japan" is a the open-subscription exhibition team, run by the committee for . It comprises skaters from the Neon Roller Monsters (Tokyo Roller Girls' Japanese-nationals-team), Tokyo Three Rollers (Tokyo's Open-To-All/Coed Team), Kokeshi Roller Dolls, Devil Dog Derby Dames, and a single skater from Hawaii's Echo City Knockouts (of Kailua-Kona).&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>beijing roller derby</category><category>devil dog derby dames</category><category>fairbanks rollergirls</category><category>glenmore reservoir dogs</category><category>hong kong roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>kokeshi roller dolls</category><category>ninjapan rollers</category><category>pacific roller derby</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><category>shang-hai rollers</category><category>tokyo roller girls</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>women's roller derby japan</category><category>yokosuka sushi rollers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 08:05:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Beijing Roller Derby and UN break ground in China: Derby for equality with HeForShe Derby Invitational</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you thought that the Japan Open was the only exciting thing happening in Asia with Roller Derby, you were wrong.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="vertical-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/13/the-future-of-derby-china/brdlogo/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-4793"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4793 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/brdlogo.jpg?w=300" alt="BRDLogo" width="300" height="216"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="vertical-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/screen-shot-2016-03-31-at-08-37-09/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-6898"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-6898 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/screen-shot-2016-03-31-at-08-37-09.png?w=223" alt="HeForShe" width="223" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.beijingrollerderby.com/"&gt;Beijing Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; have been working on a project in collaboration with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.unwomen.org/"&gt;United Nations Women&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (the UN Entity responsible for Gender Equality and Empowerment of Women), and today they have announced it publicly.
&lt;p&gt;The "&lt;strong&gt;International HeForShe Roller Derby Invitational&lt;/strong&gt;" will be a co-ed tournament, featuring skaters from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://shanghairollerderby.tumblr.com/"&gt;Shanghai Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://bangkokrollerderby.weebly.com/"&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; as well as the hosts Beijing. Hosted in &lt;strong&gt;Ditan Olympic Park&lt;/strong&gt;, Beijing, from &lt;strong&gt;7pm&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;3rd of May&lt;/strong&gt;, the event will be the first ever Roller Derby tournament of any kind in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The event was first a dream to bring a team to Beijing so we could finally hold a bout or a scrimmage. Our teammate Sustainable Devilment saw something bigger. With the new domestic violence law in China and the HeforShe campaign, she felt derby was a great way to show a sport that encourages women empowerment" said Bejing Roller Derby's Jessica Jabbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event is being described as a 'scrimmage' and an 'informal tournament', which we take to mean that it is not being undertaken for ranking purposes. In fact, the purpose of this event is more serious than sporting rankings; as part of the UN Women's HeForShe campaign, the aim is to show solidarity between all sexes with women across the globe, by the symbolic means of a full-contact sport where women are the dominant force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby's Jean-Claude Von Slamme spoke to us about the event, saying:
"Our team is really excited to be a part of this event as it will be our first chance to meet with other roller derby teams and play a full game together. For some of our skaters it will be the first time they have ever played on a full sized track (ours is a little small) so the experience will be hugely beneficial to not only individual development but also in inspiring a new motivation and enthusiasm in our team by giving them a real taste of Roller Derby as a professional sport and as a worldwide community. We're extremely grateful to Beijing Roller Derby and UN Women for giving us this opportunity and working so hard to get us all there. They have been so supportive and I hope we can show our appreciation when we arrive by making this a really memorable event for everyone involved."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a draw from a high level Roller Derby perspective here, too: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gothamgirlsrollerderby.com/"&gt;Gotham Girls Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s &lt;em&gt;Sexy Slaydie&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Miss Tea Maven&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nyshockexchange.com/"&gt;New York Shock Exchange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s &lt;em&gt;Willverine,&lt;/em&gt; will be attending, providing a training bootcamp ahead of the tournament event itself! From Beijing Roller Derby's perspective, this is also a great opportunity to further increase the visibility of Roller Derby in China, an aim which they have been pursuing with some success over the past 3 years. (The topic of the promotion of Roller Derby in such contexts is something which is also close to this Blog's interests, and we will be following up on this with an article later in the year.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gotham's Miss Tea Maven was keen to emphasise the wider importance of the event's context. "Gender Equality is incredibly important for me.  As a self identified cis-gendered straight female, every single person should be able to self identify how they would like to.  I feel like parts of the world are taking great strides in moving forward with movements like 'HeForShe'  but there is still a lot of work to be done.  The recent North Carolina transgender bill is a very saddening example of this.  We as human beings need to support our fellow human beings, and make sure that rights are equal for everyone no matter how you identify or what your birth certificate says.  It shouldn't matter - you are a human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am beyond excited to help support this cause through my favorite medium - roller derby - and being able to go to China is just an amazing experience... I can't wait for the event to start!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the UN Women's HeForShe Campaign, go here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://heforshe.org"&gt;heforshe.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can watch the tournament itself live at: &lt;a href="http://lady.163.com/special/sense/heforshe2016.html"&gt;http://lady.163.com/special/sense/heforshe2016.html &lt;/a&gt;7:00pm Beijing time (&lt;strong&gt;midday&lt;/strong&gt;, UK time - although, actually, the bout is currently just being introduced at 1pm UK time...)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>beijing roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>shang-hai rollers</category><category>un</category><category>un women</category><category>united nations</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 07:26:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Future of Derby: China</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/13/the-future-of-derby-china/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Roller derby (and especially WFTDA-rules flat track derby) has been spreading across the world in recent years, as we’ve documented on this blog, via both &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/07/visualising-the-internationalisation-of-roller-derby-part-2-of-2-2011-to-present/"&gt;analytics&lt;/a&gt;, and our &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/tag/Future-Derby/"&gt;Future Derby&lt;/a&gt; series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One area that we have yet to cover is the substantially unrepresented region of Asia. While Japan has several active roller derby leagues, and their own &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/rdjapan"&gt;umbrella organisation&lt;/a&gt;, this is thanks substantially to the presence of American Forces Overseas, who form the nucleus of those leagues, importing Roller Derby directly from the USA. As active service people tend to stay in their placement for some time, leagues like &lt;a href="http://www.kokeshirollerdolls.com/"&gt;Kokeshi Roller Dolls&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.devildogderbydames.com/"&gt;Devil Dog Derby Dames&lt;/a&gt; have a somewhat reliable core of skaters who can develop and pass on skills, despite the only slowly increasing fraction of native Japanese skaters involved. In Japan, the existence of the local RollerGame spin-off of Roller Derby also helps awareness, especially for &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TokyoRollerGirls/info?tab=page_info"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other regions of Asia, the presence of Roller Derby is much sparser - there's no evidence of roller derby in India, or the south-Asian countries, and the Republic of Korea Roller Derby league seems to have vanished from the internet. In the most populous nation on Earth, however, Chinese Roller Derby is slowly starting to build up.
We talked to the three extant Roller Derby leagues in China - Shanghai Roller Derby's &lt;a href="http://shanghairollerderby.tumblr.com/"&gt;Shang-High Rollers&lt;/a&gt; (Founders &lt;em&gt;Afronaut&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Koko Kabama&lt;/em&gt;), the first league in China from 2012; &lt;a href="http://www.beijingrollerderby.com/"&gt;Beijing Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; (Founders &lt;em&gt;Hootin' Annie&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Jay&lt;/em&gt;, Coach and long-standing member &lt;em&gt;Courtney, &lt;/em&gt;who left BRD very recently, and PR head &lt;em&gt;Izzy Pop&lt;/em&gt;) and &lt;a href="http://www.hongkongrollerderby.com/"&gt;Hong Kong Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; (League founder and President &lt;em&gt;Alison "Six" Gentry&lt;/em&gt;); both founded in 2013.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/brdlogo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4793 size-thumbnail" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/brdlogo.jpg?w=150" alt="BRDLogo" width="150" height="108"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Beijing Roller Derby Logo (by Riley Clay and Nara Yu)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/srdlogo.png"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4794 size-full" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/srdlogo.png" alt="Shang-High Rollers Logo (by Ian Mintz)" width="128" height="128"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Shang-High Rollers Logo (by Ian Mintz)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/hkrdlogo.png"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4795 size-thumbnail" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/hkrdlogo.png?w=150" alt="Hong Kong Roller Derby Logo (by )" width="150" height="81"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Hong Kong Roller Derby Logo (by Pei-Jeane Chen)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
At present, all three leagues are mostly composed of American and European expats (Beijing even have a Scottish derby connection, via ex-Granite City skater Belledefluff).
Such a high expat ration causes problems with turnover, as expats are also often highly mobile.
BRD's &lt;em&gt;Hootin' Annie&lt;/em&gt; told us that the "challenge is retention. We are mainly made up of expats and just about the time a skater is trained enough to be able to bout, it’s time for them to move. We have become a sort of farm team. We train ‘em up and send them all over the world to join other leagues."
&lt;p&gt;Shanghai’s &lt;em&gt;Afronaut&lt;/em&gt; agrees: "Shanghai life is crazy! You don't come here to do normal life things usually, you come here to work  a lot or you come here to party a lot. Most foreigners here don't stay long in the city (average 1 year) so we teach them to skate and then they're gone. The upside to that is we have ex-SHR in quite a few teams around the world. BAD girls (USA), Guadalajara (Mexico), as well as all over Europe. It's amazing!"
And &lt;em&gt;Six&lt;/em&gt; expressed the same problem from Hong Kong, "It's been a struggle to say the least, as life in HK is busy, and a lot of people are coming and going. Most of the girls we get are expats, so they might stay for a year or two, and then head back home, but we do have a stable group of girls who've been showing up since the beginning".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4792 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/brdbout.jpg?w=614" alt="BRDBout" width="614" height="345"&gt; Beijing Roller Derby demonstration bout! (Credit: NetEase)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While all recognise the importance of recruiting a more stable base of Chinese skaters into their leagues, it's hard to promote the sport in a culture where roller derby isn't really known, as &lt;em&gt;Izzy Pop&lt;/em&gt; notes. You can literally translate 'roller derby' as '轮滑德比[lúnhuá débĭ]', but that doesn't really mean much in Chinese, and "轮滑阻拦赛[lúnhuá zŭlánsài], which is more descriptive of the sport, meaning literally 'roller skating blocking competition'. The problem is that people don't know what roller derby is, so if you say either term, they still don't really know what you're talking about."
HKRD's &lt;em&gt;Six&lt;/em&gt; agrees "when recruiting, we usually say [that derby] is along the lines of rugby on wheels", a description that is familiar from European roller derby recruiting 5 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without even a shared writing system (any European can at least read the words "Roller Derby", even if they don't speak English), it is that much harder to train and advertise the sport to Chinese nationals. Even the social networks are different to those in the West and need special attention: Beijing Roller Derby are "us[ing social networks] Douban, Weixin [Latin-script branded &lt;em&gt;WeChat&lt;/em&gt;] and Weibo to help us spread the word. We also have begun work on translating our league documents into Chinese. Next up will be translating our website and other roller derby resources." This includes translating the widespread derby-specific language ("arm whip", "booty block") into natural Chinese equivalents, and even working on a translation project for the WFTDA rules themselves!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese approach to outside internet resources also causes issues - this article itself suffered some delays due to blocking of Gmail and Facebook during the communication process with the teams - which also makes viewing derby streams difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as the language barrier, there are also cultural issues, as Shanghai’s &lt;em&gt;koko kabama&lt;/em&gt; noted "The expectations of women, made by their peers and themselves are vastly different- to be single beyond your mid 20s means you are on the shelf, the traditional way means women are desperate for security and a steady, life. They certainly don't strap on skates and play a full contact sport."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby has made progress in other places where the culture is not aligned with it - see the progress of the &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/19/the-future-of-derby-the-middle-east/"&gt;Middle-Eastern&lt;/a&gt; leagues - but it does make the process of recruitment also a process of cultural outreach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also not to say that Roller sports in general are unknown in China, but they tend towards less aggressive expression. Shanghai Rollers’ have been "skat[ing] at the local skate places like skate parks and open areas. That way we meet the Chinese national skaters and we have quite a few friends who are on national teams like slalom and figure skating. Those artistic individual skating sports are the only ones that are big here."
While some of the great American and European skaters currently come from established speed skating backgrounds, it's potentially the case that the artistic skating background of Chinese skating could bring entirely new expression to a native roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the existence of a Roller Sports community in China, kit is hard to acquire in brick-and-mortar shops. Shanghai Rollers advise newbie skaters to look on Taobao, the Chinese eBay equivalent, and Hong Kong Roller Derby told us that the need to buy online "can discourage a lot of interested skaters as they want to try skates/gear on before buying it." This is perhaps a problem which has existed in most regions where Roller Derby is not established; most of the European skate stores were founded by Skaters who also had this problem, and wanted to solve it directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these difficulties, all three leagues are growing and promoting, with Beijing and Hong Kong particularly active on Facebook at the moment. It will be difficult, perhaps, for derby to grow fast enough in China for a National Team (of Chinese nationals) to exist by the time of the next Roller Derby World Cups [2016 for Men, 2017? for Women], but that doesn’t mean that Chinese Roller Derby isn’t making moves to enter the international stage.
At the time of writing, Beijing is listed as a tentative attendee at the first ever Asia-Pacific Derby Tournament, the Japan Open Roller Derby Tournament in 2016. However, the recurring issues with expat skater retention have caused them to have to pull out of the competition at this time. A selection of Beijing Roller Derby's skaters will still be attending in a spectating capacity, and we can hope that their attendance helps to raise the consciousness of roller derby in Asia as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>beijing</category><category>beijing roller derby</category><category>china</category><category>future derby</category><category>hong kong</category><category>hong kong roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>shang-hai rollers</category><category>shanghai</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/13/the-future-of-derby-china/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 13:26:04 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>