<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about bonnie colliders)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/bonnie-colliders.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Dundee's call for skaters in double header event!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/16/dundees-call-for-skaters-in-double-header-event/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dundee is hosting a double header on the &lt;strong&gt;25th August &lt;/strong&gt;at the &lt;strong&gt;DISC in Dundee&lt;/strong&gt; with tickets sold on the door for &lt;strong&gt;£6!&lt;/strong&gt; There will also be a donation table for Dundee's local &lt;em&gt;WRASAC&lt;/em&gt;, looking for wellness packages donations and home goodies, as listed on their &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/191754218184900/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-27218 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/fbimage-01.png?w=212" alt="FBImage-01" width="262" height="371"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;12:3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0, &lt;/strong&gt;with the Bonnie Colliders taking on&lt;strong&gt; Mean City&lt;/strong&gt; first and the Silvery Tayzers taking on a mixed side of skaters from across the land!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to an unfortunate drop out of a previous opponent. The Silvery Tayzers have switched up the second game to a mixed side open to opt ins! DRD are still on the look out for skaters to play in this game, starting at &lt;strong&gt;3pm. &lt;/strong&gt;It is open to: WFTDA gender policy, ideally advanced, skaters and Dundee are offering hosting, if that is needed. If you would like to opt in for the game, all you need to do is email &lt;strong&gt;DundeeRollerDerby@gmail.com&lt;/strong&gt; with your details! The deadline for opt in to play is &lt;strong&gt;22/08&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/2018.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the run up to these fantastic games, we had a wee catch up with both Mean City and The Bonnie Colliders to see how the sides are shaping up!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;"Throughout our sessions we have remained focused on our skills and gameplay while having the best time with our fellow meanies. We look forward to the challenge, the team building and most importantly, skating on track with the Bonnie Colliders."&lt;strong&gt; - Megatron&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Mean City)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;"The Colliders are buzzed to be playing on their home turf! We have a strong team and have outlined strong focuses for each skater. New tactics for ourselves and new players coming into our team have us really excited for this game. Especially since we haven't had the chance to play the wonderful meanies yet!" &lt;strong&gt;- Tiny Tearaway&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Bonnie Colliders)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-27230" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/39127098_1349993311803752_1458506761269936128_n.jpg?w=300" alt="Mean City" width="300" height="200"&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;"..We are super excited in anticipation of our bout with the Bonnie Colliders on the 25th August.  It is sure to be an exciting game that is both challenging and exceptionally rewarding.  As a league we are keen to show everyone a good time while playing our beloved sport with some amazing skaters." - &lt;strong&gt;Magatron&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Mean City)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-27231 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/32915322_1821085297956877_529342680438669312_n.jpg?w=300" alt="32915322_1821085297956877_529342680438669312_n" width="300" height="225"&gt;"Playing with other local leagues is such a rewarding challenge, we've all seen each other play in open scrims and each others' games, and its really fun to have us all come together! The Colliders work hard as a team, and as part of the DRD. We all grow together, work together and have fun together! We can't wait to get on track!" - &lt;strong&gt;Tiny Tearaway&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Bonnie Colliders)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/191754218184900/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
Where: D.I.S.C.
When: Doors open 12:30&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>mean city</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/16/dundees-call-for-skaters-in-double-header-event/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 08:00:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City host Double Header</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/24/granite-city-host-double-header/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A double header to hit Granite City on the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28th of July&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;! The &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beach leisure centre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; of &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is home to Granite City Roller Derby's &lt;strong&gt;Fight Hawks&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Northern Fights&lt;/strong&gt;; both taking on tricky opponents in this derby day duo! &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doors open at 12:30&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; with the first whistle at 1pm, entry on the door for&lt;strong&gt; £4 (under 12's go free!).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27076" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/36548337_10157716666129012_6781758626013904896_o.jpg" alt="Granite City Roller Derby" width="2048" height="1153"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start off the day it's the battle of the B teams, with the &lt;em&gt;Fight Hawks&lt;/em&gt; taking on Dundee Roller Derby's &lt;em&gt;Bonnie Colliders&lt;/em&gt;! We caught up with the captains to see how they are preparing for the weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-27075 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/37395447_1902795173120396_2721404236385484800_n-e1532295713922.jpg?w=200" alt="Image courtesy: Len Rizzo" width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fight&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Hawks Captain&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Skeevy Wonder #64&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How long skating:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;4 and a half years apparently! Time flies.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How long captaining team:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;About 8 months&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the season been for your team so far?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We're only really just kicking into gear, but it's been great figuring out our team's strengths and helping build the confidence of our newer skaters. We had a great time in Portugal, where we may not have come back with any gold medals, but we came back with heaps of goals and ideas.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have you been preparing for the upcoming game:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Following on from those pointers from our tournament in Coimbra, we've been drilling our weaknesses and honing our strengths. Practice, practice, practice!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you find playing teams within Scotland, does it change your game prep playing such a geographically close league?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;As a team, the Hawks have played teams all over Scotland, a few in England, and even teams from Spain and Portugal. We haven't played the Colliders in a long time, but being closer to Dundee and knowing more of their skaters and their styles and preferences, we have a better idea of what kind of game we are going in to. As far as I'm concerned about geographical closeness, it means I can have a proper breakfast that's not from a service station and a bit of a lie in! Boost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything in particular you say to your team to get prepped for the game? Any words of wisdom?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;As a B team, we're here to learn constantly, and get as much from every game as possible. That doesn't mean we're not competitive however, it just means win or lose we're taking away valuable experiences.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonnie Colliders Captains&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; ALLY-J &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;#92 &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;amp; Tiny Tearaway #931&lt;img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-27090" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/37711946_10156238091771068_2068850209923792896_n.jpg?w=141" alt="37711946_10156238091771068_2068850209923792896_n" width="141" height="300"&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Long Skating:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; 3 years, 6 years respectively.
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long Captaining Team&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; our first year!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the season been for your team so far?:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; It’s been a really good start, our focus skating as a team has been awesome! We constantly strive to do our very best, even if we lose a game we can still be really proud of each others performance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How have you been preparing for the upcoming game?:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; We've been pushing ourselves a lot at training. Working alongside the Tayzers to increase our knowledge of the game and to build our skills. &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you find playing teams within Scotland, does it change your game prep playing such a geographically close league?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We've played further afield against Copenhagen which was many of the Colliders' first game outside Scotland. Playing teams closer to home is just as exciting. Seeing the talent that Scotland has is incredible and being able to play alongside these people makes it all worth it. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything in particular you say to your team to get the prepped for the game? Any words of wisdom?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Don’t let the other team get into our heads! That every single person has an amazing set of skills to use, and not to forget it!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this B-team-bust-up Granite's A team &lt;em&gt;The Northern Fights&lt;/em&gt; will be taking on &lt;em&gt;Vagine Regime UK, &lt;/em&gt;a team formed by a fully inclusive community of LGBTQIA+ individuals and their supporters across the UK. We put a few questions to each of the captains to understand the teams individual run ups to games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-27098" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/37753945_1909703029096277_5673277440076546048_n.jpg?w=300" alt="Image Courtesy: Len Rizzo" width="300" height="199"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Northern Fights Captain:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Lizzee Rascal #314&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How Long Captaining?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;First year
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Long Skating?: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;5 Years&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the season been for your team so far?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;This season has been great so far. We had quite a change in the team at the beginning of the year and sadly said goodbye to old friends and welcomed some new ones. We have been focusing on British Champs, where we've been competing in Tier 3 North. It has been a fantastic challenge for us and has really pushed us to train hard. We have finished second in our tier and I couldn’t be prouder of the Fights.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have you been preparing for the upcoming game?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We've been focusing on developing and building as a team for champs throughout 2018. The upcoming game, being an exhibition game, will be a refreshing change from this, with a lot of the pressure of champs being taken off. We have still been training hard and want to bring our best game at the weekend.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you find playing teams such as VR? Does it change your strategy or prep at all?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Playing against VR is a different experience for us, as they bring a pool of talent from across the UK and will perhaps use tactics that we haven’t been up against before which will make for a challenging yet fun game.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vagine Regime captain:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Kami-Tazzy #360&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-27096 alignright" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/37825317_1875280102519140_1499359558181584896_n.jpg?w=200" alt="Image Courtesy: Nick" width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How Long Skating:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; 7. 5 years&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How long Captaining:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;First time for VR.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the season been for your team so far, do rosters change a lot?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It's been great so far. Back in April we had a tough but close game with the Rainy City C team, a great game to kick off the season with. We're really looking forward to playing Granite's awesome Northern Fights. VR UK contain a very large number of members, of all levels, from all over the UK, including some of the best players the UK can offer. Because of that, rosters are always changing, but it mainly depends on location, bout clashes, level and availability.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you prepare your skaters for upcoming games?:&lt;/strong&gt; S&lt;em&gt;ince skaters are generally from different leagues/teams it's difficult to prepare physically. Therefore communication and trust is key here. We'll have discussions on positions, and other strengths that everyone can bring. This will help the captains, LUM and Bench to come up with line up plans and strategies to fully challenge our opponents. It's certainly a bonus to have skaters on the team that have played together before, but things still may get shuffled around on the day to maximise our full potential.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How do you find putting together a mixed team to play established leagues, is there anything in particular you look for in skaters?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Depending on availability, we try to put together a strong as possible team to challenge our competitors to the max. We try to get the right mix of skaters of every position. However this is not possible at all times, we have had jammer heavy rosters in the past or vice versa. This is not really a problem, as a lot of the players are very adaptable and give it thier absolute all. We may be a challenge team but we're still a competitive team who like to rise to the challenge and aim to triumph in every game that we play.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything in particular you say to your team to get them prepped for the game? Any words of wisdom?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I ask them to bring all their focus, good sportsmanship and determination on and off the track. Additionally teamwork, integrity and to set individual as well as team goals. This sport is brilliant but it can also be mentally tough at times. One main advice I give to a lot of people is that if things don't go as planned in a jam, I encourage them to put it behind them, store it away if needed, reset and focus on the next jam. Also most importantly enjoy yourselves and embrace all the achievements, no matter how small or big they are.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;Event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/235019877294396/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;
Date: 28/07/2018
Price: £4 on the door&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was co-written by Dundee's correspondent G. Patterson and Granite's Correspondent C. Meikle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2018 season</category><category>a chat with...</category><category>aberdeen</category><category>articles</category><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>up coming games</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>vagine regime uk</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/24/granite-city-host-double-header/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:45:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>DRG's Bonnie Colliders Battle Bairn!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/18/drgs-bonnie-colliders-battle-bairn/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller girls' are hosting their second home game this season as a single header! On the &lt;strong&gt;22nd of July &lt;/strong&gt;at the &lt;strong&gt;D.I.S.C.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Dundee&lt;/strong&gt;, the Bonnie Colliders are taking on Bairn City (&amp;amp; pals!) which looks to be a mighty match! With doors opening at &lt;strong&gt;12:30 &lt;/strong&gt;and first whistle coming in at &lt;strong&gt;1pm,&lt;/strong&gt; it's gonna be a short and sweet single header. Differing from DRG's usual doubles hitters,  these two familiar sides will most certainly make the trip worth while!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-22412 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/19621172_1505774156154661_5391157900722134871_o.jpg" alt="Photo Courtesy: Laura MacDonald" width="520" height="736"&gt;
We thought we would catch up with the Bonnie Colliders Co Captains for 2017, &lt;strong&gt;Breezy Does It #289&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;HullabaLou #17&lt;/strong&gt;, to learn a bit more about leading and shaping a B team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="22420,22421" type="circle" columns="2"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q1: How has the season gone so far for you guys? You've have a few games already and you seem to come out strong both sides.
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breezy:  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;This season has been amazing so far, we've played those two games and won both, which is super exciting! The team is really starting to gel together and we are getting better every time we play. We've had a few newer skaters join us and they are coming on great and are fitting in well with the team.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HullabaLou: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's just been so epic this season, I am so so proud of everyone! To see our wee team taking the skills that we drill together every week at training and scrims, and put them into practice during games is fantastic – whether it’s fancy new toe stop spins, some super controlled one-one blocking or crushing offense; the commitment and effort from every person on the team is something that I respect hugely and do not take for granted as a Captain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q2: And so the Colliders have played a Bairn side a few times, with the most recent in 2015 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/71209" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;[FTS]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;. How does that change your look on this match-up?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I was off on maternity for all of 2015 so unfortunately wasn't part of the team on that one but I was there for the previous year and it was such a tough game! Bairn have continued to grow so much since then, really we're looking at them as a brand new opponent. Which for a lot of our Colliders this season - they will be!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The 2015 game&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; was one of the firsts for quite a few of us who had just been rostered for the B team, and was definitely quite an experience for us haha! Bairn are so lovely and we genuinely can’t wait to play them again, but will definitely be needing as many of our Collidoscopes (our loyal fans) to support us as possible!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q3: How do you guys approach a game when you are captaining, what goes through your mind?
&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;B:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I approach all games in a similar manner, nervous anticipation! The difference as a Co-Captain is that I like to check in with all the skaters to find out how they're feeling, as Lou and I want each skater to enjoy themselves and feel comfortable on game day. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ll we want as Captains is to ensure our team has an absolute blast on game day, I just want to help them smash their goals and whip out those hard-practiced skills! Colliders are definitely all about soaking up the sheer enjoyment of simply playing roller derby together! To quote our wonderful co-chair Milky “It’s just a made-up game on roller skates” and so I try to focus on that…we are from Fundee after all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q4: With the Silvery Tayzers (Dundee's A team) getting quite a lot of focus now with the league being full WFTDA members, do you feel that adds more pressure for you guys, or is it the opposite and you loose some track time as a B team?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DRG train as a league, first and foremost. We all skate together. We have skaters who've just passed their minimum skills alongside our Team Scotland skaters. It is a huge benefit to all our skaters as we work together to push each other on in every aspect. As a team, the Colliders do get lots of track time together to work as a unit, and practice our tactics and skills, but training alongside the Silvery Tayzers really pushes us out of our comfort zones and helps us develop further. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DRG definitely think of ourselves as a league rather than 2 teams – we train together, scrim together and thoroughly support each other; the success of the Tayzers and their sweeeeet wftda ranking (266th!)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;[16/07/2017 FTS]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; has only boosted our league spirit. And likewise when the Colliders smash it, the mad support from the rest of the league is just unparalleled. Personally, that’s one of the things I love most about DRG: Our wonderful bouting committee have always placed an equal importance on getting games for both Colliders and Tayzers….so short answer – no, we never lose track time!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q5: With that in mind, what do you guys aim for, for yourselves and your team? It must be hard to maintain such a close-knit team, with skaters moving on to the A team or with the new intake coming up.
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; My aim is to work alongside all of our current skaters and those moving up from the new skater programme to encourage them to practice in the hopes that our team can grow stronger. As for keeping the team close knit, I think that comes from our training atmosphere. Lou and I are very open in terms of communication and encourage skaters to bring any issues to us in the hopes that everyone feels driven but not pushed, as being a Collider is always about having the best experience possible and taking away as much as you can from both training, scrimmage and game days!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I think that as a team we definitely drive ourselves forward and regardless of experience-level our training committee has always worked us hard to constantly improve our play. Being a B team, the roster is a lot more dynamic; newer skaters come up, more experienced skaters move to the A team, and it changes a lot. We do actively focus on learning how each other blocks/jams so can we gel on track but because we all train together, even when a skater does reach a certain level experience and makes that tough decision to bout exclusively with the A team, it doesn’t really feel like we’ve lost them because we'll be drilling/scrimming with them the week after anyways. Saying that we did have a very emotional locker-room-team-cry after a speech from last season’s stepping down Captains… but I think that just goes to show how much we bond as a team…or perhaps how emotionally unstable a bunch of us are…possibly both.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out more about the upcoming game (&lt;strong&gt;Saturday 22nd July&lt;/strong&gt;) Check out the facebook event page here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/146108915947622/?acontext=%7B%22source%22%3A5%2C%22page_id_source%22%3A133126163419474%2C%22action_history%22%3A%5B%7B%22surface%22%3A%22page%22%2C%22mechanism%22%3A%22main_list%22%2C%22extra_data%22%3A%22%7B%5C%22page_id%5C%22%3A133126163419474%2C%5C%22tour_id%5C%22%3Anull%7D%22%7D%5D%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Colliders vs Bairn and pals!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open: &lt;strong&gt;12:30
&lt;/strong&gt;Tickets: &lt;strong&gt;£5 (on the door)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>captains</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/18/drgs-bonnie-colliders-battle-bairn/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 08:30:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A chat with... Bonnie Colliders Captains Khilleesi and G-Wrecks</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/16/a-chat-with-bonnie-colliders-captains-khilleesi-and-g-wrecks/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So... Dundee's B Team, the Bonnie Colliders, have had a pretty exciting year to date, which is about to get only more exciting with their first appearance in tournament - Auld Reekie's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/535844416618826/"&gt;ARRGmageddon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the weekend of the &lt;strong&gt;26th November&lt;/strong&gt;.
We had a chat with Bonnie Colliders Co-Captains Khilleesi and G-Wrecks about the upcoming challenge - and also Dundee A's upcoming trip to Tenerife in December (as both skaters are also on the A roster).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be able to listen along here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[soundcloud url="https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/293033096" params="auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true" width="100%" height="450" iframe="true" /]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>arrgmageddon</category><category>articles</category><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby tenerife</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/16/a-chat-with-bonnie-colliders-captains-khilleesi-and-g-wrecks/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 11:51:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rising Stars and Bs at Aberdeen!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/05/rising-stars-and-bs-at-aberdeen/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Granite City Roller Derby's Northern Fights have been a little distracted by British Champs in the first half of this year, leaving GCRD B, the Fight Hawks to play their home games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7236" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/4627878756.jpg" alt="4627878756" width="757" height="1069"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.granitecityrollerderby.co.uk/blog/4584694771"&gt;This weekend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; sees the trend for Scottish Double Headers with Rising Stars bouts continue as Aberdeen's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Beach+Leisure+Centre/@57.155602,-2.082094,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48840e4028217933:0x30c6b9176815da5b!8m2!3d57.155602!4d-2.0799"&gt;Beach Leisure Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; hosts the Fight Hawks taking on Dundee's B team, the Bonnie Colliders, introduced by two teams of newer skaters from around the country demonstrating their talent (and getting experience to boot).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With doors opening at &lt;strong&gt;12:30pm, May 7th&lt;/strong&gt;, this is an ideal opportunity to see these skaters, many of whom are from the several new Scottish leagues which are still working towards their first bouts, on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second bout is an unpredictable&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt; match up between Scotland's newer B teams, which should be an unmissable event. Both the Bonnie Colliders and the Fight Hawks have been working hard to develop themselves over the past year, and, while the Fight Hawks are probably the underdogs, the home team advantage could well give them the edge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that isn't enough incentive, the refreshment stall will be raising money for&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.justgiving.com/fundraising/ChristophersCLANChallenge"&gt; Christopher's CLAN Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a 12 month fundraising effort to raise £20k for teenagers and their families affected by cancer in the NE of Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always with GCRD's home games, entry is completely &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;literally, FlatTrackStats can't compare the teams, and has incomplete entries for GCRD B!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>gcrd</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>rising stars</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/05/rising-stars-and-bs-at-aberdeen/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 11:29:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls WarriARRGs take on Dundee's Bonnie Colliders</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/04/auld-reekie-roller-girls-warriarrgs-take-on-dundees-bonnie-colliders/</link><dc:creator>kirstynsmith</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a battle royale as new Auld Reekie Roller Girls team the WarriARRGs take on Dundee's Bonnie Colliders this &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="aBn"&gt;&lt;span class="aQJ"&gt;Sunday May 8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7211" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/warriarrgs1.jpg" alt="WarriARRGs1" width="960" height="640"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photograph courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two east-coast teams will lock horns in an explosive game of roller derby, as the WarriARRGs showcase the latest line-up of what will be an ever-evolving squad.&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the decision for ARRG to add a permanent ad-hoc team, WarriARRGs captain Cirque du Slay said:&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are a large and dynamic league and it is important for us to provide opportunities for all of our members to play games against outside teams, in front of an audience, to feel part of a team and to work with new people.&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“WarriARRGs will allow different groups of skaters to develop in a huge variety of ways which will help our league as a whole to get bigger and better all the time.”&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7212" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/warriarrg2.jpg" alt="WarriARRG2" width="960" height="640"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photograph courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cirque said her main focus for the team was to get a sense of team bonding and thrill the audience.&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said: “I'd like for us to learn to work together and try out our skills against an external team who train together and use tactics we're not used to.&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I'd also like for us to go on track trusting our teammates and knowing they trust us and to have fun.&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I'd like the audience to cheer themselves hoarse watching some cracking roller derby played by two teams of skaters who are on their way up.”&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is open to league members and their families and friends, who will gather at Jack Kane Sports Centre on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="aBn"&gt;&lt;span class="aQJ"&gt;Sunday May 8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to watch the WarriARRGs skaters fight their derby debut.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>warriarrgs</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/04/auld-reekie-roller-girls-warriarrgs-take-on-dundees-bonnie-colliders/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 16:20:05 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>