<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about bout reports)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/bout-reports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 08:59:33 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Guest Post: Roller Derby — Bangkok Style!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/22/guest-post-roller-derby-bangkok-style/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In another guest post, we're bringing you a report on Bangkok Roller Derby's recent bout against Pan-Asian travel team, the Spring Rollers, by Mouth Almighty; Mouth recently moved to Bangkok (after being deeply involved in UK derby), and this was her first experience of the East-Asian implementation of the sport. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, 2 weeks ago I moved from the UK to Bangkok as part of a change of employment. As a former skater with Wolverhampton Honor Rollers and  a former director of UKRDA (United Kingdom Roller Derby Association) back in Britain, I was eager to see what Roller Derby in Bangkok had to offer. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As luck would have it, within my first week of moving to Thailand, Bangkok Roller Derby were hosting an event: "Monsoon Mayhem".&lt;br&gt; So, at 7pm on Saturday 17th of November, I had my very first taste of Roller Derby, Bangkok-style. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Most Roller Derby bouts or events in the UK tend to be set in the morning or mid afternoon, in a local leisure centre or school (or whatever venue a team can manage to find that is big enough to host a game and is willing to allow teams to actually skate).&lt;br&gt;Here, Bangkok Roller Derby have the luxury of an actual Roller Dome and an evening start time (I can see why, as it had been 34°C most of the day, with a huge rainstorm in the afternoon, so the humidity factor meant that it was still about 30 degrees at 7pm). &lt;br&gt;These factors put together surely helped bring what was very close to a capacity crowd to this event, something that I fear very few Roller Derby teams in the UK have the joy of seeing at their events. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby versus Pan-Asian Spring Rollers&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:heading --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27781} --&gt;

&lt;figure class="wp-block-image"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/11/bangkok-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-27781"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/gjsheehan"&gt;Gareth Sheehan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gameplay itself was fast paced and aggressive, not violent, simply aggressive, passionate gameplay. The  girls on track seemed to truly enjoy the fun, frantic pace of the game, as did the people watching it.&lt;br&gt;An injury early on in the first half bought to my attention that first aid here in Bangkok is not at the same level as bouts in the UK. (However, this was a friendly game). A single first-aider dealt with the injured player before she was eventually taken off the track in a wheelchair (temporary, I’m sure!) to rapturous applause from both players and spectators.&lt;br&gt;The game continued at a fast pace, with fast jams but with relatively low scoring from both teams; some heavy blocks and hits but thankfully no more injuries.&lt;br&gt;The second half continued at the same frantic pace, some very fast jammers up against some skilled blocking on both teams. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Noticeable differences between UK and Bangkok Roller Derby included less referees and NSOs (this may have been due to lack of volunteers perhaps &lt;em&gt;[something which affects Roller Derby everywhere - Ed])&lt;/em&gt; but as Bangkok Roller Derby grows, and as roller derby in Asia grows in general, this will surely stop being the case. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27782} --&gt;

&lt;figure class="wp-block-image"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/11/bangkok-2.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-27782"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/gjsheehan"&gt;Gareth Sheehan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Announcing was minimal, but with a team made up of English, American, Canadian, French &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Thai players, and with a truly multicultural audience watching, perhaps announcing would have simply been lost in translation... &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also no music playing during the game, something that as a follower of UK roller derby I have become used to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing Bangkok Roller Derby did that is not the norm in UK (although is becoming more common for the big tournaments) is half time entertainment: three inline skaters (one in a dinosaur costume) dancing and doing tricks, followed by throwing cuddly toys out into the crowd, which the audience loved. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; The game finished and it was evident that the players on track, the spectators and everyone involved had enjoyed a great evening of roller derby&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:separator --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator"&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:separator --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby can be found here: &lt;a href="https://bangkokrollerderby.weebly.com/"&gt;https://bangkokrollerderby.weebly.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Their opponents, the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers, are a travel team composed of members of Beijing Roller Derby, Shanghai Roller Derby, Hong Kong Roller Derby and Bangkok Roller Derby (but are open to other Asian teams). They can be found here: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Pan-Asian-Spring-Rollers-448887468791803/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/Pan-Asian-Spring-Rollers-448887468791803/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>bout reports</category><category>guest posts</category><category>international derby</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/22/guest-post-roller-derby-bangkok-style/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 14:04:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ViQueens' Victorious Valhalla: a test for PivotStar rules.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/05/21/viqueens-victorious-valhalla-a-test-for-pivotstar-rules/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tournaments have always been a popular thing in Roller Derby, and as the community both grows and becomes more concerned with cost- and time-efficiency, this is only becoming more true. However, with a standard WFTDA-rules bout needing at least 90 minutes (and preferably 2 hours) blocked in for it, and around 14+ officials if fully-staffed, hosting large numbers of teams can be tricky, especially if you want a tournament structure capable of providing a "winner".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, there's a huge number of alternative rules for shorter game formats, thus allowing more games per day, and more teams per tournament: from the 2 minute games of Sur5al, through 21 minute Derby Sevens [both with reduced rosters too], through various ad-hoc 30, 40 and 45 minute modifications of the rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few of the above bout systems change much about the rules of the game beyond timing (and sometimes roster restrictions) - they all take the same number of officials as WFTDA standard games.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Victory or Valhalla&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-26720" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/05/screen-shot-2018-05-17-at-12-05-06.png" alt="Screen Shot 2018-05-17 at 12.05.06" width="801" height="792"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/waterfordcityviqueens/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Waterford City Viqueens&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Waterford's oldest Roller Derby league, wanted to promote Roller Derby in their city (and in Ireland) by hosting a 6 team tournament, with teams from across Eire and beyond. For a small league; in this case, just 25 members; hosting a 10 game tournament is challenging not just in terms of time, but also officiating resources. As Macks, for the Viqueens notes, "As Ireland is so small (in general, not just in derby land) securing officials was one of the toughest aspects of organising the tournament, we all know that without them...... THERE IS NO DERBY!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was also the Viqueens' first event on this scale, so they also had to work on solving all of the large tournament problems - food, water, changing rooms, scheduling and so on - for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To cope with these additional pressures, the league decided to make a more radical choice of ruleset: adopting the &lt;strong&gt;2017 PivotStar Rules&lt;/strong&gt;. To the best of our knowledge, Victory or Valhalla is the first tournament outside of North America where the PivotStar rules have been applied.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;PivotStar Rules&lt;/h4&gt;
The "PivotStar Rules" originated at the 2017 edition of &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/265489690551917/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best of the West&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a Canadian tournament. Tournament sponsors and co-organisers, PivotStar, wanted to provide a more competitive format for large-scale contests, whilst &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; reducing the amount of overhead needed for officials.
PivotStar owner, Luludemon, has explained the reasoning behind the design in more detail on her blog here: [&lt;a href="https://pivotstar.com/best-of-the-west-roller-derby-tournament/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LINK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;].
&lt;p&gt;The executive summary of &lt;strong&gt;changes&lt;/strong&gt; [and reasoning] might look something like:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20 minute games / no timeouts&lt;/strong&gt; [reduced time / more games]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 point per &lt;em&gt;pass&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [reduces load on officials/reduces need for jam referees, reduces "lead jammer advantage"]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Track cuts relative to track, not opposing players&lt;/strong&gt; [reduces load on officials, keeps game moving forwards]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
The reduction of effort provided by the latter two rules changes also allows a reduced number of referees and NSOs: PivotStar suggest having only only &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt; referees total per game (two inside and two outside), plus a single "score tracking NSO" to indicate when either jammer has completed a pass, and reduced NSOs in other positions. In testing, Waterford Viqueens determined that they needed a few more officials to help things move smoothly, so their setup assigned two score tracking NSOs (one per team) and an additional NSO for the penalty box timers, for a total of just&lt;em&gt; 11&lt;/em&gt; officials for each game!
&lt;p&gt;The tournament itself, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/339727839871496/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Victory or Valhalla&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, was organised as 2 group stages (of three teams each, unseeded), into placement bouts - a single 5th place bout for the lowest teams in each group, and a 4 team single elimination for the top 2 in each group. This gave every team a minimum of 3 games, and a maximum of 4 (for the finalists).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;
An obvious effect of the 1 point per pass rule is that scores are a quarter to a fifth as high as equivalent scores from WFTDA rules games of the same duration, as you can see below (Limerick forfeited the final against Belfast, so a bonus game was played between 3rd place (on points) Angoulême and Belfast):
&lt;table style="border:0;"&gt;&lt;colgroup&gt; &lt;col&gt; &lt;col style="width:2.3em;"&gt; &lt;col style="width:1em;"&gt; &lt;col style="width:2.3em;"&gt; &lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr style="background:pink;"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Belfast Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:right;"&gt;Cork City Firebirds&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background:lightgreen;"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Brain Damage Angoulême&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:right;"&gt;Waterford City Viqueens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background:pink;"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Limerick Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:right;"&gt;Belfast Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background:lightgreen;"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;East Coast Cyclones&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:right;"&gt;Brain Damage Angoulême&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background:pink;"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cork City Firebirds&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:right;"&gt;Limerick Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background:lightgreen;"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Waterford City Viqueens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;22&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:right;"&gt;East Coast Cyclones&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background:lightblue;"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cork City Firebirds&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:right;"&gt;East Coast Cyclones&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background:paleturquoise;"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Brain Damage Angoulême&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:right;"&gt;Limerick Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background:paleturquoise;"&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:left;"&gt;Belfast Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:right;"&gt;Waterford City Viqueens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Brain Damage Angoulême&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:right;"&gt;Belfast Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; &lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-26718" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/05/screen-shot-2018-05-16-at-16-49-44.png" alt="Screen Shot 2018-05-16 at 16.49.44" width="1021" height="764"&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Final standing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1st&lt;/strong&gt; Belfast RD
2nd Limerick RD [forfeit]
3rd Brain Damage Angoulême
4th Waterford Viqueens
5th Cork City Firebirds
6th East Coast Cyclones (Wicklow)
&lt;p&gt;(Other than Belfast topping Limerick (due to Limerick forfeiting), this reproduces the FTS European rankings of the teams competing: these results are not in FTS as yet, as they're non-standard ruleset.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
Any tournament which runs on time and has no major issues is a successful tournament... but how did the attendees react to the new format for Victory or Valhalla?
&lt;p&gt;Waterford City Viqueens performed a survey of attendees to measure just that, and have generously shared a summary of the results with us, on which we base this part of the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with all surveys of a population, there are conflicting opinions, with some people praising aspects which others disliked (for example, the summary highlights responses complaining that 20 minute games were a little short, alongside several responses lauding the short games for allowing so many games to be packed into a single day tournament). On a purely qualitative measure, then, response to the PivotStar format might be considered mixed, as skaters mentioning it were either confused by the rules, or, conversely, found them simpler.
(By contrast, officials only &lt;em&gt;positively&lt;/em&gt; mentioned the rules being simpler + more predictable, with complaints more towards the reduction in the number of officials on track.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a more quantitative measure, though, the feeling is &lt;em&gt;unambiguously&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;positive&lt;/em&gt;. Given the chance to rate various aspects of the tournament on a 5 point scale, every single aspect received a mean and median rating between 5 and 4; and no aspect had any 0 ratings at all.
Most promisingly, 100% of responding Skaters and Officials both found the tournament "worthwhile" and said that they would recommend it to others. The Viqueens pulled out a particularly positive quote from one (anonymous) respondent: "Seriously this was a fantastic event and should be a yearly thing. Like an Irish roller con: ye should be really proud of yourselves for pulling it off so well!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26728 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/05/screen-shot-2018-05-18-at-10-21-36.png" alt="Screen Shot 2018-05-18 at 10.21.36" width="540" height="614"&gt; Survey data collated by Waterford Viqueens, made available to us on request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting aspect emerging from the more detailed questions was the not inconsiderable number of officials interested in the tournament primarily &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; of the different ruleset.  22% of officials (compared to 11% of skaters) chose this as their reason, when only allowed to pick a single response. (The majority of skaters prized the ability to compete in multiple games as their reason, 73% of skaters saying so; officials were more split, with no really clear majority out of "location", "multiple games" and "rule set".)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Viqueens' part, the event was an overall success, both in terms of organisation: "The schedule was reliable and well kept to; we went over time a little before lunch, but the break allowed us to catch up", and in terms of the social effect; "The amount of derby teams was great: people got to meet different teams and play teams they hadn't played before [which] created a great sense of community".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The league, of course, pay tribute to all those necessary for the event to exist, noting that "The announcers were fantastic, [and] the Refs and NSOs did a great job and helped everything run super smoothly".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, media seems to have been the only thing that could be improved, with a Tournament Group Photo one of the things that the league would like to ensure happens next time. (We'd also recommend a group photo for the officials, the announcers, and the volunteers, as well!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd love to see more tests of the PivotStar Rules elsewhere (with the permission of PivotStar, of course - although we know Luludemon is personally excited to see people using the ruleset in general, it's always nice to ask); and we look forward to more tournaments from Waterford Viqueens in future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bout reports</category><category>competition</category><category>international derby</category><category>irish roller derby</category><category>pivotstar rules</category><category>review</category><category>surveys</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>waterford viqueens</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/05/21/viqueens-victorious-valhalla-a-test-for-pivotstar-rules/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 08:30:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>International and National Derby for Easter: The Review</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/27/international-and-national-derby-for-easter-the-review/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend saw two big Roller Derby Events - one internationally important, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/808335735910721/"&gt;Japan Open Roller Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt; in Okinawa&lt;/strong&gt;, and one nationally significant, a triple-header fixture for the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/events-calendar/2016/1/9/british-championships-triple-header"&gt;British Championships Premier Tier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Glasgow. Due to the time difference between Japan and the UK, as the first was just finishing, the second was almost about to start, so if you weren't planning on sleeping for 17 hours, you could have spent all that time continuously experiencing roller derby!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll start with the International event in this review (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/27/international-and-national-derby-for-easter-the-review/2/"&gt;you can skip to Glasgow by clicking here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we reported in our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/"&gt;preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Japan Open Roller Derby Tournament&lt;/em&gt; was an important first for Asia-Pacific Roller Derby, bringing together teams from Australia, New Zealand, Japan, Alaska and Denmark in a two day derby event hosted by Kokeshi Roller Dolls.  Our timezone-adjusted and localised &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/11/the-japan-open-schedule-timezones/"&gt;Viewing Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; now contains specific links to each bout in the video feed, so you can jump to any particular game just by clicking on the relevant YouTube link. The Viewing Guide also contains all of the scores for all bouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's fair to say that, in general, the tournament went as expected, with respect to game predictions. Adelaide Roller Derby, coming in as the expected winners by FTS rating, were awarded the Tournament Championship for the A (WFTDA Sanctioned) Tier, having defeated all three Japan-based leagues (Tokyo, Kokeshi and Devil Dog) by considerable margins.
Copenhagen, who were also expected to have done well, exceeded expectations, both in terms of their win margins against the Japan-based teams, but also against Adelaide themselves. This latter bout was a last minute addition to the schedule, but was fast-tracked for WFTDA Sanctioning, and will count for Copenhagen's ranking. As the Danish team defeated Adelaide, who reside at a much higher WFTDA rank in the current rankings, we expect Copenhagen to shoot up the tables - their FTS rating has already shifted by more than 100 points as a result of their performance at the Open!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of the other teams, perhaps the most impressive single performance in terms of endurance was that of Alaska's Juneau Rollergirls, who brought only a roster of 6 skaters to compete. Despite this significant disadvantage, they won their first two bouts (against Devil Dog Derby Dames, and Tokyo Roller Girls) convincingly, only faltering due to fatigue in their final game against hosts Kokeshi Roller Dolls. While Juneau have lost FTS rating "on paper" on their performance, it's clear that their actual ability as a team is significant, and they are underranked and underrated by WFTDA and FTS currently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the B-tier, it was New Zealand's Pirate City Rollers who topped the board, with their B-team, the Broadside Brawlers, defeating both the Japan Roller Derby Association's exhibition team, Nippon Senbatsu; and Misawa Killa Geishas by very comfortable win ratios. Given that this was the Brawlers' first ever international derby, their performance was especially impressive. The win against Misawa also gives the New Zealand B-team a more solid FTS rating for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Japan-based teams - Okinawa's Kokeshi Roller Dolls and Devil Dog Derby Dames, Tokyo's Tokyo Roller Girls, and Misawa's Killa Geishas of Misawa - did not surprise in their performances, remaining generally fairly comparable to each other (although there were no direct bouts between them). With very limited opportunities to play different teams, Roller Derby in Japan needs to grow more leagues in order to become more competitive - one reason why the appearance of the new Tokyo team, KAMIKAZE BADASS, is so important. The Japan Roller Derby Association's Nippon Senbatsu, showed a lot of spirit on track, but clearly had the lowest experience of any teams playing (in their first game, especially, they picked up a lot of penalties for failure to reform and track-cuts in situations where a more experienced team would have read the game naturally).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the significance of the Japan Open was more than just symbolic - it also genuinely represented a chance for the teams competing to play leagues which they would never normally get to compete against in other contexts. With international Derby becoming increasingly developed, it's especially important for these kind of events to continue to take place, in order to build the strength of Roller Derby, both in terms of skill, but also in terms of Community, worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were also several interviews with each competing team (except the JRDA's Exhibition Team, Nippon Senbatsu), which we've hunted down the timecodes for (click the links for each interview):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adelaide Roller Derby (1) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=4h13m10s"&gt;https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=4h13m10s&lt;/a&gt; (2) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/udx3lyF80dE#t=6h17m29s"&gt;https://youtu.be/udx3lyF80dE#t=6h17m29s&lt;/a&gt;
Copenhagen Roller Derby (1) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=2h48m36s"&gt;https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=2h48m36s&lt;/a&gt; (2) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=10h22m36s"&gt;https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=10h22m36s&lt;/a&gt;
Devil Dog Derby Dames (1) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=5h56m59s"&gt;https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=5h56m59s&lt;/a&gt; (2) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=8h47m35s"&gt;https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=8h47m35s&lt;/a&gt; (3) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/udx3lyF80dE#t=1h45m15s"&gt;https://youtu.be/udx3lyF80dE#t=1h45m15s&lt;/a&gt; (4) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/udx3lyF80dE#t=3h10m15s"&gt;https://youtu.be/udx3lyF80dE#t=3h10m15s&lt;/a&gt;
Juneau Rollergirls &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=5h51m34s"&gt;https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=5h51m34s&lt;/a&gt;
Kokeshi Roller Dolls &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=2h53m7s"&gt;https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=2h53m7s&lt;/a&gt;
Misawa Killa Geishas (1) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=1h27m51s"&gt;https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=1h27m51s&lt;/a&gt; (2) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=8h51m45s"&gt;https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=8h51m45s&lt;/a&gt;
Pirate City Rollers (1) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=7h25m55s"&gt;https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=7h25m55s&lt;/a&gt; (2) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/udx3lyF80dE#t=7h45m26s"&gt;https://youtu.be/udx3lyF80dE#t=7h45m26s&lt;/a&gt;
Tokyo Roller Girls (1) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=4h16m29"&gt;https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=4h16m29&lt;/a&gt; (2) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=10h19m14s"&gt;https://youtu.be/FkaGqkdgk9c#t=10h19m14s&lt;/a&gt;
Spectator (1) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/udx3lyF80dE#t=2h26m30s"&gt;https://youtu.be/udx3lyF80dE#t=2h26m30s&lt;/a&gt; (2) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/udx3lyF80dE#t=4h48m55s"&gt;https://youtu.be/udx3lyF80dE#t=4h48m55s&lt;/a&gt; (3) &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/udx3lyF80dE#t=4h52m47s"&gt;https://youtu.be/udx3lyF80dE#t=4h52m47s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, just for the statistics fans amongst you, this is the estimated strength of all of the A-Tier Tournament competitors (calculated via Bayesian monte-carlo), relative to Adelaide. (Juneau are a bit diffuse due to their short roster causing their last game to be atypical of their actual ability, due to exhaustion.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-6840 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/screen-shot-2016-03-27-at-20-50-47.png" alt="Screen Shot 2016-03-27 at 20.50.47" width="2384" height="954"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Closer to Home, Glasgow Roller Derby hosted their second fixtures in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/womens-tables-2016/"&gt;British Championships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Premier Tier. A triple-header, this saw GRD and Newcastle play Royal Windsor Rollergirls, followed by GRD taking on Leeds Roller Dolls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After losing both of their games against Newcastle and London in their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/02/british-champs-t3-north-gameday-1/"&gt;first hosted event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Glasgow Roller Derby had to take at least one win in this fixture to stand a chance of avoiding relegation from the Premier Tier. Since then, and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/08/european-smackdown-the-statistics/"&gt;their performance in the European Smackdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Glasgow have clearly been developing the cohesion of their new roster, and their performance was somewhat improved in the two games they played - enough to provide a solid win over Royal Windsor in the first game of the day, with the final score standing at &lt;strong&gt;203 GRD to 179 RWRG&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a 30 minute break between games, a fresh Newcastle Roller Girls continued their win streak in the Premier tier against Royal Windsor, pulling out a very convincing win against the southern English team, &lt;strong&gt;326 to 166&lt;/strong&gt;. This performance by Newcastle reinforces the signal from the previous game that they have increased in strength over the last year - and places them in good stead for their coming attendance at the US Beach Brawl tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leeds Roller Dolls capped off the day by pulling off a convincing victory over the hosts Glasgow, &lt;strong&gt;198 to 122&lt;/strong&gt;, despite a starting roster of only 11, and penalty issues in the second period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These results mean that Newcastle Roller Girls retain, for the moment, their place at the top of the Premier Tier table, with Leeds Roller Dolls just below them on points difference.
With the next British Champs fixtures seeing Newcastle play London Roller Girls (B) (in Newcastle's Walker Activity Dome, 2April) and then Leeds Roller Dolls (also in Newcastle, 23April), the top of the table is getting exceptionally competitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the number of games played so far, there's just enough data to perform a statistical inference on the actual strength of the Premier Tier teams (plotted here, relative to London Rollergirls B). Although there's not enough data for thin peaks, we can see that the evidence suggests that Newcastle and Leeds are both capable of taking the Championship this year, with a significant fraction of their possible strengths above that of London's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-6841 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/screen-shot-2016-03-27-at-21-28-08.png" alt="Screen Shot 2016-03-27 at 21.28.08" width="1370" height="884"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Glasgow's next bout will be international, as they take on Berlin Bombshells on the 23rd of April in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/events-calendar/2016/4/30/irn-bruisers-vs-berlin-rollergirls"&gt;their new venue in Bellahouston&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/strong&gt;With Berlin having recently lost star double-threat Master Blaster to London Rollergirls, this game will be a chance to see both how Glasgow continue to grow back as a team, and how dependent Berlin was on their most famous skater!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout reports</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/27/international-and-national-derby-for-easter-the-review/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 10:52:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs T3 North: Gameday 1</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/02/british-champs-t3-north-gameday-1/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;Of the six leagues that make up Tier 3 Regional North of this year’s British Roller Derby Championships – Dundee Roller Girls, Fierce Valley Roller Girls, Hallam Hellcats Roller Derby, Hull’s Angels Roller Dames, Manchester Roller Derby and Preston Roller Girls – only one competed at the same level last year: Dundee Roller Girls, who finished third in the table, with a record of three wins to two losses.  H.A.R.D. and Manchester Roller Derby both took part in Tier 2 National North, where Manchester beat H.A.R.D. in their encounter.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;Each of the other leagues moved up from Tier 4, Fierce Valley Roller Girls and Preston Roller Girls from T4 Local North as winners and runners up, and Hallam Hellcats from T4 Local Central North, as runners up.  The three teams faced off in the T4 North play-offs in November, where Hallam Hellcats beat Fierce Valley and Preston overcame Wolverhampton Honour Rollers to make the play-off final.  Hallam Hellcats took the victory on the day, and both leagues were promoted by making the final.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6023" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/fvrg1.jpg" alt="fvrg1" width="960" height="640"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;For Fierce Valley Roller Girls, T3 North contains some very familiar foes: both Dundee Roller Girls and Preston Roller Girls have faced FVRG on three occasions.  Dundee currently hold the edge with two victories to one, while FVRG have won each of their games against Preston.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6024" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/fvrg2.jpg" alt="fvrg2" width="960" height="640"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;Gameday 1 took place on Saturday 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; of February, in Preston.  The first game of the day saw FVRG take on H.A.R.D. before Dundee faced the host team.  From the first whistle, the game was very competitive, with neither team giving much ground.  H.A.R.D. took an early lead with some controlled offensive play before FVRG began to gain a foothold in the game.  Despite H.A.R.D.’s rock solid walls and good offensive play from both teams, FVRG’s jammers were finding a way through, and the first half ended with FVRG in the lead.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;H.A.R.D. started the second half very strongly, living up to their name with strong offensive play and big hits, to narrow the points gap.  Both teams fought hard and were fairly evenly matched through the second half, with the result that the score was tied at 171-171 heading into the final few jams.  Just when we thought the tension couldn’t get any higher, FVRG took the lead by one point and the jam ended with just 3 seconds on the clock.  With a time-out called by H.A.R.D., one final jam was played and a final lead change occurred, H.A.R.D. eventually winning the game by 182-178.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6022" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/drg2.jpg" alt="drg2" width="960" height="598"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span id="ecxyui_3_16_0_1_1456924961619_4040"&gt;Dundee's Silvery Tayzers travelled to Preston for their first Champs game of the season, having never met the home team before. Both teams set up in a very similar fashion using strong defensive walls and some useful offense for their jammers to take. Dundee started the game well with Preston giving away a powerjam in the first jam, allowing Dundee to move into a quick lead. Dundee were able to build on this with some good defence and recycling from their blockers allowing the jammers to score valuable points and extend the lead into halftime with the score 53 - 158 in Dundee's favour. The second half followed in the same fashion with both teams playing some great offense and Preston picking up some more points, but Dundee were able to see out the game with a 111-262 victory. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6021" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/drg1.jpg" alt="drg1" width="960" height="640"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;The next date in the T3 calendar is 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; March, when Dundee will travel to Manchester to take on the hosts, and Preston will face H.A.R.D.  The all-Scottish clash is next up at the FVRG-hosted double header on 23&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; April, which will also feature Manchester against Hallam Hellcats.  Dundee welcome H.A.R.D. at home on 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; May, when FVRG will also face Hallam Hellcats.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;Photos courtesy of Johannes von Voges&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bout reports</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/02/british-champs-t3-north-gameday-1/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 16:40:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lothian Derby Dolls Vs Dundee Roller Girls Bonnie Colliders 13 Feb 2016</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/02/19/lothian-derby-dolls-vs-dundee-roller-girls-bonnie-colliders-13-feb-2016/</link><dc:creator>kj782</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bout review by Fully Harmed &amp;amp; Killah Jules of Lothian Derby Dolls.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;57&lt;/strong&gt; v’s DRG &lt;em&gt;Bonnie Colliders&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;414&lt;/strong&gt;
13 Feb 2016, Jack Kane Sports Centre, Edinburgh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5808" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/12751972_10153290311725025_1687578989_o.jpg" alt="12751972_10153290311725025_1687578989_o" width="1080" height="720"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5807" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/12765729_10153290313055025_364153108_o.jpg" alt="12765729_10153290313055025_364153108_o" width="1080" height="720"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photographs by Laura MacDonald&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the first bout of the year for LDD and we fielded a team with mixed levels of experience, with a few skaters injured or away having babies. We felt this was a good opportunity to give our newer skaters some experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt; The Bonnie Colliders dominated the game with strong blockers making holes in the LDD walls for nippy jammers to take advantage of.  LDD had a hard time reforming their defensive walls and then lost three skaters from the game due to penalties. The second half was more positive for LDD with Fi-Nix taking an epic star pass from Jugz and Tea Wrecks hitting out her first jammer in competitive play.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;LDD's heads never went down despite getting beaten by such a wide margin. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5806" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/12755250_10153290315560025_1787426263_o.jpg" alt="12755250_10153290315560025_1787426263_o" width="1080" height="720"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photograph by Laura MacDonald&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;In roller derby things change quickly and we will be training hard until our next bout on the &lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt;th of &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt; against Mean City in Glasgow.  &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1555212058123782/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1555212058123782/ &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout reports</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>ldd</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/02/19/lothian-derby-dolls-vs-dundee-roller-girls-bonnie-colliders-13-feb-2016/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 17:43:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls - Home Season Final 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/28/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-season-final-2015/</link><dc:creator>jennifergelignite</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="spotlight alignleft" src="https://scontent.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpl1/v/t35.0-12/12359395_10153180288466022_1192149624_o.jpg?oh=24e2550bb0d345849186b5816bf3ebeb&amp;amp;oe=56835C21" alt="" width="755" height="501"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A HEART-STOPPING home season final saw the Leithal Weapons swoop to victory by just two points.
Auld Reekie Roller Girls' (ARRG) three home teams - the Leithals, Skatefast Club and the Cherry Bombers - had battled throughout autumn for the chance to take home the 2015 trophy.
Skatefast had beaten the Leithals in the first home season head-to-head and, with the Leithals struggling to field a full team for the final due to injury and illness, looked like the stronger team at the first whistle.
Skill levels were closely-matched and the lead switched several times, as both teams pushed their opponents to pull out their very best performance.
Skatefast were leading by half-time and victory seemed likely, but the Leithals re-entered the track with renewed determination.
With five minutes to the end, Skatefast had pulled ahead by 20 points, leaving the Leithals praying for a power jam.
Suddenly, the opportunity opened up with excellent defensive work from the Leithals in the very last jam.
EmKarp blasted through the Skatefast blockers and the crowd held its breath and held back tears as the points gap closed.
A smart star pass to Tuna Lovegood for an extra energy kick sealed the deal... Or so the Leithals hoped.
The unofficial result was carefully checked as both teams teetered on the brink of celebration for a score that could have gone either way.
Finally those two crucial extra points were verified and the Leithal Weapons were officially declared the 2015 winners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="spotlight alignright" src="https://scontent.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpa1/v/t1.0-9/12299301_10156272236840224_1957699839736333339_n.jpg?oh=fddaf7b01dbf9fe3a6fba64e58b5d64f&amp;amp;oe=57194B21" alt="" width="480" height="360"&gt;
Leithals captain Prawncess Die said she was thrilled for her team.
She said: "We went in as the underdogs.
"We thought we had a good chance but we were playing short and we had lost the last game against them.
"It was so close - I kept looking at the score thinking we can still do this.
"We drifted down 20 points a few times and, in the last few minutes, I did think that was it.
"I thought 'at least we've put up a close game'.
"Then to actually win was just fantastic."
Prawncess Die added she was particularly proud of the newest players on the team.
She said: "Dani was just outstanding, especially as a jammer.
"Everybody was playing really well but she played every position and switched from one to the other, which was very impressive."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skatefast Club captain Trifecta Gadget said everyone was very emotional.
She said: "It was a really tight game through every single jam and we never really felt safe.
"It was good to be in the lead at the end of the first half but I knew we were going to have to bring our strongest game.
"The teams were very evenly matched and I think we lost it on just a couple of jams against some really amazing Leithals players."
Gadget also praised the newest skaters on her team.
She said: "We all kept our defence strong and stayed together really well.
"It was only because we played so well as a team the score was so close.
"I could see how much more confident everybody was by the end and I'm really proud of every skater."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>edinburgh</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/28/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-season-final-2015/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 13:12:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>InARRGuration</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/18/inarrguration/</link><dc:creator>jennifergelignite</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/nazgul.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4856" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/nazgul.jpg?w=225" alt="Nazgul" width="225" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AULD Reekie Roller Girls’ InARRGuration bout for the league’s newest competitive skaters and guests was a victory for all.
A close-run game saw Green Eggs and SLAM! Leading with 123 points to Team Nazgul’s 99 at half-time.
But the second half saw the Nazguls race back to score 223 to 184 for a stonking win.
Team Nazgul Captain Powerhouse said the pre-game secret weapon was team brownies.
She said: “We prepared by having a meeting over drinks in the Auld Hoose to discuss rules, default tactics, any worries or issues.
“Then we had many more chats on our Facebook group - I think this helped our guest skaters a lot, and helped them feel part of the team.
“On the day, the wonderful vice-captain, Radge of Honour made amazing brownies, and I made (equally as amazing, but less tasty) posters.
“These had some simple focuses for the bench (keep positive, calm and zen) and on track (have fun, communicate and stay together).
“There was also a pink elephant, amongst other beautiful artwork, which really got the point across.”
Green Eggs and Slam Captain Hex said fizz helped the green team bond.
She said: “We had loads of chat on Facebook and then we all met up at vice captain Dead Metal's house for a meeting where we talked rules and strategy and watched derby on the telly.
“We may also have drunk some fizzy drinks...”
Hoose and Hex both admitted in the thrill of the game they barely checked the score.
Hex said: “I wasn’t actually really looking at the score.
“I noticed we were in the lead at half time and yeah! It felt good!
“I felt like we were doing really well and the score reflected that.”
Hoose said: “Once both teams settled into the game, I felt we were well matched and I was having so much fun, I barely looked at the scoreboard!
“Our bench coach, the inimitable Collie, used our team time outs really wisely, when we were able to take a breath, refocus and get back out on track raring to go.
“I think the gap in points spurred us on, and the green team really forced us to bring our top game - they were incredibly strong, aggressive with some fantastic offence.”
Hex said the turning point was half-time, when four Green players fouled out.
She said: “Oh dear, I think the turning point was our penalties.
“Everyone was giving their all and sadly it was maybe a bit too much!
“Players started to foul out and the bench was getting shorter as people were tiring.
“Team Black were also totally amazing!!!”
The second half was where Hoose felt the team came into their own because of their focus.
She said: “There were a few jams in a row where more than one green player was in the bin.
“The black team managed to keep their cool, keep low, slow and strong (SO PROUD), and take total advantage of this.
“Our fantastic line up manager, Gerry, noticed this and put on some really smart line ups, with fast jammers.
“Once we pulled away, it was going to be difficult to catch us, and added to that, there were a few foul outs on the green side - that's always going to be exhausting!
“The boost of focus carried over into the rest of the game, raised the quality of derby, and the rest is history.”
After the game, both teams headed to the pub.
Hoose said there were many sweaty hugs and lots of beer to celebrate everyone’s hard work.
She said: “It was such a great experience, and I think everyone learned a huge amount.
“I'm incredibly proud of both teams, and so grateful to ARRG, and all the officials and volunteers on the day!
“It didn't matter who won or lost. As clichéd as it sounds, we all won - every single person now has the experience of a well matched, well played game under their belt. That's invaluable.
“We all developed skills, and tried things we never thought we could do - we are now better skaters, and have a bunch of new friends to talk derby with!
Hex agreed derby love was the order of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said: “There were lots of hugs and lots of derby love! It was great how close you get in a couple of hours!
“Then not so healthy food and drink with greens, blacks, refs, nsos -- all the best people you could hope to hang out with!
“There were incredible vibes - how much all the skaters put their heart and souls into it and what an amazing team we created having never met half of the skaters before, how much hard work the organisers had put into it, all the refs, nsos, announcers, audience - everyone involved! I just felt spoiled rotten to be a part of it all! best day EVA!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auldreekierollergirls</category><category>bout reports</category><category>image</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/18/inarrguration/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 17:30:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow Roller Derby - British Champions</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/24/glasgow-roller-derby-british-champions/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby have been crowned British Champions after a stunning set of performances which saw them go on a five-game winning streak.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRD’s all-star team won the inaugural British Roller Derby Championships – with emphatic wins over teams from Edinburgh, Cardiff, Manchester, Birmingham and Middlesbrough.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The competition culminated in a two-day derby extravaganza – held in Glasgow – on May 30 and 31.&lt;/p&gt;
Hundreds of fans crowded into the ARC sports centre to cheer on their heroes and were treated to an amazing display of sporting prowess, skating skills and blistering action.&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-4717 alignright" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/glasgow_roller_derby_3_color_logo.png?w=185" alt="Glasgow_Roller_Derby_3_Color_Logo" width="185" height="300"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tribute has been paid to the all-female Glasgow league for flying the flag for Scottish sport – continuing the legacy of sporting achievement which put the city on the world’s centre stage during the Commonwealth Games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby are first in the UK Roller Derby Association rankings and second in Europe (outside of London Rollergirls) – a remarkable achievement for Scotland’s first roller derby league, started by the skaters themselves in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRD co-captain Grace Maclean – aka Mona Rampage - said: “I am so proud of my league and my team. We went unbeaten throughout the British Championships – winning all five of our games against the cream of the crop in UK roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To lift the trophy with my friends and league-mates was something I will never forget. We’ve worked so hard as a team and an organisation – it genuinely means a lot for us, our friends and our fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Winning the championship is the culmination of months of hard work from everyone involved with GRD. I hope we’ve done Scotland proud and that everyone can draw inspiration from what we’ve achieved together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first year of the British Roller Derby Championships – which featured four tiers of female teams, comprising 13 divisions. There were also three tiers for male teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow was in the top tier – alongside elite teams such as Auld Reekie Roller Girls from Edinburgh, Middlesbrough Milk Rollers, Tiger Bay Brawlers from Cardiff, Birmingham’s Central City RollerGirls and Rainy City Roller Girls from Oldham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow went into the final weekend at the top of the table, with three wins from three games – knowing two wins would secure the inaugural trophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the leagues at the other end of the table were fighting to avoid the drop into the second tier – with two teams destined to be relegated.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;That set the scene for a pulsating weekend of derby action – featuring thrills, spills and more than a few skills from all the skaters involved.&lt;/p&gt;
Thanks have been given to Glasgow Sport for its support towards the staging of the event, as well as everyone at the British Champs, UK Roller Derby Association and Derby Duck Productions.
&lt;p&gt;Saturday saw Central City RollerGirls (CCR) narrowly defeat Rainy City (RCRG) 129-124 in a fantastic opening game, with both teams desperate to win in a bid to juke around relegation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRD then took to the ARC track knowing a win would put them within a toe-stop of the British Championship. In the end they won convincingly – beating Middlesbrough Milk Rollers (MMR) 205-119.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls (ARRG) and Tiger Bay Brawlers (TBB) supplied the action for the final game on Saturday, with the Edinburgh team taking the win and all three points to remain second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Into Sunday and GRD had an early start against Rainy City. But any hopes that the Gallus Glaswegians would be caught napping were quickly put to bed as the all-stars won 227-131.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game two then served up a cracking, evenly-matched contest as Tiger Bay took on Middlesbrough. Potentially both teams had a chance of snatching second – although a massive points swing would have been needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a nail-biter the whole way – with the lead changing hands repeatedly as both teams competed brilliantly on the track. It seemed MMR had edged it in the final seconds with a dramatic 164-163 win, but a point had been missed and the readjusted final score was 164-164 – meaning the contest had to go to an overtime jam to decide the winner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone watching in the hall – and around the world via the live stream – were then treated to two minutes of action they would never forget. Both teams scored in the breathtaking final jam, but MMR edged it – just - 183-178.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;That put MMR on nine points – equal with Auld Reekie, but behind on points scored and conceded. The Edinburgh team then consolidated their second-place position against CCR, winning 168-152 in another closely-fought contest that went the full distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-4718" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/t1-table.jpg?w=300" alt="T1-table" width="464" height="174"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Glasgow co-captain Grace Maclean said: “Six sensational games took place on Saturday and Sunday – involving around 80 skaters, dozens of referees and non-skating officials, and hundreds of fans.
&lt;p&gt;“The games were also broadcast live on the Internet and watched across the world, so it genuinely was a team effort from everyone involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I want to say a massive thank-you to all who supported the event and helped to make it happen – especially the roller derby fans who provided such an amazing atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was a genuine thrill to be involved and to host the final weekend of action in the first year of the competition. To win the trophy unbeaten is a fantastic achievement for everyone associated with Glasgow Roller Derby and we hope we’ve done our city – and our country – proud.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adventure doesn’t stop there for GRD. They hope to compete again in America soon – flying the flag for Scotland in the country where modern-day roller derby was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meteoric rise of Glasgow is no fluke – it’s the culmination of years and years of training, practice scrims, skills sessions, endurance work and league organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the league, visit &lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com"&gt;www.glasgowrollerderby.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>in the news</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/24/glasgow-roller-derby-british-champions/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 17:46:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Roller Derby World Cup - Day 3 Review</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/07/roller-derby-world-cup-day-3-review/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 3 of the second ever Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup was devoted to the first stage of the Elimination round, along with the completion of the Consolation bouts for those teams not finishing in the top of their group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, due to the pairing of Group #1 seeds against Group #2 seeds in the Elimination bracket, it has to be said that the closest and most exciting bouts of the day were mostly in the Consolation round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While they seemed less certain in the first period, Team Japan pulled out easily the best performance of their tournament in the second period of their Consolation bout against Mexico, really showing how much they've developed as a team over the past few days (even if both teams had an overflowing penalty board by the end of the game...).  Switzerland v Italy was a very close to-and-fro game, especially in the first period. Once again, accumulated penalties told on both teams, and Italy pulled ahead for the win in Period 2. And Denmark v Portugal once again repeated the same story - a close first period, with Denmark turning on the gas in the second to secure a convincing win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over in the Elimination bouts, Norway, West Indies and Brasil all had predictably crushing bouts against the probable top three in the tournament; USA, England and Canada. Brasil managed to score an impressive 75 points against Canada, however, showing what a great team they've become since the 2011 Cup!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweden, New Zealand, Finland and Argentina had less easy groups to win, but triumphed over Ireland, Netherlands, Belgium, France in the end. Of these, the Argentina v France bout was the only truly close bout of the Top 16 playoffs, with the result completely unpredictable during the first period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rankings going into the Final 8 being determined by score difference in the previous single bout, this close Argentina win rather sealed their fate, as the #8 Seed must play #1, the dominant USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over to Scotland, however, where our team was unlucky enough to be drawn against Australia, #4 placed team from 2011, and probable #3 or #4 place contestors in this tournament. It was a difficult first period for Scotland, with some incredible displays of blocking and jamming on track; however, Australia managed to control the lead jammer position for the entire first period, preventing Scotland's excellence from doing anything other than limiting Aussie scoring. In the very last jam of the period, a star pass to Kerr during a leadless jam, allowed a literal last-second score, putting a single point on the board for Scotland!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejuvenated by breaking their duck, Scotland returned to the 2nd Period determined to mix it up. Liston, jamming for the first time in the game (tournament?), picked up the first lead jammer call for Scotland during the opening (power) jam and the first grand slam pass seconds later. This was the start of a much more confident play by Scotland, with Gow taking a natural lead jammer call soon after, although being forced to call after a single scoring pass after a block knocked her face first into the concrete floor (this also put her out of action in the line-up while she was checked out by the medics). A few power jams for both teams (including a couple of jams where both Scotland and Australia's jammers headed to the box simultaneously), and the Australian blocking mostly told, despite sterling blocking by Maclean, Davis, Liston, Parry (until she fouled out), Cider, Kerr, Simpson and Skinner in particular on the Scottish team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, a scrappy final jam featuring more alternating jammer penalties, brought the score to 464-35 for a deserved Australia win, but a hard fought one against Scotland's resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the quarter final, then, the drawing of high seeds against low continued to produce some predictable blowouts, with USA destroying Argentina just like they destroyed everyone else in the tournament, and England taking a very convincing win over Sweden. Being closer to the middle of the seeds, the Canada - Finland and Australia - New Zealand bouts were slightly less one sided, with Finland standing up pretty well to the #3 seed and taking home 145 pts to Canada's 290.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USA will play #4 seed Australia today, before number #2 and #3 seeds England and Canada duke it out. The winners will go through to the Final, while the losers will play for 3rd place in a last minute change to the schedule (check our&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/10/bloodthunder-world-cup-timings-uk/"&gt; UK timetable&lt;/a&gt; for the accurate timings).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, a brief digression for a slightly controversial statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blood and Thunder's official "Knockout standings" (which are based on the score differentials only for the Group of 16 bouts, as far as we can tell) are [taken from their Facebook page]:
OFFICIAL KNOCKOUT ROUND STANDINGS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team USA Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team England Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Canada B&amp;amp;T World Cup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Australia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team New Zealand Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Finland (Roller Derby)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Sweden Rollerderby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selección Argentina de Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team France Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Ireland Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Belgium Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Netherlands - Women's Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Scotland Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roller Derby Brasil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team West Indies - Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Norway Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, the Top 8 rankings may change based on the games still to play (although we at the Blog believe that England &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; have a strong chance to beat Canada to 2nd place).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's more problematic is that the placements in the bottom 8, including Scotland, are apparently based only on a single score differential, so teams like Norway, Scotland, West Indies and Brasil are penalised by taking on the eventual number 1-4 seeds in their only rank-contributing bout.
We at the Blog disagree strongly with this ranking approach, as it can be shown to underrank those 4 teams - the highest rank Scotland could expect would be 12, under this approach, which they have been assigned.
In the particular case of Scotland, it rankles more, however, as, if we compare the results of Scotland v Finland in the group stage (126-78 for Finland, a 2/3 length bout), and the results of Belgium v Finland in the Elimination stage (383:124 for Finland), it is very clear that Scotland should be ranked above Belgium. Based on other pairwise score-comparison considerations, we believe that Scotland's "true" rank in the tournament is probably &lt;strong&gt;10th&lt;/strong&gt;, narrowly ranked just above Ireland (who Scotland beat not long ago at the Road to Dallas tournament). We believe Norway is strongly penalised by their matching against USA as well, and think their rank should also be at least 2 higher than it actually is in the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full score table for the day is below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SATURDAY, DECEMBER 6, 2014
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(FULL 60 MINUTE BOUTS)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 1 (ROLL-LINE TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 2 (BLOOD &amp;amp; THUNDER TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 3 (TBD TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 7-1 (&lt;strong&gt;Canada 581&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 2-2 (Brazil 75)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 3-1 (&lt;strong&gt;Sweden 303&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 6-2 (Ireland 133)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 3 ( Japan 114) VS. 4 (&lt;strong&gt;Mexico 278&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 1-1 (&lt;strong&gt;NZ 356&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 8-2 (Netherlands 91)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 8-1 (&lt;strong&gt;USA 854&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 1-2 (Norway 6)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 2 ( Switzerland 136) VS. 5 (&lt;strong&gt;Italy 193&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 2-1 (France 162) VS. GR 7-2 (&lt;strong&gt;Argentina 205&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 4-1 (&lt;strong&gt;Finland 383&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 5-2 (Belgium 124)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 3 (&lt;strong&gt;Wales 395&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. 6 (Puerto Rico 75)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 5-1 (&lt;strong&gt;Australia 464&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 4-2 (Scotland 35)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 6-1 (&lt;strong&gt;England 708&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 3-2 (West Indies 31)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 2 (Portugal 135) VS. 7 (&lt;strong&gt;Denmark 245&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TEAM 1 (&lt;strong&gt;USA&lt;/strong&gt; 569) VS. TEAM 8 (Argentina 14)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TEAM 3 (&lt;strong&gt;Canada&lt;/strong&gt; 290) VS. TEAM 6 (Finland 145)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 1 (Chile 116) VS. 8 (&lt;strong&gt;Germany&lt;/strong&gt;330)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;01:00AM(SUN)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TEAM 3 (&lt;strong&gt;England&lt;/strong&gt; 278) VS. TEAM 7 (Sweden 72)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TEAM 4 (&lt;strong&gt;Australia&lt;/strong&gt; 284) VS. TEAM 5 (New Zealand 56)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;01:10AM(SUN)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 7 (&lt;strong&gt;Denmark&lt;/strong&gt; 332) VS. 8 (Puerto Rico 169)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>articles</category><category>blood and thunder world cup 2014</category><category>bout reports</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/07/roller-derby-world-cup-day-3-review/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 09:05:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Roller Derby World Cup Day 2 - Review</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/06/roller-derby-world-cup-day-2-review/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a second exciting day of Group bouts, here's what our table looked like:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NEW ZEALAND 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FRANCE 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SWEDEN 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FINLAND 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AUSTRALIA 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ENGLAND 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CANADA 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;USA 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NORWAY 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SWITZERLAND 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WEST INDIES 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SCOTLAND 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ITALY 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GERMANY 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DENMARK 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PUERTO RICO 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SOUTH AFRICA 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BRAZIL 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;JAPAN 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COLOMBIA 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BELGIUM 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SPAIN 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ARGENTINA 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;THE NETHERLANDS 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WALES 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PORTUGAL 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CHILE 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MEXICO 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GREECE 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;IRELAND 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
As a correction from yesterday, it appears that the labelling on the official schedule confused us: any team not in the top 2 in their group pass through to the Consolation round, with one game each (except those in Group 7 and 8 who get two games, as there's only one of them for each Group, and they got less Group games in total). Our UK and Japan time schedules are now updated to reflect that fact.
&lt;p&gt;So, on to the Derby: As is often the case for the second round of groups, most of the really tight games were in the second day. That said, we started with Finland, Australia and England getting the blow-outs that we expected against Mexico, Greece and Ireland (not to say the latter are poor teams, but the former are really exceptional).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fighting it out for the second place in their group brought grit to the Switzerland v Brasil bout, with Brasil just pulling out the edge in an exciting bout (one for the archives if you missed it). While West Indies won both their bouts (against Japan and Chile) to put themselves into the second position in Group 3, neither of their opponents disgraced themselves, with Japan showing how much they'd learned just in the previous day of play, and Chile holding on until the very last jam!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On to Scotland:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned yesterday, Scotland needed to beat Colombia in order to make it through to the Elimination round. While Colombia had periods of control on the track, taking lead jammer mostly when Scotland had a blocker deficit on track, and both teams suffered some penalty issues (there were jams for both teams where they had to cope with having only a single blocker on track), Scotland's excellent pack work, lead by Maclean, Skinner, Parry, Cider, and Davis and Kerr, told in the end ('Splat' Kerr developed a particular skill for knocking Colombian jammers out of attempted apex jumps). Despite a tired O'Carroll and her Colombian opponent spending the second-last jam taking two trips to the penalty box each, in general the Scottish jamming was also excellent, with Gow, Rogue, Hyndman and O'Carroll all able to trust their blockers, and get on with dedicating their skill to scoring. In the end, the balance of jammer penalties, and the superior track control when there was no pack deficit against them, told in Scotland's favour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scotland will play the mighty Australia on Track 1 at 9pm UK time today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belgium, Netherlands, Ireland and England, the other teams in the tournament featuring Scottish skaters, also made it through to the Elimination stage. Belgium, Netherlands and Ireland, being 2nd in their groups, face tough 1st Group place opponents today in Finland, New Zealand, Sweden, while England, having easily taken their 1st Group place, have the West Indies as their first opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Match ups in the second stage of the elimination are to be decided by the overall score difference after the first round, so even a close game could make all the difference (for the winner) for a better draw in the Quarter Final later on in the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the final Group bouts, the schedule managed to sneak in a few more special games: the first two Consolation bouts, with Colombia triumphing over Greece, and Spain taking their first win of the tournament over South Africa. We suspect that many of the viewers were tuned into the Vagine Regime Expo bout on Track 3, however, where PanGina pulled ahead from a close half time score versus Queerope to take a commanding win in the second period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day concluded with another Expo of top skill, the Team USA "Stars and Stripes" bout, where Stars took the close win against Stripes 134:129.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIDAY, DECEMBER 5, 2014  (40 MINUTE BOUTS)
&lt;/strong&gt;CONSOLATION BOUTS ARE FULL 60 MINUTE BOUTS
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 1 (ROLL-LINE TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 2 (BLOOD &amp;amp; THUNDER TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 3 (TBD TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FINLAND&lt;/strong&gt; (312) VS. MEXICO (38)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AUSTRALIA&lt;/strong&gt; (449) VS. GREECE (17)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENGLAND&lt;/strong&gt; (329) VS. IRELAND (50)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:20PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NORWAY (219)&lt;/strong&gt; VS. SOUTH AFRICA (80)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SWITZERLAND (108) VS. &lt;strong&gt;BRAZIL &lt;/strong&gt;(120)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:30PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WEST INDIES&lt;/strong&gt; (235) VS. JAPAN (70)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:40PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NEW ZEALAND&lt;/strong&gt; (250) VS. WALES (60)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRANCE&lt;/strong&gt; (310) VS. PORTUGAL (36)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:50PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SWEDEN&lt;/strong&gt; (296) VS. CHILE (39)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCOTLAND&lt;/strong&gt; (230) VS. COLOMBIA (53)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ITALY (86)VS. &lt;strong&gt;BELGIUM &lt;/strong&gt;(273)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GERMANY&lt;/strong&gt; (216) VS. SPAIN (70)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8:20PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DENMARK (85) VS. &lt;strong&gt;ARGENTINA &lt;/strong&gt;(202)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PUERTO RICO (154) VS. &lt;strong&gt;NETHERLANDS &lt;/strong&gt;(209)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8:30PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WEST INDIES&lt;/strong&gt; (104) VS. CHILE (100)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 4 (&lt;strong&gt;Colombia 305&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. 5 (Greece 136)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 6 (South Africa 143) VS. 1 (&lt;strong&gt;Spain 227&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;VAGINE REGIME EXPO BOUT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;00:00 (MIDNIGHT)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TEAM USA STARS VS. STRIPES EXPO&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>blood and thunder world cup 2014</category><category>bout reports</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/06/roller-derby-world-cup-day-2-review/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2014 07:57:08 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>