<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about bout report)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/bout-report.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:41:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls - Home Season Final 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/28/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-season-final-2015/</link><dc:creator>jennifergelignite</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="spotlight alignleft" src="https://scontent.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpl1/v/t35.0-12/12359395_10153180288466022_1192149624_o.jpg?oh=24e2550bb0d345849186b5816bf3ebeb&amp;amp;oe=56835C21" alt="" width="755" height="501"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A HEART-STOPPING home season final saw the Leithal Weapons swoop to victory by just two points.
Auld Reekie Roller Girls' (ARRG) three home teams - the Leithals, Skatefast Club and the Cherry Bombers - had battled throughout autumn for the chance to take home the 2015 trophy.
Skatefast had beaten the Leithals in the first home season head-to-head and, with the Leithals struggling to field a full team for the final due to injury and illness, looked like the stronger team at the first whistle.
Skill levels were closely-matched and the lead switched several times, as both teams pushed their opponents to pull out their very best performance.
Skatefast were leading by half-time and victory seemed likely, but the Leithals re-entered the track with renewed determination.
With five minutes to the end, Skatefast had pulled ahead by 20 points, leaving the Leithals praying for a power jam.
Suddenly, the opportunity opened up with excellent defensive work from the Leithals in the very last jam.
EmKarp blasted through the Skatefast blockers and the crowd held its breath and held back tears as the points gap closed.
A smart star pass to Tuna Lovegood for an extra energy kick sealed the deal... Or so the Leithals hoped.
The unofficial result was carefully checked as both teams teetered on the brink of celebration for a score that could have gone either way.
Finally those two crucial extra points were verified and the Leithal Weapons were officially declared the 2015 winners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="spotlight alignright" src="https://scontent.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpa1/v/t1.0-9/12299301_10156272236840224_1957699839736333339_n.jpg?oh=fddaf7b01dbf9fe3a6fba64e58b5d64f&amp;amp;oe=57194B21" alt="" width="480" height="360"&gt;
Leithals captain Prawncess Die said she was thrilled for her team.
She said: "We went in as the underdogs.
"We thought we had a good chance but we were playing short and we had lost the last game against them.
"It was so close - I kept looking at the score thinking we can still do this.
"We drifted down 20 points a few times and, in the last few minutes, I did think that was it.
"I thought 'at least we've put up a close game'.
"Then to actually win was just fantastic."
Prawncess Die added she was particularly proud of the newest players on the team.
She said: "Dani was just outstanding, especially as a jammer.
"Everybody was playing really well but she played every position and switched from one to the other, which was very impressive."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skatefast Club captain Trifecta Gadget said everyone was very emotional.
She said: "It was a really tight game through every single jam and we never really felt safe.
"It was good to be in the lead at the end of the first half but I knew we were going to have to bring our strongest game.
"The teams were very evenly matched and I think we lost it on just a couple of jams against some really amazing Leithals players."
Gadget also praised the newest skaters on her team.
She said: "We all kept our defence strong and stayed together really well.
"It was only because we played so well as a team the score was so close.
"I could see how much more confident everybody was by the end and I'm really proud of every skater."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>edinburgh</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/28/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-season-final-2015/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 13:12:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow Roller Derby - British Champions</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/24/glasgow-roller-derby-british-champions/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby have been crowned British Champions after a stunning set of performances which saw them go on a five-game winning streak.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRD’s all-star team won the inaugural British Roller Derby Championships – with emphatic wins over teams from Edinburgh, Cardiff, Manchester, Birmingham and Middlesbrough.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The competition culminated in a two-day derby extravaganza – held in Glasgow – on May 30 and 31.&lt;/p&gt;
Hundreds of fans crowded into the ARC sports centre to cheer on their heroes and were treated to an amazing display of sporting prowess, skating skills and blistering action.&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-4717 alignright" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/glasgow_roller_derby_3_color_logo.png?w=185" alt="Glasgow_Roller_Derby_3_Color_Logo" width="185" height="300"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tribute has been paid to the all-female Glasgow league for flying the flag for Scottish sport – continuing the legacy of sporting achievement which put the city on the world’s centre stage during the Commonwealth Games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby are first in the UK Roller Derby Association rankings and second in Europe (outside of London Rollergirls) – a remarkable achievement for Scotland’s first roller derby league, started by the skaters themselves in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRD co-captain Grace Maclean – aka Mona Rampage - said: “I am so proud of my league and my team. We went unbeaten throughout the British Championships – winning all five of our games against the cream of the crop in UK roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To lift the trophy with my friends and league-mates was something I will never forget. We’ve worked so hard as a team and an organisation – it genuinely means a lot for us, our friends and our fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Winning the championship is the culmination of months of hard work from everyone involved with GRD. I hope we’ve done Scotland proud and that everyone can draw inspiration from what we’ve achieved together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first year of the British Roller Derby Championships – which featured four tiers of female teams, comprising 13 divisions. There were also three tiers for male teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow was in the top tier – alongside elite teams such as Auld Reekie Roller Girls from Edinburgh, Middlesbrough Milk Rollers, Tiger Bay Brawlers from Cardiff, Birmingham’s Central City RollerGirls and Rainy City Roller Girls from Oldham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow went into the final weekend at the top of the table, with three wins from three games – knowing two wins would secure the inaugural trophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the leagues at the other end of the table were fighting to avoid the drop into the second tier – with two teams destined to be relegated.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;That set the scene for a pulsating weekend of derby action – featuring thrills, spills and more than a few skills from all the skaters involved.&lt;/p&gt;
Thanks have been given to Glasgow Sport for its support towards the staging of the event, as well as everyone at the British Champs, UK Roller Derby Association and Derby Duck Productions.
&lt;p&gt;Saturday saw Central City RollerGirls (CCR) narrowly defeat Rainy City (RCRG) 129-124 in a fantastic opening game, with both teams desperate to win in a bid to juke around relegation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRD then took to the ARC track knowing a win would put them within a toe-stop of the British Championship. In the end they won convincingly – beating Middlesbrough Milk Rollers (MMR) 205-119.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls (ARRG) and Tiger Bay Brawlers (TBB) supplied the action for the final game on Saturday, with the Edinburgh team taking the win and all three points to remain second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Into Sunday and GRD had an early start against Rainy City. But any hopes that the Gallus Glaswegians would be caught napping were quickly put to bed as the all-stars won 227-131.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game two then served up a cracking, evenly-matched contest as Tiger Bay took on Middlesbrough. Potentially both teams had a chance of snatching second – although a massive points swing would have been needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a nail-biter the whole way – with the lead changing hands repeatedly as both teams competed brilliantly on the track. It seemed MMR had edged it in the final seconds with a dramatic 164-163 win, but a point had been missed and the readjusted final score was 164-164 – meaning the contest had to go to an overtime jam to decide the winner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone watching in the hall – and around the world via the live stream – were then treated to two minutes of action they would never forget. Both teams scored in the breathtaking final jam, but MMR edged it – just - 183-178.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;That put MMR on nine points – equal with Auld Reekie, but behind on points scored and conceded. The Edinburgh team then consolidated their second-place position against CCR, winning 168-152 in another closely-fought contest that went the full distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-4718" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/t1-table.jpg?w=300" alt="T1-table" width="464" height="174"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Glasgow co-captain Grace Maclean said: “Six sensational games took place on Saturday and Sunday – involving around 80 skaters, dozens of referees and non-skating officials, and hundreds of fans.
&lt;p&gt;“The games were also broadcast live on the Internet and watched across the world, so it genuinely was a team effort from everyone involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I want to say a massive thank-you to all who supported the event and helped to make it happen – especially the roller derby fans who provided such an amazing atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was a genuine thrill to be involved and to host the final weekend of action in the first year of the competition. To win the trophy unbeaten is a fantastic achievement for everyone associated with Glasgow Roller Derby and we hope we’ve done our city – and our country – proud.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adventure doesn’t stop there for GRD. They hope to compete again in America soon – flying the flag for Scotland in the country where modern-day roller derby was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meteoric rise of Glasgow is no fluke – it’s the culmination of years and years of training, practice scrims, skills sessions, endurance work and league organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the league, visit &lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com"&gt;www.glasgowrollerderby.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>in the news</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/24/glasgow-roller-derby-british-champions/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 17:46:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs make Derby History!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/15/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-make-derby-history/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of first last weekend, from Gotham coming to the UK, through Dundee's debut of their B-team... but perhaps the most important event for the future of Scottish Derby occurred at Grangemouth Sports Centre on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After considerable hard work, from both the coaches and organisers, the skaters themselves (and encouragement from parents), Scotland's only Junior Roller Derby league, &lt;a href="http://www.fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs&lt;/a&gt;, held their first ever public bout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/10491187_665792883505850_5377019356439535080_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3540" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/10491187_665792883505850_5377019356439535080_n.jpg?w=660" alt="The Cubs, and Friends (Photo: Laura MacDonald)" width="660" height="440"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Cubs, and Friends (Photo: Laura MacDonald)&lt;p&gt;After a hard-fought game, with Team White taking and holding an early lead through to the end, despite continual resistance from Team Black, the bout ended &lt;strong&gt;White 219:168 Black&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We asked the Captains of both teams (Bon Jodie for Team White, and Purple Punisher for Team Black) to give us their own words about the bout experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bon Jodie&lt;/strong&gt;: I'm 'Bon Jodie' and I had the honour of captaining one team in Fierce Valley Roller Cubs' first public intraleague bout. To captain was an exhilarating experience and to bout for the first time was phenomenal. I was more nervous about bouting for the first time than captaining my team, but I did feel a responsibility from the start to make sure that everyone's spirits were high and they weren't too nervous and were enjoying themselves. Even though in the upcoming days I was extremely conflicted about my feelings towards my bout the second the first whistle blew the nerves were replaced by what I can only describe as determination and adrenaline rush combined. I was very proud of my team, and the other team as we all did so well, afterwards I won MVP during the awards and I was completely overjoyed, overall it was an amazing day I hope to experience again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purple Punisher&lt;/strong&gt;: The bout was meant to be fun and it was just that! Being involved and being captain for the first junior roller derby bout in Scotland was extremely nerve wracking because there was nothing to live up to, we were setting the example. We learnt so much from the bout and the crowd really helped settle the nerves. We made history and being captain was amazing!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bout awards were:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Jammer&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Arch Enemy&lt;/em&gt; (Team White), &lt;em&gt;Haylstone&lt;/em&gt; (Team Black)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Blocker&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Teeny Bash&lt;/em&gt; (Team White), &lt;em&gt;Crimson Crusader&lt;/em&gt; (Team Black)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MVP&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Bon Jodie&lt;/em&gt; (Team White), &lt;em&gt;Stunaimi&lt;/em&gt; (Team Black)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>interviews</category><category>intraleague</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/15/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-make-derby-history/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 19:44:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Guest Bout Report: Quad Nations</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/09/20/guest-bout-report-quad-nations/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Editor's Note: GCRG's own Chris 'sMACDaddy' McDonald has been kind enough to contribute this extensive bout report for the first ever Quad Nations tournament held in Swansea. Some post-hoc formatting has been applied to his original text, and links have been added for those teams who don't have a flash-only website. The remaining words in this report are entirely his own.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/image10.png"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2947" alt="image10" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/image10.png" width="577" height="185"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The tournament&lt;/strong&gt;...Quad Nations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The battleground&lt;/strong&gt;...the Cwrt Herbet Sports centre in Swansea!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The participants&lt;/strong&gt;...The &lt;a href="http://swanseacityslayers.com/"&gt;Swansea City Slayers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://belfastrollerderby.com/"&gt;The Belfast Banshees&lt;/a&gt;, Severn Roller Torrent and &lt;a href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/"&gt;The Northern Fights&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; amazing teams, &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; bouts, &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; days and a &lt;strong&gt;whole load&lt;/strong&gt; of emotion!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;This was the first 2 day tournament ever to be held in Wales and my goodness did the Swansea league put on a show! They invited the cream of the crop from all corners of the UK to their home to compete for the coveted Golden Skate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The first day would see all the teams face off against each other in 30 minute bouts to determine the seedings for the second day. From the minute you set foot in the hall, you could feel the excitement in the air. The track was being laid by the amazing crew of helpers and NSO's. Stall holders were setting up, the VIP seating was being blown up (they were inflatable, not explosive) and the skaters were trying to get themselves into the right frame of mind for what was sure to be an epic weekend of derby action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Unfortunately, there were some issues for one team early on. The Belfast Banshees (who undoubtedly had the farthest to travel for this tournament) had experienced an issue with their ferry and still hadn't arrived! But they were on their way and after a quick restructuring of the arranged bouts, it was time to get the action underway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align:center;"&gt;DAY ONE!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The first bout would see the Swansea Slayers take on Severn. these two had bouted against each other once already this year in March and Severn had come out on top. Would the Slayers be out for revenge? Being that it was only&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2948 alignright" alt="image11" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/image11.png" width="153" height="177"&gt; a 30 minute bout, there were some tentative steps from both teams in the early going. Neither wanted to give anything away, but both realised they would need to conserve energy for the long weekend ahead. Power jams were fairly limited but Scarlett Shadow of Severn and The Mortician of Swansea were sometimes jamming like there was no-one else on track! Both put in a strong opening bout showing. Hope fully the other teams were taking notes. As the 30 minutes ran out, Severn came away victorious in this first bout, scoring 81 points to Swansea's 41.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Next up, it was the Granite City Roller Girls' Northern Fights, against the hosts Swansea. These teams had never before met on track, but judging by the giggles and smiles they all shared, there was clearly some common Celtic love going around! The Slayers were on fire from the first whistle in this one. Clearly feeding off the adrenaline from the previous bout, they racked up an impressive tally. 107 points to the Fights' 51. A few mistakes from jammers had cost the Fights dearly in this one. Silly fouls!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Bout number 3
&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2949 alignleft" alt="image12" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/image12.png" width="165" height="181"&gt;
was Severn versus the Fights. The Aberdonian side are often known as a second half side and considering they had just played 30 minutes against Swansea, they went into this next bout with a lot of energy and enthusiasm. Would Severn be able to hold them back? Unfortunately not. Both teams defenses were working so hard in this one, but again, little fouls cost them dearly. Final scores for bout 3 were Severn 24 : 108 Northern Fights. The first "bonus point" of the tournament earned by the gals from up north.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Just in the nick of time, the crew from Belfast arrived! Unfortunately for them, due to the delay, they would have to play all 3 of their opening day bouts back to back! But not once did the girls complain, they just got on with the day! Their first opponents, Severn Roller Torrent! How would the Banshees cope after having spent so long travelling? How would Severn respond to their loss to the Fights? The opening few jams were very tentative with neither teaming scoring. Clearly they were sizing each other up! Both teams were limiting their jammer rotation too. A tactic to preserve the skaters for the rest of the tournament&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2950 alignright" alt="image13" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/image13.png" width="158" height="184"&gt; perhaps? Severn emerged victorious from this one, scoring 119 points. The Banshees, 23. Considering the issues, the Belfast girls had, this was a damn good showing.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Next on track to take on the Irish was the Northern Fights. These teams last met on track last year over in Belfast. The Banshees scored an impressive victory there, could they do it again? As it turns out...yes. Yes they could! They did it in spectacular fashion too. Final scores were 104 to the Banshees, 61 to the Northern Fights. Go Belfast!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The 6th bout of the 1st day of a 2 day tournament (the announcers had fun with that one!) would see the hosts, Swansea, take on the now extremely tired and long travelled Belfast. This was an exciting bout to watch. Both teams jammers were so quick on their feet it was like watching poetry in motion at times! The final scores, Swansea 98 : 45 Belfast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;So, at the end of day one, the rankings were as follows...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1st&lt;/strong&gt; - Severn Roller Torrent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2nd&lt;/strong&gt; - Swansea City Slayers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd&lt;/strong&gt; - Northern Fights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4th&lt;/strong&gt; - Belfast Banshees&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;"&gt;Day 2 would see 1st (Severn) play 4th (Belfast), then 2nd (Swansea) play 3rd (Fights) in hour long bouts. The losers of those would then play each other to contest 3rd and 4th place for the tournament before the winners faced off to determine who would skate away with the coveted...Golden Skate! &lt;em&gt;oooooooh&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/image14.png"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2951" alt="image14" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/image14.png" width="469" height="142"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align:center;"&gt;DAY TWO!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The first hour long bout of the day would see Severn Roller Torrent take on the (now rested) Belfast Banshees to determine the first finalist!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2952 alignright" alt="image15" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/image15.png" width="163" height="176"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir='"ltr'&gt;Both teams were determined to make the most of the opportunity and attacked hard from the first whistle. Ra-Ra-Rasputina for Belfast was on fire in the early going. Eventually, the pace of the game slowed as both teams found their rhythm and tried to contain each other. In the end, Severn came away with the win and booked their place in the final with a winning score of 139 to 103. A close fought bout which left both teams drained! This one literally could’ve gone either way right up until the last couple of jams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;In the 2nd bout of the day, the hosts Swansea would take on the Northern Fights. In the ranking bouts the previous day, the Slayers had picked up the win. But this…was a full hour long bout. Could the Fights avenge the defeat and book their place in the final? Yes. Yes they could. But they would have to work hard for it. The Slayers lead 126 to 59 at the end of the first half. But the Fights came out fighting in the second half. With 5 minutes left on the clock, the girls from Aberdeen had managed to get themselves into a 30 point lead. A few power jams later and the final score ended at Swansea 173 : 239 Northern Fights. There were tears from The Swansea team, most notably from Team Captain Pixie of Pain. She may have been one of the smallest skaters on track, but no-one has a bigger heart! She was consoled by her team-mates, but there was no time to rest as they would be back on track very soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/image17.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2953" alt="image17" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/image17.png" width="182" height="224"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The Slayers faced off against the Belfast Banshees next to determine the 3rd and 4th place positions for the tournament. Once again, Ra-Ra-Rasputina was jamming like a woman possessed for Belfast. They lead at the halfway mark 129 to 66. But the Slayers would not be denied. Determined to go out on a high, they staged an amazing fight back in the 2nd half. The Mortician and Pixie Of pain were immense and the final scores for this bout were Swansea 238 : 173 Belfast meaning that the Slayers would finish Quad Nations in 3rd place and the Banshees would take 4th. Considering the turmoil they had to go through just to make it to Swansea, the Belfast side could finish the weekend with their heads held high after an amazingly gutsy performance. The Slayers were dancing…their announcer was in tears, emotion was spilling out alllll over the place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2954" alt="image16" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/image16.png" width="185" height="222"&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;And so, we came to the final. This is what the whole weekend was about. Who would take home the coveted Golden Skate? We were about to find out. The atmosphere was electric and after the kit check, we were ready to get underway! Scarlett Shadow of Severn had been one of the most consistent jammers of the tournament so far and she was determined to fire her team into 1st place. But Clinically Wasted (the team captain) was in a similar frame of mind for the Northern Fights. The Fights were in the lead at half time, but only just. Severn 76 : 98 Fights. The 2nd half was frantic. Fast packs, confusion over ref calls (the noise was drowning them out!) and skaters flying everywhere! In the end, the Fights were able to extend their lead. The final scores were Severn Roller Torrent 126 : The Northern Fights 162! They had done it. After an 11 hour drive from Aberdeen, the Granite Girls had claimed the Golden Skate as their own! Now it was the turn of THEIR announcer to break down in tears!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Once they dust had settled, it was time for the presentation of the awards to each team…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4th place – &lt;em&gt;The Belfast Banshees&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Blocker&lt;/strong&gt; – #8 Mo Mawlem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Jammer&lt;/strong&gt; - #28 (team captain) Hannahbolic Steroids&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MVP&lt;/strong&gt; - #1337 Ra-Ra-Rasputina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd place – &lt;em&gt;The Swansea City Slayers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Blocker&lt;/strong&gt; – #22 Fearne Rotten&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Jammer&lt;/strong&gt; - #7 The Mortician&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MVP&lt;/strong&gt; – #17 SallyMangle Her&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2nd place – &lt;em&gt;Severn Roller Torrent&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Blocker&lt;/strong&gt; - #4ce Jedi Mistress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Jammer&lt;/strong&gt; - #11 Scarlett Shadow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MVP&lt;/strong&gt; - #10 Helen Fury&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1st place – &lt;em&gt;The Northern Fights&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Blocker&lt;/strong&gt; - #42 Pert Hits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Jammer&lt;/strong&gt; - #111 (team captain) Clinically Wasted&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MVP&lt;/strong&gt; - #09 (vice-captain) Rock ‘n’ Riot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align:center;"&gt;A huge congratulations to all the skaters who took part, a thank you to Swansea for hosting an amazing weekend of derby action. Also, a shout out to all the ref’s and NSO’s for being all kinds of brilliant!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>quad nations</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/09/20/guest-bout-report-quad-nations/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 13:38:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls Home Season 2013, Bout 1 Cherry Bombers v Leithal Weapons</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/01/22/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-season-2013-bout-1-cherry-bombers-v-leithal-weapons/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/424389_907757491774_2107291117_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-2133" alt="424389_907757491774_2107291117_n" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/424389_907757491774_2107291117_n.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="460"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Cherry Bombers Best Blocker Maulibu Barbie watches out for the Leithals' Sharlotte Fever, jamming.
&lt;p&gt;Saturday 19th of January saw the first public bout in Scotland played under the new WFTDA rules. Most famously, these rules remove minor penalties in favour of a streamlined officiation process where only major penalties can be awarded; however, they also make a host of other changed, including starting both the pack and the jammers on the same single starting whistle.
Auld Reekie started their home season last year in the first third of the year as, amongst other things, a way to warm up after the Christmas/Hogmanay break, but the timing this year has been particularly advantageous, giving them also a chance to get more practice with the new rules before bouting against other leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first bout saw last home season winners, the nautical/steampunk themed Leithal Weapons, up against "zombie highschool" themed Cherry Bombers. Both teams were playing with a reduced roster, with the Bombers particularly affected, down to only 9 skaters, and one of their star jammers, Circuit Breaker, suffering from the flu. The skate-out can be found &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ggVfYvsFSlI&amp;amp;list=PLsfV1BOiVrnEvF6D1YCYGwx1C4pdeBGeb&amp;amp;index=1"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the start, the Leithal Weapons pulled out an initial advantage, ARRG star jammer Admiral Attackbar (11:11) and vice-captain Alma Geddon (42) both scoring in the initial jams, to bring the score after the first 4 minutes to a 13 to nil lead.
Nevertheless, 13 points is nothing at the start of a bout, and the Bombers looked like fighting right back when new skater Para'beat'em'all (62) took lead jammer in the very next jam... only to pick up a track cut major during her scoring pass just before trying to call the jam off! With the power-jam for Leithals new skater Sharlotte Fever (1924) to exploit, things went from bad to worse for the Bombers, a chain reaction of penalties resulting in, at one point, only Teenie Bash (208), ex of Fair City Rollers, on the track to oppose her.
Hampered by their reduced roster, the Bombers were unable to recover quickly from their penalty situation, with the penalty box refilling as overstretched blockers picked up more penalties before their comrades could escape to join them. The Leithals capitalised, pushing the score into triple figures with multiple power jams before Teenie Bash finally managed to score for the red team,
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;6&lt;/b&gt; Cherry Bombers : &lt;strong&gt;115&lt;/strong&gt; Leithal Weapons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;still with around 12 minutes left in the period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JtiUWIvYJOo&amp;amp;list=PLsfV1BOiVrnEvF6D1YCYGwx1C4pdeBGeb&amp;amp;index=2"&gt;VIDEO&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A power-jam for Circuit Breaker, brought a much needed boost in the underdogs' score, almost tripling it to 16 before she called the jam. The Leithals struck back immediately, however, with Yin and Bang effortlessly taking lead jammer the very next jam, while Teenie Bash struggled for some time with an imposing front-wall masterminded by Leithals pivot Admiral Attackbar, although both jammers were held well on their scoring passes, Velosidy exerting herself particularly to hold back the opposing scorer. Still, Teenie managed to pick up a single scoring pass, to be followed by a second magnificent display from Circuit, taking lead jammer and sneaking in a single scoring pass ahead of an accelerating Alma Geddon in hot pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the final scoring pass for the red team this period, though, with the final 8 minutes dominated by the Leithal Weapons once more, thanks partly to a recurrence of the Bombers' penalty issues from earlier on. Playing with such a reduced roster was telling on their skaters, allowing the Leithals to dominate the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the period, the score stood at an intimidating
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt; Cherry Bombers : &lt;strong&gt;216&lt;/strong&gt; Leithal Weapons&lt;/p&gt;
-
&lt;p&gt;Half-time saw the second appearance of &lt;a href="http://www.choiredinburgh.co.uk/"&gt;Sing in the City&lt;/a&gt; at a bout, an Edinburgh-based modern choir and Auld Reekie's regular half-time entertainment for this Home Season. Beginning with a medley including "Auld Reekie", the reworked version of "Hey Mickey" that serves as Auld Reekie's anthem, the choir moved on to Coldplay's "Viva La Vida", a safe choice for a modern choir's first opening to an audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/385277_907756438884_1922633653_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-2134" alt="Ciderella chases down Circuit Breaker in one of the several jammer-on-jammer duels in the bout." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/385277_907756438884_1922633653_n.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Ciderella chases down Circuit Breaker in one of the several jammer-on-jammer duels in the bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning from half-time, the Cherry Bombers faced a difficult challenge to win with an almost 200 point deficit. In fact, an almost immediate&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zip5T4OB1mg&amp;amp;list=PLsfV1BOiVrnEvF6D1YCYGwx1C4pdeBGeb&amp;amp;index=3"&gt; power jam&lt;/a&gt; for the Leithals once more, Circuit Breaker (100) spending time in the penalty box, whilst Yin and Bang (39) racked up a few more points, immediately increased their deficit even more...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The increasingly exhausted Bombers only managing to pick up 10 points in by the end of the third 15 minutes, it was looking even better for the team in blue as they picked up 113 in the same time, bringing the score to
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;34&lt;/strong&gt; Cherry Bombers : &lt;strong&gt;329&lt;/strong&gt; Leithal Weapons&lt;/p&gt;
A long official timeout sent additional members of both teams to the penalty box and, devastatingly for a team with an already tiny roster, sent Bombers team captain Velosidy off track as she fouled out at her 7th sin-bin trip.
&lt;p&gt;With the Leithal Weapons also down on blockers, however, the very next jam saw Teenie Bash pick up a valuable 3-point pass, albeit the last scoring tha the Bombers would get for the next five minutes. Superior blocking from the Leithals continued to tell, pushing their score closer and closer to a 10:1 ratio, sitting at:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;37&lt;/strong&gt; Cherry Bombers : &lt;strong&gt;354&lt;/strong&gt; Leithal Weapons&lt;/p&gt;
with only 10 minutes on the clock.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r6djsx2XIV8&amp;amp;list=PLsfV1BOiVrnEvF6D1YCYGwx1C4pdeBGeb&amp;amp;index=4"&gt;VIDEO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just when it looked like the Leithals would actually manage to win with a 10:1 score ratio, a slightly misjudged piece of skating by Alma Geddon, returning from stradding the line to in-bounds to pick up a track cut major, handed the power jam to the Bombers' Teenie Bash, to the loud delight of all of the Cherry Bombers fans in the audience. After getting over her own elation, Teenie capitalised, pushing her team's score up by 10 vital points. After a brief team-timeout, The Bombers maintained their momentum, Circuit Breaking taking lead jammer mere fractions of a second ahead of the Leithals' Ciderella (3), and engaging in a protracted and close-fought defensive jamming duel before calling it off. With Teenie Bash back on track for the next jam, yet another Leithals track cut, this time by Yin and Bang, handed the her the second power jam of the last 5 minutes, and a 19 point power jam. Just 5 minutes had made Teenie the Cherry Bombers' highest scoring player by a landslide, bringing in more than half of the teams' score for the bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a bout timing issue causing head ref Righteous Oxide to allow one final jam, it was Kaos Moss who took back control for the Leithal Weapons for a final frosting of points, leaving the final score at:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;66&lt;/strong&gt; Cherry Bombers : &lt;strong&gt;395&lt;/strong&gt; Leithal Weapons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/74614_907756049664_1997508534_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2135" alt="74614_907756049664_1997508534_n" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/74614_907756049664_1997508534_n.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Skater awards were given to:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table border="0" align="center"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cherry Bombers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leithal Weapons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Blocker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Maulibu Barbie&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Minnie Riot&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Jammer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Teenie Bash&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Sharlotte Fever&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most Valuable Player&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Circuit Breaker&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Ciderella&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
The next bout in the Auld Reekie Roller Girls Home Season is February 16th, where the Cherry Bombers, hopefully back up to a full roster, will take on The Skatefast Club.&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>cherry bombers</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>leithal weapons</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/01/22/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-season-2013-bout-1-cherry-bombers-v-leithal-weapons/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 19:31:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fair City Rollers Vs Furness Firecrackers Bout Report</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/10/08/fair-city-rollers-vs-furness-firecrackers-bout-report/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perths finest,the &lt;a href="http://www.faircityrollers.com/"&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; played host in a James Bond themed bout against Cumbria's &lt;a href="http://www.furnessfirecrackers.co.uk/index.php"&gt;Furness Firecrackers&lt;/a&gt; on Saturday the 29th of September 2012, in the superb setting of the Bells Sports Centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/10/fcrfurness-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/10/fcrfurness-1.jpg" alt="" title="fcrfurness 1" width="614" height="188" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1799"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Stu Mackin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first few jams of the first period were very low scoring,with both teams assessing the oppositions strengths and weaknesses.Lead Jammer status alternated between the two and things were shaping up nicely for an interesting bout when,in jam 4,the scoreboard went down and an official timeout lasted until a barebones scoreboard was re-established.The enforced break of the timeout,seemed to serve Furness well and in the next few,fast-moving jams they built up a lead over Perth,with Hell For Heather and Steffinately Maybe in particular doing some excellent point scoring,Jam 7 ended 51-20 in favour of the Firecrackers.
Jam 8 saw the Maidens start a slow fightback.A powerjam in Perth's favour gave Louisville Destroier a chance to redress the points balance and despite some excellent recycling work from Furness she managed to pull the score back to 53-35.The next two jams saw the Maidens continue to chip away at the points deficit,but the combination of a  powerjam for Furness and two Maidens in the Bin in Jam 11 saw them,stretch out in front again a little,roughly halfway through the first period the scores stood at 66-50.
In the next two jams the Firecrackers extended their lead,taking lead jammer status in both and creeping the score upwards in their favour again,they continued to dominate the next few jams,denying Perth lead jammer status in all but one with excellent pack work.Jam 18 saw the turning point,when Jaggy Sw'aggie took the score to 87-74,in a powerjam for the Maidens and calling it off to start the next jam with Doh! still in the bin.Perth took advantage of this to put another ten points on the board,but not before the Furness jammer,now released,managed to score two.Perth kept up the pressure over the next two jams,taking lead in both and pulling the scores ever closer by four points with half time fast approaching,to make the score 89-88
The last jam of the half was a hard-fought one,both teams wanting to take the lead into the second period,despite some stellar walls from the Firecrackers skaters Tash Bandicoot,Steely'll Kill'Her and Kammakezzie,it was the Maidens Jaggy Sw'aggie that took the points as her opposite number,Doh!,was sent to the bin once more.Ending the first period with a Perth lead,89-98&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first jams of the second period saw Furness determined to narrow the points gap and Perth equally determined to keep things in their favour,by three jams in,the Firecrackers began to claw back some points with the score now 103-115,three more and the eight point difference had gone down to seven.An old school pivot line start saw Furness take lead ,get a powerjam and take the score to 117-124.The next jam,Doh! took lead and racked up a much-needed eighteen points in a powerjam for the visitors,score now 135-124.The next two jams saw Perth,at first hold Furness in check,allowing them to only score a few points.The following play saw Perth bring themselves back in close with a useful seven point powerjam,held back from scoring more by a disciplined Firecrackers pack bring the score to 138-133.Furness stepped up the pressure over the next two jams,denying Perth any points with some superb walls and pack work,keeping jams short,taking the four and out,building their lead to 149-133.
In jam 35 Stephinately Maybe took lead for Furness and with three of the Maidens in the bin,easily took the score up to 184-133.Perth rallied and held the next jam pointless for both teams,the next few after that saw low scoring,with some great pack work from both sides preventing either from taking full advantage,It took another three jams before the scores crept up to 192-146.With five minutes to go on the clock in jam 41,Furness failed to field a jammer,which gave Perth's Pistol Panties the opportunity to put a very impressive and much-needed 34 points on the board,much to the fans delight this brought the Maidens right back into the running,making the score now 199-180.The last two jams of the bout were again,hard-fought affairs,with the sides closely matched,despite a huge effort from Perth,the bout ended in favour of the Furness Firecrackers,final score 200-182.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/10/fcrfurness-2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/10/fcrfurness-2.jpg" alt="" title="fcrfurness 2" width="614" height="261" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1801"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Stu Mackin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MVP's for the Firecrackers were-
Best Blocker-Steely'll Kill'Her
Best Jammer-Steffinately Maybe
Best Dressed-Kit Kruger
MVP-Yorky Thud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and for Fair City Rollers
Best Blocker-Mini Me
Best Jammer-Jaggy Sw'aggie
Best Dressed-Knock Turnal
MVP-Louisville Destroier&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>fcr</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/10/08/fair-city-rollers-vs-furness-firecrackers-bout-report/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 20:37:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bout Report: Glasgow Roller Derby v Stockholm Roller Derby Double Header</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/30/bout-report-glasgow-roller-derby-v-stockholm-roller-derby-double-header/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/grdstock.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/grdstock.jpg" alt="" title="grdstock" width="614" height="274" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1224"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photograph by Sam Skipsey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bout report for the recent GRD double header against Stockholm Roller Derby is up on &lt;a href="http://aoanla.blogspot.co.uk/2012/04/bout-report-glasgow-roller-derby-v.html"&gt;Ante Ortus A Novus Lumen Ars&lt;/a&gt;.All the usual pics and video, as well as a comprehensive report to feast your eyes on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>grd</category><category>irn bruisers</category><category>maiden grrders</category><category>pictures</category><category>video</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/30/bout-report-glasgow-roller-derby-v-stockholm-roller-derby-double-header/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 10:50:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bout Report: Glasgow Roller Derby v Granite City Roller Girls &amp; Berlin Bombshells </title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/03/20/bout-report-glasgow-roller-derby-v-granite-city-roller-girls-berlin-bombshells/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/03/grd-gcrg.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/03/grd-gcrg.jpg" alt="" title="grd gcrg" width="614" height="429" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-979"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head over to &lt;a href="http://aoanla.blogspot.co.uk/2012/03/bout-report-glasgow-roller-derby-v.html"&gt;Ante Ortus A Novus Lumen Ars&lt;/a&gt; for a fine bout report for the recent &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; double header featuring GRD's Maiden Grrders against &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/GraniteCityRollerGirls"&gt;Granite City Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; and the Irn Bruisers up against the mighty &lt;a href="http://bearcityrollerderby.com/"&gt;Berlin Bombshells&lt;/a&gt;.Plus all the usual pictures and video to peruse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/03/grd-berlin.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/03/grd-berlin.jpg" alt="" title="grd berlin" width="614" height="369" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-978"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All photographs by Sam Skipsey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>grd</category><category>irn bruisers</category><category>maiden grrders</category><category>pictures</category><category>video</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/03/20/bout-report-glasgow-roller-derby-v-granite-city-roller-girls-berlin-bombshells/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 11:31:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bout Report: Fierce Valley Roller Girls vs Dundee Roller Girls in "Bruise Brothers" </title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/02/27/bout-report-fierce-valley-roller-girls-vs-dundee-roller-girls-in-bruise-brothers/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/02/bruise.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/02/bruise.jpg" alt="" title="bruise" width="614" height="446" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-893"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Laura MacDonald&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head over to &lt;a href="http://aoanla.blogspot.com/2012/02/bout-report-fierce-valley-roller-girls.html"&gt;Ante Ortus A Novus Ars&lt;/a&gt; to read the bout report for the &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girl's&lt;/a&gt; Parma Violents first public bout against &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girl's&lt;/a&gt; Silvery Tayzers.
For another view of the bout,you can read Rochelle Stewart's bout report over on the Fierce Valley Roller Girls &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/news-story.php?id=29"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.This was originally published in The Alloa Advertiser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>drg</category><category>fvrg</category><category>parma violents</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>video</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/02/27/bout-report-fierce-valley-roller-girls-vs-dundee-roller-girls-in-bruise-brothers/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 14:02:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bout Report: GCRG Intraleague: Slaughtership Down 12 Feb 2012 </title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/02/18/bout-report-gcrg-intraleague-slaughtership-down-12-feb-2012/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/02/sdownpic.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/02/sdownpic.jpg" alt="" title="sdownpic" width="614" height="365" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-875"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by Aoanla&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another quality bout report awaits your perusal at &lt;a href="http://aoanla.blogspot.com/2012/02/bout-report-gcrg-intraleague.html"&gt;Ante Ortus A Novus Lumen Ars&lt;/a&gt;,this time for the recent and much anticipated &lt;a href="http://www.granitecityrollergirls.org/"&gt;Granite city Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; first ever intraleague bout.All the usual pictures and video are there too.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>gcrg</category><category>intraleague</category><category>pictures</category><category>video</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/02/18/bout-report-gcrg-intraleague-slaughtership-down-12-feb-2012/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 12:17:38 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>