<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about british championships)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/british-championships.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 29 June 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-29062019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend's highlights are back to our two update format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've broken our rule slightly for Germany this weekend, as it's important not to miss the Mine Monsters' birthday game, but also it's a good weekend for the German Bundesliga in Erfurt. And as usual there's so much stuff in France, we're giving them two entries for two two-day events...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also two firsts this weekend; the first ever Tasmanian Tournament kicks off in Australia, and the first ever Norwegian National Tournament (and Championship) is this weekend in Sadnes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/29Jun-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-29062019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentine roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>austrian roller derby</category><category>belgian roller derby</category><category>brazilian roller derby</category><category>british championships</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>costa rican roller derby</category><category>czech roller derby</category><category>estonian roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>irish roller derby</category><category>italian roller derby</category><category>mexican roller derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>new zealand roller derby</category><category>norwegian roller derby</category><category>south african roller derby</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-29062019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 19:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BCR Host the final game day of Champs Tier 2 North</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/bcr_host_final_game_day_bct2nm/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/bairncityrollers"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; started off their 2019 and their champs campaign in the best way possible (you can read more about that here) . Their two wins in their first two Champs games saw them sit third in their group with six points despite having played one less game than the two teams above them, who had played three each. Their next two games came against those two teams: first they took on North Wales Mens and then T&amp;amp;F: Inglorious B*Stars. Both opponents took the wins in very hard fought games ending their 2019 Champs season 1st and 2nd in the group, 2 weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="British Champs Tier 2 M N leaderboard, showing the current state of play, including BCR at the middle of the table." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/MRDAside2-2019.png"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst those two teams have finished their champs season, the other teams in the group still have one more game and each team still has everything to play for. The last game day of Tier 2 North takes place on Scottish ground, with BCR hosting this fantastic battle at Grangemouth Sports Complex on the 29th of June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This double header could not have been set up more perfectly for the final set of games, as each match is a decider and will see the teams involved fighting for their final position against their opponent. Hosts BCR will be taking on The Inhuman League, with the winner of that game finishing 3rd in the group and the loser coming 4th. Whilst the other game will see Knights of Oldham play Teesside Skate Invaders, with the loser unfortunately ending up with the wooden spoon for the tier, and facing potential relegation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both games are shaping up to be quite a close battle as by their results so far each are evenly matched. So every team will be pulling out all the stops to get that final win in this years champs competition to finish above their opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors are at 1.15pm and tickets are only £5 on the door, find out more and keep up to date on the Facebook event page &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/2402082363156371/"&gt;https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/2402082363156371/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Flyer for the final fixtuer in British Champs Tier 2 M N; 29th June, 2019 at Grangemouth Sports Complex." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/BCR-flyer.png"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>british championships</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/bcr_host_final_game_day_bct2nm/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 11:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Derby - Midseason and Mansfield</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/05/midseason-update-drd-2019/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;With home games in Dundee coming few this season, DRDs Bonnie Colliders have only hosted Auld Reekie Roller Derby's C team, ASTROs last month. The two sides had played each other back in 2016, with 2 wins for Colliders to ASTRO's 1. However the inherent nature of constantly altering B/C teams rosters led to this match up being two brand new teams facing each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Photo of Shiv (Colliders Co-Captain)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/05/shiv-photo-dundee.jpg" style="width: 50%;"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Shiv #165 (Colliders Co-Captain)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Shiv #165 (Colliders Co-Captain)&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;“The ASTROs game was a tough season opener for us and even though we lost we had a fantastic time out on track! We learned a lot about how we work together as a team and it gave us some areas to focus our training on going forward”&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A closely fought game, with the new Colliders being led by Shiv #165 and Macfarlane #606, showed a settling in period for the new Dundee roster with the ASTROs side taking the win [221 v 166]. With a month of training and working together under their belt the Colliders are looking forward to hosting Mansfield Roller derby on the 25th May at the DISC in Dundee!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="DRG v Mansfield Banner" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/05/drd-v-mansfield.jpg"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Macfarlane #606 (Colliders Co-Captain)&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;“Playing against the Astros was a good way to start our season. We knew they would be a challenge but we learned a lot from it.”&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Shiv #165&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;“We’re going into the Mansfield game with a fourteen skater roster which is pretty much unheard of for Dundee! We’ve been working so hard at training and I’m hoping that we see all that hard work come together in the game.”&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A previous match up, again back in 2016, saw the Colliders take on Mansfield B to a 275 v 75 victory. What will 2019 Collider roster have to offer on the against the Mansfield A side? Will Mansfield return South triumphant?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Photo of Macfarlane (Colliders Co-Captain)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/05/macfarlane-photo-dundee.jpg" style="width: 50%;"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Macfarlane #606 (Colliders Co-Captain)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Macfarlane #606&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;“We are looking forward to the game this weekend. We've had plenty of time to train together for this game and we are really feeling the benefit of this.”&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this single header opening its doors at 2:50, and the action starting at 3pm, you are ensured some fantastic derby! For more information on the upcoming event, visit the facebook page!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 25/05/2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where: Dundee DISC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time: 2:50pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event page: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/881902268809143/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/881902268809143/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>british championships</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/05/midseason-update-drd-2019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Positive Start to 2019 for BCR</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/05/a_positive_start_to_2019_for_bcr/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018 was a mixed year for Bairn City Rollers. Whilst some members of the league were busy;
the league not as much. Although BCR had members involved in the Men’s Roller Derby World Cup
covering Power of Scotland, Wales and Italy squads (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/27/bairn-city-rollers-central-scotlands-international-derby-league/"&gt;read more about that here&lt;/a&gt;), each of their
three teams at BCR (Women’s, OTA &amp;amp; Men’s) only managed 1 game each in the whole year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many other leagues up and down the country, BCR saw quite a few members retire from Derby
after years of involvement and even a couple move on to other leagues. With numbers shrinking,
BCR looked towards recruitment and, after a positive meeting with GMRD, the two leagues decided to
pool resources and started sharing one training session a week. This helped both leagues save
on hall costs, whilst at the same time helping with numbers at training, allowing them to run better
and more complex drills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During those difficult times BCR were always looking forward and, with 2019 in mind, they decided
to enter into &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.britishchamps.com/"&gt;British Champs&lt;/a&gt; for the second time, having previously competed in 2017. Unlike their previous
entry to Champs as the Skelpies, this time around BCR decided to enter the OTA team. Again
they find themselves in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.britishchamps.com/league-tables/t2m/north/"&gt;MRDA-Tier 2 North&lt;/a&gt;, but this time as the only OTA team in the tier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, BCR have already played their first two of five games in Champs. On February 9th they
travelled down to Manchester to take on Knights of Oldham at the Thunderdome. After an early rise
for most of the team to travel down they took the win, 209 to 108.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to April 20th and
again they were on the road down South, but this time to Middlesbrough to take on Teesside Skate Invaders
(TSI). The last time BCR were in Champs, as the Skelpies, their last game of the tier was against TSI, where
BCR lost by 20 points. This time around however BCR’s OTA took the win, 180 to 136.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bairn City Rollers OTA Roster [Photo: Bairn City Rollers]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/05/bcr-article-group1.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bairn City Rollers OTA Roster [Photo: Bairn City Rollers]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next week, they will be road tripping to Newcastle to play current tier #1, North Wales Roller Derby Men's. Then, in June,
they have a trip away to Wales to play Newcastle's Tyne and Fear B, before their final game of Champs at the end of June.
BCR will be hosting the final game day of the tier in a double header at Grangemouth on June 29th where they
will skate against The Inhuman League.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With two wins in Champs so far, BCR OTA sit third in their group with six points despite
having played one less game than the teams second and first (thanks to an unbroken set of wins).
Those two wins have led to a significant increase in BCR's &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/coed/coed_europe"&gt;Flat Track Stats Global&lt;/a&gt; ranking. BCR OTA are now ranked 3rd in Europe and 20th overall of all OTA teams
on Flat Track Stats (FTS calls this selection "Co-Ed" still).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="British Champs Tier-2 MN Results Table (as of 3 May 2019) [Copyright: British Championships]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/05/bc_t2mn_3May2019.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;British Champs Tier-2 MN Results Table (as of 3 May 2019) [Copyright: British Championships]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst their wins in Champs have been a great start for their OTA team, BCR’s Central Belters have also
started their year in winning ways. They have already gotten their first game of the year out of the way taking the win over
GRD’s Maiden Grrders, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/108318"&gt;179 to 149&lt;/a&gt;. That means they have been unbeaten in seven consecutive games, stretching
back to November 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They're also starting to see their numbers increase from their recruitment drive, with new skaters and
along with some transfers arriving as well. Along with those new faces, some old ones have reappeared as some retired
skaters from other leagues have decided to pull their skates back on and have choose BCR to do just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bairn City Rollers [Photo: Bairn City Rollers]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/05/bcr-article-group2.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bairn City Rollers [Photo: Bairn City Rollers]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news doesn’t stop there: Bairn City Rollers have seen their skaters making it onto both Wales' and Power of Scotland's training
squads for the Men’s Roller Derby World Cup 2020. There is also the possibility of a BCR member appearing on the Team Italy squad, with
tryouts still taking place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With more games penned for the rest of 2019 for their Women’s and OTA team, this year is starting to look like a good one for
BCR and its members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their first home game of the season will be BCR’s final Champs game on the 29th of June: for more
information head over to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2402082363156371/"&gt;event page here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>british championships</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/05/a_positive_start_to_2019_for_bcr/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>