<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about british championship)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/british-championship.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>National Champions 2018 - a Review of the Year.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/01/09/national-champions-2018-a-review-of-the-year/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor's note: due to burn-out, and the increasingly obnoxious changes on the Wordpress backend, our end of year feature content has been delayed. We'll be releasing it over the next few weeks as we complete it. This is the first item in this content. We apologise for the delays incurred, and will update you all on the future of SRD when we know what that is.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the growth of Roller Derby worldwide, there has also come increasing regional organisation. Since 2010, and especially since the first Roller Derby World Cup in 2011 focussed thoughts on National structures, a number of nations, and nation-like entities, have begun organising various "National Tournaments" within themselves. At SRD, we consider these to be as important as any other large scale tournament - such as WFTDA or MRDA events - especially as they can also be more inclusive than such series due to reduced travel costs and membership requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, we'd like to highlight the winners of each such tournament series we're aware of in 2018 - and briefly cover the tournaments themselves. As a historical resource, we also host a summary of all of the winners of the tournaments (and some references for them) here: &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/NationalTournaments.html"&gt;National Tournaments (2010-)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;We'll start with the two largest such events (it's hard to judge which is larger, as they have exchanged places on various metrics year to year):&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;UK&amp;amp;Ireland ("&lt;a href="https://www.britishchamps.com/"&gt;British Championships&lt;/a&gt;")&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;British Champs has been running since 2015, and has made various changes to its structure over the years (the most recent to improve inclusion and accessibility). It is structured as a multi-tiered divisional system, with each "skill level" tier divided into one or more geographical "divisions"; teams promote/relegate between tiers between seasons. Since 2016, Champs has officially run parallel tournaments for WFTDA- and MRDA- conforming teams, and has also allowed competition from non-A teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, the WFTDA-side tournament winners, topping Tier 1 convincingly were: &lt;strong&gt;Central City Roller Derby (Birmingham), &lt;/strong&gt;not only winning every game against their opponents, but also achieving a significantly higher points difference than the second spot team, Liverpool.
2018 has been a good year for Birmingham teams, as the city's other team, Birmingham Blitz Dames, also hosted the first ever WFTDA Continental Cup in Europe later in the season.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MRDA-side tournament  was topped extremely impressively by &lt;strong&gt;New Wheeled Order (Manchester M)&lt;/strong&gt;, also delivering a huge points-difference advantage over second place Tyne and Fear. New Wheeled Order have had a very good few years, and we expect even more from them in 2019.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;France ("Championnat de France Roller Derby")&lt;/h4&gt;
The French National tournament series is, like the similarly sized British Champs, organised into Tiers by strength, and also loosely divided into geographical regions. (Unlike British Champs, there is competition across regions within a tier; also unlike BC, the Championnat is run directly as part of the French NGB, the FFRS.) The Championnat de France has &lt;em&gt;Feminin&lt;/em&gt;- and &lt;em&gt;Masculin&lt;/em&gt;- parallel tournaments; some leagues submit teams to the tournament which differ from their Travel teams, and the relaxed structure of the tournament also allows for "combined" team submissions from cooperating leagues. Unusually, compared to many of the other tournaments listed here, the French Championnat is fitted to the French sporting season (roughly following the European school year), and so starts in the previous winter, and finishes in the early summer each year.
&lt;p&gt;Repeating their victory in 2017, &lt;strong&gt;Nothing Toulouse (Roller Derby Toulouse)&lt;/strong&gt; retained the French Championship this year. They remain one of the few non-WFTDA member leagues to hold a Championship position in their home country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Undefeated champions since the Championnat started in 2016, &lt;strong&gt;Quad Guards (Toulouse M)&lt;/strong&gt; continued their streak for another year in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Whilst the French and British tournaments are the largest, they are not the longest running National tournaments. Next, we're going to cover the longest running tournaments in modern Derby, the four which started in 2012:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Sweden (Swedish Roller Derby Seriespel)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Swedish National Tournament,  . Like larger tournaments, the Series is split into tiers ("serien"), with the Eliteserien being the top tier. More recently, Elite tier teams have been allowed to differ from the Travel teams for their league. There is only a WFTDA-gender tournament in Sweden, to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Crime City Rollers (Malmö)&lt;/strong&gt; retained their Championship title for the third year running, placing them one more victory behind Stockholm's streak of 4 wins (from 2012 to 2015).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Finland (Suomi Cup)&lt;/h4&gt;
Finland's National Tournament is structured rather like the Swedish version, including the tendency of Elite tier leagues to submit non-Travel team rosters to the tournament. For the first time, in 2019 the Suomi Cup will be open to non-Finnish teams (making it an interesting extension of "National"), as St Petersburg Roller Derby A, the White Night Furies, compete.
&lt;p&gt;For the first time in 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Oulu Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; achieved the Championship title, breaking a run of alternating wins by Helsinki and Kallio over the previous 6 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Northern Finland also holds its own tournament - the Pohjola Cup - which started the tradition of welcoming non-Finnish participants in previous years via St Petersburg. So, in some ways, it sets the trend for its higher-profile southern relative.]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Mexico (Torneo Nacional de Roller Derby)&lt;/h4&gt;
Mexico's National Tournament series has been organised by their national governing body, the Asociación Mexicana de Roller Derby, since it began in 2012. We've covered the leadup to the current season on the blog previously here: &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/18/mexican-national-championships-2018/"&gt;Mexican National Tournament article&lt;/a&gt;. The series consists of a series of playoffs, selected by rating/ranking in the Mexican league tables (which work using the WFTDA rating scheme), with two divisions. As with many other nations, there are "varonil" and "femenil" parallel tournaments, corresponding to WFTDA- and MRDA- policies.
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Mexico City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; retained their title for a three-year streak of victories, despite&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Varonil side of the tournament, &lt;strong&gt;Disorder Roller Derby (Mexico City M)&lt;/strong&gt; also began a streak, retaining their title from 2017.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Colombia&lt;/h4&gt;
Whilst Colombia has run a National Tournament since 2012, the series has had a somewhat more complex past than the others in this category, with a couple of restructurings, and a hiatus from 2015 to 2016. In its current form, the Tournament consists of two parallel series - a multi-fixture tournament for Bogotá's many leagues (the "Torneo Distrito"), and a separate one for teams in the rest of Colombia (the "Western Region" tournament), with the top teams from both then competing at the Torneo Nacional finals. (&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/01/the-5th-colombian-national-tournament-2018-so-far/"&gt;We've written more about the 2018 series here.&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;p&gt;2018's Champions, &lt;strong&gt;Bogotá Bone Breakers&lt;/strong&gt;, also retained the Bogotá title in 2018, as well as continuing a three win streak in the national series (albeit across that 2 year gap).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Slightly less venerable than the oldest tournaments, but not in the size rank as Britain and France, our next grouping also covers a large geographical area.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Brazil (Brasileirão de Roller Derby)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brazil's national Championship, the Brasileirão, is a single-fixture event at present, which started as least as long ago as 2013 (there's some evidence it started earlier). Due to the distribution of teams in the country, it's semi-invitational, although the highest rated teams in Brazil always attend. (&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/11/the-brasileirao-brazils-national-championships-at-8/"&gt;We've written more about the history of the tournament here.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018's Brasileirão winners were &lt;strong&gt;Gray City Rebels (São Paulo)&lt;/strong&gt;, retaining the title from 2017 (and resisting Ladies of Helltown's attempts to take back the title from 2016).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Chile (Torneo X / Torneo X-Men)&lt;/h4&gt;
Chile has one of the youngest National Tournaments in Latin America, with the first Torneo X beginning in 2015. Year on year, it has gained more participants, and has had to change structure multiple times to accommodate this, currently using a playoffs and finals structure. For the first time in 2018, B teams have been allowed to compete, enabling Chile's strongest (and only WFTDA-member) league, Metropolitan Roller Derby, to compete with its Bayonetas.
Since 2017, there has also been a MRDA-gender tournament, the Torneo X-Men, run in parallel, and loosely associated with the original WFTDA-gender event.
(&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/26/chilean-national-championships-2018-torneo-x-returns/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We've covered an intro to this year's Torneo X earlier on the blog.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;p&gt;For the first time ever, 2018's winners are a B-team: &lt;strong&gt;Bayonetas (Metropolitan B | Santiago)&lt;/strong&gt;, taking a fairly commanding win in the final bout.
In the Torneo X-Men, which finished earlier in the year, &lt;strong&gt;Terror S-Quad (Santiago M)&lt;/strong&gt; were victorious for a second time in a row.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Germany (Bundesliga Roller Derby)&lt;/h4&gt;
The German National Tournament, or Bundesliga, formally started in 2015, as a multi-tier tournament run by the German NGB, Roller Derby Deutschland (RDD). In this form, its history has been tracked by Derbyposition.de since the beginning; the structure is much like the much larger French and British tournaments, but without the need for multiple geographical divisions, due to its smaller number of teams. (There were two previous events which might count as "German National Tournaments", in 2010 and 2013, but they are not part of the modern event.)
As with several other National series in nations with very high rated WFTDA-member leagues, those leagues have begun sending "non-Travel teams" to represent them in the tournament.
&lt;p&gt;For the first time in the tournament's history, &lt;strong&gt;Dresden Pioneers&lt;/strong&gt; comprehensively won the Bundesliga Division 1 in 2018.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Australia (Australian National Tournament &amp;amp; Australian Men's Nationals)&lt;/h4&gt;
Unusually, Australia has not had a formally denoted "National Tournament" for WFTDA leagues (although you could claim that the Great Southern Slam counts, given the scope of its attendance). The Australian Men's Roller Derby organisation, on the other hand, has organised an Australian Men's Nationals since 2015, as a single fixture tournament towards the end of the year.
More recently, an unusual "State-teams" style National Tournament has been launched (for the first time in 2018), with WFTDA- and MRDA- gender legs, but we're not sure if this counts as a National tournament in the same sense as the other events in this list.
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Victoria Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; won the Australian Men's Nationals, having lost it for the first time ever in 2017 (to Tasmania!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;For our final grouping, we have another eclectic selection of Nations, all united in having run a National series for 3 years or less.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;New Zealand (Top 10 Championships)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Zealand's "Top 10 Championships" have been running since 2016, although information on the second year of their organisation is a little patchy due to website bitrot. In general, the series is a flat round-robin style event, distributed across the year, with no tiering or geographical structure. As far as we are aware, there's only a WFTDA-gender version of the tournament so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Dead End Derby (Christchurch)&lt;/strong&gt; won the Top 10 Championships for the first time (ending Wellington's Richter City's streak of 2 years).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Spain (Campeonato Nacional de Roller Derby)&lt;/h4&gt;
The Spanish National tournament is a single event affair, due to the relatively small number of potential competitors in Spain at present. Organised by the Spanish National Governing body, the single tournament sees the top teams in the country play for victory in a single elimination structure. The event has run since 2016, with an additional MRDA parallel event introduced in 2017.
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Roller Derby Madrid&lt;/strong&gt; continued their unbroken win streak since the start of the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, 2018's winners in the other division were &lt;strong&gt;MadRiders (Madrid M)&lt;/strong&gt;, also continuing an unbroken win since last year.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Austria&lt;/h4&gt;
Austria's National tournament only started in 2017; before then, there was effectively only one sufficiently developed team in the country (Vienna Roller Derby), and so no way to hold such an event. Due to the small number of teams, the Austrian National Championship is a single fixture event; and due to the dearth of MRDA teams, it has only a WFTDA leg.
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Vienna Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; retained their title from 2017, although competition within the rest of the teams was strong, Vienna have a significant experience advantage in their country.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;South Africa (National Derby Fest)&lt;/h4&gt;
South Africa have held a National Championship event since 2016, although that first event included "home teams" from some of the leagues involved. As South Africa has very few leagues with travel teams, this event is a single fixture which also focuses on developing the sport within the nation. (&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/31/south-africas-national-derby-fest-2018-three-years-of-festivals/"&gt;We've written more about the history of the event here.&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, Johannesburg's &lt;strong&gt;Golden City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt; retained their win streak since the dawn of the tournament.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Belgium (Roller Derby Belgium National Tournament)&lt;/h4&gt;
Finally, we come to the newest National tournament in our list: Belgium. The Belgian national tournament, organised by rd.BE, the Belgian NGB, ran for the first time this year, as a year-long series of round-robin fixtures within tiers. (Initial tiers were drawn from FTS Europe ratings.) From the start, the rd.BE event has had a WFTDA- and an MRDA- leg.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antwerp Roller Derby (One Love Roller Dolls)&lt;/strong&gt; are the first ever holders of the rd.BE Championship title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the MRDA leg, Brussels' &lt;strong&gt;Manneken Beasts&lt;/strong&gt; achieved the first ever Championship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Special mention:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Japan (Derby Nights 4x4)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst it's structure is rather different to every other event in this list, we should note that Japan has also had a Tokyo-series first for the first time in 2018. The Derby Nights 4x4 ("DN4x4") series was a multi-fixture event with "womens" and "mens" legs, open to leagues of all affiliations in Japan. (As such, the women's division included both the World Skate/FIRS affiliated Spiral Cats, and all of the WFTDA-affiliated leagues in the Tokyo metropolitan area, from Tokyo Roller Derby to the independent Kamikaze Badass.) This was a unique ruleset, with, we believe, 4 skaters per competing team, and very short period and jam lengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Neon Roller Monsters&lt;/strong&gt; (the submitted team from Tokyo Roller Derby) won the women's division.
The new-in-2018 team, &lt;strong&gt;Tokyo Bar Hoppers&lt;/strong&gt;, won the men's division (which had only 2 teams this year!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're excited to see what happens with this tournament format, and if it expands beyond the Tokyo region to the rest of Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>asociación mexicana de roller derby</category><category>australian men's nationals</category><category>austrian nationals</category><category>brasileirão de roller derby</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>bundesliga</category><category>campeonato nacional de roller derby</category><category>championnat de france</category><category>derby nights 4x4</category><category>international derby</category><category>national derby fest</category><category>rd.be</category><category>suomi cup</category><category>swedish seriespel</category><category>top 10 championships</category><category>torneo nacional de roller derby</category><category>torneo x</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/01/09/national-champions-2018-a-review-of-the-year/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 16:53:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Geography of British Champs - 2015 to 2017</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/20/geography-of-british-champs-2015-to-2017/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since its inaugural run in 2015, the UK's "National Tournament", British Champs, has run on a complex hierarchical tiers and divisions system - with 4 (or 5 in 2016) ability-binned tiers, each subdivided into a variable number of geographically-binned subdivisions (depending on the number of teams in the tier, the number of geographical "divisions" is selected to give 5 to 6 teams per division).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a team ends the year at the top (or bottom) of its tier, it is promoted (or relegated) to an adjacent tier - but the destination &lt;em&gt;division&lt;/em&gt; must also be selected, which causes complications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a geographically split tournament division structure is, arguably, making a rod for one's own back. Quite apart from the geopolitics of "north" and "south" in the British psyche, the additional splitting constraint makes it almost impossible to balance relegation and promotion whilst keeping the bounds of the regions sensible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is increasingly hard for the UK's British Championships, as the tournament is, in fact, &lt;em&gt;shrinking&lt;/em&gt; year-on-year. In 2015, there were 72 competing women's teams; in 2016, 66, and this year there are just &lt;em&gt;61&lt;/em&gt;.
British Champs themselves &lt;em&gt;claim&lt;/em&gt; to be growing, but this is purely because they had no men's tier in 2015 - adding the 20 men's teams in 2016 makes the tournament "bigger", but only in a &lt;em&gt;technical&lt;/em&gt; sense, as there's no cross-over between the men's and women's British Champs tiers. (The Men's British Champs has not changed in size between 2016 and 2017, so overall, Champs has still declined overall in the last year.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've plotted the shapes of the various British Champs Tiers + Divisions over the years to illustrate how they've changed shape - both from teams leaving and (less so) joining the tournament; and from promotion and relegation. (The Tier 5 is not animated, as it only existed for 2016.) On these plots, the dotted straight lines mark the North-South and East-West centrelines of the UK, so you can judge how well Champs manages to represent the geography of the UK in its divisions each year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-21048" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/bct1.gif" alt="bct1" width="618" height="683"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-21049" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/bct2.gif" alt="bct2" width="583" height="681"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-21050" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/bct3.gif" alt="bct3" width="629" height="692"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-21051" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/bct4.gif" alt="bct4" width="567" height="700"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-21052" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/bct5.png" alt="bct5" width="580" height="697"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As can be seen, there are some very odd phenomena caused by the strict tier-and-geographical-division format. We can also see where excessive travel - remember, at least one pair of teams in a given fixture is hosted at another venue in their tier+division - can be a wear on opponents.
One interesting phenomenon is the general migration of several of the South divisions towards the south-west, as promotion and relegation (which is uneven in Champs) requires more central teams to be added to the East divisions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Solutions&lt;/h3&gt;
One should, of course, prefer to critique than criticise. In this spirit, we have some suggestions (drawn from work ongoing for the Roller Derby World Cup 2018) as to how British Champs could improve its efficiency, whilst still providing the core benefit of giving a guaranteed, structured, 4 or 5 games to each participating team. Our suggestions also allow matching teams to close-by opponents, of similar strength; and provided a UK-wide "ranking" and "rating" of the participants.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firstly&lt;/strong&gt;: throw away the strict categories - not just the divisions, but also the tiers. Strict boundaries are the enemy of efficient matching - the teams at the bottom of Tier X should be able to play the top of Tier X+1, and the eastmost teams in West division should be able to play the westmost teams in East division.
Teams in any tier should be able to host games for any other tier. [The German Bundesliga allows this already, for example.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secondly&lt;/strong&gt;: match each team to 5 opponents, on the basis of their proximity and strength relative to the team in question. There are well-understood algorithms for doing this: the minimum-weight, maximum-width matching algorithm has been used for much larger problems than this for decades (and is used by RDWC2018 for scheduling).
[We actually have one additional constraint here: we want the network of teams connected by bouts to span the entire set of competitors. This is easily ensured by using an alternate matching approach for one or two of the picks for each team.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thirdly&lt;/strong&gt;: scheduling of bouts should be arranged so that every team hosts 1 double or triple header. Importantly, none of the games they host should involve them competing - this avoids home team advantage - but instead should be drawn from matches where both teams are closeby. [Because we have no Tiers, there's an ample supply of such matches here.] We assign bouts to hosts by total travel distance, using maximum-weight matching again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fourthly&lt;/strong&gt;: thanks to the constraints in matching above, we can produce a ranking for the teams via any reasonable rating algorithm - Flat Track Stats' Elo-derived rating, either of the SRDRank mechanisms, or others - on the basis of all of the games played over the season. The published yearly rating can be used to establish "Champions", and also to inform the matches for next year.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Example - 2017&lt;/h3&gt;
As an example, we present how the 2017 British Champs would have looked, if run as we propose. In this case, matches have been made using SRDRank ratings from February 2017, if they existed - there are 3 teams which are problematic here (&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Durham City Rolling Angels, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Riverside Rebels Roller Derby, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Arcadia Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;) for which we assigned an "average" ranking as a placeholder. We stand by the &lt;em&gt;bouts&lt;/em&gt; themselves as the best matches possible.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The resulting assignments of bouts to hosts would be the following fixtures (these don't take into account the size of the hosting venue, which obviously may be significant for some fixtures - a more polished version that was written in less than a day would include other considerations, but the bouts themselves would be the same):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Riot City Ravens hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Swansea City Roller Derby vs Bristol Roller Derby (Women's)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames vs Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Reaper Roller Derby vs Oxford Wheels of Gory Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Leeds Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Wakey Wheeled Cats vs Spa Town Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;York Minxters Roller Derby vs North Cheshire Victory Rollers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Preston Roller Girls vs Hereford Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Royal Windsor Roller Girls hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;London Rockin' Rollers vs Big Bucks High Rollers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Hertfordshire Roller Derby vs Wiltshire Roller Derby (Womens)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;York Minxters Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Spa Town Roller Derby vs Lincolnshire Bombers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Grim Reavers vs North Cheshire Victory Rollers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Cambridge Rollerbillies vs Whippin' Hinnies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;London Brawl Saints hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;London Rockin' Rollers vs Cambridge Rollerbillies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Vendetta Vixens vs Killa Hurtz Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Wolverhampton Honour Rollers hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames vs Tender Hooligans&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Bristol Roller Derby (Women's) vs Tender Hooligans&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Leeds Roller Derby vs Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Hallam Hellcats Roller Derby vs Durham City Rolling Angels&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Grim Reavers vs Durham Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Cheshire Hellcats Roller Derbyhosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Wolverhampton Honour Rollers vs Riverside Rebels Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Bath Roller Derby Girls vs Preston Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby vs Swansea City Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Mansfield Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Nottingham Roller Derby (Women's) vs Hallam Hellcats Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Roller Derby Leicester vs Wakey Wheeled Cats&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;London Brawl Saints vs Middlesbrough Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Nottingham Roller Derby (Women's) hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Dolly Rockit Rollers vs Sheffield Steel Rollergirls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Lincolnshire Bombers vs Vendetta Vixens&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Manchester Roller Derby (Women's) vs Cambridge Rollerbillies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Reaper Roller Derby vs Riot City Ravens&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Dorset Roller Girls vs Hereford Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;North Cheshire Victory Rollers vs Plymouth City Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Sheffield Steel Rollergirls hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Spa Town Roller Derby vs Mansfield Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Leeds Roller Derby vs Birmingham Blitz Dames&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Cheshire Hellcats Roller Derby vs Grim Reavers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Cambridge Rollerbillies hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Rebellion Roller Derby vs Hertfordshire Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Vendetta Vixens vs Suffolk Roller Derby (Women's)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Rebellion Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Milton Keynes Roller Derby vs Hertfordshire Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Suffolk Roller Derby (Women's) vs Roller Derby Leicester&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Dolly Rockit Rollers vs Kent Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Bath Roller Derby Girls hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Dorset Roller Girls vs Wiltshire Roller Derby (Womens)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Riot City Ravens vs Oxford Wheels of Gory Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Big Bucks High Rollers vs South West Angels of Terror&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Swansea City Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Reaper Roller Derby vs North Devon Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Neath Port Talbot Roller Derby vs Wirral Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Cornwall Roller Derby vs Riverside Rebels Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Grim Reavers hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Lincolnshire Bombers vs Mansfield Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Norfolk Roller Derby vs Nottingham Roller Derby (Women's)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Sheffield Steel Rollergirls vs Norfolk Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Hallam Hellcats Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Mansfield Roller Derby vs York Minxters Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Nottingham Roller Derby (Women's) vs Arcadia Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;Halifax Bruising Banditas hosts:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Tender Hooligans vs Leeds Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;York Minxters Roller Derby vs Cheshire Hellcats Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;Severn Roller Torrent hosts:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Wiltshire Roller Derby (Womens) vs Wolverhampton Honour Rollers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Bath Roller Derby Girls vs Roller Derby Leicester&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Swansea City Roller Derby vs London Brawl Saints&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Hertfordshire Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Cambridge Rollerbillies vs Big Bucks High Rollers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Roller Derby Leicester vs Killa Hurtz Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Roller Derby Leicester hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Nottingham Roller Derby (Women's) vs Dolly Rockit Rollers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Milton Keynes Roller Derby vs Wolverhampton Honour Rollers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Tender Hooligans vs London Rockin' Rollers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Riverside Rebels Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Wirral Roller Derby vs Manchester Roller Derby (Women's)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Furness Firecrackers (Women's) vs Halifax Bruising Banditas&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Bristol Roller Derby (Women's) hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Hereford Roller Girls vs Bath Roller Derby Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Wolverhampton Honour Rollers vs Dorset Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Neath Port Talbot Roller Derby vs Big Bucks High Rollers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Dolly Rockit Rollers hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Sheffield Steel Rollergirls vs Nottingham Roller Derby (Women's)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Sheffield Steel Rollergirls vs Rebellion Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Royal Windsor Roller Girls vs Manchester Roller Derby (Women's)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Cornwall Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Plymouth City Roller Derby vs Reaper Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Severn Roller Torrent vs Plymouth City Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Surrey Roller Girls hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Royal Windsor Roller Girls vs London Rockin' Rollers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Big Bucks High Rollers vs Kent Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Neath Port Talbot Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers vs Swansea City Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Severn Roller Torrent vs Reaper Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Cheshire Hellcats Roller Derby vs Plymouth City Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Wolverhampton Honour Rollers vs Hereford Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Vendetta Vixens vs Severn Roller Torrent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Norfolk Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Killa Hurtz Roller Girls vs Suffolk Roller Derby (Women's)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Lincolnshire Bombers vs Killa Hurtz Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Vendetta Vixens hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Rebellion Roller Derby vs Dolly Rockit Rollers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Oxford Wheels of Gory Roller Derby vs Lincolnshire Bombers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;London Brawl Saints vs Leeds Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Lincolnshire Bombers hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Mansfield Roller Derby vs Grim Reavers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;York Minxters Roller Derby vs Grim Reavers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Suffolk Roller Derby (Women's) vs Halifax Bruising Banditas&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Arcadia Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Halifax Bruising Banditas vs Preston Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Wakey Wheeled Cats vs Furness Firecrackers (Women's)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Wakey Wheeled Cats hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Halifax Bruising Banditas vs Spa Town Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby vs Birmingham Blitz Dames&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Granite City Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;All Star Reserves vs Whippin' Hinnies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;All Star Reserves vs Durham City Rolling Angels&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Whippin' Hinnies hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Durham Roller Derby vs York Minxters Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Durham Roller Derby vs Cheshire Hellcats Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Granite City Roller Derby vs All Star Reserves&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;London Rockin' Rollers hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Cambridge Rollerbillies vs Royal Windsor Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Kent Roller Girls vs Rebellion Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;North Cheshire Victory Rollers hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Manchester Roller Derby (Women's) vs Liverpool Roller Birds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Riverside Rebels Roller Derby vs Hallam Hellcats Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby vs Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Spa Town Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Halifax Bruising Banditas vs Wakey Wheeled Cats&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;North Cheshire Victory Rollers vs Durham Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Reaper Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;South West Angels of Terror vs Neath Port Talbot Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Hereford Roller Girls vs North Devon Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Durham Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Durham City Rolling Angels vs Arcadia Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Liverpool Roller Birds vs Whippin' Hinnies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Hallam Hellcats Roller Derby vs Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;North Devon Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;South West Angels of Terror vs Swansea City Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Neath Port Talbot Roller Derby vs Cornwall Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Manchester Roller Derby (Women's) hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Arcadia Roller Derby vs Hallam Hellcats Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Mansfield Roller Derby vs Cheshire Hellcats Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Liverpool Roller Birds hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Preston Roller Girls vs Furness Firecrackers (Women's)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Furness Firecrackers (Women's) vs Spa Town Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Oxford Wheels of Gory Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Wiltshire Roller Derby (Womens) vs Milton Keynes Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Milton Keynes Roller Derby vs Dorset Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;London Brawl Saints vs Bristol Roller Derby (Women's)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Big Bucks High Rollers hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Surrey Roller Girls vs Milton Keynes Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Roller Derby Leicester vs Surrey Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Tender Hooligans hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Preston Roller Girls vs Wakey Wheeled Cats&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Riverside Rebels Roller Derby vs Durham City Rolling Angels&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Kent Roller Girls hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Killa Hurtz Roller Girls vs Surrey Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Surrey Roller Girls vs Suffolk Roller Derby (Women's)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Wiltshire Roller Derby (Womens) hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Severn Roller Torrent vs Oxford Wheels of Gory Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Bristol Roller Derby (Women's) vs Royal Windsor Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;London Rockin' Rollers vs South West Angels of Terror&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Milton Keynes Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Oxford Wheels of Gory Roller Derby vs Vendetta Vixens&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames vs London Brawl Saints&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;All Star Reserves hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Durham City Rolling Angels vs Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Arcadia Roller Derby vs Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;South West Angels of Terror hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Plymouth City Roller Derby vs Riot City Ravens&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;North Devon Roller Derby vs Bath Roller Derby Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Cornwall Roller Derby vs Wiltshire Roller Derby (Womens)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Killa Hurtz Roller Girls hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Kent Roller Girls vs Hertfordshire Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Hertfordshire Roller Derby vs Norfolk Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;Durham City Rolling Angels hosts:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Leeds Roller Derby vs Middlesbrough Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Whippin' Hinnies vs Manchester Roller Derby (Women's)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Granite City Roller Derby vs Sheffield Steel Rollergirls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Furness Firecrackers (Women's) hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Liverpool Roller Birds vs Wirral Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;All Star Reserves vs Liverpool Roller Birds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Wirral Roller Derby vs All Star Reserves&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Plymouth City Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;North Devon Roller Derby vs Cornwall Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Cornwall Roller Derby vs Dorset Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Wirral Roller Derby hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Arcadia Roller Derby vs Riverside Rebels Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Preston Roller Girls vs Hereford Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;North Devon Roller Derby vs Furness Firecrackers (Women's)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Preston Roller Girls-hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Liverpool Roller Birds vs Tender Hooligans&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Whippin' Hinnies vs Wirral Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Suffolk Roller Derby (Women's) hosts:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Norfolk Roller Derby vs Kent Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Rebellion Roller Derby vs Norfolk Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Dorset Roller Girls hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers vs Bristol Roller Derby (Women's)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Bath Roller Derby Girls vs Surrey Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Royal Windsor Roller Girls vs South West Angels of Terror&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Hereford Roller Girls hosts:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Riot City Ravens vs Severn Roller Torrent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Riot City Ravens vs North Cheshire Victory Rollers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p2"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Dolly Rockit Rollers vs Neath Port Talbot Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>analysis</category><category>articles</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>scheduling</category><category>statistics</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/20/geography-of-british-champs-2015-to-2017/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 10:25:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow ready to rock as British Champs T3 goes down to the wire</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/06/glasgow-ready-to-rock-as-british-champs-t3-goes-down-to-the-wire/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't stop believing&lt;/strong&gt; - that's the tune blasting out at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GlasgowMensRollerDerby/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; HQ where the Irn Brn are plotting a derby escape act which would make Houdini hop the apex with delight.
&lt;p&gt;This Saturday, GMRD play host to the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/133440747209468/?acontext=%7B%22ref%22%3A%222%22%2C%22ref_dashboard_filter%22%3A%22upcoming%22%2C%22action_history%22%3A%22%5B%7B%5C%22surface%5C%22%3A%5C%22dashboard%5C%22%2C%5C%22mechanism%5C%22%3A%5C%22main_list%5C%22%2C%5C%22extra_data%5C%22%3A%5B%5D%7D%5D%22%7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;final fixtures in the British Championships' Men's Tier 3 - Regional North group&lt;/a&gt; (at Glasgow's ARC Sports Centre).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD will be taking on their Celtic cousins, Men Behaving Derby (MBD), while Bairn City Rollers' Skelpies will be setting blasters to stun against Teesside Skate Invaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a decidedly Scottish-type twist, only a specific combination of results can now see GMRD qualify for the play-offs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the uninitiated, here's the short story:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April, GMRD travelled to Dublin to play the Skate Invaders, winning by 234 points to 167. GMRD were later denuded of victory due to an eligibility malfunction, with the score becoming 200-0 in favour of the Invaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD's next game against the Skelpies was then forfeited by the Falkirk team due to lack of numbers - a 200-0 win in favour of GMRD - leaving the table looking like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-20255 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/brd-table.jpg" alt="BRD table" width="1014" height="650"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, GMRD need to beat MBD on Saturday - that's a pre-requisite if GMRD want a play-off place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regardless of what flavour that victory lollipop is, the Irn Brn need to be sucking on it by Saturday evening.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Skelpies win against the Invaders then victory of any variety will be enough for the Glasgow mob.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if the Invaders win &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; GMRD win then the three top teams will be tied on six points and it goes down to scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD would need to have a better points differential than MBD to qualify for the play-offs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't worry about crunching the numbers, SRD Blog has done it for you - &lt;strong&gt;GMRD need to beat MBD by over 123 points to be certain of a play-off place.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That isn't going to be any kind of easy as MBD have already beaten both the Skelpies and the Skate Invaders this season, the latter with just 6 players!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's why Hugs &amp;amp; Kisses - GMRD's President - is sounding the rallying horn to the Irn Brn faithful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We need everyone in the West of Scotland and beyond to come out and support Saturday's double-header," he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-20254" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/18768309_10209728094985432_4231219290125343973_o.jpg" alt="18768309_10209728094985432_4231219290125343973_o" width="1600" height="1067"&gt; The Irn Brn - photo by Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"This is an amazing first for our city - a British Champs men's game at the home of Glasgow derby, the ARC sportscentre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"You are going to see two gallus games of roller derby, with the fate of three teams hanging in the balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Come out and support the Irn Brn as we attempt the great escape. We're confident we can put on a great show - don't stop believing, ken?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* Doors open at the ARC sportscentre, Glasgow, on Saturday (10 June) at 11.30am. Tickets cost £7. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/133440747209468/?acontext=%7B%22ref%22%3A%222%22%2C%22ref_dashboard_filter%22%3A%22upcoming%22%2C%22action_history%22%3A%22%5B%7B%5C%22surface%5C%22%3A%5C%22dashboard%5C%22%2C%5C%22mechanism%5C%22%3A%5C%22main_list%5C%22%2C%5C%22extra_data%5C%22%3A%5B%5D%7D%5D%22%7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Click here for more information.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teeside Skate Invaders vs Bairn City Skelpies - first whistle at 11:45&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby vs Men Behaving Derby - first whistle at 2pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>men behaving derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>teeside skate invaders</category><category>the skelpies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/06/glasgow-ready-to-rock-as-british-champs-t3-goes-down-to-the-wire/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 16:02:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs North Update 23 March:York Minxters, Whippin Hinnies and more</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/22/british-champs-north-update-23-marchyork-minxters-whippin-hinnies-and-more/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our second update on the Northern Tiers of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/"&gt;British Champs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. We're aiming to do approximately monthly updates on the Tier 1, Tier 2 North, Tier 3 North and Tier 4 North, partly through the lens of specific teams in each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the last update, the &lt;strong&gt;Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; saw our advertised bout between&lt;strong&gt; Leeds Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; and Tiger Bay Brawlers end in an impressive win for the Cardiff team (294:44). Performance stats show that at least some of this seems to have been "first game" syndrome for LeedsRD, who significantly improved their performance in the second period (scoring 70%  of their points in period 2, as well as taking less penalties). If they perform at their period 2 level, or continue to improve, they'll be a significant force in the Tier in future games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Tier 2 North&lt;/strong&gt; has seen another round of bouts, with our tracked team, Newcastle Roller Girls' &lt;strong&gt;Whippin Hinnies&lt;/strong&gt; facing the formidable Rainy City Tender Hooligans, with the Hooligans taking the win, 348:62. This is a approaching half the score ratio than Rainy B managed against Wirral, which looks promising for the Hinnies' next bout in the tier. Looking at the stats (not published yet), this was a tough game for the Hinnie's jammers, with only Ania Marx achieving lead jammer status against Rainy's exceptional blocking. Hosts Wirral also played, losing to Manchester Roller Derby with the score 101:248.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; saw our tracked team &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; win a pretty closely contended game against Halifax Bruising Banditas - finishing 130:117. The stats show particularly strong jamming performances by GCRD's Lizzie Rascal (75% Lead Jams!), Team Scotland's Udder Mayhem, and Kami-Tazzy; blocking-wise, high VTARs are with Crimson Chaos, Team Scotland's Rock'N Riot, and Pert Hits.
North Wales convincingly defeated hosts Furness Firecrackers in the other bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first &lt;strong&gt;Tier 4 North&lt;/strong&gt; bouts saw tier-champions favourites Mansfield crush Durham City Rolling Angels 398:38, and the second Durham team, Durham Roller Derby, lose to Grimsby Grim Reavers 198:110.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tier 4 North is coming around again for another set of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1002205086551977/"&gt;bouts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; this weekend, and features the &lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt;' first ever bout in British Champs (as well as hosts Mansfield versus Durham). In honour of the occasion, we caught up with their Captain, Gem O'Cide to see how they're feeling:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, let's start by talking about last year, which was a big year for the Minxters. After several years of just playing a few bouts, 2016 saw the team play 7 over the season, with some pretty challenging opponents. What lead to this surge in activity, and has it been a good thing for the team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016 was a year of practice, practice and more practice. We had a lot of changes in the team and a lot of up and coming skaters joining the rostered team- this meant our dynamics changed and we needed to learn how to play together. We very much wanted to take the "Win or Learn" approach and felt some real time game play - working as we would on game day- would be best to learn this. Everyone loves scrimming and it helped us grow confidence and learn how each other work, where our strengths lie and what we needed to improve on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After missing the first two years of British Champs, you're entering this year for the first time. Why now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to get started on the Champs journey! We've had a massive new skater intake and great retention and it would be awesome to get the ball rolling and have something yearly to aim for! Something to show everyone what we are working towards...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You're entering into the tournament in Tier 4 North. Flat Track Stats and us agree that you're pretty much in the middle of the Tier in terms of expected performance - but there's a lot of unknowns, as you've only played one of your competitors before (Grimsby's Grim Reavers). How are you preparing for the tournament&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off shout out to Reavers. We love those guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are playing and training to our strengths. We've had some great input from Rule 56, as well as other guest coaches who have analysed our play. This had helped massively in preparing by knowing what we focus on from A-team players and what direction to take our training in. This has given us concrete goals and really solidified our skills and tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your first bout in Champs looks like being a tough one - Wakey Wheeled Cats are one of the strongest teams in this Tier! What are your aims for this particular game?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Wakey game, we are going into a tough one! But this is a great challenge to practice what we have learnt, and are continuing to learn, in training. For me as Captain, all I ever want to see for my team is that they are working hard as a team and putting our training into practice. We go into and leave this as a team who wins or learns!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As well as British Champs itself, what other plans and events do York Minxters have in store for 2017?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have lots of fun things planned for our newer skaters after Champs - they have helped out with NSO roles and August will be and time of fun and folly for everyone! After Champs we will be having a bit of fun for the team, then looking at some more challenges to prepare for 2018!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upcoming bouts in other tiers are:
&lt;strong&gt;Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; - our tracked team, Leed Roller Derby, host a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/288187818265184/"&gt;massive triple header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;April 8th&lt;/strong&gt;, where they will play Bristol Roller Derby, London Brawl Saints will play Tiger Bay, and newly-rebranded Middlesbrough Roller Derby will take on Birmingham Blitz Dames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next &lt;strong&gt;Tier 2&lt;/strong&gt; bouts are on &lt;strong&gt;22nd April&lt;/strong&gt;, where Newcastle host a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1886091588294805/"&gt;double header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, with the Whippin Hinnies playing Manchester Roller Derby (which should be their closest bout yet), and Liverpool Roller Birds bouting Wirral Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tier 3&lt;/strong&gt; also plays next on &lt;strong&gt;22nd April&lt;/strong&gt;, with Aberdeen the venue, as hosts Granite City Roller Derby play the other Scottish team in the tier, Auld Reekie Roller Girls' Reserves; and Furness Firecrackers playing Halifax Bruising Banditas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>whippin hinnies</category><category>york minxters</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/22/british-champs-north-update-23-marchyork-minxters-whippin-hinnies-and-more/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 10:50:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs Schedule 2017</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/03/british-champs-schedule-2017/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, by now you're probably aware that the British Championships 2017 schedule is out (it's hosted here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/2017-british-roller-derby-champs-fixtures/"&gt;http://www.britishchamps.com/2017-british-roller-derby-champs-fixtures/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in a big, searchable, list).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the list is pretty long, we thought we'd pull out some key dates for you (and also tip our hand a bit as to teams and divisions we'll be focussing a little more on - Talk Derby To Me will be continuing their excellent overall Champs coverage this year for those who want to cover the whole thing):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; kicks off on the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Feb&lt;/strong&gt;ruary, with a double header featuring Tiger Bay Brawlers against newly-merged Leeds Roller Derby, and Birmingham Blitz Dames against Bristol Roller Derby hosted by TBB in Cardiff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; also begins a few weeks later in Wales, as South West Silures host the Crash Test Brummies on the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, by then, most of the other Tiers will have had their first bouts, with the whole British Champs schedule starting on the &lt;strong&gt;4th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Feb&lt;/strong&gt;ruary, as the &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 2&lt;/strong&gt; begins with Barrow Infernos hosting Southern Discomfort B (the first B team in the Men's tiers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friends of the blog, &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;, see their B-team, the Whippin' Hinnies, compete for the first time in &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 2 North&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch, in a battle of the B-teams against Rainy City Roller Derby's formidable Tender Hooligans; hosted by Wirral Roller Derby, this is also somewhat Manchester area themed, as the second bout of the fixture is hosts versus Manchester Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you'll have to wait until April to see some &lt;em&gt;Scottish Women&lt;/em&gt;'s action in the Champs, as &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; host a &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; double header on the &lt;strong&gt;22nd&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Apr&lt;/strong&gt;il. &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;' Reserves are travelling up to Aberdeen to take on the hosts, whilst Furness Firecrackers and Halifax Bruising Banditas will be coming up to play each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scottish Men&lt;/em&gt;'s Derby also has its first showing in Champs that month, as Men Behaving Derby host a &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; fixture on the &lt;strong&gt;16th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Apr&lt;/strong&gt;il; pitting &lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt;' Skelpies against the hosts, followed by Teeside Skate Invaders facing off against &lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, whilst the &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 4&lt;/strong&gt; North starts its series a few weeks earlier, we'll be following friends of the blog (and some of our first interviewees!) &lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt; - their first bout is on the &lt;strong&gt;25th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch against Wakey Wheeled Cats, in Mansfield; the second bout is hosts against Durham Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>york minxters</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/03/british-champs-schedule-2017/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 09:44:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs 2016 opens for Scotland</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/02/16/british-champs-2016-opens-for-scotland/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the second year of the nationwide &lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com"&gt;British Championship&lt;/a&gt;s started last week, a quirk of scheduling means that all of Scotland's teams have their first games &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, there are no less than three double-header events for British Champs this weekend featuring Scottish teams, and two of them are being hosted up in Scotland itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Auld Reekie Roller Girls, Voodoo Roller Dollies and New Town Roller Girls all having left British Champs for various reasons after the 2015 Season, there are currently 4 Scottish leagues still competing in the schedules, all of whom play this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working up the tiers, then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;Saturday&lt;/strong&gt;, Aberdeen's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.granitecityrollerderby.co.uk/"&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are hosting the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/199093520445006/"&gt;first fixture&lt;/a&gt; of the Tier 4 North Division, in their usual venue, the Beach Leisure Centre. The double header will see Blackpool Roller Derby League take on Halifax Bruising Banditas; followed by hosts Granite City taking on Durham Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-5755 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/12525411_10154612912394012_7934633322794908992_o.jpg?w=212" alt="12525411_10154612912394012_7934633322794908992_o" width="212" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;FlatTrackStats&lt;/a&gt; predicts a win for GCRD over Durham; however, the Halifax/Blackpool bout should be extremely close, potentially coming down to the final jam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GCRD are hosting at the &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Beach+Leisure+Centre/@57.1556049,-2.0820887,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x48840e4028217933:0x30c6b9176815da5b"&gt;Beach Leisure Centre&lt;/a&gt;. Doors open at 12:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Down in &lt;strong&gt;Preston&lt;/strong&gt;, both &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/dundeerollergirls/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; will be competing in the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1755123161386637/"&gt;first fixture&lt;/a&gt; in T3 North on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday&lt;/strong&gt;. FVRG will lead the schedule, taking on Hull's Angels Roller Dames; Dundee Roller Girls follow, taking on hosts Preston Roller Girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FTS's predictions here are that H.A.R.D. should triumph over Fierce Valley, while hosts Preston should lose, albeit narrowly, against Dundee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-5743 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/brit-champs-t3-gameday-1-768x768.jpg?w=300" alt="Brit-Champs-T3-Gameday-1-768x768" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This event will be held in Preston's usual venue, &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Preston's+College/@53.7849145,-2.7022612,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x487b721b0a2e51eb:0x9868b02f36edca68"&gt;Preston's College&lt;/a&gt;. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;midday&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; will be hosting the&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/events-calendar/2016/2/21/british-roller-derby-championships-double-header"&gt; first games&lt;/a&gt; of the T1 "Premier" Division, on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday&lt;/strong&gt;! While Glasgow won the T1 Division last year, they're also one of the few teams from T1 returning from the last time: this first fixture sees them facing Newcastle Roller Girls (who promoted from T2 last year) and also facing London Rollergirls B, who are new to the Championships. Glasgow will be keen to prove that they're capable of defending their title against new challengers, while Newcastle will be equally keen to show that they deserve their promotion from Tier 2, and the Brawl Saints will want to make their mark as incomers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5761" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/12646940_10156610083540389_6438710273192564289_n.jpg" alt="12646940_10156610083540389_6438710273192564289_n" width="960" height="303"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking to FlatTrackStats, it expects Glasgow to take an easy win against Newcastle, but a more challenging one against London's Brawl Saints. With the London bout second, it could be even closer than FTS expects; the statistics don't take into account the possibility that one team might be more tired after playing previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow are hosting this event at their regular venue, the &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662183,-4.2519236,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7"&gt;ARC Health and Fitness&lt;/a&gt; at Glasgow Caledonian University. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;12:45pm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>blackpool roller derby</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>durham roller derby</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>halifax bruising banditas</category><category>hull's angels roller derby</category><category>london rollergirls</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/02/16/british-champs-2016-opens-for-scotland/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 17:04:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls British Champs Game Four</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/03/dundee-roller-girls-british-champs-game-four/</link><dc:creator>julezw</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girls Silvery Tayzers host their first, long awaited home game of the season on July 11th at Dundee International Sports Centre. This game sees the Tayzers take on Sheffield Steel Rollergirls (featuring ex-DRG alumni Carnage T800), in Game four of DRG’s British Championships season. With both teams sitting on six points and with 2 wins and 1 defeat under their belt this is a must-win game for the Tayzers as their final game sees them take on league leaders Furness Firecrackers in a triple header in August.
The game at DISC is a double header with Granite City Roller Girls taking on Furness Firecrackers, giving DRG an insight into what’s in store for their final game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/110715.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4783" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/110715.png?w=212" alt="110715" width="212" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 12.30pm, first whistle at 1pm. Advance tickets £5 available from &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/1766026"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, tickets available on the door £6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join the Facebook event using this &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/upcoming?action_history=null"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/03/dundee-roller-girls-british-champs-game-four/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 20:54:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A chat with UKRDA about the British Championships</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/01/11/a-chat-with-ukrda-about-the-british-championships/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="gmail_extra"&gt;The launch of the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BritishRollerDerbyChamps?fref=ts"&gt;British Championships&lt;/a&gt; this year, as a natural growth of the increasingly successful Heartlands Series, caused and continues to cause considerable excitement in the community. (2015 seems to be the year for these, with the Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals and the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/RollerDerbyDeutschland?fref=ts"&gt;German national&lt;/a&gt; "German Roller Derby League" also starting up.)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_extra"&gt;Causing more interest was the announcement that &lt;a href="http://www.ukrda.org.uk/"&gt;UKRDA&lt;/a&gt; would be helping to organise the event. We caught up with The B reF G, UKRDA and &lt;a href="http://www.brsf.co.uk/"&gt;BRSF&lt;/a&gt; director, and man most involved with tournamentish things in UKRDA, to see what UKRDA and the Championships have planned.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_extra"&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/ukrda.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-4527" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/ukrda.jpg?w=614" alt="UKRDA" width="614" height="417"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_quote"&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;b&gt;So, coming straight to the point, how are UKRDA providing support to the British Championships. Obviously, a lot of the leagues involved are UKRDA members, but what is the organisation itself doing?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The bulk of the work is being done by the incredible, tireless efforts of the crew who are responsible for setting up the tournament. These are the same people who have built the concept over the last few years, the people behind Heartlands and the previous tournament series from which it grew. While the previous tournament concepts organised by this group have been private local or regional ventures, these people are primarily UKRDA members and have stated that their goal from the outset was create a national tournament series so it made sense to formally consult the UKRDA membership as the NGB for the sport. When they approached UKRDA it was seen by the board that a proactive group of members had developed a tournament concept and were looking for support from the community to make it happen.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UKRDA's involvement was discussed at length on the forum and our reps voted overwhelmingly in favour of being involved with this tournament, with a few modifications to the original proposal, and it has grown from there.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Directors have been involved mostly in an advisory role; having a guiding hand in the appointment process for key tournament staff, seeking guidance from national sporting bodies where appropriate or offering advice on how the logistics and operational delivery could be realised. We have also been negotiating with the Men's teams from around the UK to bring them under the same organisational umbrella as the Women's tournament as we see this as a fantastic opportunity to unite the whole UK derby community, regardless of UKRDA membership status. It is only through a united effort that we can truly drive our sport forward and build on the grass roots efforts gone to date&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I assume that one of the ways that UKRDA has helped is by providing assistance in ranking the teams involved, for assignment to the initial divisions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Q3 ranking publication was used for UKRDA teams in the tournament and the wider rankings have been taken from Flat Track Stats. This made sense as this is where the UKRDA rankings are calculated so any differential between a member and non-member team would be fairly representative. As it worked out all of the top ranked teams eligible to play in the British Champs are from UKRDA Member Leagues so the idea of making the top tiers UKRDA only fit well with the plan to have UKRDA sanctioning the upper levels of game play.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="gmail_quote"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So UKRDA is Sanctioning the top tiers as well as providing assistance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes, as the top two tiers are entirely made up of UKRDA teams all games in these tiers will be UKRDA sanctioned and will count for UKRDA rankings.  &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;em&gt; One area that we are looking to have a strong hand in coordinating is the provision of Officials for the tournament. There is still an expectation that the teams playing at any given event will be supplying their own officials, indeed it would be extremely difficult to run such a series any other way, however the UKRDA Officials Committee are looking to develop a supportive community for all UK derby officials that we hope will grow to become something that not only supports active UK derby officials regardless of league affiliation, but also that will be part of ensuring that all games are adequately staffed and that officials with suitable experience and ability are available where needed.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As this is the first time a UK tournament of this type as taken place, there may be teething problems as we go along. However, we are confident that any potential issues can be resolved through proper skater representation and fair, flexible management. This structure is one that will greatly benefit the UK roller derby community, from the grass roots to the top tiers of the game in our country.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="gmail_quote"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you concerned or offering any advice over managing the potentially increased scheduling complexity the Champs may introduce? I understand that leagues are forbidden from holding bouts on the same day as a Champs fixture in their group, which (assuming double headers) removes about 5 or 10 slots from their schedule, depending on if you do Home/Away return matchups (plus additional blocking for the Tier playoffs). For many leagues who bout once a month, that is half of their potential bouts devoted to their Division. I can imagine that UKRDA's logistical support would be advantageous in managing this organisation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt;So the scheduling has, and indeed is being managed by one of the BC crew (who has my utmost respect for this task, if they ever got the time to try I'm sure they would be a sudoku grand master!) in collaboration with the teams from each division. The idea behind it is that each team in a division of six will host one double header that will feature four teams from that division, with a season end triple header to be hosted by one of the teams, or elsewhere. There isn't a home/away return fixture for teams so there will be five games per team per division per season, plus any play-off games. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt;Teams are asked not to host any games on the same day as BC fixtures as a way of addressing the 'super-saturation' of games that has been commented upon frequently in derby media. If we're building a national tournament then we want to ensure we have the best possible audience for these games, so it makes sense that any teams involved avoid hosting events that would potentially draw spectators away from the championship games. As the divisions are for the most part geographic groupings of similarly ranked teams, it is in those teams best interests to avoid clashes and maximise the viewer figures for championship games in their area. Plus it gives any teams not competing on a given weekend the chance to go study the form of their future opponents! &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is a colossal headache trying to fit all of the games in without regional clashes, especially as we move to include the Men's Champs in this structure as that introduces three extra divisions that must be factored into the logistic planning. There are always going to be difficulties with this but I can attest that a lot of thought and planning has gone into developing a schedule that provides the best coverage with a minimum of difficulty for the teams.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt;This impacts on provision of Officials, Announcers and other support crew too, as too many games in one area would mean we have to import Refs &amp;amp; NSOs from other areas, which then has a knock on effect further down the chain. Something high on the wider agenda is avoiding burnout for Officials and that has been factored into the scheduling to try to minimise clashes with other key tournaments happening through 2015. This is something we are hoping to get more volunteers from the UKRDA membership to support as it is only going to become more complex as the tournament grows.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt;Saying that teams that bout once a month are committing half of their gaming season to the tournament is fair, however this is in return for the reduced overhead to each of finding suitable opponents (which includes gauging their level of ability against that of your own team which can be subjective at times), attempting to coordinate their own schedules with those of other teams, setting up the game contract, sourcing officials, etc. The hope is that this will present the community with an opportunity to work together and make every team's Bout Liaison role considerably less of a full time job. There is going to be derby all through 2015, whether BC happens or not. While the schedule drawn up may not be 100% to the preference of every team when compared with running their own schedule, having a single schedule for the whole nation will help avoid major clashes and allow us to develop some 'joined-up thinking' in shared marketing strategy and potential sponsorship plans that will be to everyone's benefit. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Finally, what are your hopes for the development of the British Championships on British Derby as a whole?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt;As with everything UKRDA do, we want to see the UK community come together to fulfil the massive potential this sport has and we see BC as a hugely positive thing for our community. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="yj6qo ajU"&gt;
&lt;div id=":24j" class="ajR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;We would hope that in the future the UKRDA would be able to assist even more with the organisation and structure of the tournament. The current British Champs organisers are excited by this prospect, but it would require more time and volunteers from people belonging to UKRDA member leagues.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ajR"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ajR"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ajR"&gt;The first bouts of the British Championships are happening today at &lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk/?p=1054"&gt;Tattoo Freeze&lt;/a&gt;, with the Men's thread of the championship being kicked off with Crash Test Brummies vs New Wheeled Order and The Quads of War: Milton Keynes Roller Derby vs The Inhuman League.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>british championship</category><category>interviews</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/01/11/a-chat-with-ukrda-about-the-british-championships/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 12:54:42 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>