<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about cairollers)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/cairollers.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 09:17:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Skating at the tip of Africa: Roller Derby in South Africa</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/rollerderby-za-2019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've written a bit about South African roller derby when covering their &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/31/south-africas-national-derby-fest-2018-three-years-of-festivals/"&gt;national tournament&lt;/a&gt;, but there's a lot more to be said about the community than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geography informs the way in which Roller Derby develops in a country, and South Africa's is very different to what we're used to in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of South Africa's Population density, with leagues marked." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/southafrica-popdensity.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Map of South Africa's population density, with leagues marked. [Underlay: Htonl (Public domain, Wikipedia)]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South Africa is a large country - its area is about twice that of France - but with a relatively small population - about 80% that of France. And that population is very unevenly spread across the country: the dense province of &lt;strong&gt;Gauteng&lt;/strong&gt;, containing Johannesburg and Pretoria, contains about a &lt;em&gt;quarter&lt;/em&gt; of South Africa's entire population, with another fifth concentrated around Durban in the south-east province of &lt;strong&gt;KwaZulu-Natal&lt;/strong&gt;, and a further eighth around Cape Town in the &lt;strong&gt;Western Cape&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike in most European countries, then, the 4 leagues of South Africa - located in those 4 named cities - have difficulty even travelling to play each other on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add to this the fact that the only other country with Roller Derby in Africa is &lt;em&gt;Egypt&lt;/em&gt;, at the other end of the continent, and you can get a feel for how dedicated and unique the solutions adapted by the South African leagues have had to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we'll be discussing in some depth both those problems, and their solutions, so click on to read more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/rollerderby-za-2019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (13 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cairollers</category><category>cape town rollergirls</category><category>derbyfest</category><category>durban roller derby</category><category>golden city rollers</category><category>p-town roller derby</category><category>south african roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/rollerderby-za-2019/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby without Borders: One year catchup</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/derby-without-borders-one-year-catchup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, we brought you an &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/05/derby-without-borders-an-interview-with-founder-mae-dae/"&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Mae Dae, to talk about their fantastic project, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://derbywithoutborders.org/"&gt;Derby Without Borders&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, less than a year later, the project has gone from strength to strength, helping more leagues in more countries across the world, in more ways. With so much happening, it is past time to write an update on events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby Without Borders was founded in 2017, as a project initially intended to help leagues in places where it was cost-prohibitive to get kit and other basic resources (sometimes because roller skating just wasn’t a thing in that country, often also because the cost of items was just much higher than the average wage allowed). The idea was, and still is, that donor leagues or individuals could donate “lightly used” or even new, kit to DwB, and the project would distribute items to leagues in need worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="All the places Derby without Borders has provided help to teams, so far. (Black: kit donations achieved, Blue: “start up” support, Green: advice and translation, Yellow: coaching bootcamps (and other additional support), Red: pending kit donation.)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/DwB2019.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;All the places Derby without Borders has provided help to teams, so far. (Black: kit donations achieved, Blue: “start up” support, Green: advice and translation, Yellow: coaching bootcamps (and other additional support), Red: pending kit donation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we talked to Mae back in 2018, DwB had already successfully helped Sailor City Rollers (Buenos Aires, Argentina), Golden City Roller Derby (Johannesburg, South Africa) and the Cairollers (Cairo, Egypt) with donation packs. They’ve also collected for Roller Derby Beirut (Beirut, Lebanon) (in collaboration with Quad Skate Shop), but have had difficulties getting the kit into Lebanon. Since then, they’ve also been able to support Bangkok Roller Derby (Bangkok, Thailand), Toxic Lima Roller Derby (Lima, Peru), Kyoto Roller Derby (Kyoto, Japan), and Roller Derby Beijing (Beijing, China)…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…but Derby without Borders have also been extending their goals in order to help Roller Derby in other ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, DwB is no longer just Mae Dae: since the last time we spoke, DwB has recruited a second body in the UK, in the form of Rosie Peacock (who has also set up a third donation collection point in the UK). They’ve been providing much needed support, Mae admitting “Rosie has been absolutely pivotal and an amazing addition to the team - I don’t think DwB would have gotten this far without their commitment to the project”.
The project has also grown an Advisory Board, positioned to steer the project in the right directions. In recruiting for the board, Mae tells us that they “reached out specifically to have Skaters of Colour on the board: they’re on the board to help steer the project in the direction it wants to be heading, which means engaging with intersectional, inclusionary and anti-oppressive practices.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rosie and Mae were both representing the cause at this year’s European Rollerderby Organisational Conference (EROC 2019) in Berlin with a stall, and a session on “Removing barriers to accessibility in roller derby”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“It was great to be able to talk with the theme of diversity and inclusivity, and how it relates to DwB, because it really is at the foundation of all of the work that we’re doing - this idea that we need to take down barriers to access in order to make this a more inclusive sport,”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;said Mae. In addition, every time DwB has a stall somewhere, more people learn about the project, and offer to support it. At EROC, one of the attending leagues offered to host a collection at their next bout, and to raise funds for the project.
That said, DwB and EROC in some senses were looking in different directions whilst supporting the same ethos. EROC is, intentionally, focused on improving Roller Derby within Europe; whilst Derby without Borders is inherently about looking outside, and working on how to support Roller Derby in other places, building in inclusivity and adapting culture to support other regions from the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- comment
Add images --&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Mae Dae on the Derby without Borders stall at EROC 2019 (Image copyright: Michael Wittig / Bear City Roller Derby)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/MaeDae-EROC.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Mae Dae on the Derby without Borders stall at EROC 2019 (Image copyright: Michael Wittig / Bear City Roller Derby)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that spirit, then, EROC was also the last event that Mae attended before leaving Europe themself. With Rosie positioned in the UK, Mae has courageously moved to Bangkok, Thailand, allowing them to be physically closer to one big region that would benefit significantly from DwB’s support – South East Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“Moving to Bangkok to help develop SE Asian roller derby has definitely been huge, and really pivotal.” Mae told us,  “I’m really understanding the needs of the region a lot better than I did before - and just how different the scale of roller derby is in all of Asia!”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since being closer to the action, they’ve launched an initiative to provide “consultation” services to newer leagues, giving them support and advice from the ground up (not just on how to start up a league, but also on developing local cultural competency). The first beneficiary of this is the first ever Roller Derby team in Bali: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/hotlavarollers/"&gt;Hot Lava Rollers&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with many of DwB’s new initiatives, this started with a conversation, as Mae relates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“Someone who used to skate with Crime [City Rollers] - Glitter Punch - reached out to me; she’d heard about the project, from Hanna P, and she said ‘I live in Bali now, and I’m so sad that there’s no Roller Derby. I really kinda want to make a team, and I was wondering if you could help me’”.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present, Hot Lava Rollers are just two people, and one set of kit (Glitter’s), and the team is just starting to recruit and look for spaces and other resources. Meanwhile, Mae is actively providing mentorship, on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“I’m trying to get them all the other resources that they would need, so helping them develop everything from bylaws, policies, through to making a logo, getting them social media, just… everything.”
“We’re trying to focus on consistent communication - we talk once a week, even if it’s just a 20 minute check-in. I think also it will be a learning experience in how to help support someone in starting a league without being there - I’m in Bangkok and it’s not far, only an hour’s time difference - but still, not being physically there to put in the work in the same way that I would / am with Bangkok [is a challenge].”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst advice and support is very important, when it comes to developing Derby-specific skills, there’s nothing better than a good coach. So, DwB has also been using its connections to organise specific Coaching Bootcamps in those regions involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 27th April, DwB and Bangkok Roller Derby are co-hosting a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2104905746467908/"&gt;bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; run by Canberra Roller Derby League (and Team Korea)’s ShortStop; on the 12 October, Atlanta Rollergirls (and Team USA)’s Baller Shot Caller will be running a DwB &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/781786125525096/"&gt;organised bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; in Bali! A future Bootcamp is also planned for Cairo (to be hosted by the Cairollers, with Zipblock and Freight Train), but dates and funding are still in progress on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Hot Lava Rollers founders, Rustamia Primanisa and Glitter Punch, after their first meeting with Mae [Thanks to Hot Lava Rollers &amp;amp; DwB]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/HotLavaRollers.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Hot Lava Rollers founders, Rustamia Primanisa and Glitter Punch, after their first meeting with Mae [Thanks to Hot Lava Rollers &amp;amp; DwB]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to run a bootcamp in Bali, in particular, came as a pleasant surprise even to Mae themself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“When Baller [Shot Caller] had reached out to me to ask what she could help the project with, I said, ‘well, here’s all the places I could use help with coaching’, and I let her pick.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
And she said, ‘If I have to choose one, I would say Bali. It seems more secluded, and they probably have less resources’!&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“I said, ‘it’s just two people - there’s the potential you could be teaching 5 people minimum skills’.
Baller was completely okay with that, as the gain in awareness, and value in increased representation was worth it. We did choose a date later in the year to give time for recruitment, though.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having already organised their first DwB bootcamp with Hong Kong Roller Derby (coached by Rosie Peacock and Optimus Grime of Glasgow Men’s Roller Derby), Mae is confident, however, that both bootcamps will have significant regional attendance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“The fact that we had 3 girls from the UAE travel all the way to HK just so they could attend a bootcamp and play a game , just goes to show you how isolated people are - but also how hungry they are for it. What I’m discovering about SE Asian roller derby, and Middle Eastern roller derby. is that when these things happen people will come from across the region to attend and come together.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Bali, though, the bootcamp in Bangkok will also be significant for another reason, being the first time that Bangkok Roller Derby will field a full team to compete. The bootcamp will see two games - the usual Pan-Asian Spring Rollers v Pan-Asian Spring Rollers setup, followed by the history-making Bangkok versus Hong Kong bout!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bout flyer for the next DwB bootcamp, hosted by Bangkok Roller Derby. [Image: Bangkok Roller Derby, photo by Teddy Tse]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/DwB-Bangkok-flyer.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bout flyer for the next DwB bootcamp, hosted by Bangkok Roller Derby. [Image: Bangkok Roller Derby, photo by Teddy Tse]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mae has also been active in providing resources and accessibility in other ways: at present, Roller Derby resources are overwhelmingly available in English (with Spanish probably the next largest). Whilst the WFTDA rules have a translation to the second most widely read language in the world (Chinese), there’s almost no availability in Hindi (the 3rd) and Arabic (the 6th – and 3rd most read as a second language) – and the most spoken Slavic language in the world, Russian, has a similar lack of support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DwB has projects underway to translate resources into under-represented languages to increase accessibility – in the case of Arabic, with the support of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/UAERollerDerby/"&gt;UAE Roller Derby All-Stars&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.cairollers.com/"&gt;Cairollers&lt;/a&gt;. (We’ll be catching up with the Cairollers shortly in another article, as they also have exciting news.) Russian translations of the Short Track Roller Derby ruleset have already been produced, thanks to efforts from the White Night Furies, and Abu Dhabi Roller Derby’s Spinky, as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, Mae dreams of having a “database of different resources for leagues, in all the languages; so if a league needs a framework for a code of conduct in Spanish, they can just go to the database and find something to base it on”. That’s for the future, however: the current effort is focused on getting basic rules and coaching resources translated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as translation, another issue, especially for countries with more filtered access to the Internet, can simply be access to resources at all. In China, for example, common hosts for Roller Derby resources like YouTube, Google Drive, Facebook, Twitter, Twitch, Medium and WordPress are all either permanently or irregularly blocked. Derby Without Borders is actively working with the Chinese Roller Derby community to provide access to the resources that the community needs, using hosts which are acceptable to the Chinese government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Derby without Borders continues to pursue its original goal of providing kit for skaters, as well. One of the first things that Mae noticed at Bangkok was that many of the skaters had inflexible, heavy mouthguards designed for Muay Thai. As theytold us, this isn’t really ideal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“you can’t really speak when you’re wearing them, and can barely breathe in them. So I just emailed SISU and said ‘hey, can you like just give us 20 mouthguards’ and they were like ‘yeah, sure, and just shipped them over’.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as SISU, other derby-related businesses - Steaks, Riedell, and Bont - have shown interest in supporting the project, especially as it has gained more visibility in the community. (Bont-sponsored skater Shortshop has managed to provide a set of wheels as a “prize” at her bootcamp in Bangkok, for example.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bangkok Roller Derby with SISU donated mouthguards, thanks to DwB [Image: Derby without Borders]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/Bangkok-SISU.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby with SISU donated mouthguards, thanks to DwB [Image: Derby without Borders]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this additional activity, however, is only sustainable if Derby without Borders continues to grow itself. Mae is currently working towards a new model for the organisation: regional “chapters” which can help to organise and manage the effort which DwB brings. (The Asia chapter will almost certainly be the first to be established, with recruitment happening now.)
The project is already growing fast enough to need this right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“One thing that I’m learning is understanding my own bandwidth and capability - how much I can do as one person.” Mae told us “Particularly, at this point, I’m doing all of this work because I want to do it - there’s no funding. Understanding my own bandwidth has been important because I’ve had two people reach out to me who were interested in doing the same thing in India, and whilst I absolutely want to help someone start a league in India, I think I might need to focus on one at a time, for now. I think with them I’m going to have to take a step back.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team India Roller Derby have since agreed to help support these potential seeds of Roller Derby, in collaboration with DwB, but the project still needs more people - and leagues - to join in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One Derby without Borders initiative which has been active for the start is the idea of “Sibling Leagues”: an opportunity for established leagues to pair up with specific leagues elsewhere in the world to offer them support. This support could be in terms of equipment donations, as the scheme was originally formulated with Texas collecting kit to donate directly to the Cairollers. However, as DwB evolves, it could equally be provided as knowledge exchange, guidance, and political and social support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“I would love to see that kind of Sibling league relationship develop with more leagues.” Mae told us, “instead of needing to come through DwB [to give support], it could be more like a mentorship: one league can mentor another league, and develop all their resources between the two of them. That’s what’s going to make it more sustainable in the long run [and] that’s the point of the project, creating these things for the sake of sustainability.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Quito, Ecuador’s Forajidas Roller Derby, post-recruitment in January. (Photo: Forajidas Roller Derby)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/Forajidas_roller_derby.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Quito, Ecuador’s Forajidas Roller Derby, post-recruitment in January. (Photo: Forajidas Roller Derby)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst we’ve mostly focused on activities in Asia in this update, that should not imply that DwB is not working for other regions as well. Mae told us that they have been in contact with Forajidas Roller Derby, who are currently trying to (re)establish the only league in Ecuador (in Quito, the capital).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the Forajidas have a GoFundMe ( &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gofundme.com/help-bring-roller-derby-to-ecuador"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/help-bring-roller-derby-to-ecuador&lt;/a&gt; ), they also need guidance and support in forming their league. Mae is actively looking for either a Sibling League, or a coach, or both, who can help to support the new team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, as well as helping to nurture and advise new and developing leagues, DwB is also working to support Roller Derby in other ways. Derby Without Borders can host crowdfunders for such leagues to allow them to raise funds more easily: at present, they’re hosting a GoFundMe to support Buenos Aires’ 2×4 Roller Derby on their current international travel requirements. (You can donate here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gofundme.com/2x4-international-tour-2019"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/2x4-international-tour-2019&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby without Borders is open to assisting any league or team who need their support: regardless of if that’s in SE Asia where Mae is currently focused, or in Latin America, the Middle East, Eastern Europe or Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you, or your league, or your company, want to support Derby without Borders in any way mentioned in this article (or another way you can think of), we encourage you to join in. Derby without Borders can only get better as it gets bigger - and it can only get bigger with more of the community pitching in to support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can support DwB via their Donation page [ &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://derbywithoutborders.org/donate"&gt;https://derbywithoutborders.org/donate&lt;/a&gt; ] and by buying their merch (which also lets you raise awareness of the project by wearing it everywhere) [ &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://derbywithoutborders.org/merchandise"&gt;https://derbywithoutborders.org/merchandise&lt;/a&gt; ]. Mae Dae and DwB central can be contacted by email at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:maedae@skatingoutofbounds.com"&gt;maedae@skatingoutofbounds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2x4 roller derby</category><category>argentina</category><category>bali</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>bootcamps</category><category>cairollers</category><category>china</category><category>crowdfunding</category><category>derby without borders</category><category>dubai roller derby</category><category>ecuador</category><category>egypt</category><category>forajidas roller derby</category><category>hot lava rollers</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>russia</category><category>thailand</category><category>uae roller derby all-stars</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/derby-without-borders-one-year-catchup/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 11:17:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MENA's first ever public interleague - Abu Dhabi v CaiRollers.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/18/menas-first-ever-public-interleague-abu-dhabi-v-cairollers/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Friday 20th January, a little bit of roller derby history will be made when the CaiRollers host Abu Dhabi Roller Derby in the first ever public interleague game in the MENA region: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/403635766647515/"&gt;Arabian Fights: 1001 Jams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-13990" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/srd1.jpg" alt="srd1" width="640" height="238"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's taken both leagues several years to get to this point, and we spoke to Susan Nour (Nofearteti) of CaiRollers and Abu Dhabi Roller Derby's Milene Bizachi (Milificent) to find out more about the leagues and their thoughts on the upcoming game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-13991 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/srd2.jpg" alt="srd2" width="187" height="187"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did CaiRollers begin as a league, and how has it developed over the years?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We began in 2012 after two American expats met at work at a school in Cairo and realized that they had both previously played roller derby elsewhere. Shaneikiah Bickham (Naughty Ven Close) had played with the Big Easy Roller Girls and Angie Kaster (Indie Hannah) had played with the London Roller Girls. In that first year of their acquaintance they brainstormed on how to they could get a league started here in Egypt (because skates and gear are not available), and they started small with 8 players in September 2012. They had a vision that they wanted the league to be a more homegrown effort and not populated solely by expats in Egypt, and that has been the case. Today, our league is about 25 strong made up of Egyptian women and men from various social classes, with a handful of expats rounding out the numbers.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id="x_gmail-m_-4780500211593238315divtagdefaultwrapper" dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What difficulties have you faced in getting to this point?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main difficulties have been very similar to those faced by any other derby league in the world: finding suitable practice space, financing things and drumming up interest among people who have never heard of roller derby and have no idea what it's about. In addition to those issues we also still struggle with access to gear. While you can buy some basic protective gear in Cairo, it's not as durable as one would hope for roller derby. And while you can find in-line skates here, you can't find the kind of skates needed for derby. We've been wonderfully supported with gear donations from roller derby leagues around the world, and whenever one of our league travels we try to bring back gear for those who need it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id="x_gmail-m_-4780500211593238315divtagdefaultwrapper" dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CaiRollers is already a trailblazer, as the first roller derby league in Egypt.  How does it feel to be hosting the first ever roller derby game in the MENA region?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels fantastic! We are incredibly excited and proud to be hosting this game and cannot wait to face off against our sisters from Abu Dhabi. They have been incredible about organizing their members and self-funding to get here, and it has been great working with ADRD to get this thing off the ground. Our trainers and players have also been working so hard to get ready for game day. This has been the dream since the league started four years ago, so it definitely feels like a big achievement made all the better by the fact that so many people have come together across the two leagues to make this happen.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id="x_gmail-m_-4780500211593238315divtagdefaultwrapper" dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have you been preparing for the game?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from the practical things like securing a venue, boutfits, NSOs, volunteers etc. we've been working hard in practice on our strategy and teamwork, and devoting more time to conditioning out of regular practice times.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id="x_gmail-m_-4780500211593238315divtagdefaultwrapper" dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What has the local reaction been, both to the league in general and to this game?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since our inception, local reaction has been much more subdued than on the international scale. Although we've been around four years and have received wide media coverage both locally and internationally, we still remain relative unknowns within Egypt. Those who know us and are excited about what we're doing are mostly friends and colleagues. Having said that, among that subset people are really excited and see this game for the historic event that it is! As for reaction to the game in general - to know roller derby is to love it, and once people become familiar the game they generally become serious fans. We've been very lucky to have so much support at home and abroad.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id="x_gmail-m_-4780500211593238315divtagdefaultwrapper" dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are CaiRollers hopes and plans post-game, for 2017 and beyond? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we've come to this major milestone we hope to continue finding ways to play against leagues around the world. We've already got a game lined up with a team from Marseilles in April, and are having conversations here and there with other leagues around the world so we hope to see what comes out of those. At home, we hope to continue to grow both in numbers and skill and maintain the local, homegrown nature of our league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-13992 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/srd3.jpg" alt="srd3" width="201" height="201"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did Abu Dhabi Roller Derby begin as a league, and how has it developed over the years?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller derby was started in both Dubai and Abu Dhabi by expatriates with experience from playing roller derby in leagues from the USA, UK, Canada and Australia. Dubai has had a league since 2012. Abu Dhabi started skating regularly at Zayed Sports City and duForum in 2013.  Since then our league has grown to around 40 members, with 20 skating regularly. We still struggle to retain people as expats are often moving in and out of the country, but we have a great core team now of 12 girls, 2 refs and lots of volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does it feel to be taking part in the first ever roller derby game in the MENA region?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are exciting times. It's hard to train and keep yourself motivated without having a game or competition as a goal. The lack of other roller derby teams in the area is the main reason for this. So this game not only gave us a goal, but also raised the profile of the sport in the region, hopefully opening the doors for future games and the development of new roller derby teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have you been preparing for the game?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We train twice a week, outside, for about 2 hours. We have been working on reviewing the rules of the game, ensuring everyone knows the procedures, looking at and practising different strategy drills and playing against each other. We have also been testing a few new 'moves' and seeing what works. We have a few very experienced players, but also lots of people who have never taken part in a bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your hopes and plans post-game, for 2017 and beyond?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;We hope that the event will encourage more people to take part in the sport, raise the profile of roller derby in the region and our league to grow. We also plan to host the fabulous CaiRollers' Cleopatras in Abu Dhabi at some point this year. We want to spread the derby love in the region and hopefully get more of the public and local businesses on board.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Arabian Fights has a Facebook event &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/403635766647515/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.  &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Abu-Dhabi-Roller-Derby-153725484785780/"&gt;Abu Dhabi Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/CaiRollergirls/?fref=ts"&gt;CaiRollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; can also be found on Facebook.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>abu dhabi roller derby</category><category>articles</category><category>cairollers</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>mena derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/18/menas-first-ever-public-interleague-abu-dhabi-v-cairollers/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 09:53:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Future of Derby: The Middle East</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/19/the-future-of-derby-the-middle-east/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next up in our series on the Future of Derby is another geographical region where the growth and development of the sport is pushing new boundaries: North Africa and the Middle East. Egypt's &lt;a href="http://www.cairollers.com/"&gt;CaiRollers&lt;/a&gt; swept to some fame a few years ago when they were first founded, getting attention in some major newspapers, but since then other leagues have begun emerging, in the UAE and in Lebanon...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Middle-East has, perhaps, particular challenges for Roller Derby, as it (and Asia) have less Western ideas of women and sports in popular culture. As Derby develops into a truly International sport, encountering and adapting to non-Western cultural ideals will be a key test of the sport and its leadership (as will the ability to decentralise the core of the sport itself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to all three Middle-Eastern leagues we are aware of, to find out how they see the sport developing in their region. &lt;a href="http://www.dubairollerderby.com/"&gt;Dubai Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s The Killer Purple answered questions for them, while the CaiRollers had their Nofearteti respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Roller-Derby-Beirut/763063127094159"&gt;Roller Derby Beirut&lt;/a&gt; is currently just a work in progress, and their founder provided us with the following statement: &lt;em&gt;Women of the Middle East face challenges that cannot compare in any way to the reality we know where I live, in the cold Northern Copenhagen. I've been following the amazing ladies of the CaiRollers, and the way Roller Derby enables them to claim their space in the public sphere. This is not about religion, Orientalism or naïve good-doing; it's about sharing our amazing sport and community with women around the world. It makes me happy and proud to feel the derby community reach out and help in any way they are able to; that's why Derby is so unique. I hope the ladies of Beirut will find this together whilst turning left. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[You can help Roller Derby Beirut with donations at the World Cup or otherwise via this event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/599390206837488/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/599390206837488/&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dubai:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Although Roller Derby in Dubai (and the U.A.E. in general) is young, have you considered a national team submission for the next &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;World Cup&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely. We would definitely consider submitting a National Team, and have already discussed it. The issue, however, is that few of our skaters, if any, are from Dubai/the U.A.E. This is not because we have any kind of restrictive or exclusionary policies but because of the U.A.E.’s demographics. Roughly 80% of the population is expatriate. Local women also tend to be from more protective family backgrounds. Athletic local women are certainly the exception to the rule although this is slowly changing. As it stands, the World Cup’s eligibility rules need to be modified to be able to include places like the U.A.E., Singapore, Hong Kong, Qatar, Egypt, etc. and our particular social make-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Middle-East has perhaps unique problems for the growth of derby, but some issues are common to leagues across the World. What have been your issues to date with growing and spreading derby across the U.A.E?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Possibly the primary factor that limits the growth of derby in Dubai &amp;amp; the U.A.E. is the transient nature of the population. Most people come here early on in their careers, at a time when their lives are changing rapidly, stay for a few years to benefit from the tax-free laws, and then return to their native countries to establish more permanent homes. While they’re here, they take advantage of Dubai’s proximity and ease of access to many tourist destinations, and travel frequently. This constant turnover of people, and serial absence of skaters makes it difficult to plot and monitor progress of an individual skater, and of the league. Expatriates also tend to take long breaks from work in the summer to escape the scorching, draining temperatures. This discontinuity certainly slows our progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another factor that has severely hampered our growth is the lack of infrastructure to support us. At the peak of the quad skate fashion, the U.A.E. was little more than a desert, and as such, has no old roller rinks, no old skates, no former wheely-disco-divas. What we do have is an indoor ski slope, which has that excessive appeal that Dubai prides itself on. The roller derby “story” of grassroots, female empowerment, alternative living, community driven success is not one that might appeal to decision-makers here – people that have the money, resources, and permits to build. This is Eden for big business-big government. Unless a direct monetary advantage can be leveraged, the project is dead in the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Culture probably does play a significant factor as the athletic development of girls and women is considered secondary to their moral well-being. Athletic facilities that women use are primarily built for men. We know that many derby leagues began in parking lots, etc. but try skating in 99% humidity, and 50°C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, finding a decent sports hall, with skateable flooring, has given our league a much-needed boost. With a consistent practice location and times, we’ve gained a good reputation, garnered a lot of media attention, and gotten a lot of new skaters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any hopes for development in the Derby community which would make the sport more successful in the Middle East, and Dubai in particular?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) To be perfectly honest, the only way in which we hope derby develops is in being able to include us to play in the World Cup. It could be a concern that as the sport grows, people jump on the bandwagon and beat the horses. Right now, We like that there isn’t a fat-cat commission setting rules for me to make them money. We like that derby isn’t about money. We like that we've got an international sk8rhood. We like that we’re fierce and I like that we have to fight for our right to party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Egypt (Cairollers):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The CaiRollers have been growing for about 2 years now. What challenges (and support/unexpectedly easy things) have you encountered on the way? (Are any unique to Egypt?)&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenges today remain similar to what they were when we first started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) the gear is not available in Egypt and it's not easy to get it shipped here without paying hefty fines and/or guaranteeing that something will get lost along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) Practice locations - it's difficult to find a suitable surface for us to play on, and when we do it's either too expensive. We don't have any sponsors yet and we pay for all practice venues out of dues which we try to keep to a reasonable amount so that players from all walks of life can play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) Drumming up awareness of what derby us and support and interest from women to play. In addition to which many of our founding players were expats, so in our second year we lost about 80% of the team and had to kind of start from scratch. However, we have managed to build a more local base and now the team is majority Egyptians or women who are living in Egypt for the long term, so turnover won't be as high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unexpectedly easy and awesome thing which has helped with all of the above challenges is the international support that we have received. So many teams from all over the world have supported us by talking us up, donating a ton of gear and even making financial donations to our paypal account. the amount of derby love that has come our way from ALL over the world has been overwhelming and incredible. At the end of our 1st birthday &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/video.php?v=10101801428504640&amp;amp;set=vb.320558514691079&amp;amp;type=3&amp;amp;theater"&gt;slideshow&lt;/a&gt; we had such a long list of leagues to thank and send out love to and that was an amazing thing.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Has the English-language focus of derby, especially with rules + best practice, caused any problems?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Yes, it has caused some issues in terms of teaching our own players the rules, but also in terms of drumming up interest in the game. There is no direct translation for the word Jammer in Arabic. How do we explain roller derby without being able to explain what a jammer is? [In almost all other languages, Jammer remains untranslated, or becomes something like "star" in the destination language - Ed] But we've made do. Recently we've been talking about translating our fresh meat package into Arabic. We've got parts of it translated now, but we want all the details to be available in Arabic so we can sort of be a resource for derby in Arabic.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;If there is a World Cup in 2016/17, would you consider forming a Team Egypt? (Eligibility for national teams tends to be decided by nationality, not domicile.) Have you thought about this already?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would definitely consider it but there's a lot that would go into that consideration. We don't have any sponsorship, though we've been trying to drum up some big name sponsors for a year now. We would need some serious sponsorship in order to be able to go, as many of the women on our team cannot afford to contribute much, if anything towards travel abroad. We would also like to have a couple of bootcamps and play a couple of international bouts if possible prior so that the World Cup is not our first time encountering that level of play. But as a pipe dream, it's definitely something we've talked about from time to time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;As derby grows outside the "Western" cultures of North America and Western Europe, do you see any changes either being required to grow in those new areas, or being fed back into the community from those new cultures?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
I don't think there need to be any real, fundamental changes to the game of derby in order for it to grow, but there has to be perhaps a widening in the scope of what is meant by derby culture. We've been able to adapt the 'badass' tough chick image of derby to our situation here in Egypt. We've got Egyptian women from various social classes and religious backgrounds playing together, some are veiled, some are not. When the veiled women first showed an interest in derby some of them asked if it would be possible to play with their hijab. We of course told them that there is no requirement that they wear racy clothing or have tattoos or any of these other things that they might have picked up from some of the popular media around derby (The movie Whip It is shown on a regional satellite network quite often, and I think this is where a lot of people might be getting their ideas about derby...) In any case, we've adopted a very 'come as you are' attitude here, and I think we've done a good job of reconciling the different viewpoints of our players about what derby culture is and what it should be. So I guess, that's just a long way of saying that I don't think there need to be any drastic changes to derby in order for it to grow in new areas. I think each league will sort of naturally figure out what works best for them.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>cairollers</category><category>dubai roller derby</category><category>future derby</category><category>future of derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>middle east</category><category>roller derby beirut</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/19/the-future-of-derby-the-middle-east/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 09:59:50 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>