<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about cancellations)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/cancellations.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 19:32:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>WFTDA Competitive Season Cut by COVID-19</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/04/WFTDA-COVID19/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of our updates have been cancellations recently - although we hope to get more positive content in the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, though, it's still a bit negative, as the WFTDA announced the cancellation of Playoffs and Continental Cups this season. With the ongoing effects of COVID-19 responses across all of the competitive regions in which Roller Derby happens, it was inevitable that the competitive season would be at least strongly truncated - with it unlikely that we'll see anything like a semblance of "normal training" before June, it's clear that expecting teams to launch back into the WFTDA Sanctioned competition would be unrealistic (to say nothing of the expectations this would place on Officials and Volunteers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(As far as possible, the hosts will be hosting the equivalent events in 2021, with WFTDA support for the impacts of this on the leagues.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the Rankings Committee and Competitive Play Committee have made continual adjustments to try to allow the rankings system to support teams, it's sometimes necessary to also cut back the schedule itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WFTDA &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; still planning a "Championships" event in November, although we would imagine that the nature of this will be strongly dependent on upcoming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full WFTDA statement can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://resources.wftda.org/3-30-20-covid-19-statement-and-update/"&gt;https://resources.wftda.org/3-30-20-covid-19-statement-and-update/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cancellations</category><category>covid19</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/04/WFTDA-COVID19/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>COVID-19 and Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/03/COVID19/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's hard not to be aware of the effect that the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic is causing on all human activity, globally, and Roller Derby is not exempt. COVID-19, the disease caused by
SARS-CoV-2, is stretching the health services of several nations. In order to control its spread, an increasing number of internal and external travel and gathering restrictions are being applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Italy and China, where all non-essential gatherings are currently banned, Roller Derby has stopped along with everything else. The Chinese leagues have not been able to practice since the lockdown in their
country in February (with restrictions now slowly being lifted); in Italy since the increasingly escalating actions in the last week or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An increasing number of tournaments are now beginning to cancel. In Italy, the Anguanas' March and April Sanctioned triple-headers have been cancelled; but even in countries with less internal restrictions, there are cancellations. Copenhagen Ladybugs have had to cancel their upcoming Sevens extravaganza due to the Danish advice, for example; and there are a host of cancellations across the continental USA, despite their government's lacklustre response to ongoing events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are yet to see changes to the status of the Men's Roller Derby World Cup or Rollercon, both highly-international events this year, but given the breaking news restrictions placed by the US President on travel from Schengen countries in Europe, it seems increasingly likely that there will be &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; knock-on effect. (They are both scheduled far enough in the future that it is &lt;em&gt;possible&lt;/em&gt; that we could have a pandemic peak before they happen; but once an infectious disease goes pandemic, it becomes much harder to eradicate quickly.) [Edited after initial publication to note: MRDWC have announced that they will be following all local and international advice; but this has not yet resulted in an actual change to their schedule.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://resources.wftda.org/covid-19/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt; has published risk-management guidelines for reducing the spread of SARS-CoV-2 infections if you do hold public games during this period. They essentially reduce to the usual advice that minimising physical contact, and maintaining proper hygiene standards is the most effective way to reduce the spread of the virus, along with recommendations to cancel non-essential events and follow your country's own guidelines and restrictions. (As with other examples of force majeure, WFTDA will not penalise members for cancelling Sanctioned events due to public health concerns around COVID-19.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're hoping to chat to some of the most affected regions and at least help keep their Roller Derby in the public eye a bit, even if they can't play...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...but if you want to help track all the effects on Roller Derby (or just see the results of this), we're linking to Axis of Stevil's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1mZhFN7i7s1vTUCE5g0gfy_YqFNDaUq0sAvWhI0nT1so/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;public Google Doc&lt;/a&gt; for this purpose. Stevil is part of WFTDA's "COVID19 Taskforce", who are working in managing the response to the pandemic and its medical and political effects relating to the sport and its participants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cancellations</category><category>covid19</category><category>epidemiology</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>oronaviruses</category><category>roller derby</category><category>statistics</category><category>tournaments</category><category>training</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/03/COVID19/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 07:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>