<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about cannie gingers)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/cannie-gingers.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>From Lucerne with Shoves: Voodoo's international tournament plans!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/12/from-lucerne-with-shoves-voodoos-international-tournament-plans/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While this weekend continues the tradition of being rather busy in roller derby, in Glasgow, something a little epic is being planned. Fresh from the end of the British Championships Tier 4 competition, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Voodoo-Roller-Dollies-571771319549241/"&gt;Voodoo Roller Dollies&lt;/a&gt; are hosting a mini-tournament, with an international bent. Returning from Voodoo's last tournament (only this February!) are Glasgow C, the &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/content/cannie-gingers"&gt;Cannie Gingers&lt;/a&gt;; however, flying in all the way from Lucerne (Luzern), Switzerland, the third team are &lt;a href="http://www.thehellveticats.ch/"&gt;The Hellveticats&lt;/a&gt;, part of the new wave of Swiss and Central European roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/12/from-lucerne-with-shoves-voodoos-international-tournament-plans/12006363_963059253753777_8455008463369869288_n/" rel="attachment wp-att-4938"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4938" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/12006363_963059253753777_8455008463369869288_n.jpg" alt="12006363_963059253753777_8455008463369869288_n" width="614" height="231"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2012, the Hellveticats started with the usual enthusiasm of new leagues, despite, as Referee Lucy Cat Rolls told us "that most of the girls on the team haven't even watched a roller derby game, we did our best to train and build up our league". They've been bouting since late 2013, according to Flat Track Stats, mostly playing the rest of the Swiss and Central European derby community. In fact, the tournament will not just be a new experience for the Scottish teams, as it's the furthest trip that the Hellveticats have made in their history."As we have many members with family or other responsibilities we try to get bouts which are possible to travel within a day trip. But, every now and then, we make a journey with the team - we went to [Prague] in the Czech Republic and to Nice in France. Scotland is within a very good distance by plane so we decided to travel there together, we are thrilled to be invited to this awesome event."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it happens, the fact that the tournament exists at all is actually down to the Hellveticats' enthusiasm for a long distance trip. As Voodoo's Roll-N-Pin told us: "[The Hellveticats] actually contacted us, believe it or not. They got in contact with our very own Titan and from there it progressed. We wanted to make sure that they got as much of a Scottish derby experience as possible, [so we organised the tournament around them]." Not that Voodoo have ever been shy of a tournament, as Pin admitted, "tournaments are always a great way to involve so many people at the same time. To come up against new teams and get to spend even more time in a weekend or day playing against them. I mean, who doesn't love more derby time? It's double, and even triple, the fun at times with tournaments."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Hellveticats are travelling the furthest, it's Glasgow's &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/45330"&gt;Cannie Gingers&lt;/a&gt; who are the most dangerous competitors in the tournament, sitting almost 200 places above &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/38908"&gt;Voodoo&lt;/a&gt;, and 130 above the &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/20691"&gt;Lucerne&lt;/a&gt; team, in Flat Track Stats' European ranking scheme (although our own prediction scheme places the latter somewhat closer in ability to the Glasgow team). Despite the huge challenge they represent, Voodoo are relishing the rematch. "The Canny Gingers are always a fierce opponent and are really the definition of a true challenge, " said Roll N Pin, "but with each bout we play against superior teams, we gain more knowledge , discover more tactics  and get to try out more strategies. It would take a phenomenal achievement on our part to win against them, but for us it's not all about the win. At the end of the day if the other team are walking away with bump and bruises, sore spots and dead arms or legs then we know we have put up a great fight and have made them work for it. It gives us a goal to work towards as well, a comparison to ourselves to see how much we have improved and how we can improve more." And the Cannie Gingers aren't willing to rule out the possibility of a Voodoo win, saying "there are no guarantees in Derby; just look at the Rose/Victorian/Gotham games in the WFTDA Championships. We just want to play our games and take each jam as they come!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow C are also keen to see what Swiss derby has to offer, noting that "one of the great things about roller derby is the opportunities it brings, and it's an honour to play every team we face, for the things we are taught in each game. It will be interesting to see how our styles play against each other; we hope it will also be a fun experience and that [the Hellveticats] have a good Scottish welcome".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of who actually wins, all the teams have the same goals at heart. Roll N Pin "First and foremost, and it may seem cheesy, [our goal] is to have FUN! We want to present an environment to welcome all and make sure that the players and the crowd are having fun. But hey that's not too hard to do when you've got derby, tunes and CAKE!", and Lucy Cat Roll agrees, "I guess the biggest challenge will be understanding the Scottisch dialect and resisting to the urge of drinking whisky before the first whistle ;-) We hope to have fun and to meet many nice derby people and we hope to have you over in Switzerland one day and invite you for a nice tournament, some cheese and a ton of chocolate." The Gingers also, "above all, [] just want to have a nice time! We have some established skaters, and some who will be playing their first game, so it's a nice mix. We work hard at training, and in running our league, so we just want to represent GRD in the best way we can."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voodoo Roller Dollies have a new intake planned for the end of November, and extensive plans for the future. As Pin puts it: "Voodoo's future is looking bright. We have a new intake at the end of this month (as always we are looking to expand) and we have many a teams to play again for return games. We are hoping to get more involved in the derby community and attend more scrims. Maybe even host a few ourselves. One thing is for sure we will always come back hitting harder and pushing ourselves further."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tournament starts from &lt;strong&gt;Midday&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8666126,-4.2505074,17z/data=!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7"&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt; in Glasgow Caledonian University on Saturday &lt;strong&gt;14th November&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event page can be found on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/908423505918913/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, and tickets will be £5 on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as we are aware, the planned schedule of play is:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Doors 12:00&lt;br&gt;
Skate outs 12:20&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
1st game - VRD v GRD - 12:30&lt;br&gt;
2nd game - GRD v Hell - 13:55&lt;br&gt;
3rd game - Hell v VRD - 15:20&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>cannie gingers</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>hellveticats</category><category>international</category><category>interviews</category><category>tournament</category><category>voodoo roller dollies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/12/from-lucerne-with-shoves-voodoos-international-tournament-plans/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 20:42:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow ready to roar into action in a derby double-decker</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/25/glasgow-ready-to-roar-into-action-in-a-derby-double-decker/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow’s roller derby dudes will go roaring into action on Saturday, October 4, 2014 as they aim to be the leaders of the Pack against some of England’s top skaters.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city’s first men’s roller derby team – Mean City – are once again hosting a special double-decker featuring top male and female skaters from north and south of the border.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/mean-wirrals.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-3883 alignright" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/mean-wirrals.jpg?w=300" alt="Mean Wirrals" width="416" height="164"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby will be taking on Wirral’s Pack Animals in an all-male clash, while the all-female, all-awesome Cannie Gingers from Glasgow Roller Derby will go toestop to toestop with fellow Scots, the sensational Central Belters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s going to be a rock ‘n’ roll day out for sports fans of all ages – combining skills, thrills and spills … all on skates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenny Reid, Chairman of Mean City Roller Derby (MCRD), said: “We can’t wait for this very special double-header. Mean City is Glasgow’s first and only men’s roller derby league and has been going from strength to strength since it was formed in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re genuinely thrilled to be welcoming three amazing squads to Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Pack Animals are a great team and a terrific bunch of lads – we can’t wait to line up against them. Mean City features some of the best skaters in Scotland and we will be giving our all to ensure the super summer of sport continues in Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Pack Animals hail from the wilds of the Wirral and are coming north aiming to take Mean City’s scalp, but we’re aiming to be the leaders of this Pack.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City recorded their first ever victory in August against Teesside's Skate Invaders and are hungry for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meawhile, Glasgow Roller Derby (GRD) – Mean City’s all-female sister league – is renowned throughout the roller derby world. Its A team – the Irn Bruisers –stormed America earlier this year, while its B team – the Maiden Grrders – are also a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such is the strength in depth at GRD that a third travel team has been formed – the Cannie Gingers – and they are already making a name for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mighty Central Belters – part of Bairn City Rollers – all hail from Central Scotland and will be heading west aiming to pop the Gingers’ bubble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenny added: “This is the first team these four teams have clashed and it’s going to be awesome. You’ll be treated to two full-on games of roller derby for just £5 – free entry to under-14s with a paying adult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s going to be a great showcase of all that roller derby has to offer – an action-packed afternoon of skating, scoring, skills, thrills and spills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you’ve never been to a roller derby bout, get along to the ARC on October 4 – there will be action, fun, entertainment, refreshments and more.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The double-header takes place at The ARC, Glasgow Caledonian University, Cowcaddens Road, Glasgow, on Saturday, October 4, 2014 – from 11.30am&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby has been developing as a league since its formation in 2012. Men’s roller derby is a fledgling off-shoot of the modern day all-female sport of roller derby – with the game rising in popularity with people of all genders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City train regularly in the Glasgow area and new members are always welcome to give the sport a go in a supportive environment. Equipment can be provided – just get in touch in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby"&gt;www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby&lt;/a&gt; to buy tickets for the event and to find out more about joining the revolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>cannie gingers</category><category>central belters</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>in the news</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>wirral pack animals</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/25/glasgow-ready-to-roar-into-action-in-a-derby-double-decker/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 22:51:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Close Encounters of the Thrilled Kind - derby double header</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/26/close-encounters-of-the-thrilled-kind-derby-double-header/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/3xo4jhp-imgur.png"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-3550 aligncenter" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/3xo4jhp-imgur.png?w=300" alt="3xO4jHP - Imgur" width="422" height="163"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow is bracing itself for a close encounter of the ‘thrilled’ kind as some of the grooviest skaters in Scotland and England clash as part of a unique sporting double-header.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city’s first men’s roller derby team – Mean City – will host the special event on August 23 at the ARC sports centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City will be playing Teeside’s Skate Invaders – the first time the two teams have clashed – in an all-male, action-packed contest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space will be a premium as the Invaders beam into Glasgow – hoping they can blast their way to victory against the MCRD troopers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The double bill will also see Glasgow Roller Derby’s Cannie Gingers compete against Fierce Valley Roller Girls’ Parma Violents in an all-female thrill-fest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jim Whyte, Chairman of Mean City Roller Derby (MCRD), said: “We can’t wait for this very special double-header. The skating will be out of this world with four great roller derby leagues going toestop to toestop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Mean City is Glasgow’s first and only men’s roller derby league and has been going from strength to strength since it was formed in 2012. We’re genuinely thrilled to be welcoming three amazing squads to Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Skate Invaders are a great team and a terrific bunch of lads – we can’t wait to line up against them. Mean City features some of the best skaters in Scotland and we will be giving our all to ensure the super summer of sport continues in Glasgow.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby (GRD) – Mean City’s all-female sister league – is renowned throughout the roller derby world. Its A team – the Irn Bruisers – recently stormed America, while its B team – the Maiden Grrders – are also a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such is the strength in depth at GRD that a third travel team has been formed – the Cannie Gingers – who made their competitive debut against Fierce Valley in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jim added: “Fierce Valley had the edge in the first encounter, but Glasgow will be keen to win on home soil. It’s going to be another cracking encounter between two brilliant teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Get your tickets now – just £5 in advance for two amazing full games of roller derby starring four interstellar teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s going to be a great showcase of all that roller derby has to offer – an action-packed afternoon of skating, scoring, skills, thrills and spills.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby has been developing as a league since its formation in 2012. Men’s roller derby is a fledgling off-shoot of the modern day all-female sport of roller derby – with the game rising in popularity with people of all genders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City train regularly in the Glasgow area and new members are always welcome to give the sport a go in a supportive environment. Equipment can be provided – just get in touch in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby"&gt;www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby&lt;/a&gt; to buy tickets for the event and to find out more about joining the revolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cannie gingers</category><category>fvrg</category><category>grd</category><category>mcrd</category><category>parma violents</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/26/close-encounters-of-the-thrilled-kind-derby-double-header/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 22:59:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Girls vs. Glasgow Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/28/fierce-valley-roller-girls-vs-glasgow-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 15th February, The Peak in Stirling will play host to &lt;a title="FVRG Website" href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' first bout of 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Parma Violents will take on &lt;a title="GRD Website" href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s brand new team, The Cannie Gingers, who will be making their bouting debut. This is an event not to be missed!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 2pm with the first whistle at 2.30pm. Tickets can be bought for £5 (+ booking fee) in advance from &lt;a title="But Bout Tickets from BPT" href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/560142" target="_blank"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt;, or cost £7 on the door. Under 14s go free with a paying adult.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please see &lt;a title="FVRG Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/278718162276368/" target="_blank"&gt;FVRG's Facebook Event &lt;/a&gt;for full details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/poster.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3207" alt="FVRG vs. GRD bout poster" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/poster.jpg" width="614" height="906"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; FVRG vs. GRD bout poster - image courtesy of FVRG&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cannie gingers</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>parma violents</category><category>stirling</category><category>the peak</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/28/fierce-valley-roller-girls-vs-glasgow-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 12:48:52 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>