<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about central city rollergirls)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/central-city-rollergirls.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 08:59:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>EuroClash 2018: Newcastle Roller Girls' tournament expands beyond the "Euro".</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/26/euroclash-2018-newcastle-roller-girls-tournament-expands-beyond-the-euro/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Readers of the blog will remember our coverage of Newcastle Roller Girls' first European Tournament, &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/365884340424845/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, back in 2017. Newcastle's first WFTDA Recognised Tournament brought together teams across Europe for some high level action, and prefigured performances as far ahead as WFTDA Playoffs; as well as presenting a sneak peak at two of the National teams (Scotland and Ireland) as they worked towards the 3rd Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the ridiculously tournament-filled start of this year has delayed us, we're also going to be bringing you as much coverage as we can of the return of EuroClash this year... although, given one of the attendees this time, the tournament has already outgrown its name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this initial article, we're just going to introduce you to the competitors, and their current placements in the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst 2018's edition is slightly smaller than 2017's - 9 attendees (6 returning from last time), rather than 11 - their geographic distribution is &lt;em&gt;substantially&lt;/em&gt; wider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning from 2017's inaugural event are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls (hosts)
Auld Reekie Roller Girls (soon to &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/25/auld-reekies-10-anniversary-rebrand-with-your-help/"&gt;rebrand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; to Auld Reekie Roller Derby) [Edinburgh]
Central City Roller Derby (competed last year as Central City Rollergirls) [Birmingham]
Dublin Roller Derby
Middlesbrough Roller Derby (EuroClash2017 was their first fixture after rebranding)
Tiger Bay Brawlers [Cardiff]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joining them to make up the full nine are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames
Dock City Roller Derby [Gothenburg]
Steel City Roller Derby [Pittsburgh]!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-26639" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/euroclash2018.png?w=2048" alt="EuroClash2018" width="1024" height="768"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, EuroClash served as the first step for several of the attending teams' campaigns to get into WFTDA Playoffs - Auld Reekie, Bear City, Paris and Dublin all gaining valuable ranking points from their attendance, as all bouts are WFTDA Sanctioned games.
Whilst EuroClash itself is not arranged to provide a final ranking, or a tournament cup, we did analyse the tournament itself &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Our analysis was good enough to predict the results of Paris Rollergirls' subsequent two games against other attendees, so it's probably as good as any other attempt at rating the teams...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since last year, the returning teams have played a lot of Roller Derby, with varying stories; so we can expect some changes in the matchups this time around. [We're using the FTS "WFTDA" ratings here, as not all the teams can be rated with the usually-more-accurate Europe ratings.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the time of writing, the attending EuroClash 2018 teams span a 41 position zone within FTS's rankings - but a fairly closely rated one. (FTS's built in predictor tool expects only a 2:1 score ratio between the highest rated - Dublin - and lowest rated - Auld Reekie - teams if they played today.) We've also included, in parenthesis, the WFTDA Official ratings and rankings for the teams - despite the different ordering, the "range" in strengths is about the same for WFTDA's own ratings, perhaps slightly larger.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="3" rowspan="1"&gt;FTS "WFTDA" Ratings 23 April 2018 (WFTDA Rating 31 March)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rank&lt;/strong&gt; (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Rating (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;53&lt;/strong&gt; (46)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7775/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;745.2 (391.51)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;62&lt;/strong&gt; (65)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/29732/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dock City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;732.4 (318.9)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;63&lt;/strong&gt; (68)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7948/rankings/wftda"&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;729.4 (307.57)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;70&lt;/strong&gt; (94)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7763/rankings/wftda"&gt;Central City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;713.3 (242.58)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;83&lt;/strong&gt; (62)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7949/rankings/wftda"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;691.7 (323.67)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;86&lt;/strong&gt; (95)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/3417/rankings/wftda"&gt;Steel City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;683.0 (241.15)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;88&lt;/strong&gt; (88)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7736/rankings/wftda"&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;682.2 (259.63)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;93&lt;/strong&gt; (85)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7953/rankings/wftda"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;676.0 (262.62)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;94&lt;/strong&gt; (87)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/5912/rankings/wftda"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;674.9 (259.86)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
Auld Reekie and Middlesbrough both suffered ratings reductions against 2x4 Roller Derby during the latter's Jan-Feb tour of Europe, where the Argentine team outperformed expectations against almost &lt;i&gt;everyone&lt;/i&gt;. The jury is out as to how much of this is due to 2x4's general under-ranking, and how much is due to over-ranking of the teams they played - in general, we'd expect better-than-ranking performances from both teams at EuroClash.
Middlesbrough could potentially surprise the current #1 seeds, Dublin; the gap between their WFTDA ratings is entirely due to that loss to the under-ranked 2x4, and their European rating, by comparison, places them above the Irish team (and only just below Paris)!
Similarly, Auld Reekie's European rating places them in the middle of the field, rather than at the bottom, although their trajectory is in the same direction - however, some of this is due to their bout against Leeds Roller Derby, who are almost certainly under-ranked at this point in the year.
&lt;p&gt;Hosts Newcastle have also had difficult bouts, against EuroClash 2017 returnees Central City Roller Derby - given CCR's stronger-than-previous performance against other recent opponents, we consider this to be more of a reflection on CCR than Newcastle - and Leeds Roller Derby (who, again, are simply improving themselves, as they knit together as a team after their first year). We suspect Newcastle are somewhat underranked due to their choice of opponents, and as the hosts they'll be wanting to show that at EuroClash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remaining steady, Tiger Bay Brawlers have still had a pretty good year - and even their recent loss to Central City is not a bad sign, as their performance was near identical to that at EuroClash 2017; if CCR show signs of being back on the up, then this is actually good for the Cardiff team too. The recent transfer of Kid Block back to TBB from London can only improve their strength further - we expect strong performances from the team, beyond what their current rating implies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dublin Roller Derby have also had a pretty good 2017, continuing their upward trend in the FTS European ratings, and remaining steady in the WFTDA rating. Their current placement at the top of EuroClash 2018's rankings seems solid, barring improvements from Dock City, or Middlesbrough. This could all change this weekend, however, as Dublin play some competitive sanctioned games over in the USA at Southern Discomfort 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also remaining steady for the past year, Steel City Roller Derby - after losing around 100 rating points in 2016, the team had a very stable 2017, sticking around the 680-690 rating they still reside at entering EuroClash. A return to their 2016 high would make them easily the strongest team in the tournament, but we suspect their middle-table ranking is more likely, especially given the effects of trans-Atlantic travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gothenburg's second league, Dock City Rollers, continued their generally upwards climb over 2017 (and 2016), and show no particular signs of stopping this progress in WFTDA bouts. They're one of two teams which could challenge expected #1, Dublin if they play against them. Looking at the more plentiful data in the European FTS rankings, they've suffered a "correction" to their ranking as a result of their performance in last year's Swedish national tournament, but their trend is still upward - if we believe the European values, however, they'll be better matched against Auld Reekie than Dublin's finest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representing Birmingham, we have both Birmingham Blitz Dames and Central City Roller Derby, and both seeing upwards movement in the rankings over the past year - Central City in the past month or two, and BBD earlier in 2017 - although the more detailed European ratings show signs of a correction in the Blitz Dames rating at the start of this year, albeit again against the probably-underranked Leeds Roller Derby.  We'll see if the Blitz Dames still have more rating gains to come in the WFTDA rating, as they play in the 2018 K Town Shakedown this weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be back with some more articles, and a guide to the schedule when its published, closer to the event...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash 2018&lt;/a&gt; will be hosted at the &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/6NHQpKxP5Em"&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; on the &lt;b&gt;19th&lt;/b&gt; and&lt;b&gt; 20th May&lt;/b&gt; 2018 - less than a month away! Tickets are on sale, for &lt;b&gt;£30&lt;/b&gt; in advance (£35 on the door), or at a limited special group discount price of&lt;b&gt; £100 for 4&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>birmingham blitz dames</category><category>central city roller derby</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>dock city rollers</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>euroclash</category><category>middlesbrough roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>steel city roller derby</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/26/euroclash-2018-newcastle-roller-girls-tournament-expands-beyond-the-euro/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 13:04:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: Central City Rollergirls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/28/euroclash-interviews-central-city-rollergirls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this week's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; interview, covering the attendees at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;' first international Tournament, this &lt;strong&gt;March 25&lt;/strong&gt;th to &lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt;th, we're back in the UK with one of the first teams in the UK... Birmingham's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://centralcityrollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;Central City Rollergirls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In common with many of the attendees at EuroClash, CCR A attended the Beach Brawl in Florida in 2016, winning two out of three bouts with impressive margins. They also managed to compete against two other EuroClash attendees towards the end of the year - holding Dublin to a near draw, and also playing Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year, as well as EuroClash, Central City are once again joining forces with Dublin to play San Fernando Valley Roller Derby, of California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13730 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/central-city.png" alt="central-city" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CCR's Co-Captains, Bunny Massacre and Woo Ha!, answered a few questions for us about the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In common with quite a few EuroClash attendees, CCR had their first trip to the USA last year, at Beach Brawl. As with most first-time USA trips for European teams, you got a good 40+ place rankings boost from this… but how was the experience for you generally, and did you find it different to what you expected?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bunny: We had a fantastic time. This was something that we had wanted to do for such a long time and making it a reality was incredible. The whole trip increased our bond as a team; everyone worked so hard on and off track. I had tried to curb my expectations about our tournament experience. We had taken part in European tournaments in the past which had given us a great basis to work with and unsurprisingly a lot of the set up was similar! We had anticipated challenging and tough games, and weren’t disappointed! Overall it was a wonderful experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woo: It was an incredible experience - right through from the team decision to take part to the fundraising and combined league efforts and on to the actual tournament. The team was in great shape when we arrived and ready to face the somewhat unknown. We had limited intel on the teams we were facing so we approached each game with a view to playing OUR game and nailing our strategy objectives. We learned a lot (the logistics of a USA trip alone comes with its challenges) but we loved the challenge of games outside of the norm for us and the experience of tournament play was invaluable. It was a 100% positive experience!
&lt;strong&gt;You're also one of the few teams to beat London's B team, Brawl Saints, in 2016. Even London B used to be considered untouchable by other UK teams - how was it to play them (and do you think it's a sign that the rest of UK derby is really catching up to London)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woo: What a great game it was too! We're huge fans of the LRG Brawl Saints girls! The competitive Derby landscape is an exciting place to be; teams are getting tighter, strategy is getting slicker and the UK coaching standard is at an all time high. There's so much more we've got access to now for learning from vs 2 years ago... so yes, the playing field is definitely shifting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bunny: We had been working really hard to the build up to this game, as we knew it would be stiff competition. It was also our first home game in 18 months, so there was a real mixture of excitement and nerves! There was an overwhelming sense of pride and of course happiness when the final whistle blew. They were a great team to play. As Woo says there’s so much more knowledge, strategy and coaching available to us now and in such a diverse variety of ways. This is all having a significant impact on the standard of UK game play and definite sense that a real attempt is being made to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You'll be playing hosts Newcastle, and Tiger Bay Brawlers at EuroClash. When you played them last, both in 2015, TBB had a strong win, and Newcastle a close defeat… but in the last two years, both teams have changed things up quite a bit. How are you feeling about the two games?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bunny: We have a long history with both these teams, there’s real excitement to play them again. We are well aware that both teams are going bring their A game and be incredibly challenging to play. What’s great is that they are fantastic teams to compete against, we always really enjoy facing these ladies on track and no matter how fierce the game, it will also be great fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woo: There's huge excitement here at CCR for these match ups. We're really chuffed to be part of the action. Both opposition teams represent a massive opportunity for us to bring our best game to track against a bunch of classy, hardworking women. It's going to be tough, we're under no illusion, but having played both teams previously as well as going through some changes ourselves, we're really excited to see how it plays out on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, in the time between your two fixtures, which teams are you most looking forward to watching?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woo: So many awesome match ups! It's always great to watch Paris in action - we love those girls. We're excited to see the international game at the end of the tournament, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bunny: Playing at tournaments for me always brings along the added bonus that we get to watch incredible derby too! All of the fixtures look particularly exciting, but I’m looking forward to seeing Bear City play as I haven’t had an opportunity to watch them live in a while. And, of course, watching Team Ireland, where we may get the chance to support a couple of CCR team mates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets to EuroClash are available at: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets"&gt;https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and are &lt;strong&gt;£25&lt;/strong&gt; in advance. More information is available at the event page, linked at the top of this article.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>euroclash</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/28/euroclash-interviews-central-city-rollergirls/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 13:03:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Champions in Reserve: Auld Reekie B start off a busy year.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/09/champions-in-reserve-auld-reekie-b-start-off-a-busy-year/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While it's usually the A teams for a league which get most of the action, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.arrg.co.uk"&gt;Auld Reekie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; B, the All-Star Reserves, are setting themselves up for a very exciting 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as becoming only the joint-second B team to compete in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/"&gt;British Champs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (along with Newcastle B, the Whippin' Hinnies, and following London Rollergirls B last year), they're also taking Auld Reekie's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1623816624593204/"&gt;second bout of the year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; this weekend, against Central City Rollergirls B, the Slay Belles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14708 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/02/asrvccrsb.jpg" alt="asrvccrsb" width="851" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught up with Pukeahontas, ASR Co-Captain, for a quick chat about the team's past and future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The All-Star Reserves had a fairly busy year last year - even managing some international derby against Dresden. What was your highpoint of 2016?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016 was a mixed bag for me personally, I was off skates for the first 6 months of the year with a knee injury. But then to come back and skate in three amazing games against Batter C, Newcastle Whippin Hinnies and Granite City Northern Fights was incredible. My high point would have to be the Newcastle game, I felt this game was where we really came together as a team on track, we found our rhythm in the second half and I was gutted when I realised it was the last jam. Then we got to watch our pals in the All Stars skate an amazing game, have great chat with the lovely Newcastle skaters in the pub, and a hilarious coach trip back to Edinburgh. For me that day was what being part of ARRG is all about - playing a hard game of derby, and having a great time with great people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first bout of the year is against Central City B… whose A team will be at &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/12/euroclash-2017-the-teams/"&gt;EuroClash &lt;/a&gt;with ARRG A. Does this add a bit of symbolism to your bout… and how are you preparing for it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it does add a bit of symbolism, and I actually just think it’s really cool that we have this great level of play in the UK that leagues are well matched like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve been training hard, and drilling our tactics on repeat. We want to make sure that we are working as a unit on track, and that all the skaters on the roster trust each other. We don’t know too much about Central City B, we are preparing for a hard game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Reserves are also one of two Scottish teams in Tier 3 North of British Champs this year. What are your aims for the tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a team meeting about our plans for the year recently, and when we were discussing our goals and how the team might be a completely different line up before we play our games in August; one skater said that, no matter what might change, our goal should be that we feel like team, that everyone is welcomed and trusted. I’d love to support and encourage that environment as captain over the course of the tournament, and I guess winning our tier would be pretty great too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, the All-Star Reserves will be hosting the Slay Belles at Meadowbank Stadium, Edinburgh. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;2.2opm &lt;/strong&gt;on Saturday &lt;strong&gt;11th Feb&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catering provided by Bonnie Burritos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; online, or &lt;strong&gt;£8&lt;/strong&gt; on the door, or £6 for concessions, or free for under 14s. (online sales at: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2860993"&gt;http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2860993&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all star reserves</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/09/champions-in-reserve-auld-reekie-b-start-off-a-busy-year/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 11:14:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash 2017 - The Teams</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/12/euroclash-2017-the-teams/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;When Newcastle Roller Girls announced their intent to host a women's derby equivalent of the Men's European Cup (hosted by their sibling league, Tyne and Fear), there was understandable excitement... but the hosts have been remarkably secretive about the leagues involved, with the only hints being that the attendees were amongst the best teams in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Now, finally, the roster of competitors is announced, so we've made this quick guide to the teams (and will have individual features later on). EuroClash will be March 25th to 26th, at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Walker+Activity+Dome/@54.968707,-1.558266,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487e7068944e76d1:0xe1a6394d9f25325!8m2!3d54.968707!4d-1.556072"&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Newcastle. Tickets available &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.org.uk/buy-tickets/euroclash-2017"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-13774" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/euroclash.jpg" alt="euroclash" width="851" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, who are the teams competing in the first ever &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/365884340424845/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13711 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/newcastlerg_1.png" alt="newcastlerg_1" width="122" height="250"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Starting with the hosts, we have &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;. British Championships 2016 Premier Tier Winners, and currently ranked 76th by WFTDA (13th in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/europe"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and 13th by &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;*), the Canny Belters have had a strong 2016 - competing in the USA for the first time, at Beach Brawl in Florida (losing only to the mighty Rainy City) almost immediately after taking that British Championships win. In fact, the Belters have only lost to two teams in the last year - Rainy City and Edinburgh's Auld Reekie (who they also defeated in a rematch). As the hosts, home team advantage will also help their performance, and it would be a mistake to underestimate their chances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13716 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/leedsrollerderby-09.jpg" alt="leedsrollerderby-09" width="200" height="200"&gt;Staying within the UK, &lt;strong&gt;Leeds Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; are "technically" a new league, formed by merger of Hot Wheel Roller Derby and Leeds Roller Dolls at the end of 2016. Leeds Roller Dolls were ranked 65th by WFTDA, and their European Rankings were 23rd FTS, 22 SRD Rank; whilst Hot Wheel had Euro rankings of 31 and 25 respectively. We &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/19/by-their-powers-combined-they-are-leeds-roller-derby/"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on their merger at the time, and are excited to see what the combined pool of talent can accomplish in a single roster. Leeds Roller Dolls had their second trip to the USA in 2016, performing significantly above expectations; after placing solidly in the middle of the Champs Premier Tier rankings. Hot Wheel, by contrast, played their first European tournament in 2016, attending A Skate Odyssey, where they met surpassed expectations (beating their seeding by 4 places); they also managed to come second-from-top in British Champs Tier 2, clearly on the up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13765 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/mmr1.jpg" alt="mmr" width="222" height="200"&gt;Middlesbrough Milk Rollers&lt;/strong&gt; are possibly the highest ranked English team attending Euro Clash, with an impressive 56th position on the WFTDA rankings (9th in Europe by FTS, and 4th by SRD Rank)! MMR declined to participate in British Champs in 2016, but had an absolutely impressive year of competition, defeating almost all comers (including Connecticut and New Jersey) despite playing away for each and every bout. The only team to defeat them was London B, the Brawl Saints, which is not a bad record at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13730 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/central-city.png" alt="central-city" width="200" height="200"&gt;Central City Rollergirls&lt;/strong&gt; are the 83rd WFTDA ranked team (16th in Europe by SRD, and 20th by FTS), and one of the first Roller Derby leagues in the UK, representing Birmingham. CCR are the second team in this list to have spent their 2016 breaking into the USA via Beach Brawl, where they won more than they lost. They also defeated London B earlier on in the year, still a rare accomplishment for a UK team. The Birmingham team had quite a quiet year by comparison with the hectic adventures of some of the others in this list, and will have a lot of energy for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13735 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tigerbay.jpg" alt="tigerbay" width="200" height="183"&gt;Moving outside England, Wales' &lt;strong&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/strong&gt; are the best that their country has, ranked 75th by WFTDA (14th FTS, 12th SRD Rank in Europe). Declining to compete in British Champs in 2016, TBB instead competed against a wide range of European opponents, defeating London B, but narrowly failing against the mighty Rainy City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;After a lull in 2015, the general feeling is that Cardiff's all-stars have regained their best performance and are ready to go further in 2017; they're also a strong component of the current, and very strong, Welsh National Team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13740 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/arrg-logo.png" alt="arrg-logo" width="200" height="89"&gt;And representing the northern part of the UK, Edinburgh's &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; are the strongest team in Scotland, placing 60th in WFTDA (16th FTS, 20th SRD Rank in Europe). Auld Reekie made some waves last year by declining the offer to compete in WFTDA Playoffs, using the time to work more on their own performance - and they also declined British Champs 2016 as well. They did spend some time in the USA earlier in the year, competing at The Big O 2016, but had perhaps a more impressive start to 2016 where they defeated both our hosts Newcastle and Ireland's finest, Dublin. They'll be wanting to recapture that energy for the start of 2017... and will have a boost from their significant presence in the Team Scotland training squad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;For our remaining teams, we have to head outside the UK, so by distance, we first have...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13744 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/drd-logo.png" alt="drd-logo" width="200" height="213"&gt;...&lt;strong&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;, ranked 86th by WFTDA (but 11th in Europe by FTS and SRD Rank). Dublin have had a very exciting 2016, playing their first bouts in the USA at (yes!) Beach Brawl and winning against everyone except Newcastle Roller Girls! This performance didn't slow them down at all, as they also had one of the busiest schedules of 2016 as well, playing 15 bouts over the year, 10 of them away! With strong representation in Team Ireland, the Dublin team is definitely a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13749 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/paris.png" alt="paris" width="200" height="200"&gt;Moving a little further into Europe, &lt;strong&gt;Paris Rollergirls&lt;/strong&gt; are one of the two most exciting teams in France, ranked 71st by WFTDA, but 8th (or 9th) in Europe by FTS (SRD Rank). Hotly tipped for greatness in 2017 by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://thederbyapex.com/trending-french-roller-derby-56c5e691b036"&gt;The Derby Apex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the potential strength of Paris is also reflected in the performance of the French National Team, which they are a significant contributor to - Equipe de France is yet to lose a game with their current roster! Paris also burst onto the USA scene in 2016 at... (you've guessed it!) Beach Brawl, losing only the single bout. Much of the rest of their busy 2016 schedule was consumed by the French Nationale Elite Tier, which they topped, winning each and every bout in the 2015/6 season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13756 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/bcrd-bear-city-roller-derby_0.png" alt="bcrd-bear-city-roller-derby_0" width="200" height="200"&gt;From Berlin, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;Bear City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; are also one of the older teams in Europe, established back in 2008 . Ranked 50th by WFTDA (and 12th in Europe by FTS, 14th by SRD Rank), the Berlin Bombshells are the only team in this competition to have competed in WFTDA (Division 2) Playoffs in 2016, placing a strong 5th out of the 10 competitors, and defeating 4th seed Cincinnati on the way. In fact, Bear City spent more time competing in the USA than anywhere else in 2016, as the majority of their remaining bouts were at the Midwest BrewHaHa, with only two bouts in Europe (against Kallio Rolling Rainbow and Glasgow Roller Derby). Whilst Bear City the league also won the German Nationals (the Bundesliga), we believe this was strictly an exhibition team which differed from BCRD's normal A roster...
EuroClash sees the Bombshells return to Europe to take on the other rising stars of the continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;But that's not all, as we also have the excitement of a National Teams bout as well!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13777 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/ireland.jpg" alt="ireland" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13779 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/scotland.png" alt="scotland" width="200" height="200"&gt;Teams &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; met at the Road to TBC in Cardiff this November, with the Irish taking the win... but neither team had finalised their roster at that point. This rematch is taking place after final selections for Team Scotland [their selection bout is February 11th], and the Scots will be keen to show what they can do with the team that will be heading to the World Cup in Manchester. Meanwhile, Team Ireland were exceptionally green at the Road to TBC, and they will be that much more experienced as a squad by March...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We will be posting interviews with each of the teams competing at EuroClash over the next few weeks, to get into more depth about each of the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;* European rankings on SRD Rank computed from the set of all Women's Travel Teams in Europe known to the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bear city roller derby</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>euroclash</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>middlesbrough milk rollers</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>paris rollergirls</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/12/euroclash-2017-the-teams/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 19:15:31 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>