<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about cherry bombers)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/cherry-bombers.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 11:56:53 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>ARRG and Glasgow Home Seasons Final!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/23/arrg-and-glasgow-home-seasons-final/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Saturday (&lt;strong&gt;28th November&lt;/strong&gt;) sees Home Teams Tournaments on both coasts, as &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/23/arrg-and-glasgow-home-seasons-final/www.glasgowrollerderby.com"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; both host extravaganzas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4565" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/grd.jpg" alt="grd" width="960" height="349"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby are rolling their entire &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1507855322868655/"&gt;Home Season&lt;/a&gt; into one giant event, with the &lt;em&gt;Bad Omens&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Death Stars&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;T-Wrecks&lt;/em&gt; playing each other in a 5 hour triple header tournament. Last year, the Bad Omens took the trophy, but nothing is certain with the new format! As well as GRD skaters, the teams will be filled out by a few guest skaters from other leagues. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;11:30am&lt;/strong&gt;, for team skateouts at 11:50, and first whistle for Bad Omens v Death Stars at 12midday. As always, sponsors Pinto will be hosting the post-event food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are available from &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/glasgow-roller-derby-home-teams-2015-tickets-19466660305"&gt;Eventbrite&lt;/a&gt; (£5), or on the door for £7. As always, the venue is the &lt;strong&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/strong&gt; at Glasgow Caledonian University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5127" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/12187986_10156212279470224_6004105078402073441_o.jpg" alt="12187986_10156212279470224_6004105078402073441_o" width="2048" height="761"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, on the other coast, Auld Reekie's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1640621156210592/"&gt;Home Season&lt;/a&gt; will be coming to a triumphant conclusion with the Home Teams Final Double Header. As well as the Final itself, which sees the &lt;em&gt;Leithal Weapons&lt;/em&gt; play off against &lt;em&gt;The Skatefast Club&lt;/em&gt; for the 2015 trophy, third-place team the &lt;em&gt;Cherry Bombers&lt;/em&gt; will take on mysterious guest team &lt;em&gt;The Rolling Bones&lt;/em&gt;. Last year, The Skatefast Club managed to take the win over the Leithals, so this year's repeat should be even harder fought, as the Leithal Weapons seek to redress the balance. (The event will also be preceded by the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/528300763986400/"&gt;Auld Reekie Derby Taster Session&lt;/a&gt;, so those interested in seeing what Roller Derby is all about can make a whole day of it!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARRG has arranged a special license for a bar, and there will be both half-time entertainment and a charity fundraising raffle. There will also be separate seating areas for families and young children, and a children’s craft corner to keep the youngest fans amused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are £6 in advance, £8 on the door, available on &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2252540"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt;. Unwaged and Senior (over 65's) fans can enter for the discounted rate of £5 per ticket,  and disability leisure card holders and a carer may enter free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, the event will be held at &lt;strong&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/strong&gt;, on London Road. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt; for a 1:30 start.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bad omens</category><category>cherry bombers</category><category>death stars</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>home season</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>home teams</category><category>leithal weapons</category><category>skatefast club</category><category>t-wrecks</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/23/arrg-and-glasgow-home-seasons-final/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 16:34:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls: Home Season 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/28/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-season-2014/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/argg-2014-hs.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/argg-2014-hs.jpg" alt="argg 2014 hs" width="614" height="237" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3200"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls kick off their 2014 Home Season on Saturday the 1st of February with a bout between The Cherry Bombers and last years' winners, The Leithal Weapons. All Home Season bouts take place at Meadowbank Sports Centre,Edinburgh. Doors open at 2pm and entry is £7 or £5 plus booking fee when bought &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/531419"&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future bout dates for your diary are..
  15th February - Leithal Weapons Vs Skatefast Club.
  8th March - Skatefast Club Vs Cherry Bombers.
  5th April - Home Season Final.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>cherry bombers</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>leithal weapons</category><category>skatefast club</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/28/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-season-2014/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 03:37:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls:Home Season 2,Bout 2-Cherry Bombers Vs Skatefast Club</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/02/11/auld-reekie-roller-girlshome-season-2bout-2-cherry-bombers-vs-skatefast-club/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/arrg-hs2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/arrg-hs2.jpg" alt="arrg hs2" width="614" height="227" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2066"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; present the second bout of this years Home Season,with a match between The Cherry Bombers and The Skatefast Club.
The bout takes place at Meadowbank Sports Centre,London Road,Edinburgh on Saturday the 16th of February.Doors open at 2pm and entry is £7 on the day,or £5(plus booking fee) &lt;a href="http://bombersvsskatefast13-es2.eventbrite.com/#"&gt;in advance&lt;/a&gt;.
More details at the Facebook &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/817440581730141/"&gt;event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>cherry bombers</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>skatefast club</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/02/11/auld-reekie-roller-girlshome-season-2bout-2-cherry-bombers-vs-skatefast-club/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 14:10:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls Home Season 2013, Bout 1 Cherry Bombers v Leithal Weapons</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/01/22/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-season-2013-bout-1-cherry-bombers-v-leithal-weapons/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/424389_907757491774_2107291117_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-2133" alt="424389_907757491774_2107291117_n" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/424389_907757491774_2107291117_n.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="460"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Cherry Bombers Best Blocker Maulibu Barbie watches out for the Leithals' Sharlotte Fever, jamming.
&lt;p&gt;Saturday 19th of January saw the first public bout in Scotland played under the new WFTDA rules. Most famously, these rules remove minor penalties in favour of a streamlined officiation process where only major penalties can be awarded; however, they also make a host of other changed, including starting both the pack and the jammers on the same single starting whistle.
Auld Reekie started their home season last year in the first third of the year as, amongst other things, a way to warm up after the Christmas/Hogmanay break, but the timing this year has been particularly advantageous, giving them also a chance to get more practice with the new rules before bouting against other leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first bout saw last home season winners, the nautical/steampunk themed Leithal Weapons, up against "zombie highschool" themed Cherry Bombers. Both teams were playing with a reduced roster, with the Bombers particularly affected, down to only 9 skaters, and one of their star jammers, Circuit Breaker, suffering from the flu. The skate-out can be found &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ggVfYvsFSlI&amp;amp;list=PLsfV1BOiVrnEvF6D1YCYGwx1C4pdeBGeb&amp;amp;index=1"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the start, the Leithal Weapons pulled out an initial advantage, ARRG star jammer Admiral Attackbar (11:11) and vice-captain Alma Geddon (42) both scoring in the initial jams, to bring the score after the first 4 minutes to a 13 to nil lead.
Nevertheless, 13 points is nothing at the start of a bout, and the Bombers looked like fighting right back when new skater Para'beat'em'all (62) took lead jammer in the very next jam... only to pick up a track cut major during her scoring pass just before trying to call the jam off! With the power-jam for Leithals new skater Sharlotte Fever (1924) to exploit, things went from bad to worse for the Bombers, a chain reaction of penalties resulting in, at one point, only Teenie Bash (208), ex of Fair City Rollers, on the track to oppose her.
Hampered by their reduced roster, the Bombers were unable to recover quickly from their penalty situation, with the penalty box refilling as overstretched blockers picked up more penalties before their comrades could escape to join them. The Leithals capitalised, pushing the score into triple figures with multiple power jams before Teenie Bash finally managed to score for the red team,
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;6&lt;/b&gt; Cherry Bombers : &lt;strong&gt;115&lt;/strong&gt; Leithal Weapons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;still with around 12 minutes left in the period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JtiUWIvYJOo&amp;amp;list=PLsfV1BOiVrnEvF6D1YCYGwx1C4pdeBGeb&amp;amp;index=2"&gt;VIDEO&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A power-jam for Circuit Breaker, brought a much needed boost in the underdogs' score, almost tripling it to 16 before she called the jam. The Leithals struck back immediately, however, with Yin and Bang effortlessly taking lead jammer the very next jam, while Teenie Bash struggled for some time with an imposing front-wall masterminded by Leithals pivot Admiral Attackbar, although both jammers were held well on their scoring passes, Velosidy exerting herself particularly to hold back the opposing scorer. Still, Teenie managed to pick up a single scoring pass, to be followed by a second magnificent display from Circuit, taking lead jammer and sneaking in a single scoring pass ahead of an accelerating Alma Geddon in hot pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the final scoring pass for the red team this period, though, with the final 8 minutes dominated by the Leithal Weapons once more, thanks partly to a recurrence of the Bombers' penalty issues from earlier on. Playing with such a reduced roster was telling on their skaters, allowing the Leithals to dominate the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the period, the score stood at an intimidating
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt; Cherry Bombers : &lt;strong&gt;216&lt;/strong&gt; Leithal Weapons&lt;/p&gt;
-
&lt;p&gt;Half-time saw the second appearance of &lt;a href="http://www.choiredinburgh.co.uk/"&gt;Sing in the City&lt;/a&gt; at a bout, an Edinburgh-based modern choir and Auld Reekie's regular half-time entertainment for this Home Season. Beginning with a medley including "Auld Reekie", the reworked version of "Hey Mickey" that serves as Auld Reekie's anthem, the choir moved on to Coldplay's "Viva La Vida", a safe choice for a modern choir's first opening to an audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/385277_907756438884_1922633653_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-2134" alt="Ciderella chases down Circuit Breaker in one of the several jammer-on-jammer duels in the bout." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/385277_907756438884_1922633653_n.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Ciderella chases down Circuit Breaker in one of the several jammer-on-jammer duels in the bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning from half-time, the Cherry Bombers faced a difficult challenge to win with an almost 200 point deficit. In fact, an almost immediate&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zip5T4OB1mg&amp;amp;list=PLsfV1BOiVrnEvF6D1YCYGwx1C4pdeBGeb&amp;amp;index=3"&gt; power jam&lt;/a&gt; for the Leithals once more, Circuit Breaker (100) spending time in the penalty box, whilst Yin and Bang (39) racked up a few more points, immediately increased their deficit even more...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The increasingly exhausted Bombers only managing to pick up 10 points in by the end of the third 15 minutes, it was looking even better for the team in blue as they picked up 113 in the same time, bringing the score to
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;34&lt;/strong&gt; Cherry Bombers : &lt;strong&gt;329&lt;/strong&gt; Leithal Weapons&lt;/p&gt;
A long official timeout sent additional members of both teams to the penalty box and, devastatingly for a team with an already tiny roster, sent Bombers team captain Velosidy off track as she fouled out at her 7th sin-bin trip.
&lt;p&gt;With the Leithal Weapons also down on blockers, however, the very next jam saw Teenie Bash pick up a valuable 3-point pass, albeit the last scoring tha the Bombers would get for the next five minutes. Superior blocking from the Leithals continued to tell, pushing their score closer and closer to a 10:1 ratio, sitting at:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;37&lt;/strong&gt; Cherry Bombers : &lt;strong&gt;354&lt;/strong&gt; Leithal Weapons&lt;/p&gt;
with only 10 minutes on the clock.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r6djsx2XIV8&amp;amp;list=PLsfV1BOiVrnEvF6D1YCYGwx1C4pdeBGeb&amp;amp;index=4"&gt;VIDEO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just when it looked like the Leithals would actually manage to win with a 10:1 score ratio, a slightly misjudged piece of skating by Alma Geddon, returning from stradding the line to in-bounds to pick up a track cut major, handed the power jam to the Bombers' Teenie Bash, to the loud delight of all of the Cherry Bombers fans in the audience. After getting over her own elation, Teenie capitalised, pushing her team's score up by 10 vital points. After a brief team-timeout, The Bombers maintained their momentum, Circuit Breaking taking lead jammer mere fractions of a second ahead of the Leithals' Ciderella (3), and engaging in a protracted and close-fought defensive jamming duel before calling it off. With Teenie Bash back on track for the next jam, yet another Leithals track cut, this time by Yin and Bang, handed the her the second power jam of the last 5 minutes, and a 19 point power jam. Just 5 minutes had made Teenie the Cherry Bombers' highest scoring player by a landslide, bringing in more than half of the teams' score for the bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a bout timing issue causing head ref Righteous Oxide to allow one final jam, it was Kaos Moss who took back control for the Leithal Weapons for a final frosting of points, leaving the final score at:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;66&lt;/strong&gt; Cherry Bombers : &lt;strong&gt;395&lt;/strong&gt; Leithal Weapons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/74614_907756049664_1997508534_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2135" alt="74614_907756049664_1997508534_n" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/74614_907756049664_1997508534_n.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Skater awards were given to:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table border="0" align="center"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cherry Bombers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leithal Weapons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Blocker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Maulibu Barbie&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Minnie Riot&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Jammer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Teenie Bash&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Sharlotte Fever&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most Valuable Player&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Circuit Breaker&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Ciderella&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
The next bout in the Auld Reekie Roller Girls Home Season is February 16th, where the Cherry Bombers, hopefully back up to a full roster, will take on The Skatefast Club.&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>cherry bombers</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>leithal weapons</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/01/22/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-season-2013-bout-1-cherry-bombers-v-leithal-weapons/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 19:31:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls:Home Season 2,Bout 1-Cherry Bombers Vs Leithal Weapons</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/01/08/2065/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/arrg-hs2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/arrg-hs2.jpg" alt="arrg hs2" width="614" height="227" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2066"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; kick off the new year with their second Home Season, featuring a bout between the Cherry Bombers and, last seasons winners, the Leithal Weapons.
The action takes place at Meadowbank Sports Centre, London Road, Edinburgh,on Saturday the 19th of January.Doors open at 2pm.Entry is $7 on the day, £5(plus booking fee) for an &lt;a href="http://bombersvsweapons13.eventbrite.com/#"&gt;advance single bout ticket&lt;/a&gt;, or there is also the option of a &lt;a href="http://arrghomeseasonticket2013.eventbrite.com/#"&gt;Season ticket&lt;/a&gt;, which will allow entry to all Home Season bouts for £15(plus booking fee)
Please note, Season tickets may only be purchased up to the first game.
More info at the Facebook &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/397978563615883/"&gt;event page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>cherry bombers</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>leithal weapons</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/01/08/2065/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 11:24:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bout Report: ARRG Home Seasons Final: Double Header</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/05/13/bout-report-arrg-home-seasons-final-double-header/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/05/hsf.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/05/hsf.jpg" alt="" title="hsf" width="614" height="632" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1252"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Sam Skipsey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head over to Ante Ortus A Novus Lumen Ars for a bout report on the &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; Home Season final double header.
All the usual photos and video to peruse plus two reports,you can find the first,a bruising bout between &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s Hells Belles and The &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Cherry-Bombers/274799135908869"&gt;Cherry Bombers&lt;/a&gt;, over &lt;a href="http://aoanla.blogspot.co.uk/2012/05/bout-report-arrg-home-season-2012.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
For coverage of the final bout,between The &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/theskatefastclub"&gt;Skatefast Club&lt;/a&gt; and The &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Leithal-Weapons/209794282441077"&gt;Leithal Weapons&lt;/a&gt; click &lt;a href="http://aoanla.blogspot.co.uk/2012/05/bout-report-arrg-home-seasons-final.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>bout reports</category><category>cherry bombers</category><category>grd</category><category>hell's belles</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>leithal weapons</category><category>skatefast club</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/05/13/bout-report-arrg-home-seasons-final-double-header/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 11:01:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls-Home Season Final 2012</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/25/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-season-final-2012/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/home-season-final-facebook.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/home-season-final-facebook.jpg" alt="" title="Home Season Final Facebook" width="600" height="846" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1169"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of ARRG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday the 28th of April,&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; host the much anticipated final of their first Home Season in style with a double header.First up is a bout between Arrg's &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Cherry-Bombers/274799135908869"&gt;Cherry Bombers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby's&lt;/a&gt; Hells Belles.The main event is to decide which Home Team will be crowned champions and will see the &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/theskatefastclub"&gt;Skatefast Club&lt;/a&gt; go up against the &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Leithal-Weapons/209794282441077"&gt;Leithal Weapons&lt;/a&gt; in what should be a really hard fought bout. 
This takes place at Meadowbank Sports Centre,London Road,Edinburgh,entry is £7 on the day or £6 &lt;a href="http://arrg2012homeseasonfinal.eventbrite.com/?ebtv=C"&gt;in advance&lt;/a&gt;.
Please note this is an evening event,doors open at 5pm with the first bout at 5:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>cherry bombers</category><category>grd</category><category>hell's belles</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>leithal weapons</category><category>skatefast club</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/25/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-season-final-2012/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2012 00:56:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bout Report: ARRG Home Season 2012: Cherry Bombers v The Skatefast Club 7th April 2012 </title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/18/bout-report-arrg-home-season-2012-cherry-bombers-v-the-skatefast-club-7th-april-2012/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/dsc02410.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/dsc02410.jpg" alt="" title="SONY DSC" width="614" height="276" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1122"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photograph by Sam Skipsey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you head over to &lt;a href="http://aoanla.blogspot.co.uk/2012/04/bout-report-arrg-home-season-2012.html"&gt;Ante Ortus A Novus Lumen Ars&lt;/a&gt; you can read the bout report from the most recent installment of the Auld Reekie Roller Girls Home Season.A closely fought match between the &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Cherry-Bombers/274799135908869"&gt;Cherry Bombers&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/theskatefastclub"&gt;Skatefast Club&lt;/a&gt; with all the usual pictures and video to peruse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>bout reports</category><category>cherry bombers</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>pictures</category><category>skatefast club</category><category>video</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/18/bout-report-arrg-home-season-2012-cherry-bombers-v-the-skatefast-club-7th-april-2012/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 21:39:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls-Home Season:Cherry Bombers Vs Skatefast Club</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/03/31/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-seasoncherry-bombers-vs-skatefast-club/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/03/a3-home-season-poster-sfcvscb.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/03/a3-home-season-poster-sfcvscb.jpg" alt="" title="A3 Home Season Poster LWvsCB" width="614" height="869" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1007"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of ARRG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third installment of the &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; first Home Season rolls around with a bout between the &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/theskatefastclub"&gt;Skatefast Club&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Cherry-Bombers/274799135908869"&gt;Cherry Bombers&lt;/a&gt;.
With ARRG's third home team,the &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Leithal-Weapons/209794282441077"&gt;Leithal Weapons&lt;/a&gt; winning both their previous encounters,this bout will decide who they play in the final at the end of April.
The bout takes place at Meadowbank Sports Centre,London Road,Edinburgh on Saturday the 7th of April.Entry is £7 on the door ,or £6 &lt;a href="http://skatefastvbombers.eventbrite.com/?ebtv=C"&gt;in advance&lt;/a&gt;.Under 14's go free.Doors open at 2pm&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>cherry bombers</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>leithal weapons</category><category>skatefast club</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/03/31/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-seasoncherry-bombers-vs-skatefast-club/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 12:07:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Leithal Weapons Vs Cherry Bombers Bout Report</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/01/30/leithal-weapons-vs-cherry-bombers-bout-report/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/lw-v-cb-bout-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/lw-v-cb-bout-1.jpg" alt="" title="lw v cb bout 1" width="614" height="347" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-829"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photograph by Sam Skipsey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you head over to &lt;a href="http://aoanla.blogspot.com/2012/01/bout-report-auld-reekie-roller-girls.html"&gt;Ante Ortus A Novus Lumen Ars&lt;/a&gt; you can read an excellent review of the first &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;ARRG&lt;/a&gt; Home Season Bout between the &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Leithal-Weapons/209794282441077"&gt;Leithal Weapons&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Cherry-Bombers/274799135908869"&gt;Cherry Bombers&lt;/a&gt;.
An excellent review with pictures and video to peruse.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>cherry bombers</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>leithal weapons</category><category>pictures</category><category>video</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/01/30/leithal-weapons-vs-cherry-bombers-bout-report/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 14:31:30 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>