<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about chile)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/chile.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Chilean National Championships 2018 - Torneo X returns!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/26/chilean-national-championships-2018-torneo-x-returns/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chile's National Tournament, the mysteriously named &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TorneoX/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Torneo X&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, has been running for as long, or longer, than many of the better-known European tournaments, having begun in 2015. (The Men's Derby equivalent in Chile, Torneo X-MEN, started 2 years later.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the 4th event coming up at the start of next month, we're giving you a quick overview of the tournament and the players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Chile is a long, thin, country, as the tournament has expanded, it has done so mostly north/south, following the areas of highest population density. A bit like Scotland, Chile has a band of high population (in this case, roughly in the middle of the country), surrounded by low density rural areas to the north and south. Torneo X 2018 fills this entire high density area, for the first time in its history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26980 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/torneox_map.gif" alt="TorneoX_map" width="600" height="568"&gt; Torneo X's growth over time since inception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, Chillán's Chillanrolleras retained the title from the previous year, maintaining an unbroken streak since they joined the tournament. However, Viña del Mar's Tacones Bandidos pushed them until the very last bouts for that title, so a repeat performance in 2018 is definitely not assured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is especially true as, with 2018's tournament growing to become the biggest yet, there are even more challengers for the cup. Especially likely to want to make a big splash are Santiago's Metropolitan Roller Derby, the only WFTDA-member league in the tournament, although it's their B-team, the Bayonetas, who are competing here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Torneo X 2018 will consist of 4 fixtures across the coming months, spread across the competing regions:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1st&lt;/strong&gt; Fixture: Osorno (Deskarriadas) &lt;strong&gt;4-5 August [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/212354766088268/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2nd&lt;/strong&gt; Fixture: Santiago (Adrenaline) &lt;strong&gt;8-9 September&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd&lt;/strong&gt; Fixture: Viña del Mar (Tacones Bandidos) &lt;strong&gt;6-7 October&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final&lt;/strong&gt; Puerto Montt (Diosas Volcanicas) &lt;strong&gt;9-10 November&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-26981" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/torneox_map.png?w=602" alt="TorneoX_map" width="602" height="1024"&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The historical rankings for the previous editions of the tournament are: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rank&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2015&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nativas RD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chillanrolleras&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chillanrolleras&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deskarriadas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deskarriadas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tacones Bandidos&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Diosas Volcanicas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nativas RD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Diosas Volcanicas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Diosas Volcanicas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deskarriadas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A Sangre Fría RD (Osorno)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adrenaline&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;RD Valdivia / Cuello Negro [as "Indomitas" 2018]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chillanrolleras Derby Club&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chíllan's premier team, and twice winners of the Torneo X, Chillanrolleras were bouting as early as 2013, although we have a gap in our records in 2015. From 2016, they've hosted multiple tournaments - including fixtures for the 2017 Torneo X itself - and have rarely lost a bout. SRDRank's current (unpublished) rating places them as the favourites to win the Torneo X title, and maintain their streak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chillanrolleras, as with many teams in Chile, have a brother league - Chillanrolleros - who share resources with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tacones Bandidos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tacones Bandidos are based in the coastal region of Vińa del Mar, Valparaíso. In their current form, they date from 2014, as a partnership with men's team, Bototos Bandidos.
The Tacones have had a pretty busy year to date - playing not just Chilean teams, but also Buenos Aires' Sailor City Rollers B, who they fought to a near-draw within the last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd rate the Tacones as likely to strongly contest the second place with the tournament newcomers from Santiago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diosas Volcánicas Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puerto Montt &amp;amp; Puerto Varas's Diosas Volcánicas are one of the older teams in Chile, dating back to 2012, founded by Dahmenatrix from San Diego Derby Dolls. They're one of the most southerly teams in Roller Derby (and certainly in Latin America), with only a few teams in southern Argentina and New Zealand much more to the south.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They've had a difficult time finding practice space, and have had periods where most training was outside (in one of the wetter regions of Chile!). This year, they've finally achieved stable training space - in a local prison gym! - and have been working on recruitment and training more intensively since then.
Their aim for 2018 is to qualify for the finals (in the top 4 of the table)... and then who knows how high in 2019?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deskarriadas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deskarriadas are the largest team in Osorno, founded in May 2014. They're the hosts of the first fixture of this year's Torneo X, in the first weekend in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Deskarriadas have been working towards the Torneo X all year, aiming to improve on their performance last year (where they placed 4th). In the first two years, they managed 2nd place, which is, we assume, their target for 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adrenaline Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adrenaline Roller Derby, one of two Santiago-based teams in the tournament, are the youngest contestants, founded in 2016. This relative youth has counted against them in ratings, and we'd consider them likely to be contesting in the same position as last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As hosts of the second fixtures in the tournament, home team advantage may well help them to beat expectations, in a fairly close lower half of the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indomitas RD Valdivia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby Valdivia consists of two member teams - the men's team, Indomitos, and the women's team, which used to be called Cuello Negro ("Black Swans"), but rebranded to Indomitas this year, whilst keeping the same logo. This rebrand was triggered by a complete rebuilding of the team, with the new "Indomitas" very different to the old 2015-2017 Cuello Negro in terms of skaters.
The Indomitas told us that they have spent the past year in intensive drilling, so that all their tactics are instinctive. They are prepared to demonstrate the heart, tenacity and perseverance that they can bring to the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nativas Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Temuco's first team, the Nativas date back to 2013. As with many of the teams here, they have "womens" and "mens" teams - although we can't find a name for the women's team except "Nativas Roller Derby". As one of the oldest teams in Chile, the Nativas competed in the first ever Torneo X, although they skipped the 2017 edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to a sparsity of bout data for the Nativas in FTS, we consider the returning team to be something of a wild card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metropolitan Roller Derby B, Bayonetas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santiago's Metropolitan Roller Derby are the only Chilean members of the WFTDA, with their travel team currently ranked at 122 (May 31 ranking release) by WFTDA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their B-team, the Bayonetas, have existed since 2014, and are one of the few teams in this tournament to have played extensively internationally - at least within South America. Out of the Chilean leagues, they've played nearby Valparaíso's Tacones Bandidos most often, with wildly different results - beating them 2 to 1 early in 2017, and losing by a similar ratio by the end of that year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>chile</category><category>international</category><category>international derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>torneo x</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments2018</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/26/chilean-national-championships-2018-torneo-x-returns/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 12:07:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Brutal kind of Derby: Chilean Men's short-derby tournament.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/04/a-brutal-kind-of-derby-chilean-mens-short-derby-tournament/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of exciting things happen in Roller Derby without getting the attention they deserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these has been the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Torneo-Brutal-709201495857174/"&gt;Torneo Brutal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a unique short-format-derby tournament which has been held by the Chilean leagues for the last few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to organiser Lola Paranoia about the genesis of the tournament, and the currently completed Third Edition of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"In August 2015 was the first edition of the Torneo Brutal. The idea was copied from a similar tournament in Argentina, where a friend participated and told us the experience. At that time, we had little competition in the country, few leagues, so the format of the tournament seemed perfect."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking for a host, Vina del Mar's men's league - Tacones Bandidos - were most excited and agreed to be hosts for the first ever Torneo Brutal , and the two sequels so far!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way, Lola's artist friend Picota, and Rambla and Mr. Sokram, joined the project as organisers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The format is similar to the European "Derby Sevens", with 6-skater teams (plus a bench) playing 30 minute games, otherwise according to WFTDA/MRDA Rules. Like many Sevens tournaments, the teams are CoEd/Open-To-All (or "Roller Derby mixto"), which is also a more popular approach in Latin America in general, and are essentially "exhibition teams" created for each edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third edition of the Tournament sees 11 teams compete in a single-elimination bracket, which is easily managed with the smaller format games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Teams - Zicod'lia, La Mafia Del Sur, Virutas, Mujeros, Emoticon Team, Cosmopolitan, Team Sexy, Cousins Power, Chalabota, Malbec Madness, and Jurassic Quad - draw skaters from across Chile, as well as across the border from Mendoza, Argentina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An intense tournament resulted in a win for Emoticon Team over Viruta, with a narrow 119-94 scoreline, with Viruta finishing the 30 minutes with only 2 players on track. (The reduced starting roster means that Torneo Brutal does not have a minimum-roster to continue competing after injury or foul-outs.) The exciting footage is available here, via Facebook Live: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/709201495857174/videos/1126079294169390/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/709201495857174/videos/1126079294169390/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this edition of the tournament complete, the intent is definitely there for a 4th edition - possibly incorporating elements from other short-format roller derby around the world. We'll keep you informed about details as they emerge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-17398" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/17505208_10155115703413766_6259473394845813480_o.jpg?w=768" alt="17505208_10155115703413766_6259473394845813480_o" width="768" height="1024"&gt; The Torneo Brutal Trophy - the "Trofeo Brutal" - made by Picota and other artists&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>articles</category><category>chile</category><category>international derby</category><category>latin american derby</category><category>short format tournaments</category><category>torneo brutal</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/04/a-brutal-kind-of-derby-chilean-mens-short-derby-tournament/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 15:04:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC Team Review: Team Chile Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/12/mrdwc-team-review-team-chile-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Completing our set of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; team profiles, we're covering the newest team from Latin America, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamChileRDM/"&gt;Team Chile Roller Derby Masculino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chile are in group Orange, facing England, Italy, Sweden and fellow Latin Americans Argentina. With England almost certain to take the top spot in the group, Chile will be in a difficult spot to take the other promotion slot, as only Italy is as inexperienced as they are. The Latin America match up between Argentina and Chile should also be fascinating to watch...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-8244 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/11051780_1459842104328566_1210320533841469507_n.jpg" alt="11051780_1459842104328566_1210320533841469507_n" width="720" height="705"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to Team Chile's Marmota at the team warmup in Calgary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Firstly, how does it feel representing Chile, as they attend the Men's World Cup for the first time?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, as Chile, and speaking f0r my teammates, I want to say that this is really an honour. Because this sport, especially in my country, is really really new - most of us have been playing roller derby for 2, 3 years at most. So we're a new team, and we're not playing the modern, modern roller derby where graces and new formations are used. So, I don't know - we're used to playing the walls, like all roller derby used to be played. We're used to playing the defensive game, this is mostly our strategy. So, then, we're trying to play a it little faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's an honour, and it was really hard, because each and every one of us had to pay for their ticket, their accommodation. The only thing we got [in sponsorship] from a Chilean company was the uniform. And this is really bad. But I think it's a mixed work - if we don't move, then who is going to move? But, we don't get much attention - we hope that for the next World Cup we will be bigger! I hope!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So that happened to Women's Team Mexico in 2011:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happened to the Women's Chilean team in 2014 too! But women seem more persuasive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who are you most looking forward to playing here?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Argentina!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ah, yes, you're both in the same group. Are you confident?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not a confident player now - my team is really more confident than I, because I expect to pay more attention for the first jams, and then decide how I feel after that. &lt;em&gt;But&lt;/em&gt;, we know them - most of our team have played the Argentine team, which is basically the ThunderQuads. My team, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ComplotDerbyClub"&gt;Complot&lt;/a&gt;, was in the first &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/64046"&gt;Torneo HARD&lt;/a&gt; [hosted by ThunderQuads] Tournament, and we came in second. So, we know how they play - and I don't know if they know how we play. I don't know if they've done their homework! [Our relative obscurity] is our one advantage - Argentina are strong, and they're bigger than us, I don't know if you saw some of the players! And they're really really fast - we have to pay a lot of attention to their lines and their offense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that game, that game I want to play right now! The other teams, we don't know - we watched them in the last World Cup on the streams, but Argentina is our neighbouring country, so the rivalry is there! Like Scotland/Ireland or Canada/USA!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you hope to get out of the World Cup, what are you aiming for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, personally, first: I am aiming to get to know as many people as we can. I think the only way the sport is going to grow and become stronger is if we all team up, and all team up together with the other team, and we work together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I think we are wanting, as a team, to develop our play more together. Because, Chile is a long country - it was really hard for all of the guys to get together for even one training a month. We don't have the advantage of some teams which just get to play together all the time...
Team Chile's first bout is against Argentina on Track 2 at &lt;strong&gt;6pm&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;UK time&lt;/em&gt; (11am Calgary)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Team Chile Roster is:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;1080&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Hijoeperra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;111&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Waffen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Kiltro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Memeiro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;27&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Viruta Thunder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Vieja&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Petit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Mr. Sokram&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;416&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Capitán Basuritas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Aquilez&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;7018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Kamikaze&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;77&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Manquelipe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Cy8org (Cyborg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;8000&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Mecánico&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;88&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Toro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;95&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Zakumi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;969&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Rocka&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;99&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Marmota&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;m30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Picóta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;s66&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Insane&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Bench Coach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Pony Tolueno&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Bench Manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Loca Zeppelin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>chile</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/12/mrdwc-team-review-team-chile-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 07:22:30 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>