<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about co-ed roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/co-ed-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 08:59:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Mean City Roller Derby: Relaunch 2017</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/17/mean-city-roller-derby-relaunch-2017/</link><dc:creator>meancityrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-19258" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/received_10158754925150594.jpeg?w=300" alt="received_10158754925150594" width="300" height="300"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;Roller derby is a very DIY sport, so people at different levels will always be looking to achieve different goals within the sport. For some, their purpose is to advance as far as their body will allow. For others, it’s a great way to get out a couple of nights per week and let off some steam in a fun, friendly environment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby fall somewhere in the middle, as we're made up of a wide variety of different people and personalities – we have actors, students, scientists and even a Thai masseur! It's our members that make our league special. Although we have lives outside of derby, we'll always be there for each other, both on and off the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we're looking to continue to build upon progress we've made as a league and as a group of friends. Next Saturday&lt;strong&gt;, 20th May 2017&lt;/strong&gt;, will be our first bout of the year and we are hoping to capitalise on the hard work we've put into our training. Not only that, we are rebranding and will be debuting our new logo and team tops for the first time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logo really captures the good humour of the league and the spirit of Glasgow, Mean City's home and stomping ground.  We don't want to give too much away until game day, but we can say the logo is indeed still purple! This has been a long time in the making, but we can proudly say it looks fantastic. A big thank you to our Design Team and to Roller Derby City for our awesome new uniforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are facing tough opposition. Our ladies' team are playing the Granite City Fight Hawks from Aberdeen. We played them up north in &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85548"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and were narrowly defeated, so we will be looking to make the most of the home advantage! Our co-ed/open team will then be playing the Portsmouth Scurvy Wenches who are travelling up to Glasgow for the bout. They are more unknown to us, so should make exciting opponents. We also hear they like a good after party, as do we!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-19259" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/received_10158754874915594.jpeg?w=300" alt="received_10158754874915594" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The action starts at &lt;strong&gt;12pm&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662012,-4.2516905,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8661982!4d-4.2494965"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARC: Health &amp;amp; Fitness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Glasgow Caledonian University, Cowcaddens Road, Glasgow, G4 0BA. Entry is &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; per person/under 14s free,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets available from the Facebook event page here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1288036437909237/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1288036437909237/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>annoucements</category><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>pictures</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/17/mean-city-roller-derby-relaunch-2017/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 14:08:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bairn City's co-ed bout to celebrate their 4th birthday</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/05/bairn-citys-co-ed-bout-to-celebrate-their-4th-birthday/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bairn City Rollers became Scotland's first co-ed league back in 2012. Now as they approach their 4th birthday they are kicking of celebrations and ending their 2016 season in the best way they could, a co-ed game. Their opponents will be the Brawler Buddies, who are made up of skaters from &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/granitecitybrawlers/"&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GraniteCityRollerDerby/"&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/dundeerollergirls/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In change from the norm, there will be no advanced ticket sales for this event. Instead in celebration of their 4th birthday BCR are inviting spectators to pay what they want on the day. That's right, &lt;span class="_4n-j fsl"&gt;just turn up on the game and pay whatever you like.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game will take place at Grangemouth Sports Complex on Saturday the 15th of October, doors will be open from 2.15pm and first whistle will be at 2.40pm, for more information &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/527945357409228/"&gt;visit the event page here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/527945357409228/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-9205" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/bcr-banner.jpg?w=700" alt="bcr-banner" width="700" height="259"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bcr</category><category>central belters</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>grangemouth</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>skelpies</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/05/bairn-citys-co-ed-bout-to-celebrate-their-4th-birthday/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 19:38:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>History in the making with Mad Macs in Glasgow</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/12/history-in-the-making-with-mad-macs-in-glasgow/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What a day - what a lovely day!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby’s coed team will make their competitive debut on Saturday, August 22, at the ARC sports centre in Glasgow.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The Glasgow league – which is open to people of all genders and none – are rostering a team of men and women for the first time in a public game.&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/11754374_670745089728581_5681492131485587611_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-4852 alignright" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/11754374_670745089728581_5681492131485587611_o.jpg?w=300" alt="11754374_670745089728581_5681492131485587611_o" width="482" height="330"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
It comes less than a year after the league voted to become coed – with Mean City's membership on the rise.
&lt;p&gt;The event on August 22 has a distinctly dystopian feel – entitled Mad Macs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain Gordon Hendry said: “According to Fury Road, the future belongs to the Mad - but we reckon it belongs to the Mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To celebrate Mean City becoming the first coed league in the West of Scotland, we have got together with some lovely skaters across the country to present a coed bout with class written through it like a stick of rock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In the purple and silver corner, wearing battered leather and a grizzled grin are the men and women of Mean City Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And in the blood-splattered white corner are Furiosa's Furies - some of Scotland's most talented - and toughest - skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s going to be marvellous, mad and – above all – it’s going to be Mean. We've been training hard for this and genuinely can't wait. Get your tickets now."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since becoming a coed league, Mean City Roller Derby’s membership has grown and grown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, demand is so strong that the league has organised another fresh skater intake – Tuesday, September 1 at the ARC – 7.15-9pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/12/history-in-the-making-with-mad-macs-in-glasgow/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 20:35:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Double Header: GCRG Presents Cherry Poppers and Co-ed</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/05/31/double-header-gcrg-presents-cherry-poppers-and-co-ed/</link><dc:creator>zenrhe</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Girls are proud to announce an exciting day of Roller Derby to take place at the home of our sisters - Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We will be supplying you derby fans with two exciting bouts!
&lt;p&gt;Granite City’s co-ed team ‘&lt;strong&gt;Of Fights and Men&lt;/strong&gt;’ skate together for the first time against the much respected and fantastic ‘&lt;strong&gt;Jakey Tayzers&lt;/strong&gt;’.
So come along and watch the mixed teams of men and women battle it out on track!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s not all...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are so excited to also announce that the first bout of the day will be&lt;strong&gt; an all female ‘Cherry Popper’&lt;/strong&gt; to get you warmed up! Two teams made up from 7 different Scottish leagues, with some skaters making their debut. Ladies from Nasty Nessies Roller Girls, Dundee Roller Girls, Bairn City Rollers, Fierce Valley Roller Girls, Auld Reekie Roller Girls, Glasgow Roller Derby and of course Granite City. Watch, support and take note -
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; You will be witnessing some of Scotland’s best new talent on track.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="ngg-singlepic ngg-center" alt="Double Header 130713" src="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/wp-content/gallery/events/double_header_130713.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So get this date in to your diaries, it's not to be missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets on Sale soon! Online Advance: £5, Door: £6 Under 14s Free with paying adult
Doors open: 11.30am. First bout 12pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cakes, Merchandise and Local Vendors will also be there.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;Join our &lt;span class="fblink"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/232381250219767/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disc&lt;/strong&gt;
Dundee International Sports Centre, Mains Loan - Dundee
&lt;a href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/locations/disc-2/"&gt;Details&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date/Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date(s) - 13/07/2013
&lt;i&gt;11:30 am - 5:00 pm&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Disc" href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/locations/disc-2/"&gt;Disc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[googlemaps https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=s_q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=Disc+Dundee+International+Sports+Centre,+Mains+Loan,+Dundee&amp;amp;aq=3&amp;amp;oq=dundee+in&amp;amp;sll=53.800651,-4.064941&amp;amp;sspn=10.717687,28.54248&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hq=Disc+Dundee+International+Sports+Centre,&amp;amp;hnear=Mains+Loan,+Dundee,+Dundee+City,+United+Kingdom&amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;ll=56.476266,-2.958927&amp;amp;spn=0.008882,0.006295&amp;amp;output=embed&amp;amp;w=425&amp;amp;h=350]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>aberdeen</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>double header</category><category>dundee</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>jakey bites</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/05/31/double-header-gcrg-presents-cherry-poppers-and-co-ed/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 10:44:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lets hear it for the boys!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/08/lets-hear-it-for-the-boys/</link><dc:creator>thejammingpony</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A female perspective on Merby and CO-ED Roller Derby.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until the past couple of years Roller Derby has been a sport ‘rolled’ out on a predominantly female playing field. There have always been men around, be it in an official capacity or those of the infamous derby widow - ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However those who wished to play on a competitive level have taken the proverbial bull by the horns with Merby leagues are popping up all over the UK. Scotland in Particular has no less than 4 up and coming all male leagues. Their collective bouting team the Jakey Bites have been established for over a year now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arrival of Men’s Roller Derby has been met with mixed reaction on roller derby scene, some embracing it fully and others feeling a little put out that the male specimen are perhaps trying to steal our feminine thunder………God can’t they let us have anything!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being part of a league who have taken to Integrating with open arms, I have had a fantastic opportunity to skate and compete with the some of the Jakey Bites in the past year, skating in the Uk’s first ever CO-ED derby bout with The Jakey Tayzers last September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result I have become a keen supporter for CO-ED and men’s roller derby. The thought of this might seem a bit overwhelming for some but I believe it can make you a more rounded and skilled skater in the long run. I have skated for 2 years now, predominantly in all female training and bout situations and I thought I would take this opportunity to answer some of the questions or allay some of the fears people might have about Male and Co-Ed roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;DO THEY HIT HARDER?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate to emasculate anyone here but the answer to this is not really. I have found that taking a hit from a guy is no different from being hit by the girls. The fact that they don’t really have hips takes a bit of getting used to but the impact of the hit isn't as scary as it might seem.  Put it this way, if you have ever been hit by Cider from Auld Reekie then you have nothing to worry about and are fully prepared…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;ARE THEIR TACTICS DIFFERENT?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever we first started training for the CO – ED bout this was definitely one of our questions, in all honesty we thought for some reason they were going to be all offence and no discipline (not sure why, guess we were stereotyping). This wasn't the case at all; for the most part their tactics are exactly the same as what we are doing on the female side of things. They are definitely very skilled and know their stuff; I didn't find it any different from skating with my female team mates. They have had to adjust to the new rule set exactly the same as we have. From watching various Merby bouts last year there really wasn't much difference in the tactics played and there certainly wasn't any less glitter surprisingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;IS IT AWKWARD?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we all know, roller derby can be a very 'handsy' sport, it is full contact and I suppose it would be normal to wonder if it gets a bit awkward when playing CO-ED. This one is really in the eyes of the beholder to be honest, I personally haven’t ever felt awkward or anything likes that whilst skating. Whether that comes from knowing them quite well or from being in the zone on track I’m not sure but it certainly has never been an issue. You know the bond you have with your team mates on track, well that bond is completely possible in CO-ED as well and it is a pretty gratifying experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;ARE THEY BETTER THAN US?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer to this hangs on the word better; it’s not so much a case of better as different. Roller derby caters for differences; it’s one of the most appealing aspects of the sport which is known for celebrating individuality. In some cases they may be a little stronger and taller than us but……being a big player or a hard hitter isn't the be all and end all if you are smaller and faster. In truth they are as varied and unique as we are on the female side of things. Tall, small, fast, strong, hard-hitting, positional and/or agile everyone has strength it's just finding out how they compliment each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;ARE THEY JUST A BUNCH OF “LADS?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cracking dirty jokes and messing around? As for the dirty jokes I know some female skaters who could make them blush……….But in all seriousness the answer here is no. They are 100% dedicated to the sport and the progression of their regional leagues, the passion they have for the sport is no less than we have in the female leagues and the drive they have shown in starting from scratch has been nothing short of impressive. As a female skater they have always been nothing less than welcoming and supportive of me and since skating with them I have seen a real improvement in certain areas of my skating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a personal perspective I am fully in support of Merby in the UK. I would urge everyone to support their local Merby league alongside their local derby league, Capital City in Edinburgh, Mean City in Glasgow, The Skelpies in the Central Belt and The Tayminators in Tayside. I have had the pleasure of knowing people from most of these teams and can tell you they are a cracking bunch of guys, we should be proud to have them as a part of the Scottish Roller Derby scene. I hope to see a lot more CO-ED action in the future with my Jakey Tayzers. The Skelpies League, Bairn City are already establishing a Co -Ed league so it is onward and upward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to make up your own mind or have a male friend you’d like to wrangle into taking up the sport, the Jakey Bites (Comprising of members from 3 out of 4 of the aforementioned teams) have a bout coming up against The South Wales Silures on April the 6&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; in Grangemouth. Check their Facebook page for event details and ticket sales. The venue only holds 100 so buy in advance to avoid disappointment. Bairn City men’s team will also be playing South Wales the day after on the 7&lt;sup&gt;th &lt;/sup&gt;at the same venue, for more details and ticket sales check their Facebook pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.facebook.com/events/122071404642449/      (SKELPIES VS. SILURES)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.facebook.com/events/432929060108875/     (JAKEYS VS. SILURES)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a title="Jakeys VS. Silures" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/522492_342652352503139_928642489_n.png"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-2291 aligncenter" alt="522492_342652352503139_928642489_n" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/522492_342652352503139_928642489_n.png" width="506" height="567"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/10889_619537551396047_724006372_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-2292 aligncenter" alt="10889_619537551396047_724006372_n" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/10889_619537551396047_724006372_n.jpg?w=211" width="506" height="567"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>image</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>merby</category><category>roller derby</category><category>the jakey bites</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>the tayminators</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/08/lets-hear-it-for-the-boys/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 16:57:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Co-ed derby...it's not just for the girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/07/07/co-ed-derby-its-not-just-for-the-girls/</link><dc:creator>pandacatkaty</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/07/co-ed-derby.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/07/co-ed-derby.jpg?w=487" alt="Image"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The creation of the Jakey Bites, Scotland's first men's roller derby team, has created an interesting aspect of roller derby, bringing the boys off the sidelines and onto the track.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to attend the first Dundee Roller Girls scrim session that included members of the Jakey Bites, who were preparing for their first bout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beforehand, some of the girls I had spoken to were a bit apprehensive about it; others were really up for it. Some thought that the boys would cause more damage on track, others thought it would be great fun. And besides, the boys weren't as experienced as a lot of the girls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everyone who was there seemed to have a great time, and as a spectator, it was interesting to see the difference between guys and girls on track, what the physical differences between men and women brought to, and took away from, the performances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An interesting observance made to me by a Jakey not that long ago emphasises this point. He told me that men don't do as much hip checking as women. The fact is, that men don't have "hips" per se, their waists are narrow while their shoulders are wide, so they will go for a shoulder/side hit. But this may be where co-ed derby can help shape merby strategy: men skating with women can see how moves like hip checks can be effective and start incorporating that into training sessions. And with most male skaters not using hip checks, it could become an interesting tactic that can give a men's team an edge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I asked for the thoughts of some fellow skaters (male and female) and although it was mostly positive, there were some concerns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley's Frocky Horror said: " Being a Jakey wife I have seen first hand the damage that boys can do to each other, so I wouldn't be happy bouting or scrimming with boys. Having said that at FVRG we trained with our refs and learned to hit with them too. We don't do that now, just right at the start."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During my time at the Fair City Rollers, this was our situation too. Danimal, our league's guy ref, often trained with us, to the point where no one really batted an eyelid when we saw him lacing up his skates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girl Gadget said: "I understand the reservations that some female skaters have about skating with boys. I have done it at DRG before and found it be just as much fun as skating with girls. As it stands now, games are more about tactics than just going out and hitting each other. There is much less hitting than there was when I first started. Legal target zones are always an issue, regardless of sex. If you take Psychomilly for example, she's our tallest skater and struggles with legal target zones, yet is an amazing blocker and hits harder than anyone I know. I think both sides have much to gain from playing co-ed."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nasty Nessie Cherry Bow added: "I feel that women have reached a point now where we can comfortably compete and play alongside with our male counterparts on the track. Women can hit hard and are fast just as there are women who are slower and more tactical. We come in all shapes and sizes and so do the men! There are female skaters out there who weigh more than a male skater (myself included) who can take a hit and stay put regardless if that hit is from a man or a woman. Equally we can give as well as receive and I know there's a few men out there who have been sent flying by a well placed hit from a female skater. Additionally I think this will bring more men into the sport and we need all the fresh blood we can get to make sure this fantastic sport keeps going and evolving."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She even added that she felt there should be co-ed bouts, which would allow for a "new dimension of play".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, a lot of the men don't take for granted that their presence at scrims will be welcomed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Former Jakey Bite and long-time GCRG ref Buffy Boiler explained: "In my opinion co-ed is fine on the proviso that everyone, boys and girls, knows what they're getting into and that there is absolutely no stigma attached to people saying they're not comfortable with doing it. I would never expect to just rock up to a girls league scrim session and be welcomed to play - it would have to be something agreed in advance."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Whether or not there will be co-ed derby bouts remains to be seen, but one thing is for sure...men will be welcomed by many at scrims in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>jakey bites</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/07/07/co-ed-derby-its-not-just-for-the-girls/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 12:09:59 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>