<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about coaching)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/coaching.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:41:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Derby Stance 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/derbystance-2019/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the past three years, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com"&gt;Rule 56&lt;/a&gt; have been helping to drive and develop coaching in Roller Derby; both in terms of coaching itself, and also resources for developing those coaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt='The Derby Stance 2019 logo: 3 brown solid circles of increasing darkness overlapping left-to-right, with blue whistle inside the last. Text "Derby Stance Online Coaching Summit Nov 22-24 2019".' src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/DerbyStanceEvent.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very visible part of this has been their &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/derby-stance"&gt;Derby Stance&lt;/a&gt; branded coaching community events; starting with a physical &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/03/uks-first-coaching-summit-derby-stance/"&gt;Coaching Summit&lt;/a&gt; back in &lt;em&gt;2016&lt;/em&gt;, and developing into a more extensive, and entirely virtual event in 2018 (2017 tested the concept with a series of individual webinars across the year). Holding the event online, with dedicated conference hosting services, was a response to the global nature of Roller Derby, and the global need for coaching resources and community; having to travel half-way across the world for a conference is not only expensive, but also wasteful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2018 Derby Stance was extremely successful, with attendees describing it with terms like "mind-blowing" and "by far the most helpful coaching training I’ve received in five years"!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Derby Stance Online Coaching Summit is returning for 2019, and Rule 56 have continued to build on and improve on what has been before. As the name suggests, this is, once more, a virtual-only event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with 2018's edition, individual "webinars" which make up the entire 3 day event, are separately bookable; you can buy tickets for just the sessions you're interested in. (If you're planning on attending a lot of the event, though, there's also whole-weekend tickets available, for a discount.).
In a change from last year, these are organised into two types: &lt;em&gt;"Seminars"&lt;/em&gt; (60 minute presentations, with time for questions) and &lt;em&gt;"Workshops"&lt;/em&gt; (90 minute interactive sessions led by the session leader; these are limited to &lt;em&gt;20&lt;/em&gt; attendees each).
(Regular attendees of EROC, the European Roller derby Organisational Conference, will recognise this division from there, where it is pretty effective at supporting different kinds of interaction.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that's not all: just like a physical conference, the 2019 Derby Stance will have fringe and break-out events, organised as ad-hoc Facebook Live mini-streams. (Rule56 has already been trialing this with a series of "5 minutes with ..." events over the past year, and they work very well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike most physical conferences, a benefit of the virtual nature is that all Seminars (but not Workshops) will be available after the fact as recordings if you miss them; and simultaneous automated real-time transcriptions will be available during each session, including translated into a range of languages, to aid inclusion and understanding. (For those who can't attend at all, "watch-later" tickets will also be available to access all the content purely post-hoc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="3x4 Checkerboard of portraits (with names) of all of the Derby Stance 2019 speakers and workshop leaders, with Rule56 logo in the middle." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/Derbystance2019.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Photo credits: Nadia Kean and Jennifer B Gaskins (by Zakas Photography); Devoida Mercy (by Louise O'Rourke Photography); Furrocious (by No limit Lien); Dr. Astrid Coxon (by Martin Quadling); Squirrel Power (by Robin Dodd / Purple Turtle Photography); Miss Tea Maven (by David Dyte); Kaio-kensi (by Owen Clayton); all other photos uncredited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any Conference or Summit lives and dies by its roster of speakers, and this year's Derby Stance has a very exciting line-up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smarty Pants (Strong Athletic)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is your Coaching actually working? (Workshop)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Squirrel Power (Monterey Bay Derby Dames)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coaching Slower Learners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rosie Peacock (New Wheeled Order, Power of Scotland)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategic Coaching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Devoida Mercy (Philly Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bridging the Perception Gap about Coaching between Adults and Juniors (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Furrrocious (Amsterdam Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to structure feedback, and adjust to different training styles (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structuring and building your training session (Workshop)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michelle Welton and Gie ‘uppercase’ Carr (Rose City Rollers)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coaching mixed-level practices in Adult and Junior programs (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kaio-kensi (Montreal Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organic Drill Design - replicating real game scenarios in drills. (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building a healthier brain safety culture (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr. Astrid Coxon (Suffolk Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coaching the 'un-coachable' (Workshop)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jennifer B Gaskins (New Jax City Rollers)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to coach when you don't have a coach (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rita Giddens (Fort Myers Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coaching for a Positive Culture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miss Tea Maven (Gotham Girls Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to design optimal training plans for your Jammers. (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Processes and Steps to designing best Practice, including footage analysis. (Workshop)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, Rule 56 will be chairing &lt;em&gt;"Round Table"&lt;/em&gt; discussion sessions throughout the event, with topics decided dynamically as the Summit progresses; and the entire event will be introduced with a &lt;strong&gt;WFTDA Keynote Presentation&lt;/strong&gt; the day before the Summit itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets for both individual sessions, and the whole event, are &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/derbystancetickets"&gt;on sale now&lt;/a&gt; . Advance sales for "watch later" tickets for Seminars are cheaper than they will be post-event; and remember that there are only 20 spots for each Workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby Stance Online Coaching Summit 2019 will run from &lt;strong&gt;22 November 2019 to 24 November 2019&lt;/strong&gt; (with the keynote on the 21st).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Derby Stance would like to thank: WFTDA, Roller Dirty Soaps and Steaks Contact Wear for committing to sponsor this event, and help develop coaching resources.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>coaching</category><category>derby stance</category><category>rule 56</category><category>webinar</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/derbystance-2019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The MacIntyres Take Over Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/the_macintyres_take_over_roller_derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's often said that the junior part of any sport is the most important part, as it contains its future.
Scottish Junior Roller Derby's first club, Fierce Valley Roller Cubs, is no more, but two of its graduates are now starting to make waves in Scotland, and the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We thought it was a good time to talk to Skye ("Bee"), and Callie ("Cal-amity") MacIntyre; earlier this year, Skye (guest) bench-coached the victorious Lincolnshire Bombinos away against Newcastle Junior Roller Derby, with Callie awarded Best Jammer in the same bout. They both have a lot of past experience, and ideas for the future, of Roller Derby, so what better people to talk to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Picture of the Lincolnshire Bombinos team, including Callie, and Skye (Bench coach)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/Callie_and_Skye.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Lincolnshire Bombinos, with Callie (#999) and Skye (Bench, right). [Photo: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.incidentlight.co.uk/"&gt;incidentlight&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So I guess we'll start with a bit of history: how long has it been since you two started derby?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Callie and I both started in about June 2014, through Fierce Valley [Roller Cubs] and we haven't stopped since! Callie had a wee few months break between Cubs disbanding and Rollerstop opening up, but that hasn't swayed her in any way. Roller derby is one of the main sports that both of us have picked up and kept at as there is so much appeal for us 😁😁&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, let's talk about the appeal for each of you: why did you start playing... And why are you still playing now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;I started to play because it was a different kind of sport: it wasn't like anything that I had played before, and I though it was really interesting. Now I play because I love to meet new people when I play against different teams, and I gain new experiences when I play with different teams because everyone is taught differently.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Roller Derby is appealing because there is such a lovely community, that's the main thing for me. Granted, there's some competition between skaters/teams but that's present in any sport. I have always loved roller skating, ever since I was wee. I'd love to continue with derby and have loads of new experiences like trying for Team Scotland and maybe playing for the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;Nothing has really changed for us as we were still juniors (except the rules, haha) but the changes make Derby. We can adapt to it and grow from learning all these new things that are being introduced. I love that derby is becoming more mainstream and the sport that we love and spend most of our time playing, is becoming bigger and more people are growing to love Roller Derby too 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, for you, Skye, you're now on the Bairn City Rollers, was that a big change for you, moving from Juniors to the BCR training and bouting ?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;It was a scary jump as a junior because I'd seen all these adult Derby games and been thinking "wow... this is intense..." but, when I finally made the jump, the only difference was that everyone else was physically bigger (as in stronger and more skilled). It was still the same game, it was still the same rules, and I still loved it. I'd really urge anyone who's been in Juniors and is about to age out to make the jump, it's so worth it! It may be daunting but go for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;Callie is itching to move up to adult derby 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Callie, before the game we're going to get onto, you had a previous practice &amp;amp; Scrimmage with the [Lincolnshire] Bombinos - how did that happen, and do you have memories / thoughts about it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Initially I went to Team GB [Junior Roller Derby] training in Oldham, where I met some of the Bombinos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's where I got my foot in the door... My mum struck up a friendship with one of the Bombinos coaches (Beverley Gormley) who has been fantastic, sending us links for games we might be interested in. I then went to a mixed game in Sheffield and I met the rest of the Bombinos there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have become really good friends with Eve (Lady Macdeath) and a few of the other Bombinos. At the game the children's parents, who have never met me, were supporting me all through the game and I won best jammer too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;I was feeling really accomplished: I've been playing Roller Derby for a very long time, and to get an award for a very exciting game was so good.  To hear the Bombinos shouting encouraging words was a fantastic feeling, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Skye, looking pensive." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/Skye1.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Skye [Photo: David Prentice]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, let's talk about the game in more detail!
How was it being benched by / benching your sister?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;I thought it was really fun because I know her very well and I respect her, so it was easy listening to her and everyone in the team respected her . She was really supportive towards the whole team and never gave up which made everyone respect her more. She was so enthusiastic which I loved about her.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;It was really fun as I have played against, and alongside, Callie but never benched her in a game situation. I've never had a chance to take a step back and see her get her "game face" on and see her play as an independent skater. She listened to me as well (which she never does!) which was amazing and just seeing her having fun meant a lot 😊&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, this was also your first time benching a public game, Skye... How much practice had you had previously?
(and would you do anything different next time you bench?)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;I've had previous experience coaching Juniors and benching internal scrims but in all honesty, I was still asking questions about effective benching when we got to Newcastle 😂 . As it was a junior game, though, I felt confident benching the game for them.
I've been looking to bench a public Juniors game for ages and amazingly this opportunity popped up, and I'm super grateful to the Bombinos for allowing me to bench.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for doing anything differently; I hadn't trained with [the Bombinos] so I didn't know what their tactics were and how they played, so I'd try and do a bit more research 😊.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the feedback I got from the Bombinos was great! They all enjoyed my benching and how I handled it: they felt that I was very relatable as I am about their age, and was very relaxed and not intimidating. They also said that I was very supportive when shouting "you've got this!" And "keep going!" etc. as they passed the bench. So much so that they commented on the [Bairn City Rollers] page that they liked me so much that they were wanting to steal me and take me to Lincolnshire 😁😁&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;All I wanted to do was help lead them to victory, and they did us proud with an over 100 point lead 😊😊&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And are you tempted to try more non-competitive roles in future (announcing? Refereeing?)
(Callie: how do you feel about trying a non-skating role? Anything tempt you?)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;I would love to bench a game once, maybe refereeing. I've always been interested in benching as it is something I feel like I would be strong at. I always have experience when I'm training as I am usually captain when we are doing scrims.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;I would potentially look at refereeing as I got older. I would happily do the cake stall at derby games again though 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;I would love to bench again and I would be more than happy to help out as an NSO, but coaching, benching, and skating is where it's at for me at this exact moment in time. I'm even thinking about attending the Coaching bootcamp in York later this year [ ], because I know there is a lot of junior skating talent that is ready to be developed and I want to be one of the people that could help 😊😊.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Picture of Callie, Jamming, for Lincolnshire Bombinos" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/Callie1.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Callie, jamming [Photo: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.incidentlight.co.uk/"&gt;incidentlight&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, Callie: what interests you about benching?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;I'd really like to bench because it gives me better leadership experience, I also have some more re games under my belt than the newer kids. I would love to guide them and use the skills and tactics I have learned through my previous games with Fierce Valley Roller Cubs and the more recent games with Lincolnshire and the Sheffield and Newcastle juniors to take other juniors to a win. Although, its not the winning that counts really, its that everyone feels good and enjoys themselves&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That's a very positive attitude to have!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;That's what Derby has taught me: we lost at our Sheffield game, but I came away with a lot more friends I would never have met if I hadn't been there&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Speaking of all the contacts you guys now have, what're your plans for the future in general, as skaters?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;For me, trying for Team Scotland and the World Cup. That's the dream 😁😁&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For 202x?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Yeah 202x. I've made friends with Eve who is about to age up to the adult teams and she may potentially try out as well 😊&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;For me, it's attending more games with the other Juniors, aiming for Team GB: I would love to represent Scottish Junior Derby as part of that.
I want to help my sister coach and develop other kids, as well as me, until I am 16 and can move to an adult team. Then I want to push myself as far as I can with that. Team GB is a huge focus for me for the future.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you feel that it would help to have more Junior Derby in Scotland, or is the Rollerstop team in Glasgow enough to keep new talent coming?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Personally, I think we we need more. There are new teams out there but games are few and far between at the moment. I am travelling to England to get games on my level because I have been skating for years whereas some others are very new to it. Once they are all up and running it will be great but a larger number of teams over the Scotland area will encourage more teams to travel to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully there will be other leagues who see the value in a junior team and maybe start some up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talent we have in Scotland is there, it just needs a helping hand 😀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;Skye is coaching the kids [at Rollerstop] right now but I know she has an idea that I hope she can develop.
It's doing concentrated training for level 3 skaters with a view to getting them ready for going to an adult team. Also for Junior British Champs if it happens and for trying out for Team GB. Right now it's just an idea, but it would let kids like me train on a level that perhaps some newer skaters aren't at yet, and would hopefully give them drive to get there and join in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Skye, jamming, in Bairn City Rollers bout." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/Skye2.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Skye [Photo: Dave Moore]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Skye, do you want to talk a bit about that plan too?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;My mum was talking to a few people who wanted to discuss the idea of a Junior British Champs for the future and the options for that, and it came to mind that whilst the kids are training, why not "up the level" for the kids who want to take that next step. The "tweens" who aren't old enough for adult teams but are ready for the next level of game play which is essentially adult games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;What do they do in the inbetween times? I know, I have been there and it's tough. Adults want to help train, but the idea of maybe full contact scrimmage with people who are legally still children can be offputting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, in Australia, there's a whole multi-level thing for modified contact scrimmage and so on, which might help with that, too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;If that would help then yeah, all for it and looking at it. Anything to bring more people to the sport and keep them with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would love to talk with coaches for adult teams, see if there can be some sort of programme of skills that can be shared, best practise maybe to keep the kids inbetween Junior and Adult leagues active and keen and looking forward to their next steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;Mum and I honestly just talked about it 2 days ago. It made sense because when I was in limbo, before the Bairns took me on, I nearly quit and it would have been a mistake to have done that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was very difficult for junior derby in Scotland in general, about then&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;We thought we were losing it altogether, no one's fault, but we are so glad it didn't disappear totally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;I owe a lot to Coach CB and the rest of the Fierce Valley team, and the Bairns as well 😊&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Callie, what about you - how did you manage in the gap between FVRC closing, and then your current Rollerstop + sort-of-guest-Bombinos-skater position?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;I kept up skating at Rollerstop in general, just to keep me moving. Rollerstop Derby lessons came at the right time, although we even looked at the logistics of going to Newcastle for Derby if need be, but it just wouldn't have worked long term.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I know your mum's been very committed to helping you keep going in Roller Derby...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Haha, she hasn't been at home for the last few weekends because of derby, always driving us to games, supporting us, washing our kit (!) (the most important part) and meeting more Derby parents to get us out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;She sees the benefits in Derby to us, confidence, health, experiences and new friends 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's a really good relationship you three all have 🙂&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Mum has been a huge support in our derby career, she's been our taxi driver to games and a massive help. She continues to support us through our derby lives 😊&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, this has been a great interview, really: but I want to hand over the mic to you guys, if there's anything you want to add that we've not covered?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Both Callie and I think that Junior Roller Derby needs to be spoken about and put out there a wee bit more and we are glad that there is more recognition about the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;I'm also super glad about the fact that (some) teams are opening up to 16-17 year olds as it's giving Juniors more of a chance to train.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;[I] would love to see more Junior teams in Scotland so there are more teams to play and gain more experience, and that some games between teams across the border and here become more frequent 😊&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>coaching</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>team gb junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/the_macintyres_take_over_roller_derby/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 06:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EROC 2019: The return of Europe's community conference.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/03/eroc-2019-the-return-of-europes-community-conference/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst it skipped a year in 2018, due to the potential conflict with the Roller Derby World Cup, one of the most important events in European Roller Derby is returning for 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2063064350378242/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;European Roller Derby Organizational Conference&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will be 10 years old at the time of its next edition, running from January 31st through February 3rd 2019, in its usual host city of Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2009, EROC has provided a place for the entire European derby community to come together to share experience, build contacts, and plan the future. It's been an invaluable starting point for several of the European National Governing Bodies, as well as helping to seed derby future across the continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/?attachment_id=27817#main" rel="attachment wp-att-27817"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27817" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/eroc2019.jpg?w=700" alt="" width="700" height="700"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular hosts, &lt;strong&gt;Bear City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;, have extended the conference to an additional day for the first time ever, providing two days of Workshops (Thursday + Friday) and two days of Sessions (the weekend) to bring together Europe's Roller Derby community in discussion and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst EROC has always existed to help build the European community, this year has a particular focus on "Inclusivity", with several sessions and workshops specifically covering aspects of that area. (Those that do not explicitly cover the topic will still interact with it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there will be a lot of sessions and workshops to cover: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8 workshops&lt;/strong&gt; (longer, more interactive topics) of which the titles and conveners of 6 have been released:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Bout preparation: Footage Analysis, Data and Statistics (Michael Watson)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Retention &amp;amp; Growth - your league, our sport (Crazylegs)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Roller Derby Coaching Qualification (Hydra (Rule56))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Inclusive Practice and Accessibility (Feminist Killjoy)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Your League’s Brand - Does it say what you want? (Crazylegs)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Breaking down walls - how to work with conflict management (Maurine Filip)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20 sessions&lt;/strong&gt; (shorter, more directed topics) of which the titles of 9 have been released:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Group Dynamics and Conflict Management (Pernilla Hellan and Lisa Plüschke)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Just another brick in the wall? What we need to know about the individual to create a good fit (Maurine Filip)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The Evaporating History of Roller Derby: fighting the Ephemerality of Digital Media (Sam Skipsey)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Inclusive Practice and Accessibility (Feminist Killjoy)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;False Economies: Is our DIY Approach holding back our sport? (Hydra (Rule56))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Junior Derby (Barney Trubble)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;How Skateboarders dealt with FIRS, best practices for WFTDA and FIRS (Shiran Habekost)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Is it in the walls? How organisational structures affect behaviour (Maurine Filip)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The first WFTDA Continental Cup Feedback Experience and best Practices (Birmingham Blitz Dames)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other unconfirmed topics previously mentioned as appearing include (unless we've missed a few covered above):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whipping your finances into inclusive shape&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low level harassment, aggression, consent, bystanders behaviour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Officiating crew selection process. Sexism and discrimination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open divisions and all-gender roller derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long lasting officiating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, that's still not all, as in addition, special sessions will be held, including a Round Table meeting with NGBs / National Teams and Governing Bodies, A League Fair (including space to sell merch and advertise your league), a 2 day WFTDA Officiating Clinic (weekend)...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and the requisite on-skates events, including the "EROC All-Stars Scrimmage" on Saturday afternoon/evening, and Chicks in Bowls Berlin beginners' bowls and ramps sessions on Sunday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the inclusive focus, &lt;strong&gt;Group Discounts&lt;/strong&gt; for multiple-tickets are available for consortia of smaller leagues banding together to share costs (meaning that, for example, if you and three other leagues can each only afford to send a single delegate each, you can pay together for 4, and get the same benefits as a single league sending 4 delegates); &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; all of those leagues are less than 3 years old, have less than 20 members, and are EROC first timers. If your league does not qualify, there are also a &lt;strong&gt;limited number of "Soliprice" (free, host-subsidised)&lt;/strong&gt; tickets available, to delegates with a strong case for why inclusion is particularly important to them (and/or how they will bring EROC experience back to their league).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; encourage leagues from newer areas to send a delegate, if they are able: EROC is only as good as the breadth of experience and viewpoints at it, and some of the most valuable opinions are from some of the newest places with derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registration is available via the following link: &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScUDoNk7cHaAqDsFIa1vjdCeHBwPjnlVjl-bvRRLhYz3Im_tg/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScUDoNk7cHaAqDsFIa1vjdCeHBwPjnlVjl-bvRRLhYz3Im_tg/viewform&lt;/a&gt; with Early Bird discounts lasting until the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with the additional on-skates activities available with an additional submission here:  &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfLPe5crURLG9pbhqL3bLoR1xvPRzhshloOmRXTS-ZaVVHOiw/viewform?fbclid=IwAR039VtJfOwx3aQs2xrbQXlF6DbtTbJekb4uePbsULouqX1iG2MreXW9l04" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfLPe5crURLG9pbhqL3bLoR1xvPRzhshloOmRXTS-ZaVVHOiw/viewform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2019</category><category>articles</category><category>bear city roller derby</category><category>coaching</category><category>eroc</category><category>european derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>rdwc</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/03/eroc-2019-the-return-of-europes-community-conference/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 11:14:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Stance 2018: Rule56's Coaching Summit returns, now International!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/31/derby-stance-2018-rule56s-coaching-summit-returns-now-international/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, we &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/03/uks-first-coaching-summit-derby-stance/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reported&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the first Derby Stance event: the UK's first ever "Coaching Summit", organised by North of England based coaching team Rule 56. Over a weekend of sessions from speakers across the UK (and one from the USA), the Roller Derby coaching community didn't just learn from each other, but also built some strong bridges and enthusiasm for pushing Coaching further in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the year and a bit since that big launch, Rule 56 have been continuing to &lt;a href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/happenings/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;develop coaching resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. With the aid of teleconferencing technology, they successfully provided a very effective short series of coaching webinars with Strong Athletic's Smarty Pants (as we &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/01/rule-56-now-coming-online-on-monday-6th/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reported&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/16/uk-coaching-rule-56-webinars-and-more/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;on&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; too), with attendees from across Europe and the Americas. They've also been running physical bootcamp sessions for skaters, like the upcoming "bite-sized" bootcamp on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1751163414965701/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working in Walls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on August 11th...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, whilst there was a second &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1979086938976164/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby Stance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; summit in February (taking advantage of the Roller Derby World Cup the weekend before to bring all those international skaters to one place), organising truly large-scale international coaching events has always been difficult, especially with our grass-roots amateur sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now! This winter, Rule56 are bringing together all the things they've learnt to make the &lt;em&gt;third&lt;/em&gt; Derby Stance a simultaneously larger, more international... and more &lt;em&gt;accessible&lt;/em&gt; event - by moving it entirely online!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-27125 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/derbystance2018.png" alt="derbystance2018" width="828" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby Stance Online&lt;/strong&gt; will be a 4 day virtual event, running from &lt;strong&gt;29 November&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;2 December&lt;/strong&gt; this year. Just like a physical event, there will be many different sessions to sign up with, grouped into 5 themes:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Just Start Coaching [5 sessions]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Strategic Coaching [4 sessions]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Mental Performance [5 sessions]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Game Day [3 sessions]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Juniors [3 sessions]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
as well as introductory and closing sessions, and a special session led by WFTDA's Beat-her Bones, representing WFTDA Education.
&lt;p&gt;Each of the 23 sessions will be available as a separate webinar, and can be signed up for (and paid for) independently of any others; of course, you can also sign up for the entire summit, as if it were a "physical" meeting as well, if you want. The flexibility of being able to pick and choose just the sessions you want, however, is a big advantage of the online-only format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with other webinars, the entire session will also be available to rewatch after the fact - so, even if your timezone makes it hard to attend the session live (or if you want to review a session later), you can still access all that coaching expertise, at your own convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other advantage of the online-only format is that it's immensely easier to pull together expert speakers and session leaders from across the entire globe. Rule 56 has managed to collect 14 of the best coaches in Roller Derby, and beyond, to contribute sessions to this event:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-27123 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/rule56__map-e1532701421288.png" alt="RULE56__map" width="1920" height="850"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smarty Pants&lt;/strong&gt; (Strong Athletic), &lt;strong&gt;Vivien Leigh-thal&lt;/strong&gt; (Rainy City Roller Derby), &lt;strong&gt;Booty Quake&lt;/strong&gt; (Roller Derby Athletics), &lt;strong&gt;Maurine Filip&lt;/strong&gt; (Stockholm Roller Derby), &lt;strong&gt;Rosie Peacock&lt;/strong&gt; (Glasgow Men's Roller Derby, Team Scotland Coach 2018), &lt;strong&gt;Devoida Mercy&lt;/strong&gt; (Philly Roller Derby), &lt;strong&gt;Maha El Nasser&lt;/strong&gt; (Rule 56), &lt;strong&gt;Papa Whisky&lt;/strong&gt; (Boulder County Bombers), &lt;strong&gt;Jess Paternostro&lt;/strong&gt; (Team Canada Roller Derby), &lt;strong&gt;Furrrocious&lt;/strong&gt; (Amsterdam Roller Derby)
&lt;strong&gt;Ballistic Whistle&lt;/strong&gt; (Southern Discomfort), &lt;strong&gt;Louise Capicotto&lt;/strong&gt; (Sport Psychology Consultant), &lt;strong&gt;Luludemon&lt;/strong&gt; (Terminal City Rollergirls), and &lt;strong&gt;Treblemaker 909&lt;/strong&gt; (Central City Roller Derby) are each contributing at least one session to the schedule (and some up to three).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can reserve tickets - for individual webinars, or the whole event - (and learn more about the summit) at the official website here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/derby-stance-online"&gt;http://www.rulefiftysix.com/derby-stance-online &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;from&lt;strong&gt; August 1st.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coaching</category><category>derby stance</category><category>international</category><category>rule56</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/31/derby-stance-2018-rule56s-coaching-summit-returns-now-international/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 08:32:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Directory: a new (UK-focused) resource for growing the sport.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/21/derby-directory-a-new-uk-focused-resource-for-growing-the-sport/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A perennial question from people starting derby: from rookies joining a new team, through to the most scary challenge, people starting an entirely new league or team, is "how do I do this?".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst there are actually a lot of resources out in the wild concerning various aspects of roller derby, they're often fairly disorganised and dispersed, or strewn across various Facebook and other social media groups which aren't necessarily the easiest to find. (The original roller derby leagues in the UK created a newsgroup for this, which eventually evolved into UKRDA, but things have moved on since then.) Additionally, there's a big problem with link-rot and social media decay in modern resources, which can easily lead to a given source of information vanishing, becoming stale, or otherwise more useless over time. (We wrote a little about this issue &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;earlier this year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26888 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/derbydirectory.jpg" alt="DerbyDirectory" width="426" height="426"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://derbydirectory.info/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby Directory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aims to solve all of this, at least in the UK; although its resources are mostly useful regardless of where your league is based. The brainchild of two of Border City Roller Derby, Carlisle's members - coach, referee, and founder Schrödinger's Phat #1691, and coach and skater Hoolia #2122 - this website aims to collect together, and organise, all the information you need to start up a league, or start off as a newbie skater. As Border City has only very recently transitioned to the state of being a "bouting" league, the issues of beginning skaters, and beginning leagues, are very fresh in the minds of all involved.&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps as a result, the site's organisation is really very good, with categories from the Rookie Corner (a step-by-step guide to the frequently asked questions of people new to derby), and Kit (including an itemised list of the mandatory kit items, with suggested products, ordered by price), through a comprehensive guide to Skate Care, links to Bootcamps and Coaches who are available to run sessions, and even a guide on Starting a New League.
In all cases, the clean, simple style, and clearly defined categories help to get to the information you need, quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with all projects like this, the proof of the pudding will be in the longer term - but both of the founders seem committed to maintaining and updating the site - both expanding it, and fighting the entropic forces of link rot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They're also still collecting offers of additional information - and especially Coaches available to run sessions for their mini-classified section there. If you're a Coach whose time is available for other teams, do let the Derby Directory team know!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coaching</category><category>communication</category><category>derby directory</category><category>in the news</category><category>reviews</category><category>training</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/21/derby-directory-a-new-uk-focused-resource-for-growing-the-sport/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 10:15:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee's Beginner Bootcamp Bonanza</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/16/dundees-beginner-bootcamp-bonanza/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-20568" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/bootcamp-banner-blog.png" alt="Skate Tay Victory!" width="727" height="315"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girls are hosting their first ever bootcamp on the &lt;strong&gt;first of July&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;Manhattan Works, Dundee! &lt;/strong&gt;Open to all, this bootcamp is welcoming pre mins skaters as well as recently passed individuals looking to cement their derby skillz! This event boasts four hours (&lt;strong&gt;11am - 3pm) &lt;/strong&gt;of minimal contact training, with on skates tickets selling out on day 1 - &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;spectator tickets are left for a mere £10 a head!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breaking the day down into sections: the five DRG coaches are Goldginger #77, G-Wrecks #713, Hubs #88, Landsborough #792 and Liston #07! Attendees can look forward to the following lessons:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;♥ Wall work with Hubs and G-Wrecks! ♥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter  wp-image-20812" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/walls.png?w=300" alt="walls" width="446" height="336"&gt; &lt;em&gt;"We can't wait to get started on our block for the bootcamp! Sharing skating skills with newer skaters and encouraging everyone, no matter their skating levels, to engage with the core skills needed to further roller derby in Scotland is something we both really want to be a part of! It's really the best way to start the summer!!"&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;♥ Jammer work with Landborough and Goldginger ♥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter wp-image-20811" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/jammers.png" alt="jammers" width="437" height="336"&gt; &lt;em&gt;"Our league has really benefited from specific jammer drills and discussions on how to approach the Star. Being able to share our experiences not only on a skills level but also a coaching level is a really exciting prospect! We'll work you hard but it'll be worth it!"&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;♥ Footwork with Liston ♥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-16584" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/laura-liston.png" alt="Laura Liston" width="271" height="355"&gt; &lt;em&gt;"The building blocks for good wall work always starts with footwork! Lateral movement, recaptures and even jammer work relies on skaters having a strong base of footwork! I'm hoping to break down some of the more daunting skills for skaters to work on before bringing them into the wall! If you're stronger as one, you're stronger together."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to on skates tickets selling out on the first day, the DRG have added extra off skates spectator tickets to allow more to attend! Spectators will be welcomed in discussions of skills and drills throughout the day, to ask questions to any of the coaches as well as take notes, pictures and videos. As this bootcamp is aimed at post/pre mins, the coaches are hoping that skaters will take their newly polished skills back to their leagues to extend the learning process around Scotland (and further afield!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information please visit the event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1852866768310688/?ref=br_rs" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
Link for off skates tickets (£10) can be found: &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2932707" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coaching</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>roller derby bootcamp</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/16/dundees-beginner-bootcamp-bonanza/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 09:00:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UK Coaching: Rule 56, Webinars, and more!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/16/uk-coaching-rule-56-webinars-and-more/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of our short series on Coaches and Coaching initiatives in the UK (which started with a look at the Derby Form Check initiative), it would be remiss of us not to cover this next topic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-19248 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/rule56.jpg?w=600" alt="Rule56" width="300" height="300"&gt; Logo by Lee Moyer Designs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 56&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the North-of-England based coaching business responsible for the UK's first Coaching Summit last year, have not been resting on their laurels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuing their association with Texas Rollergirls' Smarty Pants, (also of &lt;a href="http://www.getsmartycoaching.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get Smarty Coaching&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) Rule 56 have been spreading communication via their series of Coaching Webinars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hosted on &lt;a href="https://rule56.clickmeeting.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ClickMeeting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the Webinars make use of videoconferencing technology to allow coaches and skaters from around the world to attend a virtual seminar-like experience - with the advantage that collaboration is enhanced by shared whiteboards and the like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRD attended two of these hour-long sessions, where Smarty took the attendees (representing leagues from Illinois through Spain, and within the UK from Southhampton all the way up to Orkney) through an engaging look at a particular topic. In our cases, these were the "general purpose" introductory Coaching sessions - called Coaching 101 and 201 on the model of American University course numbering - which covered concepts such as "how to coach adults", "different styles of interaction when coaching", and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants were all engaged regularly by Smarty - and the advantage of the online format was that Smarty could always look back at the chat stream at a later moment, without breaking her flow, to pick up responses and questions. This was definitely handled well as a component of the seminar - whilst Smarty stuck to her slides generally, the responses from the attendees were woven into variation and extension on each topic as it was addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-19251" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/screen-shot-2017-05-01-at-19-45-51-a.png" alt="Screen Shot 2017-05-01 at 19.45.51-a" width="3080" height="1750"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explicitly collaborative "brainstorming" sessions were also well managed, with the shared whiteboard eliciting some genuinely free discussion, as you can see below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-19252" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/screen-shot-2017-05-01-at-20-23-43-a.png" alt="Screen Shot 2017-05-01 at 20.23.43-a" width="3070" height="1746"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spoke to Steph Howarth, of Tiger Bay Brawlers, who also participated in both sessions, who was equally positive. "Although I've been playing roller derby for a while, I'm relatively new to coaching. So it was great to have the chance to learn from Smarty's experience - she's clearly cares passionately about good coaching. I was particularly interested in learning how to structure practices and communicate my ideas better. Smarty's seminars really helped with this - I came away with a heap of new ideas."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remaining sessions are still available to book from the Rule 56 Facebook Events page: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/rule56/events/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/pg/rule56/events/&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;/strong&gt;or the ClickMeeting link earlier in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next session will be on "Indicators in Coaching", on the 5th June - there's still time to book this! After that, the 12th sees a session titled "Creating Team Success", and the 19th a seminar on dealing with "Questions at Practice".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other initiatives on the way from Rule 56, apart from actually coaching people, include a series of bootcamps - starting with one at the most northerly league in the UK, Orkney ViQueens! This is going to be an exciting one to attend, as Team England (and Rainy City)'s Missy Rascal is making her way up to lead the event as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can catch up with Rule 56 at their coaching venue in Manningham Sports Centre in Bradford, online at their webinar series, or meet Hydra (#56 herself) at &lt;a href="http://www.euroderbycon.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Euro Derby Con&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in mid-July, Barcelona!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coaching</category><category>rule56</category><category>smarty pants</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/16/uk-coaching-rule-56-webinars-and-more/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 20:50:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UK Coaching: Derby Form Check</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/05/uk-coaching-derby-form-check/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;One of the hot topics in Roller Derby, always, is Coaching. In recent times, since the Derby Stance Coaching Summit, we've seen even more collaboration and discussion in the area of UK Coaching - with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com"&gt;Rule56&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s Coaching Webinars a direct follow on from this. However, there's initiatives happening even in the furthest reaches of the UK's geography... as our guest writer, and founder of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/403911146657994/"&gt;Derby Form Check&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Ronie Walters (of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/OrkneyViqueens/"&gt;Orkney ViQueens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) explains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-18605" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/derbyformcheck.jpg?w=300" alt="DerbyFormCheck" width="300" height="210"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the great things about roller derby is the grassroots ethos. We all know the ethos: "by the skaters for the skaters". You don’t need to jump through a lot of hoops and regulations to set up a roller derby league, you can just have the idea and get going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly what we did in Orkney. Orkney is a small group of islands, off the North coast of Scotland. To get to us you need to get either a plane or a ferry. Obviously travelling to train with a local league is not really an option in this situation, so when we wanted to get started, we had to start from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roller Derby Community is lovely. Everyone is really supportive and I’ve made some great contacts whom I consider friends I’ve just not met yet, which has been awesome. But... it kind of feels like everyone is re-inventing the wheel.
Every single league I’ve encountered is using the WFTDA min-skills in some form as their standard for knowing when a skater is safe to play.
Every single league runs some form of “fresh meat” training program to get their skaters through those min skills.
Yet trying to find a training program to use as a template has been almost impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went to join the UKRDA to use that as a resource, yet, at present, you have to have been skating for 6 months as a team to be eligible to join – leaving you alone to muddle through until that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were lucky enough to manage to get a couple of people to do the BRSF [British Roller Sports Federation] level 2 coaching course recently in Luton (from what I can gather, it’s not been run for a while) so that was amazing for us, and we learnt a lot from it in terms of coaching cues and coaching skills. We also attended the Rule 56 online coaching pilot, and are excited for the next sessions coming up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule 56, like us, are looking for more joined up approaches to Roller Derby Coaching. They also believe we have some incredibly awesome coaches and skaters amongst us, we just need a more effective way to share them. The more we can share resources and skills, the faster we can progress as a sport, and the better the experience for those coming into the sport as new skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be nice if, one day, new leagues starting in the UK could simply go to one place, and find all the information they needed.
This could be something as simple as UKRDA offering an associate membership so leagues can have access to the resources they need for that six month waiting period. This could then offer things like policies and constitutions, a clearly laid out min skills program, information on how to test a min skill and tell if your skater has mastered it, a resource for learning how to coach effectively, and access to a library of videos of real skaters complete with feedback on where they can improve, as well as video of ideal form to know what you are looking to get your skaters to.
The latter part of this has taken a step forward recently, with the introduction of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCoWo7DaL7OZGmG6gijWd7SQ"&gt;WFTDA Ed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; min skills videos. For the first time, there is some standardised indication of what a skill should look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, how do you get from where you are now, to that perfect form? Something I read recently in PEAK, when it was being discussed in the roller derby book club, was the notion of deliberate practice. Peak posits that there is no such thing as people with innate talent or ability. Even the likes of Beethoven or Tiger Woods are great because they have put in a lot of practice.
But this is not just about spending time; it’s about deliberate practice. Taking a skill and breaking it down into its elements, then practicing the elements making use of effective feedback to help you master the different parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a new club, we are learning together. We have some skilled skaters, but no-one with roller derby experience, or with experience in how to observe a skater and break the skill down for them with feedback to allow them to practice the elements and build it back up. It occurred to me that if we as a wider roller derby community could share video footage of us skating, we could all benefit from the feedback experienced skaters could provide. We are all individual, and we all learn differently. Sometimes the way someone explains something just clicks for you and, all of a sudden, you master that tricky bit you have been stuck on for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roller Derby Form Check&lt;/em&gt; aims to provide this opportunity. As a new Facebook group, it only has a few videos at present, but with over 370 members, it has the potential to be a very powerful resource. The hope is that gradually people will start to post a video of themselves doing a skill they are struggling with. So rather than a written post of how you're struggling with your 27/5 or you just can’t get transitions but don’t know why, you can film yourself. You will then get personalised feedback, rather than generic answers, or written descriptions which can be hard to visualise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our dream for the group is that over time we build a library of people demonstrating common issues with the minimum skills, with a whole range of ways of explaining how they can work to improve from different people.
Some of those explanations will hopefully also come with a video of them demonstrating the techniques they are suggesting. Using this, coupled with the “perfect” examples from WFTDA Ed, will really allow for some really powerful coaching resources to develop. We can already see that coaches are finding it helpful to learn additional ways to explain things and break skills down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you are stuck on a skill you just can’t seem to master, no matter how often your coach explains it, post a video. Maybe someone else’s tips will help you. If you are a coach and you have one skater that you just can’t figure out how to help, ask them if they are OK with posting a video and see if other people’s explanations can help them break through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Derby Form Check is a (closed) Facebook Group, open for registration: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/403911146657994/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/groups/403911146657994/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coaching</category><category>orkney viqueens</category><category>rule56</category><category>video</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/05/uk-coaching-derby-form-check/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 09:36:29 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>