<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about coed)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/coed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 08:59:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Are you ready for a skating spooktacular?</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/19/are-you-ready-for-a-skating-spooktacular/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9817" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/fb-hallowmean-a.jpg" alt="fb-hallowmean-a" width="3545" height="1305"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tricks or treats? Why choose when you can have both – and a whole lot more – at Mean City’s closing home game of the year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow’s only coed league will be hosting a devilish double dunt of derby delights on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 29 October&lt;/strong&gt; at the Dear Mean Place – aka the &lt;strong&gt;ARC Sportscentre in Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hallowe'en is when things go bump in the night - &lt;strong&gt;HallowMean&lt;/strong&gt; is when things go bump on the track and there are trick and treats for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, the &lt;strong&gt;Mean City ladies&lt;/strong&gt; – fresh from a gallus bout against Granite’s Fight Hawks and looking to maintain their forward momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Meanies have been reaping the benefits of a greater emphasis on tactics, fitness and skills – with fresh recruits bolstering the settled squad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their opponents on 29 October will be the out-of-this-world &lt;strong&gt;ASTROs (Auld Reekie All Star Rookies)&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s going to be a stern test of the Mean City ladies’ resolve, as well as a showcase for some of Scotland’s finest up and coming skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second game will see &lt;strong&gt;Mean City's coed team&lt;/strong&gt; ghosting to the track to take on &lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers' Belter Skelpers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tis the season to be fearful and while there’s no fear among the Mean City ranks, there will be some trepidation given the excellent form the Belter Skelpers have been in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bairn City Rollers’ coed team recently played a mix of Aberdeen and Dundee skaters – the Brawler Buddies – and really brought their A game, winning with a well-oiled performance combining offence, defence and excellent tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City’s coed team may lack the experience of their opponents, but they have spirit, guts and tenacity in abundance and will match them skate for skate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City President Elaine Hunter – aka Roller Dobby - said: “We can’t wait to round off our home season in style with a spook-tacular thriller for all the family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Trick or treat – why choose when you can have both? There will be skating, fun, cakes and cracking tunes – what else are Saturdays made for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Tickets are just &lt;b&gt;£4&lt;/b&gt; in advance – that’s just £2 per game – or &lt;b&gt;£5&lt;/b&gt; on the door. It’s a bargain and you’ll be supporting grassroots sport at the same time. Under-14s get in free.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean City presents HallowMean - Saturday 29 October 2016 - doors open at the ARC Sportscentre at noon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;For more information on the event – &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/312912055752880/"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;For tickets – &lt;a href="http://www.meancityrollerderby.com/tickets.php"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>coed</category><category>in the news</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/19/are-you-ready-for-a-skating-spooktacular/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 15:36:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Team who Sur5ed: Fierce Valley host Harry Potter-themed open event</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/18/the-team-who-sur5ed-fierce-valley-host-harry-potter-themed-open-event/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's now become a tradition that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://fvrg.co.uk"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; host big events towards the end of the year, and this year is no different. After the success of previous Sur5al tournaments, FVRG are adding an additional detail this year: all teams are coed (or "open", as we believe the newly popular term is).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;22nd&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;October&lt;/strong&gt; sees this event, with a Harry Potter theme embraced by many of the teams, at Fierce Valley's usual venue of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Grangemouth+Sports+Complex/@56.0117322,-3.7230718,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x488879aaeb85b4ed:0x204ad804f85c6304!8m2!3d56.0117322!4d-3.7208831"&gt;Grangemouth Sports Complex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantage of Sur5al is that you can host a relatively large number of teams in a surprisingly small space of time, and the Scottish roller derby community have taken full advantage of this, with the following teams signed up to skate:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="display:inline-block;width:120pt;"&gt;Golden Snatches&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style="color:#ffff00;background-color:#000000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yellow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Captain: &lt;em&gt;Dita Von Cheese&lt;/em&gt; [Fierce Valley Roller Girls])&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="display:inline-block;width:120pt;"&gt;Snapes on a Plane&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style="color:#3366ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Captain: &lt;em&gt;Thump'her&lt;/em&gt; [Fierce Valley Roller Girls])&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="display:inline-block;width:120pt;"&gt;Slytherwins&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Green&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Captain: &lt;em&gt;Fury Eyes Only&lt;/em&gt; [Auld Reekie Roller Girls])&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="display:inline-block;width:120pt;"&gt;Block Street Boys&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;Black&lt;/strong&gt;. Captain: &lt;em&gt;Tiny Tearaway&lt;/em&gt; [Dundee Roller Girls])&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="display:inline-block;width:120pt;"&gt;Neville loves Prada&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style="color:#808080;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Captain: &lt;em&gt;Khileesi&lt;/em&gt; [Dundee Roller Girls])&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="display:inline-block;width:120pt;"&gt;Why so Sirius?&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style="color:#ff6600;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orange&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Captain: &lt;em&gt;Sadie O'Hades&lt;/em&gt; [Glasgow Roller Derby])&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="display:inline-block;width:120pt;"&gt;Immobulud&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style="color:#ffffff;background-color:#000000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;White&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Captain: &lt;em&gt;Skimbleshanks&lt;/em&gt; [Mean City Roller Derby])&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="display:inline-block;width:120pt;"&gt;Nameless Ones&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Captain: &lt;em&gt;Sylk&lt;/em&gt; [Mean City Roller Derby])&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="display:inline-block;width:120pt;"&gt;Snitches and Bitches&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style="color:#ff00ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pink&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Captain: &lt;em&gt;Hazzard&lt;/em&gt; [New Town Roller Girls])&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="display:inline-block;width:120pt;"&gt;Magic Hot Pocket&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style="color:#800080;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purple&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Captain: &lt;em&gt;Harm&lt;/em&gt; [Lothian Derby Dolls])&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
With ten teams taking part, the usual Sur5al round robin format will require a massive &lt;em&gt;45&lt;/em&gt; bouts, each lasting a single jam, for a total of 90 minutes of track time (probably approaching 2 hours of total time).
&lt;p&gt;In total, we are told that, in addition to those teams providing captains, skaters from Bairn City Rollers, Ayrshire Roller Derby, Granite City Roller Derby, Granite City Brawlers, and Capital City Roller Derby are also represented, making this a truly inclusive event for the Scottish derby community. (Even the officials are represented, as Block Street Boys Captain Tiny Tearaway is returning to the track from her now usual Refereeing role for this event.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;14:45&lt;/strong&gt; for a prompt 15:00 start. Tickets cost &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; (+ booking fee) &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2639837"&gt;online from Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;£7&lt;/strong&gt; on the door (under 14s free, with an adult). Harry Potter fancy dress welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event page for more up to date information and afterparty details is : &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1766885553525356/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1766885553525356/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>coed</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>open</category><category>sur5al</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/18/the-team-who-sur5ed-fierce-valley-host-harry-potter-themed-open-event/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 14:59:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital City Host the Final SMRDN game of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/27/capital-city-host-the-final-smrdn-game-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year we saw the launch of the Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals (SMRDN), which saw Bairn City Rollers, Mean City and Capital City all fight for the bragging rights of being the top Scottish Men's team. With two games played and two wins to BCR's Skelpies they have taken the title of champions for this year. There is however still one more game left to play which is sure to be an exciting clash for more than one reason, which is Capital City vs Mean City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone wp-image-4863 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ccrd-banner-smrdfin.jpg?w=614" alt="ccrd-banner-smrdfin" width="614" height="227"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two teams have yet to met on track in a public game, with this their first encounter deciding who will take second place in this years SMRDN and the looser picking up 3rd and last place for 2015. With so much to play for, both teams will be fighting for every point from the first whistle to the last. And if this wasn't enough to tempt you along, Capital City have turned the event into a double header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get everyone ready for the main event, they are putting on a coed game first at which we will get to see some of the the Granite City Brawlermen in action for the first time as they join forces with some of the girls from Granite City Roller Girls as well as other guys and girls from the likes of Capital City, Mean City and Bairn City to form both of the coed teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This double header will take place at Meddowbank on Saturday the 19th of September, for more information visit the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4864" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ccrd-tall-smrdfin.jpg" alt="ccrd-tall-smrdfin" width="513" height="720"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>ccrd</category><category>coed</category><category>double header</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>mcrd</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mens roller derby scotland</category><category>scottish men's roller derby nationals</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><category>smrdn</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/27/capital-city-host-the-final-smrdn-game-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 11:21:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital City’s cherry popping bouters</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/30/capital-citys-cherry-popping-bouters/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scotland has seen some co-ed action over the last couple of years involving the likes of Dundee Roller Girls, The Jakey Bites, Fierce Valley, Granite city, Mean City, New Town and Bairn City Rollers. On Sunday the 20th of July Capital City Roller Derby joined those leagues after putting together a co-ed team to take on Bairn City Rollers co-ed team the Belter Skelpies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was Capital City’s first foray on a flat track since the league formed, with their team comprised of their own skaters as well as skaters other halfs and friends to form Capital Chums on the day. Whilst Capital City already have some recognisable men’s skaters in their ranks, they also have a few fresh new faces in the world of Scottish Men’s Derby. On the day they had Buyer’s remorse, Bish bash Josh, Critical Hit and Niko Blocker Gorey all popping their bout cherry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game itself was a very close fought battle with the lead changing every couple of jams till the last whistle, but it was the Belter Skelpies who took the win by five points in an epically loud and dramatic last jam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the dust has finally settled since their first bout, I took a moment to catch up with some of the Capital City guys and ask them about how they prepared for their first bout and how it went on the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Niko Blocker Gorey&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;    &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;#31      (NBG)
Critical Hit&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;    &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;            &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;#2d6    (CH)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/nbg-ch-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-3560" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/nbg-ch-1.jpg?w=300" alt="Niko and Critcal hit in action together" width="300" height="163"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Niko and Critcal hit in action together&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How did you find out about Derby and CCRD?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(CH):&lt;/b&gt; I was at a comic convention in Inverness where ICRD (or the Nasty Nessies back then) were promoting themselves. They told me about ARRG so I dragged a pal of mine along to see what it was about. We watched in complete confusion until someone explained how the game worked. After that I kept going back to the games, and in January 2013 the announcer mentioned there was a men's league starting up. A couple of weeks later I was starting down the long road to mins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(NBG):&lt;/b&gt; I went along to an ARRG bout in 2009, went to a few bouts at Meadowbank thereafter, and then got season tickets for the home seasons they put on. In 2012 the Edinburgh International Film Festival screened a roller derby documentary called "Leave It On The Track", and for the next six months I remember saying to my wife wistfully (and repeatedly) 'gosh, it'd be great to try out roller derby. I wonder if a men's team is likely. I'd like to give that a go'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 2012 I spotted CCRD's facebook page, and my wife noted that I would be the ultimate hypocrite to not get in touch after 6 months of wittering about my interest. So, I did, got in touch with a founder member of CCRD, and in January 2013 came to my first training session!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Having not skated previously how did you find working towards and passing your mins?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(CH):&lt;/b&gt; It was harder than I thought on only two hours of skate time per week. Looking back on it, I should have gone out to as many other training opportunities as I could have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(NBG):&lt;/b&gt; I literally had never been on skates before. We had the old Fisher-Price 'strap on over your shoes' kids skates which I really didn't use (my brother did); I tried a friend's inline skates for 5 minutes once before deciding it wasn't for me, and may have gone ice skating 20 times in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mins pace was very much a snail's crawl. I know from other sports I have played (more than 15 years ago), that I am very much interested in the technicalities of doing something, and I will drill them to the point where people think I am insane. CCRD were great at giving me the time and space to pass my minimum skills at my own pace, there was no pressure and it really felt like an environment that supported people who wanted to race up, pass quickly and get scrimming experience, versus people like me who plodded along passing things slowly but (hopefully!) competently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What would you say has been your biggest achievement so far in derby?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(CH):&lt;/b&gt; It's early days yet, so not much apart from not breaking myself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(NBG): &lt;/b&gt;It has to be my first bout. I did the best I could, which by an absolute measure was very poor - but, with only one scrim prior to it, my experience is relative. And by that measure I was happy: I scored some points, got to try all positions out, only committed two penalties and adjusted to stop them recurring. Now I'm just looking forward to more training, more scrims and more game time, just logging the hours and getting more and more skill and game experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/nikoblockergory.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-3558" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/nikoblockergory.jpg?w=252" alt="niko blocker gorey vs iHorror" width="252" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; niko blocker gorey vs iHorror&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Did you get any pre first bout nerves? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(CH):&lt;/b&gt; Just a bit nervous was all. Having scrimmed a fair bit I knew some of what I was getting into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(NBG):&lt;/b&gt; Honestly, no. But, I have always believed you can only train for so long, and just try to execute what you've learned as well as you can in the middle. Once you get on track, so much is going on, that you don't have time for nerves. I think you just have to be true to your training, and stay calm, and undoubtedly with more experience it'll become second nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What sticks in your memory most from your first bout?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(CH):&lt;/b&gt; I got lead and points!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(NBG)&lt;/b&gt;: I think it'll be the jam where I was pivoting: it was early doors and I hadn't jammed, and got passed the star, at which point I absolutely went for it. I burst through the pack made at least one pass, which may be the only score I got all bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Did you get any good advice that helped you on track or prepare for the bout?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(CH):&lt;/b&gt; Zen...just be zen...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(NBG):&lt;/b&gt; The bench manager for my first bout is our league's captain and chair, who has absolutely moved heaven and earth to keep the league running and training well, so I have a mountain of respect for him, and his advice was simply 'remember your training' and 'stay calm'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/critical-hit.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-3559" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/critical-hit.jpg?w=300" alt="Critical hit up against a Bairns wall" width="300" height="180"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Critical hit up against a Bairns wall&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Is there any advice you could give others who still have their first bout to come?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(CH):&lt;/b&gt; Scrim, scrim and scrim some more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(NBG):&lt;/b&gt; I would say don't pass up an opportunity to scrim as much as you can before the bout, to gain that game-like experience. I didn't do this: I don't drive, so further afield scrims weren't really viable, plus I have the white picket fence life so trying to carve out time for derby can be a tricky balancing act. So, if you hear 'scrims' mentioned, get to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Are there any skaters (Male or Female) who inspire you?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(CH):&lt;/b&gt; So, so many. If I start naming people I'll be here all day. All the folk who do the training at CCRD, and all the people I see regularly at scrims who give me advice, you're all great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(NBG):&lt;/b&gt; I think the catalyst from going from 'this is fun to watch' to 'I'd like to give this a try' was Teenie Bash (208) from ARRG. I'm a Cherry Bombers fan (4 lyfe!) and she was absolutely excellent for them in the 2012 home season. I'm on the short side for a guy, and when I saw Teenie jamming and blocking against women considerably taller and broader than her, I realised the sport isn't predicated on size, and I guess I saw the opportunity for everyone in roller derby which makes the sport so great and progressive. So in the meantime I hope she isn't too embarrassed by me letting her know this way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/nbg-ch-2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-3557" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/nbg-ch-2.jpg?w=300" alt="Niko Blocker Gorey and Critical Hit in action" width="300" height="192"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Niko Blocker Gorey and Critical Hit in action&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Skaters generally set goals for themselves, now that you have played in your first bout what goal's are you now looking to achieve/work towards?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(CH):&lt;/b&gt; Get through those darn walls! I seem to be able to get past three blockers but I don't have the acceleration to break free of the last one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(NBG):&lt;/b&gt; I think that from now on I'll adopt the default position where I'll go to every scrim I can manage to and rack up some on track game-like experience. Beyond that, I've realised I'm not turning my back on the sport soon, so have shelled out for some good skates, so it's going to be more training, more scrims, more bouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think my primary goal is that I'd like to get lead jammer in my next bout: I didn't get it once at my first, so that's the next life experience to check off!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Images courtesy of Laura MacDonald &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>cherry poppers</category><category>coed</category><category>critical hit</category><category>interviews</category><category>niko blocker gorey</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/30/capital-citys-cherry-popping-bouters/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 19:34:23 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>