<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about coimbra)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/coimbra.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Granite City's Hawks off to Fight in Portugal!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/15/granite-citys-hawks-off-to-fight-in-portugal/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As well as the exciting home games in Scotland this weekend, there's also an equally exciting away game, as Aberdeen's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GraniteCityRollerDerby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; send their B team off to Portugal to play in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/596021074083791/"&gt;Quad Cup 2018!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second iteration of the Quad Cup, the 2017 version seeing hosts, Coimbra's Rocket Dolls Roller Derby, play Black Thunders Roller Derby of Madrid, Lyon Roller Derby B team, Gones'n'Roses, and the exhibition team Liberty Rebellion in a 2 day round robin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26858" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/quadcup2018.jpg" alt="QuadCup2018" width="2048" height="1071"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This 2018 iteration of the European tournament pits the Fight Hawks against the returning teams of the hosts, and Black Thunders Roller Derby in a round-robin format in one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These will be the first games for the Fight Hawks this year, after their final bout in 2017, an extremely closely fought &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/98576"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 point win&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; against York Minxters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their opponents, meanwhile, have had one or two bouts already this year: Black Thunders playing Las Palmas to an overwhelming win early in the year; and both teams having faced As Brigantias (A Coruña, hosts of the upcoming WFTDA Playoffs in August). Whilst neither team defeated A Coruña's finest, the Black Thunders did considerably better than Coimbra, with a mere 34 point loss on an overall low-scoring game. As the Madrid team also defeated all comers in the 2017 Quad Cup, they must be the favourites this time around as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flat Track Stats agrees, with their European rating (at the time of publication), giving Black Thunders a 91% chance of victory over the hosts, and a 95% chance of victory over the Fight Hawks, who come in as the underdogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of these, however, the Fight Hawks are also the clear wildcards - with few close connections between their rating games and those of the two Iberian teams, they have the highest uncertainty in their performance; and their "rating momentum" was upward for the entirety of last year. With even FTS's pessimistic prediction giving Granite City B an expected 21:25 score ratio against the hosts (translating to perhaps a 20 to 30 point final score difference), it seems very possible for Aberdeen to provide the upsets this weekend. Given the disruptive behaviour of their namesakes, what would be more appropriate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Quad Cup 2018 will be held in the &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/qnbiz2Jpvh62"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pavilhão Multiusos de Coimbra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Coimbra, Portugal, with the first bouts starting at &lt;strong&gt;11am&lt;/strong&gt; (WEST, BST) on the &lt;strong&gt;17th June&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coimbra</category><category>european derby</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>rocket dolls roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/15/granite-citys-hawks-off-to-fight-in-portugal/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 10:11:18 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>