<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about crowdfunding)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/crowdfunding.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>How to help Team GB Juniors make history for JRDA Championships!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/05/23/how-to-help-team-gb-juniors-make-history-for-jrda-championships/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018 is a great year for World Cups in Roller Derby. Not only has it featured the 3rd Roller Derby World Cup itself, in Manchester; and the 3rd Men's Roller Derby World Cup, in Barcelona... but it will also see the first truly international &lt;a href="https://www.juniorrollerderby.org/2018champsandwc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Junior Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, as JRDA extends its Championships to include an National Teams tournament, including European representation for the first time..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great Britain will be one of 6 National or Quasi-national teams competing in the event, taking on Europe (also debuting), and the returning Teams of Canada, Australia, USA East and USA West for the JRDA World Cup Trophy, between &lt;strong&gt;23rd&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;24th July&lt;/strong&gt; (the two days following JRDA Champs), in Philadelphia, PA, USA!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll recognise some of the skaters involved in Team GB from the Roller Derby World Cup's Junior Roller Derby exhibition bout (and some of the others in that exhibition are in Team Europe, competing against them!); in fact, Team GB and Team Europe's mastermind, Phil Rutter, was responsible for organising that as well! (He's also the JRDA "European Regional Coordinator".)
Team GB Juniors has a host of other talent behind it, however: Head Coach, Toots, is a long established member of Lincolnshire Rolling Thunder + England Men's Roller Derby; also repeat members of England Men's are two support Coaches, Reaper (also of Southern Discomfort), and Tom-A-Hawk (also of Lincolnshire Rolling Thunder); the third support coach being England Roller Derby and London Roller Girls' equally skilled and experienced Beth Lord.
Beyond the coaches, there's a huge organising committee you can see &lt;a href="https://teamgbjuniorrollerderby.org/organisers/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough about the adults, though, you'll want to see the actual skaters! If you've missed the announcements, then here they are:
&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26763 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/05/collage-finished.jpeg" alt="collage-finished" width="712" height="712"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a National team is expensive - and it's especially expensive when you have to fly intercontinentally, and even &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; so when you're a Junior team (and thus need adults around for legal reasons too) - costs for Team GB Juniors will be at least £20000 overall...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, &lt;a href="https://teamgbjuniorrollerderby.org/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team GB Junior Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; have been raising funds for some time - supported by some excellent teams across the UK in providing events! This way, you can both support the UK's Junior Roller Derby community, and also experience awesome Derby too...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26762 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/05/gbjuniors.jpg" alt="GBJuniors" width="415" height="415"&gt; Team GB Juniors logo by &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thatbeastjen/"&gt;Jen Smith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up: Peterborough's Borderland Brawlers Roller Derby host a double header (2 June 2018), combining some all-gender roller derby with the best of UK junior derby.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;2 June 2018, Peterborough: [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/431804163914209/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Borderland Brawlers (Open To All, Peterborough) versus Mustard City Rollers (Open To All, Norwich) [FTS]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Team GB Junior Roller Derby versus The World (UK Junior skaters): Level 3 Junior Derby Exhibition!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
If you'd like to learn something as well, Team GB Juniors also have you covered, as Rainy City Roller Derby are generously providing the Thunderdome to them to host a combined adult/junior bootcamp!
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;16 June 2018, Oldham: Brutecamp, with Rosie Peacock and Optimus Grime. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2209024095992483/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Team Scotland /  Glasgow Men's Roller Derby's Rosie Peacock, and Power of Scotland / Glasgow Men's Roller Derby's Optimus Grime host an all day bootcamp event:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Morning: Adult intermediate skill bootcamp + scrim&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Afternoon: Juniors Level 3 bootcamp + scrim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Learn from two national squad level skaters and coaches with extensive international experience!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
But that's not all! Eastbourne Roller Derby's annual Outdoor Roller Derby festival, Eastbourne Extreme, will also be featuring an exhibition bout from Team GB Juniors, and opportunities to help support the team!
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;15 July 2018, Eastbourne: [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/700320030175090/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Eastbourne Extreme Outdoor Roller Derby Tournament
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Team GB Juniors Exhibition Event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
That will be your last chance to see Team GB Junior Roller Derby before all the skaters jet off to represent their combined nations at the Junior Roller Derby World Cup!
&lt;p&gt;If you can't make it to any of these events, and missed the chance to donate to Team GB Juniors at other events in the last few months - don't worry! You can also help the team entirely via the Internet by:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Donating to the Team Crowdfunder: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/teamgbjuniorrollerderby"&gt;https://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/teamgbjuniorrollerderby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Donating to individual Skater Crowdfunders (a bunch of these show up as "related crowdfunders" at the bottom of the Team fundraiser page)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Buying Team GB Juniors Merch: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://teamgbjuniorrollerderby.org/shop/https://teamgbjuniorrollerderby.org/shop/"&gt;https://teamgbjuniorrollerderby.org/shop/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Buying tickets in the Team GB Juniors Prize Draw (with prizes including signed national teams merchandise from USA Roller Derby, Team Wales Men &amp;amp; Power of Scotland's Optimus Grime, tickets to the Men's European Cup, fantastic artwork and more) &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://teamgbjuniorrollerderby.org/prize-draw/https://teamgbjuniorrollerderby.org/prize-draw/"&gt;https://teamgbjuniorrollerderby.org/prize-draw/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Volunteering your time to support any of the events above!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>crowdfunding</category><category>fundraiser event</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>jrda</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>team gb juniors</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/05/23/how-to-help-team-gb-juniors-make-history-for-jrda-championships/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 15:10:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Scotland Events: Fundraiser coming to a close!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/06/team-scotland-events-fundraiser-coming-to-a-close/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While over on Facebook, we've been regularly sharing info about the preparations for the various National Teams heading for the two Roller Derby World Cups next year... we've been saving a blog post for the Scottish National teams, starting with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Team-Scotland-Roller-Derby-235701999922927/"&gt;Team Scotland Roller Derby.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13779 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/scotland.png" alt="scotland" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In common with many of the teams heading for the 3rd Roller Derby World Cup in Trafford, England, Team Scotland are &lt;a href="https://www.crowdfunder.co.uk/team-scotland-roller-derby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;raising money&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to support their attendance. (Being a National Team has all the costs you would expect, from training venues, equipment, travel and accommodation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a special consideration this time around, &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; of the funds raised by TS will be donated to the charity &lt;strong&gt;Mind&lt;/strong&gt;, in support of mental health - and if you feel like you need a more tangible personal benefit for donating, all donations above &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; are eligible for Team Scotland branded merch, with donations above &lt;strong&gt;£75&lt;/strong&gt; enabling you to sponsor a specific Team Scotland Rostered Skater (who will wear a sponsors patch provided, during the World Cup).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have just until the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; to donate to the fundraiser, and help it reach its goal of just £2000, so please consider donating!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donation link is here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.crowdfunder.co.uk/team-scotland-roller-derby/"&gt;https://www.crowdfunder.co.uk/team-scotland-roller-derby/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in competing with Team Scotland, as well as supporting them, there's also the opportunity still to sign up as part of the mash-up team who will get to scrim against TS at their November training session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up in the Manhattan Works venue (Dundee Roller Girls' training venue), you will get to play with the best skaters that Scotland has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's still time to sign up here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/111479986185051/?"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/111479986185051/?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, if you'd like to help Team Scotland, rather than compete against them, applications are now open for the position of "Team Sports Therapist" attending the team for their training sessions, and competition, including the World Cup itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apply here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScwqegWr0F1-lAoO0hrXqrFLDx-fi1ueSwz7K9wZP4D3HugcA/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScwqegWr0F1-lAoO0hrXqrFLDx-fi1ueSwz7K9wZP4D3HugcA/viewform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on in the Year, Team Scotland will be making appearances at a few other events, so stay tuned to see how you can catch them on track before the World Cup!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>crowdfunding</category><category>fundraising</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/06/team-scotland-events-fundraiser-coming-to-a-close/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 14:13:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Save our Sharks in September!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/12/save-our-sharks-in-september/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Partly because it's grass-roots itself, Roller Derby has always been happy to raise money for other good causes. The &lt;strong&gt;3rd&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;September&lt;/strong&gt; might have a first even for Roller Derby, though, as Glasgow Caledonian University's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662153,-4.2519289,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8662153!4d-4.2497349"&gt;ARC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; hosts a double-header extravaganza with the aim of raising money to save endangered sharks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organiser, Lisa Alexander, used to skate for Perth's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.faircityrollers.com/"&gt;Fair City&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and Edinburgh's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk"&gt;Auld Reekie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, before taking a break from derby in order to dedicate herself to her degree in Environmental Science with the University of the Highlands and Islands. As part of this, she's raising funds to support and participate in a conservation study in Fiji.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8656" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/08/12573840_1555556068098928_7116823209862002714_n.jpg" alt="Shark Conservation" width="650" height="366"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharks are surprisingly endangered, mostly due to overfishing (for sharksfin soup and other foods), and the fact that, as apex predators, pollution affects them far more severely than other animals (as they eat all the pollution in their prey, too). Unfortunately, apex predators are also extremely important to the ecosystems they're part of - just as wolves kept deer populations under control in Scotland until we wiped them out, sharks manage the population of the rest of the ocean's inhabitants, and a threat to them is a threat to the entire balance of the sea's ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While she also has a more formal fundraising page &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.myprojectsabroad.org/fundraising/4pP1eK"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (which has more information on the plan and situation), Lisa always planned to include Roller Derby in her approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I guess it was always a fundraising event that I had in mind," she told us. "I've been involved in Roller Derby for 5 years and, although I've stopped skating to concentrate on the project, I felt like I still had the experience and support network to make it a successful fundraiser.
I know how amazing and supportive the Roller Derby community is, and I knew that they would get behind the project; because, who doesn't love sharks, or roller derby?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With skaters participating from all across Scotland's leagues, the event will feature both a female and a co-ed mixed bout, as well as a host of stalls, a raffle (with a selection of prizes including handmade glass vases, and climbing tickets!), tombola, and plenty of shark-related theming and puns, it will be worth turning up even without the good cause. A shark-shaped stamp has even been sourced for stamping entrants...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Facebook event page is here: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/829978330437565/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/829978330437565/&lt;/a&gt; with the tickets available from Brown Paper Tickets here: &lt;a href="http://m.bpt.me/event/2580086"&gt;http://m.bpt.me/event/2580086&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 12:20 for the first bout around 20 to 30 minutes later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are £10 on the day (free for under 14s), or just £8 in advance online.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>crowdfunding</category><category>fundraiser event</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>sharks</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/12/save-our-sharks-in-september/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 18:13:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital City crowdfund to help put on their first bout</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/25/capital-city-crowdfund-for-first-bout/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we all know putting on a bout can be a very costly venture for any league especially when it comes to your first. So when Capital City announced last month that they would be hosting their first home bout they were a little nervous. Being a relatively small league (around 14 members), they know only too well how difficult it can be bringing in enough money to cover costs. So they have come up with a novel way to help raise the funds they need to put on their double header bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a first for Scottish roller derby, they are looking to crowdfund for their bout to help raise money ahead of the big day. The aim is to raise money to help cover the majority of costs that need to be paid ahead of the bout, which breakdown as:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Meadowbank Hall Hire: £930&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Public Liability Insurance: £200&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Emergency Medical Technicians: £100&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Track Rope and Tape: £100&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Programme Printing: £50&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Over on their crowdfunding page they allow you to pre order items such as bout tickets and merch (t-shirts/caps/tote bags) along with some more special one off items, such as picking a song on the bout day playlist, blowing the first whistle for the game, getting your very own Capital City Uniform and much more. They have even auctioned off their skate out song which was snapped up only minutes after their campaign went live.
&lt;p&gt;Purchasing items help items Capital City put on their bout, but it will also save you money. As bout tickets and merch are cheaper for those who pre-order than they will be on the day as a thank you to those helping them. You will have to be quick as you can only purchase items until the 1st of November when their crowdfunding campaign ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to pre-order your tickets or are feeling a little flush with cash and want to buy some other things then head over to their crowdfunding page at indiegogo via the link below to find out details of all the things on offer:
&lt;a href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/capital-city-roller-derby-s-double-header-29-11-14"&gt;https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/capital-city-roller-derby-s-double-header-29-11-14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out more about their crowdfunding campaign watch the video below from Capital city&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=66QK04yIVFU&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>crowdfunding</category><category>first bout</category><category>fundraising</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby edinburgh</category><category>merchandise</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>video</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/25/capital-city-crowdfund-for-first-bout/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 10:39:29 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>