<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about crowdfunding)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/crowdfunding.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:48 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Derby without Borders: One year catchup</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/derby-without-borders-one-year-catchup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, we brought you an &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/05/derby-without-borders-an-interview-with-founder-mae-dae/"&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Mae Dae, to talk about their fantastic project, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://derbywithoutborders.org/"&gt;Derby Without Borders&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, less than a year later, the project has gone from strength to strength, helping more leagues in more countries across the world, in more ways. With so much happening, it is past time to write an update on events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby Without Borders was founded in 2017, as a project initially intended to help leagues in places where it was cost-prohibitive to get kit and other basic resources (sometimes because roller skating just wasn’t a thing in that country, often also because the cost of items was just much higher than the average wage allowed). The idea was, and still is, that donor leagues or individuals could donate “lightly used” or even new, kit to DwB, and the project would distribute items to leagues in need worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="All the places Derby without Borders has provided help to teams, so far. (Black: kit donations achieved, Blue: “start up” support, Green: advice and translation, Yellow: coaching bootcamps (and other additional support), Red: pending kit donation.)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/DwB2019.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;All the places Derby without Borders has provided help to teams, so far. (Black: kit donations achieved, Blue: “start up” support, Green: advice and translation, Yellow: coaching bootcamps (and other additional support), Red: pending kit donation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we talked to Mae back in 2018, DwB had already successfully helped Sailor City Rollers (Buenos Aires, Argentina), Golden City Roller Derby (Johannesburg, South Africa) and the Cairollers (Cairo, Egypt) with donation packs. They’ve also collected for Roller Derby Beirut (Beirut, Lebanon) (in collaboration with Quad Skate Shop), but have had difficulties getting the kit into Lebanon. Since then, they’ve also been able to support Bangkok Roller Derby (Bangkok, Thailand), Toxic Lima Roller Derby (Lima, Peru), Kyoto Roller Derby (Kyoto, Japan), and Roller Derby Beijing (Beijing, China)…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…but Derby without Borders have also been extending their goals in order to help Roller Derby in other ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, DwB is no longer just Mae Dae: since the last time we spoke, DwB has recruited a second body in the UK, in the form of Rosie Peacock (who has also set up a third donation collection point in the UK). They’ve been providing much needed support, Mae admitting “Rosie has been absolutely pivotal and an amazing addition to the team - I don’t think DwB would have gotten this far without their commitment to the project”.
The project has also grown an Advisory Board, positioned to steer the project in the right directions. In recruiting for the board, Mae tells us that they “reached out specifically to have Skaters of Colour on the board: they’re on the board to help steer the project in the direction it wants to be heading, which means engaging with intersectional, inclusionary and anti-oppressive practices.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rosie and Mae were both representing the cause at this year’s European Rollerderby Organisational Conference (EROC 2019) in Berlin with a stall, and a session on “Removing barriers to accessibility in roller derby”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“It was great to be able to talk with the theme of diversity and inclusivity, and how it relates to DwB, because it really is at the foundation of all of the work that we’re doing - this idea that we need to take down barriers to access in order to make this a more inclusive sport,”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;said Mae. In addition, every time DwB has a stall somewhere, more people learn about the project, and offer to support it. At EROC, one of the attending leagues offered to host a collection at their next bout, and to raise funds for the project.
That said, DwB and EROC in some senses were looking in different directions whilst supporting the same ethos. EROC is, intentionally, focused on improving Roller Derby within Europe; whilst Derby without Borders is inherently about looking outside, and working on how to support Roller Derby in other places, building in inclusivity and adapting culture to support other regions from the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- comment
Add images --&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Mae Dae on the Derby without Borders stall at EROC 2019 (Image copyright: Michael Wittig / Bear City Roller Derby)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/MaeDae-EROC.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Mae Dae on the Derby without Borders stall at EROC 2019 (Image copyright: Michael Wittig / Bear City Roller Derby)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that spirit, then, EROC was also the last event that Mae attended before leaving Europe themself. With Rosie positioned in the UK, Mae has courageously moved to Bangkok, Thailand, allowing them to be physically closer to one big region that would benefit significantly from DwB’s support – South East Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“Moving to Bangkok to help develop SE Asian roller derby has definitely been huge, and really pivotal.” Mae told us,  “I’m really understanding the needs of the region a lot better than I did before - and just how different the scale of roller derby is in all of Asia!”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since being closer to the action, they’ve launched an initiative to provide “consultation” services to newer leagues, giving them support and advice from the ground up (not just on how to start up a league, but also on developing local cultural competency). The first beneficiary of this is the first ever Roller Derby team in Bali: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/hotlavarollers/"&gt;Hot Lava Rollers&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with many of DwB’s new initiatives, this started with a conversation, as Mae relates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“Someone who used to skate with Crime [City Rollers] - Glitter Punch - reached out to me; she’d heard about the project, from Hanna P, and she said ‘I live in Bali now, and I’m so sad that there’s no Roller Derby. I really kinda want to make a team, and I was wondering if you could help me’”.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present, Hot Lava Rollers are just two people, and one set of kit (Glitter’s), and the team is just starting to recruit and look for spaces and other resources. Meanwhile, Mae is actively providing mentorship, on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“I’m trying to get them all the other resources that they would need, so helping them develop everything from bylaws, policies, through to making a logo, getting them social media, just… everything.”
“We’re trying to focus on consistent communication - we talk once a week, even if it’s just a 20 minute check-in. I think also it will be a learning experience in how to help support someone in starting a league without being there - I’m in Bangkok and it’s not far, only an hour’s time difference - but still, not being physically there to put in the work in the same way that I would / am with Bangkok [is a challenge].”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst advice and support is very important, when it comes to developing Derby-specific skills, there’s nothing better than a good coach. So, DwB has also been using its connections to organise specific Coaching Bootcamps in those regions involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 27th April, DwB and Bangkok Roller Derby are co-hosting a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2104905746467908/"&gt;bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; run by Canberra Roller Derby League (and Team Korea)’s ShortStop; on the 12 October, Atlanta Rollergirls (and Team USA)’s Baller Shot Caller will be running a DwB &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/781786125525096/"&gt;organised bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; in Bali! A future Bootcamp is also planned for Cairo (to be hosted by the Cairollers, with Zipblock and Freight Train), but dates and funding are still in progress on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Hot Lava Rollers founders, Rustamia Primanisa and Glitter Punch, after their first meeting with Mae [Thanks to Hot Lava Rollers &amp;amp; DwB]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/HotLavaRollers.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Hot Lava Rollers founders, Rustamia Primanisa and Glitter Punch, after their first meeting with Mae [Thanks to Hot Lava Rollers &amp;amp; DwB]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to run a bootcamp in Bali, in particular, came as a pleasant surprise even to Mae themself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“When Baller [Shot Caller] had reached out to me to ask what she could help the project with, I said, ‘well, here’s all the places I could use help with coaching’, and I let her pick.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
And she said, ‘If I have to choose one, I would say Bali. It seems more secluded, and they probably have less resources’!&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“I said, ‘it’s just two people - there’s the potential you could be teaching 5 people minimum skills’.
Baller was completely okay with that, as the gain in awareness, and value in increased representation was worth it. We did choose a date later in the year to give time for recruitment, though.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having already organised their first DwB bootcamp with Hong Kong Roller Derby (coached by Rosie Peacock and Optimus Grime of Glasgow Men’s Roller Derby), Mae is confident, however, that both bootcamps will have significant regional attendance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“The fact that we had 3 girls from the UAE travel all the way to HK just so they could attend a bootcamp and play a game , just goes to show you how isolated people are - but also how hungry they are for it. What I’m discovering about SE Asian roller derby, and Middle Eastern roller derby. is that when these things happen people will come from across the region to attend and come together.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Bali, though, the bootcamp in Bangkok will also be significant for another reason, being the first time that Bangkok Roller Derby will field a full team to compete. The bootcamp will see two games - the usual Pan-Asian Spring Rollers v Pan-Asian Spring Rollers setup, followed by the history-making Bangkok versus Hong Kong bout!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bout flyer for the next DwB bootcamp, hosted by Bangkok Roller Derby. [Image: Bangkok Roller Derby, photo by Teddy Tse]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/DwB-Bangkok-flyer.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bout flyer for the next DwB bootcamp, hosted by Bangkok Roller Derby. [Image: Bangkok Roller Derby, photo by Teddy Tse]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mae has also been active in providing resources and accessibility in other ways: at present, Roller Derby resources are overwhelmingly available in English (with Spanish probably the next largest). Whilst the WFTDA rules have a translation to the second most widely read language in the world (Chinese), there’s almost no availability in Hindi (the 3rd) and Arabic (the 6th – and 3rd most read as a second language) – and the most spoken Slavic language in the world, Russian, has a similar lack of support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DwB has projects underway to translate resources into under-represented languages to increase accessibility – in the case of Arabic, with the support of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/UAERollerDerby/"&gt;UAE Roller Derby All-Stars&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.cairollers.com/"&gt;Cairollers&lt;/a&gt;. (We’ll be catching up with the Cairollers shortly in another article, as they also have exciting news.) Russian translations of the Short Track Roller Derby ruleset have already been produced, thanks to efforts from the White Night Furies, and Abu Dhabi Roller Derby’s Spinky, as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, Mae dreams of having a “database of different resources for leagues, in all the languages; so if a league needs a framework for a code of conduct in Spanish, they can just go to the database and find something to base it on”. That’s for the future, however: the current effort is focused on getting basic rules and coaching resources translated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as translation, another issue, especially for countries with more filtered access to the Internet, can simply be access to resources at all. In China, for example, common hosts for Roller Derby resources like YouTube, Google Drive, Facebook, Twitter, Twitch, Medium and WordPress are all either permanently or irregularly blocked. Derby Without Borders is actively working with the Chinese Roller Derby community to provide access to the resources that the community needs, using hosts which are acceptable to the Chinese government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Derby without Borders continues to pursue its original goal of providing kit for skaters, as well. One of the first things that Mae noticed at Bangkok was that many of the skaters had inflexible, heavy mouthguards designed for Muay Thai. As theytold us, this isn’t really ideal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“you can’t really speak when you’re wearing them, and can barely breathe in them. So I just emailed SISU and said ‘hey, can you like just give us 20 mouthguards’ and they were like ‘yeah, sure, and just shipped them over’.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as SISU, other derby-related businesses - Steaks, Riedell, and Bont - have shown interest in supporting the project, especially as it has gained more visibility in the community. (Bont-sponsored skater Shortshop has managed to provide a set of wheels as a “prize” at her bootcamp in Bangkok, for example.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bangkok Roller Derby with SISU donated mouthguards, thanks to DwB [Image: Derby without Borders]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/Bangkok-SISU.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby with SISU donated mouthguards, thanks to DwB [Image: Derby without Borders]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this additional activity, however, is only sustainable if Derby without Borders continues to grow itself. Mae is currently working towards a new model for the organisation: regional “chapters” which can help to organise and manage the effort which DwB brings. (The Asia chapter will almost certainly be the first to be established, with recruitment happening now.)
The project is already growing fast enough to need this right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“One thing that I’m learning is understanding my own bandwidth and capability - how much I can do as one person.” Mae told us “Particularly, at this point, I’m doing all of this work because I want to do it - there’s no funding. Understanding my own bandwidth has been important because I’ve had two people reach out to me who were interested in doing the same thing in India, and whilst I absolutely want to help someone start a league in India, I think I might need to focus on one at a time, for now. I think with them I’m going to have to take a step back.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team India Roller Derby have since agreed to help support these potential seeds of Roller Derby, in collaboration with DwB, but the project still needs more people - and leagues - to join in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One Derby without Borders initiative which has been active for the start is the idea of “Sibling Leagues”: an opportunity for established leagues to pair up with specific leagues elsewhere in the world to offer them support. This support could be in terms of equipment donations, as the scheme was originally formulated with Texas collecting kit to donate directly to the Cairollers. However, as DwB evolves, it could equally be provided as knowledge exchange, guidance, and political and social support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“I would love to see that kind of Sibling league relationship develop with more leagues.” Mae told us, “instead of needing to come through DwB [to give support], it could be more like a mentorship: one league can mentor another league, and develop all their resources between the two of them. That’s what’s going to make it more sustainable in the long run [and] that’s the point of the project, creating these things for the sake of sustainability.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Quito, Ecuador’s Forajidas Roller Derby, post-recruitment in January. (Photo: Forajidas Roller Derby)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/Forajidas_roller_derby.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Quito, Ecuador’s Forajidas Roller Derby, post-recruitment in January. (Photo: Forajidas Roller Derby)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst we’ve mostly focused on activities in Asia in this update, that should not imply that DwB is not working for other regions as well. Mae told us that they have been in contact with Forajidas Roller Derby, who are currently trying to (re)establish the only league in Ecuador (in Quito, the capital).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the Forajidas have a GoFundMe ( &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gofundme.com/help-bring-roller-derby-to-ecuador"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/help-bring-roller-derby-to-ecuador&lt;/a&gt; ), they also need guidance and support in forming their league. Mae is actively looking for either a Sibling League, or a coach, or both, who can help to support the new team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, as well as helping to nurture and advise new and developing leagues, DwB is also working to support Roller Derby in other ways. Derby Without Borders can host crowdfunders for such leagues to allow them to raise funds more easily: at present, they’re hosting a GoFundMe to support Buenos Aires’ 2×4 Roller Derby on their current international travel requirements. (You can donate here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gofundme.com/2x4-international-tour-2019"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/2x4-international-tour-2019&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby without Borders is open to assisting any league or team who need their support: regardless of if that’s in SE Asia where Mae is currently focused, or in Latin America, the Middle East, Eastern Europe or Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you, or your league, or your company, want to support Derby without Borders in any way mentioned in this article (or another way you can think of), we encourage you to join in. Derby without Borders can only get better as it gets bigger - and it can only get bigger with more of the community pitching in to support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can support DwB via their Donation page [ &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://derbywithoutborders.org/donate"&gt;https://derbywithoutborders.org/donate&lt;/a&gt; ] and by buying their merch (which also lets you raise awareness of the project by wearing it everywhere) [ &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://derbywithoutborders.org/merchandise"&gt;https://derbywithoutborders.org/merchandise&lt;/a&gt; ]. Mae Dae and DwB central can be contacted by email at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:maedae@skatingoutofbounds.com"&gt;maedae@skatingoutofbounds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2x4 roller derby</category><category>argentina</category><category>bali</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>bootcamps</category><category>cairollers</category><category>china</category><category>crowdfunding</category><category>derby without borders</category><category>dubai roller derby</category><category>ecuador</category><category>egypt</category><category>forajidas roller derby</category><category>hot lava rollers</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>russia</category><category>thailand</category><category>uae roller derby all-stars</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/derby-without-borders-one-year-catchup/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 11:17:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to help Team GB Juniors make history for JRDA Championships!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/05/23/how-to-help-team-gb-juniors-make-history-for-jrda-championships/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018 is a great year for World Cups in Roller Derby. Not only has it featured the 3rd Roller Derby World Cup itself, in Manchester; and the 3rd Men's Roller Derby World Cup, in Barcelona... but it will also see the first truly international &lt;a href="https://www.juniorrollerderby.org/2018champsandwc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Junior Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, as JRDA extends its Championships to include an National Teams tournament, including European representation for the first time..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great Britain will be one of 6 National or Quasi-national teams competing in the event, taking on Europe (also debuting), and the returning Teams of Canada, Australia, USA East and USA West for the JRDA World Cup Trophy, between &lt;strong&gt;23rd&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;24th July&lt;/strong&gt; (the two days following JRDA Champs), in Philadelphia, PA, USA!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll recognise some of the skaters involved in Team GB from the Roller Derby World Cup's Junior Roller Derby exhibition bout (and some of the others in that exhibition are in Team Europe, competing against them!); in fact, Team GB and Team Europe's mastermind, Phil Rutter, was responsible for organising that as well! (He's also the JRDA "European Regional Coordinator".)
Team GB Juniors has a host of other talent behind it, however: Head Coach, Toots, is a long established member of Lincolnshire Rolling Thunder + England Men's Roller Derby; also repeat members of England Men's are two support Coaches, Reaper (also of Southern Discomfort), and Tom-A-Hawk (also of Lincolnshire Rolling Thunder); the third support coach being England Roller Derby and London Roller Girls' equally skilled and experienced Beth Lord.
Beyond the coaches, there's a huge organising committee you can see &lt;a href="https://teamgbjuniorrollerderby.org/organisers/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough about the adults, though, you'll want to see the actual skaters! If you've missed the announcements, then here they are:
&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26763 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/05/collage-finished.jpeg" alt="collage-finished" width="712" height="712"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a National team is expensive - and it's especially expensive when you have to fly intercontinentally, and even &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; so when you're a Junior team (and thus need adults around for legal reasons too) - costs for Team GB Juniors will be at least £20000 overall...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, &lt;a href="https://teamgbjuniorrollerderby.org/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team GB Junior Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; have been raising funds for some time - supported by some excellent teams across the UK in providing events! This way, you can both support the UK's Junior Roller Derby community, and also experience awesome Derby too...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26762 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/05/gbjuniors.jpg" alt="GBJuniors" width="415" height="415"&gt; Team GB Juniors logo by &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thatbeastjen/"&gt;Jen Smith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up: Peterborough's Borderland Brawlers Roller Derby host a double header (2 June 2018), combining some all-gender roller derby with the best of UK junior derby.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;2 June 2018, Peterborough: [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/431804163914209/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Borderland Brawlers (Open To All, Peterborough) versus Mustard City Rollers (Open To All, Norwich) [FTS]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Team GB Junior Roller Derby versus The World (UK Junior skaters): Level 3 Junior Derby Exhibition!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
If you'd like to learn something as well, Team GB Juniors also have you covered, as Rainy City Roller Derby are generously providing the Thunderdome to them to host a combined adult/junior bootcamp!
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;16 June 2018, Oldham: Brutecamp, with Rosie Peacock and Optimus Grime. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2209024095992483/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Team Scotland /  Glasgow Men's Roller Derby's Rosie Peacock, and Power of Scotland / Glasgow Men's Roller Derby's Optimus Grime host an all day bootcamp event:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Morning: Adult intermediate skill bootcamp + scrim&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Afternoon: Juniors Level 3 bootcamp + scrim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Learn from two national squad level skaters and coaches with extensive international experience!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
But that's not all! Eastbourne Roller Derby's annual Outdoor Roller Derby festival, Eastbourne Extreme, will also be featuring an exhibition bout from Team GB Juniors, and opportunities to help support the team!
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;15 July 2018, Eastbourne: [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/700320030175090/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Eastbourne Extreme Outdoor Roller Derby Tournament
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Team GB Juniors Exhibition Event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
That will be your last chance to see Team GB Junior Roller Derby before all the skaters jet off to represent their combined nations at the Junior Roller Derby World Cup!
&lt;p&gt;If you can't make it to any of these events, and missed the chance to donate to Team GB Juniors at other events in the last few months - don't worry! You can also help the team entirely via the Internet by:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Donating to the Team Crowdfunder: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/teamgbjuniorrollerderby"&gt;https://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/teamgbjuniorrollerderby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Donating to individual Skater Crowdfunders (a bunch of these show up as "related crowdfunders" at the bottom of the Team fundraiser page)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Buying Team GB Juniors Merch: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://teamgbjuniorrollerderby.org/shop/https://teamgbjuniorrollerderby.org/shop/"&gt;https://teamgbjuniorrollerderby.org/shop/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Buying tickets in the Team GB Juniors Prize Draw (with prizes including signed national teams merchandise from USA Roller Derby, Team Wales Men &amp;amp; Power of Scotland's Optimus Grime, tickets to the Men's European Cup, fantastic artwork and more) &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://teamgbjuniorrollerderby.org/prize-draw/https://teamgbjuniorrollerderby.org/prize-draw/"&gt;https://teamgbjuniorrollerderby.org/prize-draw/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Volunteering your time to support any of the events above!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>crowdfunding</category><category>fundraiser event</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>jrda</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>team gb juniors</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/05/23/how-to-help-team-gb-juniors-make-history-for-jrda-championships/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 15:10:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Scotland Events: Fundraiser coming to a close!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/06/team-scotland-events-fundraiser-coming-to-a-close/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While over on Facebook, we've been regularly sharing info about the preparations for the various National Teams heading for the two Roller Derby World Cups next year... we've been saving a blog post for the Scottish National teams, starting with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Team-Scotland-Roller-Derby-235701999922927/"&gt;Team Scotland Roller Derby.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13779 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/scotland.png" alt="scotland" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In common with many of the teams heading for the 3rd Roller Derby World Cup in Trafford, England, Team Scotland are &lt;a href="https://www.crowdfunder.co.uk/team-scotland-roller-derby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;raising money&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to support their attendance. (Being a National Team has all the costs you would expect, from training venues, equipment, travel and accommodation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a special consideration this time around, &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; of the funds raised by TS will be donated to the charity &lt;strong&gt;Mind&lt;/strong&gt;, in support of mental health - and if you feel like you need a more tangible personal benefit for donating, all donations above &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; are eligible for Team Scotland branded merch, with donations above &lt;strong&gt;£75&lt;/strong&gt; enabling you to sponsor a specific Team Scotland Rostered Skater (who will wear a sponsors patch provided, during the World Cup).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have just until the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; to donate to the fundraiser, and help it reach its goal of just £2000, so please consider donating!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donation link is here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.crowdfunder.co.uk/team-scotland-roller-derby/"&gt;https://www.crowdfunder.co.uk/team-scotland-roller-derby/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in competing with Team Scotland, as well as supporting them, there's also the opportunity still to sign up as part of the mash-up team who will get to scrim against TS at their November training session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up in the Manhattan Works venue (Dundee Roller Girls' training venue), you will get to play with the best skaters that Scotland has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's still time to sign up here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/111479986185051/?"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/111479986185051/?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, if you'd like to help Team Scotland, rather than compete against them, applications are now open for the position of "Team Sports Therapist" attending the team for their training sessions, and competition, including the World Cup itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apply here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScwqegWr0F1-lAoO0hrXqrFLDx-fi1ueSwz7K9wZP4D3HugcA/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScwqegWr0F1-lAoO0hrXqrFLDx-fi1ueSwz7K9wZP4D3HugcA/viewform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on in the Year, Team Scotland will be making appearances at a few other events, so stay tuned to see how you can catch them on track before the World Cup!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>crowdfunding</category><category>fundraising</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/06/team-scotland-events-fundraiser-coming-to-a-close/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 14:13:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Save our Sharks in September!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/12/save-our-sharks-in-september/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Partly because it's grass-roots itself, Roller Derby has always been happy to raise money for other good causes. The &lt;strong&gt;3rd&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;September&lt;/strong&gt; might have a first even for Roller Derby, though, as Glasgow Caledonian University's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662153,-4.2519289,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8662153!4d-4.2497349"&gt;ARC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; hosts a double-header extravaganza with the aim of raising money to save endangered sharks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organiser, Lisa Alexander, used to skate for Perth's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.faircityrollers.com/"&gt;Fair City&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and Edinburgh's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk"&gt;Auld Reekie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, before taking a break from derby in order to dedicate herself to her degree in Environmental Science with the University of the Highlands and Islands. As part of this, she's raising funds to support and participate in a conservation study in Fiji.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8656" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/08/12573840_1555556068098928_7116823209862002714_n.jpg" alt="Shark Conservation" width="650" height="366"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharks are surprisingly endangered, mostly due to overfishing (for sharksfin soup and other foods), and the fact that, as apex predators, pollution affects them far more severely than other animals (as they eat all the pollution in their prey, too). Unfortunately, apex predators are also extremely important to the ecosystems they're part of - just as wolves kept deer populations under control in Scotland until we wiped them out, sharks manage the population of the rest of the ocean's inhabitants, and a threat to them is a threat to the entire balance of the sea's ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While she also has a more formal fundraising page &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.myprojectsabroad.org/fundraising/4pP1eK"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (which has more information on the plan and situation), Lisa always planned to include Roller Derby in her approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I guess it was always a fundraising event that I had in mind," she told us. "I've been involved in Roller Derby for 5 years and, although I've stopped skating to concentrate on the project, I felt like I still had the experience and support network to make it a successful fundraiser.
I know how amazing and supportive the Roller Derby community is, and I knew that they would get behind the project; because, who doesn't love sharks, or roller derby?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With skaters participating from all across Scotland's leagues, the event will feature both a female and a co-ed mixed bout, as well as a host of stalls, a raffle (with a selection of prizes including handmade glass vases, and climbing tickets!), tombola, and plenty of shark-related theming and puns, it will be worth turning up even without the good cause. A shark-shaped stamp has even been sourced for stamping entrants...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Facebook event page is here: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/829978330437565/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/829978330437565/&lt;/a&gt; with the tickets available from Brown Paper Tickets here: &lt;a href="http://m.bpt.me/event/2580086"&gt;http://m.bpt.me/event/2580086&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 12:20 for the first bout around 20 to 30 minutes later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are £10 on the day (free for under 14s), or just £8 in advance online.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>crowdfunding</category><category>fundraiser event</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>sharks</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/12/save-our-sharks-in-september/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 18:13:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital City crowdfund to help put on their first bout</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/25/capital-city-crowdfund-for-first-bout/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we all know putting on a bout can be a very costly venture for any league especially when it comes to your first. So when Capital City announced last month that they would be hosting their first home bout they were a little nervous. Being a relatively small league (around 14 members), they know only too well how difficult it can be bringing in enough money to cover costs. So they have come up with a novel way to help raise the funds they need to put on their double header bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a first for Scottish roller derby, they are looking to crowdfund for their bout to help raise money ahead of the big day. The aim is to raise money to help cover the majority of costs that need to be paid ahead of the bout, which breakdown as:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Meadowbank Hall Hire: £930&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Public Liability Insurance: £200&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Emergency Medical Technicians: £100&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Track Rope and Tape: £100&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Programme Printing: £50&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Over on their crowdfunding page they allow you to pre order items such as bout tickets and merch (t-shirts/caps/tote bags) along with some more special one off items, such as picking a song on the bout day playlist, blowing the first whistle for the game, getting your very own Capital City Uniform and much more. They have even auctioned off their skate out song which was snapped up only minutes after their campaign went live.
&lt;p&gt;Purchasing items help items Capital City put on their bout, but it will also save you money. As bout tickets and merch are cheaper for those who pre-order than they will be on the day as a thank you to those helping them. You will have to be quick as you can only purchase items until the 1st of November when their crowdfunding campaign ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to pre-order your tickets or are feeling a little flush with cash and want to buy some other things then head over to their crowdfunding page at indiegogo via the link below to find out details of all the things on offer:
&lt;a href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/capital-city-roller-derby-s-double-header-29-11-14"&gt;https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/capital-city-roller-derby-s-double-header-29-11-14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out more about their crowdfunding campaign watch the video below from Capital city&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=66QK04yIVFU&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>crowdfunding</category><category>first bout</category><category>fundraising</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby edinburgh</category><category>merchandise</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>video</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/25/capital-city-crowdfund-for-first-bout/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 10:39:29 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>