<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about ddt2016)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/ddt2016.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Meanwhile in Europe: the Daga Denter Tournament (2016)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/17/meanwhile-in-europe-the-daga-denter-tournament-2016/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of conversation this weekend and today about a roller derby event in the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this has overshadowed another tournament held last weekend (15, 16 October): the second &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1605499439760237/"&gt;Daga Denter Tournament.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; This yearly event sees teams from Southern/Central Europe compete (under WFTDA) rules to determine a champion. The tournament is the "traditional" in derby terms single-elimination with consolation rounds structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[For those of you wanting to catch up on the scores, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/85830"&gt;Flat Track Stats has you covered&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/dagadenter.html"&gt;own timetable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; has the FTS links for bouts, plus links to the livestream archive (which will be updated to precise offsets for each bout by the end of the day).]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competing this year were: hosts Roller Derby Milano (the Harpies), Zurich City Roller Girls, Munich Rolling Rebels, Prague Roller Derby, Vienna Roller Derby, Roller Derby Lyon (the Grrriottes Girrrls), Barockcity Roller Derby and Roller Derby Torino (the Bloody Wheels). Outside of the main competition, there was also an exhibition bout between Tel Aviv Roller Derby and Athens Roller Derby - one of the first public appearances of the former league!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, due to delays and roster reductions resulting from injuries earlier in the second day, the 7th Place playoff was cancelled (as marked on our timetable). We thought this was an ideal opportunity to see what we can predict about the placements, using our usual statistical tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, predictively, we can use the new &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/08/ranking-the-world-and-other-fts-visualisations/3"&gt;SRD Rankings&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;for&lt;strong&gt; October 2016&lt;/strong&gt; to predict what was most likely to happen.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;Official result
&lt;span style="font-family:inherit;font-size:inherit;"&gt;(no 7th/8th playoff)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;Prediction:
SRD Rank (rank to left, rating to right)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Porto
Milano
Zurich
Vienna
Munich
Prague
Lyon/BarockcityTorino&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;268 &lt;strong&gt;Porto&lt;/strong&gt; .54403
309 &lt;strong&gt;Vienna&lt;/strong&gt; .52250
355 &lt;strong&gt;Zurich&lt;/strong&gt; .50977
461 &lt;strong&gt;Milano&lt;/strong&gt; .47029
504 &lt;strong&gt;Munich&lt;/strong&gt; .45568
558 &lt;strong&gt;Prague&lt;/strong&gt; .43985
574 &lt;strong&gt;Barockcity&lt;/strong&gt; .43424
809 &lt;strong&gt;Lyon&lt;/strong&gt; .37317
1049 &lt;strong&gt;Torino&lt;/strong&gt; .30649&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
So, as can be seen, we mostly predicted the tournament correctly, except for the strong placement of Milano. As the hosts, however, they will have benefitted from home team advantage, but we estimate this to be on the order of +0.01, not enough to bridge the rating gap. It's also true that Vienna performed unexpectedly poorly against Zurich, so it may be that they are in fact overranked by us.
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, however, we can also use our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/08/european-smackdown-the-statistics/"&gt;Bayesian inference toolkit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to analyse the tournament itself, isolated from past expectations. As always, this produces graphs showing the estimated range of team strengths (relative to the winner - in this case Porto), with height showing the likelihood of that result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9499" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/milano_vienna-dagadenter21.png" alt="milano_vienna-dagadenter2" width="2000" height="1100"&gt; Highlighting Milano, Vienna, relative to Porto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9498" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/milano_barock_torino_zurich_munich_vienna_lyon_prague-dagadenter21.png" alt="milano_barock_torino_zurich_munich_vienna_lyon_prague-dagadenter2" width="2000" height="1100"&gt; Fully coloured image of all strengths, relative to Porto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, as can be seen in the highlighted image, inference strongly supports the evidence that Vienna and Milano are actually of near identical strength (and that Zurich is &lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt; stronger than the pair). Taking into account home-team advantage, we're pretty confident that &lt;em&gt;Vienna&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;em&gt;overranked&lt;/em&gt; in our SRD Rankings at present (or had a really bad tournament). It's also true of Flat Track Stats, who recorded this as a&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85905/rankings"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; near upset&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;, expecting a narrow win and getting a comprehensive one. This also means that we predict that &lt;em&gt;Zurich&lt;/em&gt; would have attained &lt;em&gt;2nd&lt;/em&gt; place, if they'd been in the other half of the bracket and able to play the hosts. [This kind of &lt;em&gt;technical&lt;/em&gt; misranking is pretty common in single-elimination tournaments, which is why our blog position is that they should be avoided if possible].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inference also supports the reverse ranking of Barockcity and Lyon for 7th/8th place, supported mostly on their relative performances against Torino (the only team they both played). (Again, looking at Flat Track Stats, it appears that they also rated Barockcity higher than they performed - the rating of Barockcity has been revised down almost 20 points in FTS as a result of DDT2016, taking them from close to Lyon to noticeably below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We expect that in our November monthly update for the SRD Rankings, Barockcity and Vienna will drop in ranking.  We're also pretty happy to declare &lt;strong&gt;Lyon&lt;/strong&gt; as our &lt;strong&gt;7th place&lt;/strong&gt; finalist from the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would also like to congratulate the Harpies on a great tournament, from a remote viewers' perspective, with good streaming and regular updates; and Roller Derby Porto on a convincing win.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>ddt2016</category><category>european derby</category><category>statistics</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/17/meanwhile-in-europe-the-daga-denter-tournament-2016/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 14:06:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>