<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about deadly divas roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/deadly-divas-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Derby Review 2014: Non-bouting Leagues Roundup</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/09/derby-review-2014-non-bouting-leagues-roundup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While many of our Scottish leagues have held bouts in the past year, that doesn't make the newer, or relaunching, members of the Scottish Roller Derby community any less important. New leagues are an important part of the derby community, spreading skating to places that it hasn't been before. So, let's spend a little time catching up on what the non-bouting leagues have been doing in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013, Scotland continued to gain new leagues at an impressive pace. Leaving aside Voodoo Roller Dollies (who will be covered in a different article), women's derby leagues sprouted up in Dumfries and Galloway, and in Ayrshire. As is traditional, both the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Doonhame-Derby-Dolls/161632670699789"&gt;Doonhame Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ayrshirerollerderby"&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; were founded by women who wanted to skate, but found themselves too far from the existing leagues to join one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/doonhameandfriends1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3255" alt="Doonhameandfriends1" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/doonhameandfriends1.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="408"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Doonhame Derby Dolls, and friends from GRD and Mean City Roller Derby (Sourced from DDD Facebook page.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;The Dolls have been particularly successful, as skater Claire Warner noted "Our first meet saw 50+ in attendance and that number has grown since (with over 70 paid up members now on the books)!"
As with any new league, that success was supported by the wider derby community, as Claire told us "Our first night was led by Jodie from Glasgow Roller Derby (the woman who had inspired [founders] Debz and Grace) and Cat, a Windsor Rollergirl who luckily for us had just moved to the area, and who has been coaching us ever since. We have had other guest skaters joining in and sharing their skills too, Bruisedog from Mean City, and Turbolinz from GRD came for a visit, Tessington World of Adventures from Granite City Roller Girls and Hazzard from LRG have all dropped in to share their skills, knowledge and love of derby with us, the freshest of fresh meat."&lt;/p&gt;
Doonhame have been exceptionally organised in themselves, as well. In the last four months, they've managed to set up their league branding and management structure, gain sponsorshop, and also garner a huge amount of local media attention, including a spot on ITV Borders News. They've even managed to hold two RollerDisco fundraisers, the funds from which they are planning on using to subsidise costs for skaters on low incomes.
From all of that, you would not be wrong in guessing that their plans for 2014 are.. expansive.
"There is sooo much more planned for this year too (we have just been away on a Dolls development planning weekend)!", Said Claire, "Not only do we plan to gain affiliation, sponsorships/funding to improve access opportunities for other local women, we aim to hold our own local bootcamp to help us work towards passing minimum skills, put on a demonstration bout and hopefully be scrimmaging by the end of the year. In addition to all this we are also looking to take part in local charity fundraisers, spreading the Derby Love and helping those in need in our local community. we will also be running roller disco's on a regular basis throughout the year and hopefully we are about to start organising our own junior derby league!!"
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/ayrshire2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3257" alt="Ayrshire Roller Derby's earliest skaters." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/ayrshire2.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="411"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Ayrshire Roller Derby's earliest skaters. (Sourced from ARD Facebook page)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Dolls were inspired by one Glasgow Roller Derby skater, Ayrshire Roller Derby was inspired by another. As Lorna McIlvanney told us: "We wanted to start up an Ayrshire league but thought it would be difficult and never had the time to do it. Then at Rollerstop, we spotted Sylk from GRD and approached her to see if she might be able to help us set up. She said she would give advice and help with training as and when. [...] We have had massive amounts of help from Sylk, along with various Mean City skaters. We have been invited to scrim with other leagues (once we are mins passed) and have had messages of support and offers of help from many, which has been awesome."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARD have exciting plans for 2014, as well, as Lorna explained, "We are planning on getting to as many bouts as possible and getting involved where we can e.g. as NSO's etc. Our sights are set on passing mins shortly. We have fundraising plans and recruitment drives coming up. Then, scrims for experience and hopefully we'll be ready for our very first bout. We hope to one day base ourselves in the three Ayrshire (North, East, South) and maybe have our home teams structured that way. That's further down the line obviously, but it nice to have goals."
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;⁂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;As well as the brand-new leagues of 2013, leagues founded from 2012 and earlier still continued to develop over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
In Glasgow, the &lt;a href="http://deadlydivasrollerderby.webs.com/"&gt;Deadly Divas&lt;/a&gt; experienced a hiatus for various personal reasons. A spiritual-successor league, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/renfrewshirerockinrollers"&gt;Renfrewshire Rockin' Rollers&lt;/a&gt;, also appeared, with similar stated aims, but is also currently static. RRR Co-founder, Juggs Knock'her said "At the moment due to a lot going on in our personal lives things are on hold. We plan to have a fairly relaxed approach to skating, as well as training to WFTDA rules and Renegade. We are looking to recruit both women and men. Basically derby is about fun and we hope to keep it that way."
With the Deadly Divas also hinting that they might be waking up, it remains to be seen what happens in the space of second-leagues in Glasgow.
&lt;p&gt;Moving northwards, the resurgence of Perth's &lt;a href="http://www.faircityrollers.com/"&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; continued apace in the past year. League chair Pistol Panties was excited about their continued growth, "Initially, we were holding open sessions and just trying to build our numbers up, with the rec sessions, and we have achieved that. We had a big fresh meat intake in August, funded by a local charity geared towards increasing attendance at women's sports, which was a great success and we had a great response from everyone. That really was a stroke of genius, because it allowed us to invite all Scottish leagues along to an open scrimmage, which not only meant we got to see our friends, but it allowed the girls to get a real flavour of what Roller Derby is really about. We now have good numbers of regular attendees, and a team of (very nearly) mins passed skaters."
The league even managed to one-up most of the rest of Scotland, organising a guest coaching session from Steel City Rollergirls' Shrinking Violet in June. "We worked on basic skills, which was really useful even for the more experienced skaters, we all wanted longer with her, so we did a bit of off-skates afterwards too!".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City are now holding regular fresh meat sessions, with the last one being on the 27th of January, and regular training sessions are up to 3 hours a week. "We feel excited about this year," said Pistol, "and to be in a position to be thinking about getting back to competing in the near future. Basically, the only way is up!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/icrdlogo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-3250 " alt="Inverness City Roller Derby's new, striking, logo." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/icrdlogo.jpg?w=614" width="368" height="362"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Inverness City Roller Derby's new, striking, logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inverness' Nasty Nessies Roller Girls underwent a few changes over 2013, not least a change of name and branding. The newly styled "&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/InvernessCityRollerDerby"&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;" will retain the "Nasty Nessies" name and logo for their travel team. While ICRD has not yet bouted, their skaters continue to make appearances in exhibition and cherry popper bouts hosted by other leagues, and travel to open scrims in the rest of Scotland. They've also been working on an interesting outreach project, as Scarlett O'Horror told us: "We've just completed a collaboration with &lt;a href="http://www.fixers.org.uk/"&gt;Fixers&lt;/a&gt; - a group that helps promote community participation and challenge stereotypes. We made a film with them, featuring our own lovely skaters, which will be premièred in Inverness - very exciting!"
2014 looks like being the year for roller derby in Inverness, however, "We have a lot planned for this year! We will hopefully move into a new training venue this year, and have a few more mixed bouts lined up, including participating in a bout in April, which is really exciting for us. Some very lucky members are also off to Texas to watch the World Cup in December - picking up tips and training ideas, no doubt! And t-shirts. Always t-shirts."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, at the northernmost point of Scotland, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ShetlandRollerDerby"&gt;Shetland Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; has continued to hold both derby and open skate sessions throughout the year. Men and women are welcome, and the Open skates in particular have been popular.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;⁂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;As you can see, it's been an eventful year with the growing leagues of Scotland, and 2014 promises to be even more interesting!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>deadly divas roller derby</category><category>derby review 2014</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>renfrewshire rockin' rollers</category><category>shetland roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/09/derby-review-2014-non-bouting-leagues-roundup/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 15:22:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Monthly Diary Special: Deadly Divas in June: Juggs Knock'her</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/06/21/monthly-diary-special-deadly-divas-in-june-juggs-knockher/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We know how much everyone looks forward to the Monthly Diaries (or at least, I like to believe you do!), and felt bad about short changing our loyal viewers with only one entry last month. So, this month we have an extra bonus diary to make up for it, from Glasgow/Renfrewshire's newest league: &lt;a href="http://deadlydivasrollerderby.webs.com/"&gt;Deadly Divas Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;, here's Juggs Knock'er.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/06/dsc01592.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-2714" alt="Juggs lining up to jam at the Diva's practice session." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/06/dsc01592.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Juggs lining up to jam at the Diva's practice session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What first attracted you to Roller Derby?&lt;/strong&gt;
A few mates mentioned it about a year ago and thought nothing of it at the time.Then I saw that Deadly Divas Roller Derby were starting up and decided to give it a bash! Always been a bit of a tomboy and loved skating as a kid so thought why not! I haven't looked back since and made some amazing friends as well as discovering a lot about myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who are your derby heroes?&lt;/strong&gt;
That's a hard one! Bonnie D Stroir from the San Diego Derby dolls has to be mentioned as I watched her loads on youtube and still do! Also have to mention my derby wife AJ la Kaos here as she has been there encouraging me and the others from day one and she shows a great fighting spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby names are an important aspect of the sport, especially when you're starting out. How did you choose your name, and how does it reflect your personality on track?&lt;/strong&gt;
Initially I chose the name Ms Clara-Hell, as Clarabelle has been a nickname that has stuck with me for years with friends and family alike. However the more and more practices and other skating events I attended it became apparent that Juggs was more appropriate! Take from that what you will! As it is a bit of a more risque name, I feel that sums me up pretty well on track as I take a lot of risks... an attitude I have had for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was your biggest initial difficulty?&lt;/strong&gt;
I'd have to say the whole thing. I ice skated as a child and teenager and thought I would pick it up easily. The first training session was tough, I realised how unfit I was and how appaulling my skating skills were, I could not be upright for more than a couple of minutes and spent most of it on my arse! But I did go away that day having learned how to get up after a fall, falling safely and discovering that I am no quitter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lots of roller girls find it hard not to spread the word about their new sport. How have you been spreading the word?&lt;/strong&gt;
Basically every chance I have had I'm speaking about derby practice and skating! People are always asking me what derby entails and I love telling them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the most important thing you’ve learnt/ done this month?&lt;/strong&gt;
Training towards these new minimum skills. A lot of hard work to do, and a lot of frustration that comes with it! Also been doing some coaching with the fresh meat which has helped me learn a lot, and made me reflect on my own basic skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What were the most difficult and the best things?&lt;/strong&gt;
The most difficult has been dealing with my own skating skills and crossovers especially! The best things have to be skating with other people and getting psyched up about derby! I;ve been fortunate enough to be welcomed to the New Town Roller Girls practices where I've learned many skills and made some amazing friends. To be honest, although my derby career is still in the early stages, I've loved every moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's new with the Deadly Divas this month?&lt;/strong&gt;
We have been working on the new mins, recruiting, and working on strategy.... watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>ddrd</category><category>ddrg</category><category>deadly divas roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>monthly diary</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/06/21/monthly-diary-special-deadly-divas-in-june-juggs-knockher/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 21:04:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Deadly Divas Recruiting now!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/22/deadly-divas-recruiting-now/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/photo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2367" alt="photo" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/photo.jpg" width="360" height="379"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Good news for prospective skaters in the Glasgow and East Renfrewshire area, as Glasgow's second Roller Derby league, the Deadly Divas, have started actively recruiting again. We featured the Divas in our end of year round up, along with other newer Scottish leagues, so you can read about them &lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/31/scotlands-newest-leagues-a-year-in-derby/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;Those interested should contact them on their &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/deadlydivasrollerderby"&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt; page, or via &lt;a href="mailto:DeadlyDivasRD@gmail.com"&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>ddrd</category><category>deadly divas roller derby</category><category>fresh meat</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/22/deadly-divas-recruiting-now/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 12:43:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Scotland's Newest Leagues: A Year in Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/31/scotlands-newest-leagues-a-year-in-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the bigger leagues have had their 2012 filled with bouting, the rapid growth of derby in Scotland means that there are many other leagues who have been spending the past year growing and moving towards bout readiness. With Inverness' Nasty Nessies covered in a special edition of their Monthly Diary to come, we thought that &lt;a href="http://newtownrollergirls.wordpress.com/"&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/31/scotlands-newest-leagues-a-year-in-derby/deadlydivasrollerderby.webs.com"&gt;Deadly Divas Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.shetlandrollerderby.com/"&gt;Shetland Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://lothianderbydolls.com/"&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; all deserved the time to tell us how they'd been doing over the past 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Town, based in Livingston, and the Derby Dolls, based in Edinburgh and the Lothians, are near contemporaries, and both have been growing and developing over the past year. Both leagues have spent the past year growing and developing their skills towards passing mins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, after a slow start to the year, everything started coming together for New Town Roller Girls in the last 6 months, their numbers swelling to 18 by the end of this year, with 4 skaters, and referee The Real Scrim Shady, already mins-passed. The league's founder, Hazzard, was keen to credit "Reff Goldblum of FVRG," as "the man that helped us pass our mins and has been a great help to us!", with others being equally positive about the recent attendance by Auld Reekie's Circuit Breaker, and the many other skaters from other leagues who have visited them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ladies in black and electric blue also held their first fundraiser in November, the event also serving as the official unveiling of their newly printed boutfits. If Hazzard was upbeat about roller derby and their place in the community,  "I thought [derby] was amazing from when I first found out about it and all that's really changed is that I've come to know the sport better and love the camaraderie of the community and the sheer fun of being involved!", The Real Scrim Shady was even more positive, stating "First time I went along, it was a bunch of people who didn't even know each other's names, nervously skating round the hall following the instructions of Hazzard and Reff Goldblum. It was fun for sure, but since then everyone knows each other, people push each other to do better and give pointers where needed, there's a noticeable anticipation in the run-up to each session. People look forward to it and, as far as I can see, great progress has been made. It feels like a team now instead of just a bunch of friendly strangers."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/31/scotlands-newest-leagues-a-year-in-derby/tumblr_mde5ngyydu1rfp2kio3_1280/" rel="attachment wp-att-2025"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2025" alt="New Town Roller Girls at their Fundraiser this year." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/tumblr_mde5ngyydu1rfp2kio3_1280.jpg" width="614" height="408"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; New Town Roller Girls at their Fundraiser this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Town are very much looking forward to having enough team members mins-passed to bout, although the team is divided on who their first opponents should be, with skater Bump-Her Stick-Her feeling that "Fierce Valley seem to be our closest 'buddies' but bouting against them would be terrifying as they are amazing", with Hazzard taking the more conservative choice of close buddies "Deadly Divas Roller Derby could well be our first bout partners but you do never know..."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lothian Derby Dolls have advanced slightly faster than their peers in attaining a full roster of mins-passed skaters, aided by their acquiring of experienced derby coach Cain Unstable. Duke Box, speaking to us for the league, mentioned both Cain, and offered "thanks to Lead Jammer Magazine, Inkabilly and Into The Nitemare [derby store]" for their donations and sponsorship. The league also held a successful Halloween themed roller-disco, which had good attendance and promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duke Box was also clear that the Derby Dolls, while branding themselves "a team for the Lothians" with "skaters from all across the Lothian area; Mid, West, East and Edinburgh" have been getting on well with the well-established Auld Reekie in the capital itself. "Having ARRG in Edinburgh has allowed us opportunities both to watch them play and support them" she said, adding that the Derby Dolls "have also had some of our skaters join them in scrimmaging this year and hope to have the chance to more in the future, as we wish for all leagues close to us."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Derby Dolls are now capable of fielding a full roster of skaters, they are cagey about their first bout; an initially prematurely announced inaugural fixture has since been delayed or rescheduled. Whenever their initial bout is held, LDD will be attending the Into The Nitemare store-sponsored 'Battle of Britain' tournament in November. As one of the two unseeded competitors, it will be interesting to see how they fare, and a good learning experience for them in the process (even experienced teams like Glasgow Roller Derby and Auld Reekie find extended tournaments to be an exhausting endeavour).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/31/scotlands-newest-leagues-a-year-in-derby/459658_316736258439825_267676052_o/" rel="attachment wp-att-2039"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2039" alt="A Christmas-themed group photo from the Lothian Derby Dolls 2013 calendar." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/459658_316736258439825_267676052_o.jpg" width="614" height="417"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A Christmas-themed group photo from the Lothian Derby Dolls 2013 calendar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Deadly Divas and Shetland Roller Derby, meanwhile, have both only been recruiting since partway through the year, Shetland having been actively growing since July, and the Divas since September! At this early stage in their existence, a lot of the focus has been on gaining numbers and experience. Shetland's Shock Blocker put a lot of effort into outreach via local press and radio appearances, also providing taster sessions for those unsure to experience the meaning of derby. The Divas leveraged some less conventional internet media, including Gumtree and eBay, but also the Glasgow press. In the end, word-of-mouth, both online via their Facebook and Web pages, and offline via the inability of new roller girls to speak about anything else, may have been their most significant factors, taking them, in the words of founder AJ La Kaos, from "only 3 of us then 2 left; As it stands now in less than 3 months we have around 20 members which is phenomenal!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both have also been welcomed by the derby community, the Divas getting regular support from Glasgow's men's derby team Mean City Roller Derby, as well as the Pan-Scotland Jakey Bites, and turning up to New Town Roller Girls' open practices on Sunday afternoons; Shetland via their closest neighbours Nasty Nessies, who made a flying visit, following on from a visit from the Forth Valley's Bairn City Rollers earlier in the year. For the Divas, AJ La Kaos noted that "Being the second league in Glasgow has brought up a few complications especially with recruiting and sourcing a venue. We try very hard not to step on GRD's toes in both respects with branding ourselves as a south side team", while the advantage of being in the middle of things allows them to "go to as many bouts as possible, its a great way to see the sport in its full glory. It also keeps us motivated seeing what we're all working towards." The Divas have the advantage of ex-GRD skater Viper as their coach, who also serves as their "biggest inspiration in the derby world" according to La Kaos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/31/scotlands-newest-leagues-a-year-in-derby/704125_411805645558435_407723866_o/" rel="attachment wp-att-2042"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2042" alt="The Deadly Divas even managed to get themselves into the papers!" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/704125_411805645558435_407723866_o.jpg" width="614" height="421"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Deadly Divas even managed to get themselves into the papers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being the most remote roller derby league in the UK causes the opposite problem for Shetland Roller Derby,  preventing easy access to live derby hosted on the mainland, and to physical skate stores. Shock Blocker said that the team "owes a special place in our hearts to Marshall Lawless (of 5th Blocker Skates [and Glasgow Roller Derby]) for answering all of our questions, and managing to get stuff up to Shetland at a reasonable price".
The remoteness of Shetland also has another effect on the league, in terms of its makeup. While all roller derby leagues have a mix of ages present, Shetland's overall deficit of University-age individuals is reflected in the more mature demographic of the league, as well. This has not limited their advancement, Shock Blocker commenting that "Our skaters have really grown as a team, and we've been supporting each other learning together. It's been amazing to watch people that have never skated get better and better, and we've all certainly learned a lot."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2012 has been a year of great expansion for Scottish Roller Derby, with the four teams above, and Inverness' Nasty Nessies, all making strides towards doubling the number of bouting leagues in the country. By the end of 2013, the community will only be enriched further as each league passes their mins and becomes bout-ready. We asked each of the league representatives what their aims for 2013 were, and they kindly responded with many words. Rather than take them out of context, we present them here unedited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadly Divas Roller Derby (AJ La Kaos):
&lt;em&gt;2013 will hopefully be a huge year for us as a team, we're working hard towards getting everyone mins passed and having our first proper bout! For me personally, I'm looking forward to that first day on track watching my new family kick some ass: win or lose it won't matter as we're all there for each other and that's all that really matters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shetland Roller Derby (Shock Blocker):
&lt;em&gt;2013 will be our year of getting our team mins passed, trying to attract more skaters, and educating the public a bit more about the sport. We are delighted to receive any skaters who'd like to come up to Shetland, and show them around. If we can gather enough funding, maybe plan a trip to the mainland.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Personally, I'd like to improve my skating skills, my understanding of the rules, and hopefully see more bouts in person.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the meantime, we at Shetland Roller Derby would like to wish all the Scottish teams a big thank you, Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year! xx&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Town Roller Derby:
(Hazzard)
&lt;em&gt;In the next year we hope to have enough skaters mins passed and experienced to start having some closed door bouts atleast! Then on to the big scary world of open bouts and trying to find somewhere to hold them at home too!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The Real Scrim Shady)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There's still much work to be done, but over the next wee while I'm interested in helping NTRG improve their skating and developing the fitness levels necessary for a bout. I've been skating for years and I like helping other people avoid some mistakes that I made in the process of learning to be comfortable on skates. I want to see all NTRG members be comfortable enough on skates that they can be thinking about the bout rather than worrying about staying on their feet. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I've seen progress in the short time I've been involved, for example 4 skaters passing mins. But I'd like to see training become a bit more intense. Circuit Breaker is coming back to help us with exactly that and I'll try to help Hazzard maintain the level of training and push it harder when the time’s right. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em id="__mceDel"&gt;&lt;em id="__mceDel"&gt;&lt;em id="__mceDel"&gt;&lt;em id="__mceDel"&gt;&lt;em id="__mceDel"&gt;&lt;em&gt;As for what I see for myself within the next year, I'm learning about the game pretty quickly right now and I'm looking to get a set of quads (I’m a fruitbooter btw). I aim to gain enough knowledge and understanding of bouts to move on from the role I've already had as NSO. The eventual goal is to become a ref but I don't know just now how long I can expect that to take.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls (Duke Box):
&lt;em&gt;Well 2013 so far does have us taking part in The Battle of Britain; a tournament that is being organised by Into The Nitemare. We also have a couple of things that are being organised bouting wise and will be announced next year when finalised and confirmed. Just a lot more hard work in training and some fun events in store for us also. It is definitely the year the Dolls will make a great one for all our skaters and those who supports us. So a big thanks to all who have got us to the end of 2012 it has been a great start.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Thanks to: Lothian Derby Dolls' Duke Box; New Town Roller Girls' Hazzard, Millie Manslaughter, Bump-her Stick-her and The Real Scrim Shady; Shetland Roller Derby's Shock Blocker; and Deadly Divas Roller Derby's AJ La Kaos for their contributions to this report.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ddrd</category><category>deadly divas roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>ldd</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>ntrg</category><category>shetland roller derby</category><category>srd</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/31/scotlands-newest-leagues-a-year-in-derby/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 17:21:31 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>