<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about derby stance)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/derby-stance.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:41:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Derby Stance 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/derbystance-2019/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the past three years, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com"&gt;Rule 56&lt;/a&gt; have been helping to drive and develop coaching in Roller Derby; both in terms of coaching itself, and also resources for developing those coaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt='The Derby Stance 2019 logo: 3 brown solid circles of increasing darkness overlapping left-to-right, with blue whistle inside the last. Text "Derby Stance Online Coaching Summit Nov 22-24 2019".' src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/DerbyStanceEvent.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very visible part of this has been their &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/derby-stance"&gt;Derby Stance&lt;/a&gt; branded coaching community events; starting with a physical &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/03/uks-first-coaching-summit-derby-stance/"&gt;Coaching Summit&lt;/a&gt; back in &lt;em&gt;2016&lt;/em&gt;, and developing into a more extensive, and entirely virtual event in 2018 (2017 tested the concept with a series of individual webinars across the year). Holding the event online, with dedicated conference hosting services, was a response to the global nature of Roller Derby, and the global need for coaching resources and community; having to travel half-way across the world for a conference is not only expensive, but also wasteful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2018 Derby Stance was extremely successful, with attendees describing it with terms like "mind-blowing" and "by far the most helpful coaching training I’ve received in five years"!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Derby Stance Online Coaching Summit is returning for 2019, and Rule 56 have continued to build on and improve on what has been before. As the name suggests, this is, once more, a virtual-only event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with 2018's edition, individual "webinars" which make up the entire 3 day event, are separately bookable; you can buy tickets for just the sessions you're interested in. (If you're planning on attending a lot of the event, though, there's also whole-weekend tickets available, for a discount.).
In a change from last year, these are organised into two types: &lt;em&gt;"Seminars"&lt;/em&gt; (60 minute presentations, with time for questions) and &lt;em&gt;"Workshops"&lt;/em&gt; (90 minute interactive sessions led by the session leader; these are limited to &lt;em&gt;20&lt;/em&gt; attendees each).
(Regular attendees of EROC, the European Roller derby Organisational Conference, will recognise this division from there, where it is pretty effective at supporting different kinds of interaction.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that's not all: just like a physical conference, the 2019 Derby Stance will have fringe and break-out events, organised as ad-hoc Facebook Live mini-streams. (Rule56 has already been trialing this with a series of "5 minutes with ..." events over the past year, and they work very well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike most physical conferences, a benefit of the virtual nature is that all Seminars (but not Workshops) will be available after the fact as recordings if you miss them; and simultaneous automated real-time transcriptions will be available during each session, including translated into a range of languages, to aid inclusion and understanding. (For those who can't attend at all, "watch-later" tickets will also be available to access all the content purely post-hoc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="3x4 Checkerboard of portraits (with names) of all of the Derby Stance 2019 speakers and workshop leaders, with Rule56 logo in the middle." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/Derbystance2019.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Photo credits: Nadia Kean and Jennifer B Gaskins (by Zakas Photography); Devoida Mercy (by Louise O'Rourke Photography); Furrocious (by No limit Lien); Dr. Astrid Coxon (by Martin Quadling); Squirrel Power (by Robin Dodd / Purple Turtle Photography); Miss Tea Maven (by David Dyte); Kaio-kensi (by Owen Clayton); all other photos uncredited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any Conference or Summit lives and dies by its roster of speakers, and this year's Derby Stance has a very exciting line-up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smarty Pants (Strong Athletic)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is your Coaching actually working? (Workshop)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Squirrel Power (Monterey Bay Derby Dames)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coaching Slower Learners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rosie Peacock (New Wheeled Order, Power of Scotland)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategic Coaching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Devoida Mercy (Philly Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bridging the Perception Gap about Coaching between Adults and Juniors (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Furrrocious (Amsterdam Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to structure feedback, and adjust to different training styles (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structuring and building your training session (Workshop)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michelle Welton and Gie ‘uppercase’ Carr (Rose City Rollers)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coaching mixed-level practices in Adult and Junior programs (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kaio-kensi (Montreal Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organic Drill Design - replicating real game scenarios in drills. (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building a healthier brain safety culture (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr. Astrid Coxon (Suffolk Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coaching the 'un-coachable' (Workshop)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jennifer B Gaskins (New Jax City Rollers)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to coach when you don't have a coach (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rita Giddens (Fort Myers Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coaching for a Positive Culture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miss Tea Maven (Gotham Girls Roller Derby)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to design optimal training plans for your Jammers. (Seminar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Processes and Steps to designing best Practice, including footage analysis. (Workshop)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, Rule 56 will be chairing &lt;em&gt;"Round Table"&lt;/em&gt; discussion sessions throughout the event, with topics decided dynamically as the Summit progresses; and the entire event will be introduced with a &lt;strong&gt;WFTDA Keynote Presentation&lt;/strong&gt; the day before the Summit itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets for both individual sessions, and the whole event, are &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/derbystancetickets"&gt;on sale now&lt;/a&gt; . Advance sales for "watch later" tickets for Seminars are cheaper than they will be post-event; and remember that there are only 20 spots for each Workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby Stance Online Coaching Summit 2019 will run from &lt;strong&gt;22 November 2019 to 24 November 2019&lt;/strong&gt; (with the keynote on the 21st).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Derby Stance would like to thank: WFTDA, Roller Dirty Soaps and Steaks Contact Wear for committing to sponsor this event, and help develop coaching resources.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>coaching</category><category>derby stance</category><category>rule 56</category><category>webinar</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/derbystance-2019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Stance 2018: Rule56's Coaching Summit returns, now International!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/31/derby-stance-2018-rule56s-coaching-summit-returns-now-international/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, we &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/03/uks-first-coaching-summit-derby-stance/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reported&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the first Derby Stance event: the UK's first ever "Coaching Summit", organised by North of England based coaching team Rule 56. Over a weekend of sessions from speakers across the UK (and one from the USA), the Roller Derby coaching community didn't just learn from each other, but also built some strong bridges and enthusiasm for pushing Coaching further in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the year and a bit since that big launch, Rule 56 have been continuing to &lt;a href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/happenings/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;develop coaching resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. With the aid of teleconferencing technology, they successfully provided a very effective short series of coaching webinars with Strong Athletic's Smarty Pants (as we &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/01/rule-56-now-coming-online-on-monday-6th/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reported&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/16/uk-coaching-rule-56-webinars-and-more/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;on&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; too), with attendees from across Europe and the Americas. They've also been running physical bootcamp sessions for skaters, like the upcoming "bite-sized" bootcamp on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1751163414965701/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working in Walls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on August 11th...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, whilst there was a second &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1979086938976164/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby Stance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; summit in February (taking advantage of the Roller Derby World Cup the weekend before to bring all those international skaters to one place), organising truly large-scale international coaching events has always been difficult, especially with our grass-roots amateur sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now! This winter, Rule56 are bringing together all the things they've learnt to make the &lt;em&gt;third&lt;/em&gt; Derby Stance a simultaneously larger, more international... and more &lt;em&gt;accessible&lt;/em&gt; event - by moving it entirely online!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-27125 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/derbystance2018.png" alt="derbystance2018" width="828" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby Stance Online&lt;/strong&gt; will be a 4 day virtual event, running from &lt;strong&gt;29 November&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;2 December&lt;/strong&gt; this year. Just like a physical event, there will be many different sessions to sign up with, grouped into 5 themes:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Just Start Coaching [5 sessions]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Strategic Coaching [4 sessions]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Mental Performance [5 sessions]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Game Day [3 sessions]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Juniors [3 sessions]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
as well as introductory and closing sessions, and a special session led by WFTDA's Beat-her Bones, representing WFTDA Education.
&lt;p&gt;Each of the 23 sessions will be available as a separate webinar, and can be signed up for (and paid for) independently of any others; of course, you can also sign up for the entire summit, as if it were a "physical" meeting as well, if you want. The flexibility of being able to pick and choose just the sessions you want, however, is a big advantage of the online-only format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with other webinars, the entire session will also be available to rewatch after the fact - so, even if your timezone makes it hard to attend the session live (or if you want to review a session later), you can still access all that coaching expertise, at your own convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other advantage of the online-only format is that it's immensely easier to pull together expert speakers and session leaders from across the entire globe. Rule 56 has managed to collect 14 of the best coaches in Roller Derby, and beyond, to contribute sessions to this event:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-27123 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/rule56__map-e1532701421288.png" alt="RULE56__map" width="1920" height="850"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smarty Pants&lt;/strong&gt; (Strong Athletic), &lt;strong&gt;Vivien Leigh-thal&lt;/strong&gt; (Rainy City Roller Derby), &lt;strong&gt;Booty Quake&lt;/strong&gt; (Roller Derby Athletics), &lt;strong&gt;Maurine Filip&lt;/strong&gt; (Stockholm Roller Derby), &lt;strong&gt;Rosie Peacock&lt;/strong&gt; (Glasgow Men's Roller Derby, Team Scotland Coach 2018), &lt;strong&gt;Devoida Mercy&lt;/strong&gt; (Philly Roller Derby), &lt;strong&gt;Maha El Nasser&lt;/strong&gt; (Rule 56), &lt;strong&gt;Papa Whisky&lt;/strong&gt; (Boulder County Bombers), &lt;strong&gt;Jess Paternostro&lt;/strong&gt; (Team Canada Roller Derby), &lt;strong&gt;Furrrocious&lt;/strong&gt; (Amsterdam Roller Derby)
&lt;strong&gt;Ballistic Whistle&lt;/strong&gt; (Southern Discomfort), &lt;strong&gt;Louise Capicotto&lt;/strong&gt; (Sport Psychology Consultant), &lt;strong&gt;Luludemon&lt;/strong&gt; (Terminal City Rollergirls), and &lt;strong&gt;Treblemaker 909&lt;/strong&gt; (Central City Roller Derby) are each contributing at least one session to the schedule (and some up to three).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can reserve tickets - for individual webinars, or the whole event - (and learn more about the summit) at the official website here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/derby-stance-online"&gt;http://www.rulefiftysix.com/derby-stance-online &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;from&lt;strong&gt; August 1st.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coaching</category><category>derby stance</category><category>international</category><category>rule56</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/31/derby-stance-2018-rule56s-coaching-summit-returns-now-international/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 08:32:02 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>