<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about derby sevens)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/derby-sevens.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:41:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Dundee Sevens Extravaganza!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/27/dundee-sevens-extravaganza/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;October 21st&lt;/strong&gt;, Dundee Roller Girls will be showcasing all the charisma, uniqueness, nerve and talent roller derby has to offer by hosting their open to all: &lt;strong&gt;Sevens Extravaganza&lt;/strong&gt;!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-24432" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/save-the-date.png" alt="Save The Date" width="3100" height="1430"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Seven teams consisting of only seven skaters will battle against each other in 21 minute games of high intensity roller derby! All in the hopes of being crowned the most sickening team of all!!
&lt;p&gt;This is the first time that DRG are bringing the thrills of a sevens tournament to Dundee, with no timeouts, no official reviews and only 7 skaters per team! What more could you want from a day of derby? How about 7 awesome &lt;strong&gt;RuPaul's Drag Race&lt;/strong&gt; inspired team names with their very own catchphrases???
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Laganja Estranja&lt;/em&gt; – &lt;strong&gt;YES GAWD!
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Adore Delano&lt;/em&gt; –&lt;strong&gt; PARTY!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Team Shangela&lt;/em&gt; – &lt;strong&gt;HALLELOU!
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Alaska&lt;/em&gt; -&lt;strong&gt; HIIEEEEEE!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Bianca Del Rio&lt;/em&gt; –&lt;strong&gt; Not Today Satan
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Bob the Drag Queen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; – Purse Furst
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Jinkx Monsoon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; – Water off a Ducks Back&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-24507" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/filal-7.png" alt="Dundee Logos for Sevens" width="1536" height="1236"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DRG still have team applications open so don’t miss out! Apply here with your team of seven: &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdEzC2MrWUOW7SsJge19qlwrMAsFYKzOEuvuFXFflaLUzoFFw/viewform" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Application for Full Seven&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not quite got a full team of seven? Don't worry Dundee have thought of that as well and are now accepting single skater applicants to skate in a mixed side: &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdwK9wmfSPJ5DJCjT8a8hQqBhGlZYDLB9-rP-fTRLbPv-pZPQ/viewform?usp=sf_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Application for Single Skaters
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you think Dundee have left out the most on-the-nose team name you could think of: WELL THINK AGAIN! Team RuPaul has been left for the most important group of the whole day.... The Officials!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-24515 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/21744549_10155556403215821_1030918533_n.jpg?w=250" alt="Officials are the best aren't they??" width="250" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spectator tickets will also be available for your friends and family to come to this full day event at &lt;strong&gt;Dundee International Sports Complex (D.I.S.C)&lt;/strong&gt; on Mains Loan. There will be a chance to buy Dundee's Merch (including the limited edition coveted Tie Dye shirts!!), a classic bake sale for all your daily cake consumption needs as well as a handful of local business to be announced as vendors, across &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/dundeerollergirls/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;DRG's Social Media&lt;/a&gt; in the upcoming weeks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you come and stay? Or will you just Sashay Away?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;Doors are open at &lt;strong&gt;0930&lt;/strong&gt; with first whistle at &lt;strong&gt;10am&lt;/strong&gt;!!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#ff0000;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;Tickets on the door: &lt;strong&gt;£6
&lt;/strong&gt;Check out the event page for more details: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/119203058730604/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>derby sevens</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/27/dundee-sevens-extravaganza/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 11:30:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City Roller Derby update: British Champs T3 and beyond</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/22/granite-city-roller-derby-update-british-champs-t3-and-beyond/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've been a little remiss with our &lt;a href="https://www.britishchamps.com"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;British Champs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Northern Divisions updates since the middle of the season, so we're back a with a special catchup with our teams from each Tier, continuing with Tier 3's Granite City Roller Derby!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-22709" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/gcrd.png?w=300" alt="GCRD" width="300" height="300"&gt; GCRD!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City's Northern Fights had an exceptional 2016 in Champs, entering Tier 3 in 2017 by promotion after topping the table. They've continued their excellent Champs performance in Tier 3 - they currently top the table here as well, unbeaten, with extremely strong victories in 3 of 4 of their games so far. (The only close game was their first, against Halifax's Bruising Banditas.)
The rest of the Tier 3 Champs table is more even at the moment with, tentatively, Auld Reekie's Reserves and the newly-rebranded North Wales Roller Derby in the most likely places to take the second top spot. We'll know more after the second-last fixtures of the Tier, today, hosted by North Wales, with the final bouts happening August in Edinburgh as Auld Reekie host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Northern Fights co-Captain, Berocca Bama had the following to say: "2017 Tier 3 North has been a very exciting and challenging time for the Northern Fights of GCRD. As a result of hard training and solid dedication of the players and league, we have really grown and bonded as a team since Tier 4 in 2016 which meant we felt strong to compete in Tier 3 North 2017 and the results so far are far beyond our wildest dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have had so many enjoyable games, the most thrilling of which was against ARRG B. The team that ended our winning streak in 2016, we knew ARRG were going to be really tough opponents. We are sure anyone who was there to see this Champs game would agree it was a nail biter to the end!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking forward to playing the Furness Firecrackers in the final Champs game in August; we know they'll bring it! It's a very important game for us, as a victory here should see us through to play-offs, if our maths is right..."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City are also hosting events outside of Champs, starting with their very own tournament in a weeks time, the &lt;strong&gt;29th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;July&lt;/strong&gt;! &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Sevens&lt;/strong&gt; will be the most heptamerous of Sevens tournaments, with seven co-ed/OTA teams competing, each with the traditional seven skaters, in 21 minute games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And after Champs Tier 3 North comes to an end in August (except for the Tier 3 promotion playoffs, 16/17 September), the Northern Fights will be hosting 2 games of their own, up in Aberdeen. These will also be great opportunities to see GCRD's B team, the Fight Hawks, as both events are double headers!
We don't have dates for these events yet, but of course we will feature them as soon as we have more information...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;British Champs Tier 3 N Fixture (&lt;strong&gt;22 July Today&lt;/strong&gt;!): &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/863580253744360/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/863580253744360/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;British Champs Tier 3 N Final Fixture (&lt;strong&gt;12 Aug&lt;/strong&gt;, Edinburgh): &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/479889502352774/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/479889502352774/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City Roller Derby host Scottish Sevens (&lt;strong&gt;29 July&lt;/strong&gt;): &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1468759543169257/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1468759543169257/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>british champs</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>derby sevens</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>northern fights</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/22/granite-city-roller-derby-update-british-champs-t3-and-beyond/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 07:39:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow's Magnificent 7s ride out!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/13/glasgows-magnificent-7s-ride-out/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned in our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/21/upcoming-bouts-special-jan-2017-edition/"&gt;January round-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the only announced bouts in Scotland in January are in the last two weeks of the month. In fact, by far the larger event is the closer, as the &lt;strong&gt;21st&lt;/strong&gt; sees Glasgow Roller Derby bringing &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1209413072459985/"&gt;Derby Se7ens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to Scotland for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Sur5al, which Glasgow have also hosted previously, Se7ens is a condensed Derby format, inspired by Rugby Sevens which is a very successful variant of the Union game - the first Sevens tournament was held by Essex Men's Roller Derby, and is now an annual event. The benefit, of course, is that you can get more teams to compete in less time, and hence possibly have a higher density of fun. It's also an ideal way for skaters to ease themselves back onto track, before the competitive season really gets going...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experimenting with the Derby Se7ens format to add even more 7s, the Magnificent 7s event sees 7 teams of 7 skaters each play 7 minutes of derby against each other (for a total of 21 bouts, and 147 minutes) to determine the victor*.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To celebrate this inaugural issue of what might become an annual event, GRD have also worked with well-known Scottish Derby photographer, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://boutday.com/"&gt;Dave McAleavy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;to produce this themed poster:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13843 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/7s-2.jpg" alt="7s-2" width="400" height="560"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is often the case with these intense formats, the event has drawn in a wide representation of skaters, with the following teams submitted:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How The West Was Won&lt;/strong&gt; [in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;Black&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] - Team Scotland Roller Derby's entry, an epic mixture of ARRG and GRD skaters from the National Team's Training Squad.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soy Division&lt;/strong&gt; [in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#ffffff;background-color:#999999;"&gt;White&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] - Skaters from the Soy Division vegan exhibition team, including GRD and New Town.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hateful 7&lt;/strong&gt; [in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;Green&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] - a mix of Fierce Valley, Bairn City, and Auld Reekie skaters, discounted from Tarantino's efforts.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/strong&gt; [in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#ff6600;"&gt;Orange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] - Granite City Brawlers' representation, the northernmost team all the way from Aberdeen.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Seven Deadly Spins&lt;/strong&gt; [in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;Blue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] - a mix of mysterious skaters operating under pseudonyms. We're not sure which one is Wrath, but we don't really want to find out!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean City&lt;/strong&gt; [in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;Red&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] - Mean City Roller Derby's finest skate out to serve justice.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GMRD&lt;/strong&gt; [in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800080;"&gt;Purple&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] - Glasgow Men's Roller Derby... or  in this context, Gringos from Mexican Ranch, Dudes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;11am&lt;/strong&gt; with the first game set to begin at 11.30am, and are hosted, as always, at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662153,-4.2519289,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8662153!4d-4.2497349"&gt;ARC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at Glasgow Caledonian University.
Tickets are &lt;strong&gt;£8&lt;/strong&gt; in advance (from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/event-tickets/the-magnificent-7s-1"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and &lt;strong&gt;£10&lt;/strong&gt; on the door, which is still less than 50p a bout...
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*The conventional Derby Sevens, as run by Essex Mens, has 21 minute games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>derby sevens</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/13/glasgows-magnificent-7s-ride-out/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 09:55:15 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>