<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about derby review 2014)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/derby-review-2014.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Bairn City Rollers - A Roundup of 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/01/25/bairn-city-rollers-a-roundup-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>ihorror67</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4532 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/295797_379246515524520_1556620922_n.jpg?w=300" alt="295797_379246515524520_1556620922_n" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Scottish Roller Derby Blog caught up with Archibald Wreck, Skelpies Vice, and Entropy who will captain the Central Belters to discuss the 2014 season with the Bairn City Rollers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 marked the second year of Bairn City Rollers' existence. How did it go?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AW:&lt;/strong&gt; “It’s been a year of real growth and setting the ground works for an exciting near future. On the Belters' side they have steadily grew in numbers to reach the point where everyone now has to compete for a place and a really solid team is starting to be moulded. The Skelpies have cemented a very credible position in the men’s European rankings and Judder, iHorror, Dreads, rED Baron, Scrim Shady and Dead Hardy all played for their country at the Men’s World Cup in March.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Ent:&lt;/strong&gt; “2014 was a busy year for us. The Belters have had great influx of skaters this year! This means we’ve had the opportunity to develop as a team and really get to know each other. We’ve also had some great results this year against some really tough opponents and we placed well in a Sur5al tournament. I agree, Archie! The Skelpies have slowly but surely climbed their way up the rankings this last year!"
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any particular highlights?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ent:&lt;/strong&gt; “The first win for the Skelpies in January was a great start to the year. The Belters coming close to a second win against The Flaming Noras was a great achievement (especially after the bus journey from hell!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;The Sur5al in Stirling was a particular highlight for me. We were able to win a few jams and we held our own against some really strong teams.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;a name="wm:mid.1417784839814:a38600794519702598"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a name="webMessengerRecentMessages"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; AW&lt;/strong&gt;: “Like Entropy just mentioned, the Skelpies picking up their first win in January against friendly-rivals Mean City Roller Derby was an early highlight. Equally impressive was the showing against Tyne &amp;amp; Fear’s The Inglorious B*Stars in June, which saw a narrow loss against a substantially higher ranked team. They also took part in a Sur5val tournament in Oldham, hosted by the Knight of Oldham. I feel we were largely unknown but managed to place really well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;Over on the Belters side there was an agonisingly close defeat to The Flaming Nora’s in Barrow earlier in the year. I also agree with Entropy on this one, The five Belters who competed in a Sur5al tournament in Stirling was a highlight for me. The tournament saw them turn more than a few heads with several victories including a win over a Glasgow B-side.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bairn City hosted their annual co-ed bout again the “Capital Chums”, a team made up of skaters from ARRG and Capital City. How did you feel it went?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AW&lt;/strong&gt;: “That was a fantastic day for everyone involved in the league, whether playing in the game or not. To have achieved victory against a team which included several male and female international players was a great achievement, especially with several “cherry poppers” in the Belter Skelpers making their debut that day. We did not forget how great Capital Chums were, however, and voted them our favourite opponents of 2014 at our end of year awards ceremony in November.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;a name="webMessengerRecentMessages1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a name="wm:mid.1417803087892:46accc4a3171accc27"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Ent:&lt;/strong&gt; “ You're right Archie, that game was a great day for the league. It highlights just how much we have grown in our two years! The Capital Chums were great opponents and the game was a lot of fun for everyone involved. The fact that the game was so close, it came right down to the last jam, just shows how exciting the day was!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As Scotland's only bouting coed league, do you plan on pushing coed further in 2015? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AW&lt;/strong&gt;: “I believe some feelers have been sent to some prospective opponents, so we shall see what emerges in the next few months!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;It will certainly remain an important element of this league, as we were founded as the first co-ed league in Scotland and it remains a principle we promote and encourage. We were pleased to see Mean City announce their decision to go co-ed recently and wish them the best in developing this within their own league in 2015 and beyond.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ent&lt;/strong&gt;: “Being a co-ed league is what makes BCR who we are and its really important for us to see the co-ed aspect of roller derby in Scotland develop. The fact that there are now other co-ed leagues in the country means that future of co-ed derby in Scotland is going to be exciting!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can we expect from both teams in 2015?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ent:&lt;/strong&gt; “The strengthening of both teams is what the main focus of 2015 will be. We already have a few games lined up for the early half of the year which will hopefully highlight the work the Belters and the Skelpies have put in to further improve the teams.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AW:&lt;/strong&gt; “Steady, solid improvement from both teams and a few surprises along the way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;The Skelpies did not play as many bouts in 2014 as originally planned but are already looking at a potentially busy calendar for the first half of 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;Both teams are already booked into tournaments (in Edinburgh and Wales) and have individual bouts in the process of being organised as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;The Belters will continue to mould a strong unit out of the enviable position they now find themselves in with regards to team numbers. The Skelpies will re-inforce their existing squad with a focus on male intake within the league over the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;2015, we’re coming to get you!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby would like to wish Bairn City Rollers' all the best for their 2015 season.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep a look out for games involving all three teams in 2015!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>derby review 2014</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/01/25/bairn-city-rollers-a-roundup-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 09:14:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Review 2014: Nitemare, Voodoo and Hades... and Bob.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/12/derby-review-2014-nitemare-voodoo-and-hades-and-bob/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A slightly unusual Review entry this time: not a league, but a collection of Derby Happenings all tied together by one common feature: Falkirk's own skate and roller derby store, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/intothe.nitemareclothing"&gt;Into The Nitemare&lt;/a&gt;. We thought that, what with having their own exhibition team, founding two others during the year &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; putting on a national tournament, they probably deserved an article to themselves...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/img_0002.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-3280" alt="img_0002" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/img_0002.png?w=614" width="368" height="553"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Titan and Raven, Into The Nitemare, at the end of Battle of Britain (Copyright: Sam Skipsey)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/img_0001.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3281" alt="Newcastle Roller Girls, winners of BoB." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/img_0001.png?w=614" width="614" height="408"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Newcastle Roller Girls, winners of BoB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This has been an eventful year for Into The Nitemare's derby involvement, with Team Nitemare holding their first exhibition bouts, the formation of Hades Roller Boys and Voodoo Roller Dollies, and the successful hosting of Scotland's second ever national tournament, Battle of Britain. What has been the standout experience for the two of you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve had an amazing year derby wise, and there are far too many highlights to name just one. Team Nitemare was just amazing, I remember welling up at the skateout. Just so proud to see two amazing groups of such talent under one roof. The Jakey Tayzers proved to be a force to be reckoned with and as it turns out, many of them have found themselves on their gender's National Team Scotland. That was also the day of the Hades debut, which was one of the most exciting bouts I’ve had the pleasure of experiencing…I got so wrapped up in the game I have since been sacked as Line Up…by my own husband no less, hehe. I am so not cut out for that position.
The Hades boys put together a charity bout in November, just the week before BoB, which got people coming from all over the UK, and we were chuffed to bits that all these people made such an effort to come, from Manchester Roller Derby, Blackpool Roller Derby League and Belfast Men's Roller Derby, not to mention representation from leagues all over Scotland. It was an amazing day.
Then we get to BoB…well that was a year in the making and we’d again like to pass along our thanks to all that made it possible. We had representation from wider Europe and even the good ole USofA. The only drawback of the day was not skating in it!
As for the Voodoo Roller Dollies, well you’ll have to keep your eyes peeled for our upcoming news but needless to say we’re training hard in preparation for an incredible first year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coming back to the events in sequence, last time we spoke, we talked about your plans for coed exhibition team, Team Nitemare. This year, they managed to bout for the first time, taking on the Jakey Tayzers for a narrow 174:215 loss and then travelling to play Middlesborough Milk Rollers' Milk Invaders away to a resounding 278:168 win! How was the experience of building to those two bouts?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beauty of Team Nitemare is that we have built on it throughout the year and we have expanded our ranks. There were a few hiccups in the the run up to the Jakey Tayzer bout, but in true roller derby fashion, it pulled together and ran smoothly on the day. The Tayzers were a formidable force and showed how well a co-ed team can work together. All of the lead up to the Milk Invaders (Middlesborough Milk Rollers and Teeside Skate Invaders Mash up) was all down to the lovely Terri Sudron and we the team. It was intense in the run up though, especially the first one, it was almost like Christmas, so much tension for an hour or so of watching it all come together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Nitemare's debut was also Hades Roller Boys', the second bout pitting them against Ireland's Men Behaving Derby, for a narrow win. Hades later played Wirral's men's team away in December. This is a bit of a reversal for the two of you, with Raven getting to cheer on Titan[Cronos?] for the first time! Tell us a bit about the experience…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit here, I was a very bad wife and abandoned Titan to go and have fun at Team Scotland Try-outs… The debut is the only bout I’ve seen of Hades, as their next one was over in Montpellier against the Kamiquads.
Although I will be at their next game, most definitely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A little after Hades was founded, the Falkirk area also gained its third women's team in Voodoo Roller Dollies. With Fierce Valley and Bairn City already in the region, how are Voodoo planning on distinguishing themselves?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We set ourselves apart from the two other big teams in the area by being small. We are not looking at expanding to league proportions but our initial aim is to gain a roster of 20. I’ve been a part of a big and fast growing league and found that it wasn’t for me. I like feeling that I know all of my team mates and we speak every day. We aim to conduct the team with as little of the traditional structure as is expected. So if you’re looking to become a new blood at Voodoo, you can expect to have fun , just skate and be a valued member of VRD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capping off the year for Into The Nitemare was the 6-way Battle of Britain tournament, pitting teams from across the UK (with a few last minute substitutions from the original lineup) against each other. With three teams in the event, Scotland did creditably, with Dundee finishing a strong second after Newcastle's Whippin Hinnies' first place.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; How was the experience of running your first big event? Anything you'd do differently next time [will there be a next time]?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoB as it was fondly known was a great day. We were so proud to see Scotland do so well, with Dundee rampaging home in silver position, Lothian Representing extremely well on the day despite injury and some brand new skaters and the Belters getting their first win.
Newcastle, having stepped in at the last minute, were valiant in their win, Belfast showing some massive hits and the Reapers playing their first open bouts and getting that first public win under their belts too. The day was fantastic and without the help of Teams, Refs, NSOs, Photographers, Announcers and event staff it would not have been possible. As I said before the nature of derby is to throw a spanner in the works and there were more than a few in the final weeks of preparation with two teams pulling out, venue issues and then on the day a minor mishap with a team bus..but it all came together in the end.
Special mention has to go to Head Ref: Ella Bella Bang Bang (ARRG) and our Head NSO [Crashing] Wookiee [Broken Zebra] (GCRG) without whom, I would have been pretty much a wreck.
Will we do another tournament? Maybe, you’ll just have to wait and see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With all that happening in 2013, Into The Nitemare must have plans for 2014. Is there anything you can reveal now, or is it all secret?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not secret, but it hasn’t been announced yet. We have a busy year ahead in all aspects, Hades, Voodoo and Team Nitemare , so you’ll just have to watch on the facebooks and twitters to keep abreast of all our happenings!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>battle of britain roller derby tournament</category><category>derby review 2014</category><category>hades roller boys</category><category>into the nitemare</category><category>team nitemare</category><category>voodoo roller dollies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/12/derby-review-2014-nitemare-voodoo-and-hades-and-bob/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 19:34:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Review 2014: Non-bouting Leagues Roundup</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/09/derby-review-2014-non-bouting-leagues-roundup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While many of our Scottish leagues have held bouts in the past year, that doesn't make the newer, or relaunching, members of the Scottish Roller Derby community any less important. New leagues are an important part of the derby community, spreading skating to places that it hasn't been before. So, let's spend a little time catching up on what the non-bouting leagues have been doing in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013, Scotland continued to gain new leagues at an impressive pace. Leaving aside Voodoo Roller Dollies (who will be covered in a different article), women's derby leagues sprouted up in Dumfries and Galloway, and in Ayrshire. As is traditional, both the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Doonhame-Derby-Dolls/161632670699789"&gt;Doonhame Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ayrshirerollerderby"&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; were founded by women who wanted to skate, but found themselves too far from the existing leagues to join one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/doonhameandfriends1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3255" alt="Doonhameandfriends1" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/doonhameandfriends1.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="408"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Doonhame Derby Dolls, and friends from GRD and Mean City Roller Derby (Sourced from DDD Facebook page.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;The Dolls have been particularly successful, as skater Claire Warner noted "Our first meet saw 50+ in attendance and that number has grown since (with over 70 paid up members now on the books)!"
As with any new league, that success was supported by the wider derby community, as Claire told us "Our first night was led by Jodie from Glasgow Roller Derby (the woman who had inspired [founders] Debz and Grace) and Cat, a Windsor Rollergirl who luckily for us had just moved to the area, and who has been coaching us ever since. We have had other guest skaters joining in and sharing their skills too, Bruisedog from Mean City, and Turbolinz from GRD came for a visit, Tessington World of Adventures from Granite City Roller Girls and Hazzard from LRG have all dropped in to share their skills, knowledge and love of derby with us, the freshest of fresh meat."&lt;/p&gt;
Doonhame have been exceptionally organised in themselves, as well. In the last four months, they've managed to set up their league branding and management structure, gain sponsorshop, and also garner a huge amount of local media attention, including a spot on ITV Borders News. They've even managed to hold two RollerDisco fundraisers, the funds from which they are planning on using to subsidise costs for skaters on low incomes.
From all of that, you would not be wrong in guessing that their plans for 2014 are.. expansive.
"There is sooo much more planned for this year too (we have just been away on a Dolls development planning weekend)!", Said Claire, "Not only do we plan to gain affiliation, sponsorships/funding to improve access opportunities for other local women, we aim to hold our own local bootcamp to help us work towards passing minimum skills, put on a demonstration bout and hopefully be scrimmaging by the end of the year. In addition to all this we are also looking to take part in local charity fundraisers, spreading the Derby Love and helping those in need in our local community. we will also be running roller disco's on a regular basis throughout the year and hopefully we are about to start organising our own junior derby league!!"
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/ayrshire2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3257" alt="Ayrshire Roller Derby's earliest skaters." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/ayrshire2.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="411"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Ayrshire Roller Derby's earliest skaters. (Sourced from ARD Facebook page)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Dolls were inspired by one Glasgow Roller Derby skater, Ayrshire Roller Derby was inspired by another. As Lorna McIlvanney told us: "We wanted to start up an Ayrshire league but thought it would be difficult and never had the time to do it. Then at Rollerstop, we spotted Sylk from GRD and approached her to see if she might be able to help us set up. She said she would give advice and help with training as and when. [...] We have had massive amounts of help from Sylk, along with various Mean City skaters. We have been invited to scrim with other leagues (once we are mins passed) and have had messages of support and offers of help from many, which has been awesome."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARD have exciting plans for 2014, as well, as Lorna explained, "We are planning on getting to as many bouts as possible and getting involved where we can e.g. as NSO's etc. Our sights are set on passing mins shortly. We have fundraising plans and recruitment drives coming up. Then, scrims for experience and hopefully we'll be ready for our very first bout. We hope to one day base ourselves in the three Ayrshire (North, East, South) and maybe have our home teams structured that way. That's further down the line obviously, but it nice to have goals."
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;⁂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;As well as the brand-new leagues of 2013, leagues founded from 2012 and earlier still continued to develop over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
In Glasgow, the &lt;a href="http://deadlydivasrollerderby.webs.com/"&gt;Deadly Divas&lt;/a&gt; experienced a hiatus for various personal reasons. A spiritual-successor league, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/renfrewshirerockinrollers"&gt;Renfrewshire Rockin' Rollers&lt;/a&gt;, also appeared, with similar stated aims, but is also currently static. RRR Co-founder, Juggs Knock'her said "At the moment due to a lot going on in our personal lives things are on hold. We plan to have a fairly relaxed approach to skating, as well as training to WFTDA rules and Renegade. We are looking to recruit both women and men. Basically derby is about fun and we hope to keep it that way."
With the Deadly Divas also hinting that they might be waking up, it remains to be seen what happens in the space of second-leagues in Glasgow.
&lt;p&gt;Moving northwards, the resurgence of Perth's &lt;a href="http://www.faircityrollers.com/"&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; continued apace in the past year. League chair Pistol Panties was excited about their continued growth, "Initially, we were holding open sessions and just trying to build our numbers up, with the rec sessions, and we have achieved that. We had a big fresh meat intake in August, funded by a local charity geared towards increasing attendance at women's sports, which was a great success and we had a great response from everyone. That really was a stroke of genius, because it allowed us to invite all Scottish leagues along to an open scrimmage, which not only meant we got to see our friends, but it allowed the girls to get a real flavour of what Roller Derby is really about. We now have good numbers of regular attendees, and a team of (very nearly) mins passed skaters."
The league even managed to one-up most of the rest of Scotland, organising a guest coaching session from Steel City Rollergirls' Shrinking Violet in June. "We worked on basic skills, which was really useful even for the more experienced skaters, we all wanted longer with her, so we did a bit of off-skates afterwards too!".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City are now holding regular fresh meat sessions, with the last one being on the 27th of January, and regular training sessions are up to 3 hours a week. "We feel excited about this year," said Pistol, "and to be in a position to be thinking about getting back to competing in the near future. Basically, the only way is up!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/icrdlogo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-3250 " alt="Inverness City Roller Derby's new, striking, logo." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/icrdlogo.jpg?w=614" width="368" height="362"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Inverness City Roller Derby's new, striking, logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inverness' Nasty Nessies Roller Girls underwent a few changes over 2013, not least a change of name and branding. The newly styled "&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/InvernessCityRollerDerby"&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;" will retain the "Nasty Nessies" name and logo for their travel team. While ICRD has not yet bouted, their skaters continue to make appearances in exhibition and cherry popper bouts hosted by other leagues, and travel to open scrims in the rest of Scotland. They've also been working on an interesting outreach project, as Scarlett O'Horror told us: "We've just completed a collaboration with &lt;a href="http://www.fixers.org.uk/"&gt;Fixers&lt;/a&gt; - a group that helps promote community participation and challenge stereotypes. We made a film with them, featuring our own lovely skaters, which will be premièred in Inverness - very exciting!"
2014 looks like being the year for roller derby in Inverness, however, "We have a lot planned for this year! We will hopefully move into a new training venue this year, and have a few more mixed bouts lined up, including participating in a bout in April, which is really exciting for us. Some very lucky members are also off to Texas to watch the World Cup in December - picking up tips and training ideas, no doubt! And t-shirts. Always t-shirts."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, at the northernmost point of Scotland, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ShetlandRollerDerby"&gt;Shetland Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; has continued to hold both derby and open skate sessions throughout the year. Men and women are welcome, and the Open skates in particular have been popular.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;⁂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;As you can see, it's been an eventful year with the growing leagues of Scotland, and 2014 promises to be even more interesting!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>deadly divas roller derby</category><category>derby review 2014</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>renfrewshire rockin' rollers</category><category>shetland roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/09/derby-review-2014-non-bouting-leagues-roundup/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 15:22:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Review 2014: Dundee Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/14/derby-review-2014-dundee-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another day, another league Review for 2013. Moving a little further North than the last few, Silvery Tayzers Captain Psychomilly was happy to talk about &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/img_0341-copy.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3158" alt="Dundee Roller Girls taking on Lothian Derby Dolls at Battle of Britain (Photo: Laura MacDonald)" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/img_0341-copy.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Dundee Roller Girls taking on Lothian Derby Dolls at Battle of Britain (Photo: Laura MacDonald)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compared to 2012, 2013 has been a slightly more mixed year for the Silvery Tayzers; a couple of losses at the start of the season against Rainy City and Glasgow's Maiden Grrders, followed by an improving streak (a narrow loss against Newcastle's Whippin' Hinnies, and an almost unbroken winning streak since). You said last year that Dundee were aiming higher for their competition in 2013; how did you work to raise your game and fight back over the year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team has worked really hard this year to push our skills and to keep our tactics current with the new rules set introduced. We saw more losses this year than last, but we really were playing with the big girls this year! Over the year I think we settled into our new roster and became more comfortable working together as a team. In the latter half of the year, we took our tactics back to basics and worked on developing our skills together, which definitely paid off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There's also been several changes to the roster over 2013, starting the season with several regulars missing or moved to other locations, and then Suffra-Jet moving to Glasgow to join GRD in the middle of the year, and Cult Friction moving to Edinburgh to join ARRG (and changing her skatename!), ending with Dr Carnage's last bout You've also picked up a bunch of new (or returning) skaters, who we saw in the last few bouts of the year. How are you adapting to the changing makeup of Dundee this year? Do you think this kind of cyclic mutability is good for the team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DRG have always had a pretty fluid roster as we're a university team - there's two universitys in Dundee, but it's a small city when it comes to finding a job, so a lot of our veteran skaters have moved for the sake of their careers. It's always hard to see someone you've trained with leave, but we're so, so proud of everyone who has moved on and become even more skilled.
This season, we've had some absolutely inspirational skaters move from newbies to Tayzers almost seamlessly. Having so many new skaters get on the Tayzer's roster has meant that as a team we've worked even harder to bond on track and to support each other. BoB and our home game against FVRG were the most 'together' I felt the team all year and it's a total pleasure to skate with so many committed new skaters. I think having new skaters move up to the Tayzers is good for us as a team - they bring fresh ideas and their enthusiasm and motivation is infectious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With all the preparation for the second ever (Women's) Roller Derby World Cup in 2014, several of Dundee's skaters have been trying out for national teams. Crazily InSanne got into Team Netherlands, and there's a few of your skaters who attended the Team Scotland first round tryouts. It's a great thing for Scottish derby to have skaters featured in potentially multiple national teams… do you see more of this and other international involvement in Dundee's future?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm so excited to see DRG represented at the World Cup. Sanne has gone from strength to strength this year and I think you'd struggle to find someone more committed to the sport. Her behind the scenes work to keep our team running as well as the time she spends honing her skills, fitness and knowledge is outstanding. It'd be a total dream to represent DRG as part of Team Scotland, but the competition is so, so high!
I'd love to see Dundee more involved in international derby, particularly now that there's more and more leagues in Europe visiting Scotland. Hopefully this year we can experience our first international bout!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking outside of Dundee, there's been a continuing growth in Scottish Roller Derby over 2013, with Bairn City Rollers, Lothian Derby Dolls and New Town Roller Girls all holding their first bouts this year. Dundee played two of those league already, and donated a skater or two to New Town's cherry popping bout roster. Now that Dundee is firmly in the upper-half of Scottish teams in terms of experience, do you feel you have a responsibility to newer teams? How does the increasing breadth of derby spread interact with how you see DRG placing itself in Scotland?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expansion of derby in Scotland this year has been amazing. We've found the newer leagues have provided a great opportunity for some of our newer skaters to get involved with scrimmages and bouts with skaters of their level. We've also seen skaters from a lot of the newer leagues in Scotland visiting us for our open scrimmages, which is a really good way of sharing learning and techniques, as well as getting to know the leagues better. In the beginning, DRG received so much training and advice from the larger leagues at the time, we realise how important it is to be supported by more experienced teams. We love to help out other leagues in any way we can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This was the first year Dundee Roller Girls played in a tournament, signing up to IntotheNitemare's Battle of Britain at the last minute due to cancellations. Despite Newcastle pipping you to the top spot, Dundee did very well - are you planning on more tournaments after this experience? How did the tournament compare to the usual single-bout context?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd love to take part in more tournaments. It's a fantastic way of bonding as a team and I think we kept the momentum going throughout the day. I couldn't have been any more proud to captain DRG at the tournament. We worked together so well as a team - particularly with 6 skaters new to the Tayzers. BoB was one of my favourite experiences in derby.
I think tournaments differ to single bouts in that it's over just as you get into your stride. Keeping the motivation and morale up through the day was really important to us - we had a team quiz, a poster of the roster made up of pugs and a gold-star system of goals to keep us all focused and smiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For much of this year, Dundee have continued their support of Co-ed Derby with the Dundee Co-ed Scrims continuing to be extremely popular for skaters across Scotland, and the Jakey Tayzers returning to play more co-ed derby on track. How's Dundee's relationship with Co-Ed developed over the year? Will the Jakey Tayzers remain a more exhibition team, or is there possibility of a more formal arrangement?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dundee have always supported co-ed derby and will continue to do so. This year we've moved to having monthly co-ed scrimmages. Co-ed is a great way to challenge ourselves, as skating with men means we have to skate that little bit smarter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the Jakey Tayzers...I think we already see ourselves as more than an exhibition team. Still unbeaten!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On a personal note, you’ve had a busy year: referreeing at as many bouts as you’ve played in, appearing on Team Steve for Scotland’s first Men v Women bout against the Jakey Bites, as well as regaining the captaincy of Dundee for the last bouts of the season (and trying out for Team Scotland(!)). How do you fit it all the derby in? Is there a temptation to choose one or other of refereeing or bouting?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been really lucky over the past few years, with ARRG and GRD giving me the opportunity to officiate loads of their bouts, including my first WFTDA Sanctioned bouts, which was a total honour. I also loved reffing the Men's European Roller Derby Champs. It was an incredible experience and I met loads of really inspirational officials. I'm also lucky to have such a supportive home league who've given me the opportunity to captain them again and help build the team and I've had the most fun bouting with them this year, especially at Battle of Britain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart is definitely still in bouting, I love DRG, though I do often get told that I'll have to choose either skating or officiating eventually. I find that a really strange idea and one that I think only female officials seem to be pushed into - I can think of a number of male skaters who skate high level derby who also officiate, but women in the same situation seem to be expected to choose one or the other. Until my schedule means I can't manage both, I'm happy sharing my time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, can you let us in on any of Dundee Roller Girls' plans for 2014?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm...well, we have a massive year planned for the team, but sadly I can't reveal too much just yet! It's safe to say we're working hard to expand and develop our wee team, so watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>derby review 2014</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>review</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/14/derby-review-2014-dundee-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 11:49:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>