<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about doonhame derby dolls)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/doonhame-derby-dolls.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Granite City's Sparkling Year peaks with Glasgow rematch.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/23/granite-citys-sparkling-year-peaks-with-glasgow-rematch/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Granite City Roller Derby's rebranding (from Roller &lt;em&gt;Girls&lt;/em&gt;) at the end of last year obviously prefigured some kind of Pokémon style evolution to a new level of performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year has been an exceptional one for the league to date. A-team, the Northern Fights, absolutely demolished their Division in British Champs, taking the top spot after convincing wins against fellow Tier 4 North members Spa Town, Halifax Bruising Banditas and Blackpool Roller Derby League, and earning promotion into Tier 3 North next season. They've gotten 3 skaters into the Team Scotland 2016 Training Team. And their B-Team, the Fight Hawks, have embarked on a second successful year of bouts, working their way up the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Granite City are trying to top things off with a double header at home on &lt;strong&gt;27 August&lt;/strong&gt;, placing the Northern Fights against Glasgow Roller Derby's tough B-team, the Maiden Grrders; whilst the Fight Hawks take on a mixed team of great skaters from Doonhame Roller Derby, Ayrshire Roller Derby and Mean City Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught up with GCRD's &lt;strong&gt;Krusty&lt;/strong&gt;, the Northern Fights' Co-Captain (and Team Scotland Training team member) Udder Mayhem (&lt;strong&gt;Christine&lt;/strong&gt;), and Fight Hawks' Co-Captain and Northern Fights Bench Manager Pert Hits (&lt;strong&gt;Sam&lt;/strong&gt;) to see how the league feels about their year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8850" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/08/13925480_10155196192769012_6950054464319126321_o.jpg" alt="13925480_10155196192769012_6950054464319126321_o" width="1448" height="2048"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Obviously, 2015 was not a good year for Granite City at Champs, ending with your relegation to Tier 4 from Tier 3. This season, however, you've really stepped into gear, convincingly topping the table for promotion back up into T3! Did you make this a conscious aim for the year, and what changes did you make to help it happen?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christine:&lt;/strong&gt; 2015 was a challenge for us. We lost some experienced skaters, but we also gained new ones, however, we hadn’t quite gelled into the team we knew we could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disappointment at the beginning of 2015 forced us to refocus our tactics and to adopt the use of specific line-ups. To facilitate this, the Fights organized extra “team time” dedicated training sessions, which was funded through the skaters own fundraising efforts (e.g. boot sales, personal fundraising etc.). We were very determined to be the awesome team we knew we could be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn’t win all of our games, but we started to perform much better against higher ranked teams, and finished British Champs 2015 with a convincing win against Halifax Bruising Banditas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 2016, fortnightly team-focused sessions have continued as part of our structured training, and are now funded by the league for both the Fights and the Hawks. We recognised the importance of training as a team, especially as GCRD continues to grow. We’ve gelled really well this year as a result, and this is reflected in our performance in Tier 4. We hold regular team meetings to revisit our goals, and are planning for a more successful time in Tier 3 in 2017. Bring it on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam:&lt;/strong&gt; The regular team training has certainly helped the team bond and act as an effective unit. These sessions also allowed the 2016 Bench staff (myself and Krusty) to really focus on the team, feedback what was working and direct the team to further their game, the game they want to play. It has been really pleasing to see the team numbers grow, allowing them to move away from specific line-ups and into a direction where they know each other and their play and it doesn’t matter who they are lined up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GCRD have also had a good year in National terms, with 3 skaters (including two of your highest rated jammers in Champs) making it through to the Team Scotland Training Squad selection. I think last time you had 4, but it's also true that less GCRD skaters tried out this time. How do feel about your skaters making the training team (and the training team itself having skaters from so many leagues)?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christine:&lt;/strong&gt; As one of selected skaters, I am obviously delighted that I managed to make it through to the training squad, along with the brilliant Rock’N Riot and Jo Mamma. All three of us are also coaches, and we are keen to soak up as much as we can and bring it back to GCRD training sessions, so that the skills we learn can be passed on to benefit the rest of the league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer the other question, I am personally thrilled to see so many talented skaters from a variety of leagues! It will keep things interesting as every league is different, and we can all learn new and awesome things from each other. We had our first session a couple of days ago, and it was a fantastic and positive experience. I asked the question “how many hours did you drive to get here?” many times that day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam:&lt;/strong&gt; Echoing Christine, we are very proud of our skaters being selected for the Team Scotland training squad. Each year we have had good representation at Team Scotland try outs and then onto Team Scotland itself. Seeing such a variety of leagues represented on the training team is so reassuring that the sport in our wee country is really progressing and skaters really advancing. Some exceptional high-level derby being played across the country!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This upcoming bout against Glasgow's Maiden Grrders is your first non-Champs bout this year. This is something of a delayed rematch - the last time Granite City faced the Maidens was in 2013, where Glasgow took a convincing win. How are you feeling about this time around?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christine:&lt;/strong&gt; We look forward to welcoming the Maidens to Aberdeen, and are excited for the challenge! A lot has changed since 2013 and it will be a very different experience for both teams involved. For instance, when the Fights last played the Grrders, I was more focused on passing my minimum skills! We’ve been working very hard the past few months, and this will be a good test for us as we approach Tier 3 again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam:&lt;/strong&gt; The best test for us! The team are really looking forward to this challenge, aiming for all the hard work to pay off and give the Grrders a run for their money. I think the skaters involved, from both teams, have changed so much since 2013 it will be really fun game both to be part of, but to watch too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the Northern Fights busy with British Champs, GCRD B have had most of the flexibility in their fixtures. You’ve taken on both Dundee B (the Bonnie Colliders) at home, and more recently, Auld Reekies ASTROs away. Are the Fights jealous of your free schedule, and what’s next for the Hawks?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christine:&lt;/strong&gt; I guess I am a little bit jealous, but pinning down games has been somewhat of a challenge for both the Fights and the Hawks, especially in the first half of the year. A lot of work has been done behind the scenes to try and remedy it, however, there were home game slots for both May and July that I couldn’t find a team for the Fights to play against, and July’s date was completely cancelled in the end. Now we are approaching autumn, and Champs is finishing for most teams by this point, we are finding it much easier. We have one more home game against Sheffield Steel Roller Girls in October, and are playing ARRG’s All Star Reserves in November, which should keep the Fights busy! It should also challenge us, and help us to prepare for Tier 3 next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam:&lt;/strong&gt; If they are they’ve certainly not voiced it… but I guess travelling (half) the length of Britain once a month for 3 or 4 months keeps you busy and focused. They are certainly excited about the few home games we have planned for the later half of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hawks have a few games in the pipeline, a couple more double header home games and an away game too. As a team, we are still evolving and finding our game but as time is moving on we are gelling better as team too. As Co-Captain, I’m excited for the skaters to get more games under the belt and get the opportunities to play and show-case their hard work. I am also really looking forward to training with our freshly minimum passed skaters and helping build them up to game time! Some very exciting skaters are on the up through not only our minimum course, but our Intermediate training group too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first time for the Fight Hawks taking on a mixed team of skaters from across Scotland. How do you plan for that, and how are you feeling about taking on some of the rising stars from Ayrshire and Doonhame?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam:&lt;/strong&gt; Our plan is probably similar to if we were preparing for any other league team; play &lt;em&gt;OUR&lt;/em&gt; game. Training alongside the Northern Fights, and scrimming against them as teams, has really helped us focus on our weaknesses and up our skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are really looking forward to taking on Ayrshire and Doonhame! As noted previously, I am always super impressed and excited by the calibre of roller derby coming out of every league and I expect these two leagues to be no exception. I hope we are a suitable warm up for Ayrshire before their first home bout on September 10th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, personally, having spent the first few Hawks games as their Bench due to injury, I am so super excited! I was with the Hawks standing on the side-lines during their game with Mean City, and really look forward to playing against some of the Mean City ladies in this game too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We believe that this bout is also raising funds for some great charities, can you tell us a bit about this?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Krusty: &lt;/strong&gt;At every home game we host, we try to give some exposure to local charities within Aberdeen and surrounding areas. We have supported local charities at every home game and managed to raise substantial amounts of pennies on our cake stall, our home bakes are kindly donated by skaters, friends and family. We are overwhelmed by the donations we receive and the generosity of our supporters (and officials!) that purchase our fine home bakes. Sales from our cake stall on the 27&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; August will be donated to &lt;strong&gt;Befriend a Child&lt;/strong&gt;, they are Aberdeen's only 1:1 befriending service for vulnerable children and young people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also decided for this game that we would like to ‘borrow’ an idea we saw Sheffield Steel Rollergirls post up, holding a bra amnesty in support for &lt;strong&gt;‘Smalls for All’&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s something my work is doing too and it’s a fantastic idea! We are looking for brand new pants and new or worn bras that still have good wear in them. It’s an easy thing to organise but it will be greatly received by Smalls for All who is a charity which helps women and children in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone has any great suggestions for our next charity appeal, come speak to us at the game on Saturday!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City's Double Header is at their usual venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Beach+Leisure+Centre/@57.155602,-2.082094,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48840e4028217933:0x30c6b9176815da5b!8m2!3d57.155602!4d-2.0799"&gt;Aberdeen Beach Leisure Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;August 27th&lt;/strong&gt;. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;12:30pm&lt;/strong&gt;, for the first whistle at 1:10pm. Tickets are just &lt;strong&gt;£4&lt;/strong&gt; on the door. The Facebook event page is here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1717081471898842/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1717081471898842/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/23/granite-citys-sparkling-year-peaks-with-glasgow-rematch/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 18:31:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Skaters on track for New Town Cherry Popper</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/09/new-skaters-on-track-for-new-town-cherry-popper/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;March 19th&lt;/strong&gt; sees the Livingston area's &lt;strong&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; host a one of roller derby's traditions - a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1048868645164481/"&gt;cherry popper bout&lt;/a&gt;, showcasing new skaters from a mix of leagues. The bout will be held in New Town's current bouting venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/DSZTrnU8cYo"&gt;Blackburn Community Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6395" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/412387_204493976333497_2093997456_o.jpg?w=600" alt="412387_204493976333497_2093997456_o" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skaters from Auld Reekie Roller Girls, Bairn City Rollers, Lothian Derby Dolls, Doonhame Derby Dolls, Ayrshire Roller Derby, Fair City Rollers and Preston Roller Girls will join host New Town's own new skaters on track in two exhibition teams: The Morello Mashers (skating in hot pink) and the Women of Mass Destruction (skating in sapphire).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an ideal opportunity to see the potential of new roller derby skaters as they play their first bout in public. It's particularly exciting to see skaters from some of Scotland's leagues who are not publicly bouting yet, as this is a preview of perhaps what we might expect from Ayrshire, Doonhame and Fair City when they enter public bouts as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a slightly later game than we normally have in Scotland, with doors opening at &lt;strong&gt;4:45pm&lt;/strong&gt;, for a 5:15pm start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are available online from &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2521813"&gt;brownpapertickets&lt;/a&gt; for just &lt;strong&gt;£4&lt;/strong&gt;. Under 14s are free. Tickets will also be available on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>cherry poppers</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/09/new-skaters-on-track-for-new-town-cherry-popper/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 21:19:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-bouting Leagues Roundup of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/30/non-bouting-leagues-roundup-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year has seen another uptick in the number of new leagues in Scotland, with both &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HelginRollerDerby"&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/WeeCRD"&gt;Wee County Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; joining the ranks of &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/InvernessCityRollerDerby/"&gt;Inverness City&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/FairCityRollers/"&gt;Fair City&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Ayrshire-Roller-Derby-Official-618921518215712/"&gt;Ayrshire&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DoonhameDerbyDolls"&gt;Doonhame Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; as leagues making the journey towards their first public bout. As traditional, we're covering all of these leagues together in a Review of the Year, as usually bouts are a big part of what the bouting leagues cover about in their own articles. Since we have so many non-bouting leagues this year, however, we're splitting this article over several pages for readability - click the links at the bottom of each page to move between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every league forms its own relationships with the wider derby community when starting out, but some of our non-bouting leagues have developed particularly close ties.
Inverness City Roller Derby were very happy that Helgin Roller Derby started up nearby in Elgin, and the two have been combining resources:
"Helgin are fantastic and are growing so fast.
We try to go through as often as possible to coach them and help them with anything they may need help with and they often come through to us for a session and with such a big turn out at these sessions it boosts team morale."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5376" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/pudz.jpg" alt="PuDz" width="960" height="540"&gt; Power of Scotland's PudZ, selfie with combined Inverness and Helgin skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helgin are equally happy with the relationship, as they benefit from ICRD's experience and numbers. "All of our skaters rave about Nat from ICRD’s sessions for days afterwards – she really works us hard and we learn a lot! […] We’re looking to link up with ICRD at least once a month in 2016, so that we can all get a bit more contact and pack skills practice – something that can prove difficult if you’ve got a session with low numbers."
Of course, Helgin have also been keeping up their connections with the team to the East of them, and Granite City have been as supportive as they were at Helgin's founding, even donating kit and support for their fresh meat sessions. The Brawlermen also donated Power of Scotland's PudZ for a training session, "Our session with PudZ from Power of Scotland was brilliant – it was our first proper session where we got to practice game tactics and we learned so much!", which also included ICRD, "we had PudZ from POS run a session on walls and pack work which was also tremendously good fun."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, at the south end of the country, Dumfries' Doonhame Derby Dolls made the fortuitious discovery of nearby Carlisle's &lt;a href="http://www.bordercityrollers.com/"&gt;Border City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;, who are newly founded this year. The two leagues have quickly become quite attached, as Doonhame noted: "We only recently discovered that Carlisle had a team on the go through Facebook, one of our girls is from the area and she never even knew haha! This is now the closest team to us! We got in touch and done our own first ever guest coaching with 3 of our girls travelling down to their training night and they couldn't have been more welcoming, they're a great bunch of guys as we expected and they were so pleased to learn and understand where to go from where they'd got to. Georgie and Chloe Holmes helped start is up and have done well starting from scratch. We have kept in touch and they have been along to support us at games in Newcastle and Glasgow, making wee banners and being total fangirls which is amazing (it's usually us fangirling others!). "
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h6&gt;RECRUITMENT AND TRAINING&lt;/h6&gt;
All of the non-bouting leagues have been focussing on the three most important things for any newer league: recruiting skaters, training them to pass mins, and raising money to support all of this.
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, &lt;em&gt;Helgin&lt;/em&gt; held several successful fresh meats this year, recruiting 19 since we &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/23/helgin-roller-derby-scotlands-northernmost-league/"&gt;interviewed them last&lt;/a&gt;, and have also gained some transfers from other leagues "We’ve gained another few regular skaters, including some skaters formerly of Granite City Roller Derby, New Town Roller Girls and Belfast City Rockets, and we’ve now got enough people training on a regular basis to be looking to put a team together". They also have a tremendously organised public training plan, as anyone can see from the regular updates on their Facebook page, "This started back when we were chopping and changing venues a lot, as we were still trying to find permanent training locations, and we needed to keep people informed of where the sessions were. Many people commented that they liked knowing what was coming up, so we just kept it going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We like to be organised, and have a progressive training plan so that we can see the development of our Fresh Meat – sometimes sessions go to plan, sometimes you’ve got an odd number of people there and the ‘paired work’ session plan goes out the window! Slowly but surely we’re working it all out, and we hope to get our next batch of Fresh Meat minimum skills passed much quicker."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They've also been doing quite well at fundraising, having entered multiple grant shortlists, and also "doing rather well with community fundraising, and held another successful pub quiz at the end of August, keeping us afloat for a bit, and we’re looking to put on another at the end of January or beginning of February, to boost funds for 2016."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inverness&lt;/em&gt;, being one of the more established leagues in this article, has been growing a little more slowly, "We've had a few intakes but the struggle to find new members in Inverness is ongoing, we've lowered the age limit to 16 to try grow the team a little, we've got a few new(ish) faces and everyone is coming on leaps and bounds, and we should fingers crossed have them all mins passed just after the new year."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perth's&lt;em&gt; Fair City Rollers&lt;/em&gt; have had an interesting year, given that we reported last year that they were aiming to bout in 2015. Instead, this year has been one of introspection and consolidation. "Over the past year we've redefined ourselves as a team; who we are, what we do and where we're headed.  Our direction has become more bout focused and we've started to work towards becoming an actual bouting team again.
Over the past year we've worked on aligning focus and skills, and recruitment.  We're currently about halfway through our training programme of the new skaters we recruited in September, and are aiming to bout in 2016"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-5372" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/11880588_901492176606579_4883872526247151434_n.jpg?w=300" alt="11880588_901492176606579_4883872526247151434_n" width="300" height="300"&gt; The Wee-County Golden Gauntlet logo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clackmannanshire's &lt;em&gt;Wee Country Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt; have been attempting to retain the momentum from their initial launch (which we interviewed them about &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/29/a-wee-chat-with-wee-county-roller-derby/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), partly by launching their distinctive gauntlet logo,
We really wanted our logo to describe the fight we have for derby, and our community spirit rolled into one. Its our take on the clackmannshire logo of the gauntlet, with 'Look Aboot Ye' as a tag line. It works as a double meaning, having to be aware at all times who and what is around you on track.
There was a real buzz around the team in the beginning, it was great: lots of attention and press coverage. We had a strong initial recruitment and kept a steady flow of interest, with word of mouth travelling fast. It has been a challenge to form a solid basis for the team, but we have a great foundation of members now. Its been a tough year, of trial and error and lots of personal growth. We were overwhelmed by the support and commitment of the members we do have, as they get stuck in and really help to make our team a family.
Looking at how far we've come and comparing it to how far we have to go to allow us to have our debut bout is quite a step, but were confident that we have the determination and the strong mind set to make it happen."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5381" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/11050639_820246781416517_7188774811881300574_n.jpg" alt="11050639_820246781416517_7188774811881300574_n" width="540" height="960"&gt; Coach Graeme Gow keeping a watchful eye on the paceline at Ayrshire Roller Derby (Credit: Sally Wilkes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt;, meanwhile, have enough mins-passed skaters that they're starting to attend scrims and the like. "ARD have had an excellent year. We were joined by coach Graham Gow of Power of Scotland and Mean City fame. Our team may be small at the moment but it is growing all the time! Our mins passed players are regularly participating in open scrims and learning all they can. We would really like to thank all  the local teams that have helped and supported us this last few months." In addition, ARD have been at a whole host of fundraising and publicity-related engagements, including a stall at their local Christmas Fair. They've also had enthusiastic spectating presence at many bouts this year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, to the south, &lt;em&gt;Doonhame&lt;/em&gt; have been growing strong,
"Recruitment was a challenge to start, with maybe 6-10 people showing up at the start of the year, we then took a break from 'Fresh Meat' open nights and 're-evaluated our training / introduction methods. We then went on to having 2 of our most successful openers in Sept and October with a full house (of 30odd) both nights, and around half of that number dedicating and joining the team! Its the keeping them excited and committed that's the harder bit. We try to encourage everyone to the best of their ability and push those wishing to be pushed, but at a pace that's comfortable with them. We have been very lucky to be able to have a lot of amazing players come along and guest coach for us. To be able to have such a high profile skater like Stefanie Mainey come and guest at our bootcamp in May 2015 was amazing! She was brilliant  and really put us through our paces on the track and giving us some great insights! We love learning new stuff and stretching our mindsets."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5368" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/received_10153711888193956.jpeg" alt="received_10153711888193956" width="600" height="339"&gt; Doonhame's 7 cherry popping skaters at Bristol Roller Derby's event. (Credit: Andy Jardine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Ayrshire, Doonhame have a strong core of mins-passed skaters now, but they've been seeking out public cherry-popper bouts as well as scrims. Most notably, they even managed to appear on film in their first ever appearance (at Bristol Roller Derby's Summer Double Header): "There was 7 of us that popped our cherries in Bristol. It wasn't just any normal cherry popper though, we were filmed by the BBC 'See, hear' programme to promote the abilitly to skate with deaf / hoh players. What a rush! It was so nerve racking, exciting and hundreds of miles away from home, but we did it!
After we got the taste, we actively started to look for cherry poppers, charity games, closed scrimms, anything to let us get out there to play. Its really difficult, frustrating, when you have a handful of players passed skills, gagging to play, but not enough players yet for a full team! Which leads to all of these brilliant events opening up their doors to us, where you learn just how special roller derby is. This has meant us travelling to Edinburgh, Dundee and Newcastle for scrimms and bouts to join other teams. The friendships and camaraderie throughout playing with other teams would be the highlight of travelling, and of course gaining the experience and playing along side some awesome derby gals. "
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h6&gt;PLANS FOR NEXT YEAR&lt;/h6&gt;
We asked each of the leagues about their plans for next year, and it looks like most of them have the same aim in mind: getting on track for their first public bout!
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doonhame&lt;/em&gt;: "All in all I think 2016 is going to be amazing for DDD as we are pushing our girls hard to try and bag a full team line up to finally play as a proper DDD full team. Until then though the girls that have passed will be playing in mixed scrim and bouts when they can and it's great we're always thought of to take part. 2016 will just be Onwards and upwards for DDD. Watch this space!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ayrshire&lt;/em&gt;: "We reckon we will be putting a team together at the beginning of next year and we REALLY cant wait to get stuck into playing!
I feel like it will be next year's [update] that has all the exciting stuff in it!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fair City&lt;/em&gt;: "[We] are hoping to pop our collective team cherry at the start of March 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, within the year of the restructure, we'll be back on track and competing against other teams.  Exciting times for the FCR!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wee County&lt;/em&gt;: "For next year we're hitting training and promotion head on, really pushing ourselves to the limits i know we can achieve. New and improved training programmes will be put in place to fully structurise the fresh meat members, also one for the more advanced skaters.
Were looking to get into the community in a big way, and doing our bit for local charities.
Our goal for 2016 is to integrate roller derby into the Wee County in a big way, so as always, look aboot ye."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Helgin&lt;/em&gt;: "Well, fingers crossed, we get all of our current skaters mins passed in early 2016, and then we’re going on the road to join some boot camps and open scrims to get a bit more experience in game play.  This, along with regular training with ICRD will hopefully have us bout-ready by the end of the year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re planning to hold three more Fresh Meat intakes – probably around February, May and September to keep our skater numbers up, and probably a similar number of fundraisers to keep us going financially. We’re also hoping to get our Business Plan finished over the Festive period (since our training venues are closed and we can’t skate :() and will be able to widen the net of the funds we can apply to, so that we can get scrim vests, more hire kit, more people first aid trained, and even cover our hall hire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve also been in discussions with Moray Sports Centre (a new state-of-the-art sports centre planned to be built on the southern boundary of Elgin) and things are looking hopeful that we may well have a new home in the future – one large enough to host bouts!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inverness&lt;/em&gt;: "We are looking forward to 2016 and having a team ready to start playing after all these years, we will be frequenting Dundee's open scrims with everyone learning to nso's for a couple of turns and then scrimming when mins passed, also we will have a regular session every month with Helgin to keep building on pack skills and game play.  Fingers crossed that later in 2016 Icrd will hit the track as a team!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all goes to the plans above, it's quite possible that next year, there will be no non-bouting leagues roundup, as there'd only be one or two leagues left to cover in it! As always, it's an exciting time with the growth of Scottish derby, and 2016 might see the next big wave of leagues entering the bouting world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>review of the year</category><category>wee county roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/30/non-bouting-leagues-roundup-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 12:29:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Interview With: The Deaf and Hard of Hearing Roller Derby Skaters Worldwide Community Group</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/19/an-interview-with-the-deaf-and-hard-of-hearing-roller-derby-skaters-worldwide-community-group/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;While Roller Derby tries its hardest to be an accepting place, it is sometimes hard for a majority population to understand the needs of a minority, and the actions of individuals can always fall below the standards the community may aspire to. This was highlighted last year, when Meat Train was not placed in the New Zealand National Women's Derby squad, apparently due to concerns that as a hard of hearing individual, it would be too hard to accommodate her into the training routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;One of the consequences of the outcry over this was the foundation of the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Deafderbyskaters"&gt;Deaf and Hard of Hearing Roller Derby Skaters Worldwide&lt;/a&gt; Facebook group, in order to promote and support deaf and Hard of Hearing skaters in roller derby. (At this point, a brief aside is necessary on terminology: when used with a capital D, "Deaf" is used to identify as a member of the Deaf community; as opposed to "deaf", which refers to the medical state. A HoH (Hard of Hearing) person may also identify as Deaf if they are part of the community, despite not being "medically deaf". )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The community recently got some wider attention in the UK when UK rep (and &lt;a href="http://www.doonhamederbydolls.co.uk/"&gt;Doonhame Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; skater) Firefoxx was filmed by &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b006m9cb/episodes/guide"&gt;BBC SeeHear&lt;/a&gt; when attending a bout down in Bristol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We took the opportunity to ask some questions of the current team behind the Deaf and Hard of Hearing Roller Derby Worldwide Facebook group. Our interviewees are: Meat Train (also known as Marcia), her (Hearing) partner Lex, referee Davie Darko and Firefoxx. Meat Train skates for &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/wfrdl"&gt;Whenua Fatales Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;/ Hutt Valley Vanguard Roller Derby, New Zealand and is HoH going deaf, Davie Darko referees for &lt;a href="http://www.rocderby.com/"&gt;Roc City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and is HoH, and Firefoxx skates for Scotland's own Doonhame Derby Dolls and identifies as Deaf. Firefoxx is sponsored by Skates.co.uk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/3.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4815" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/3.jpeg?w=300" alt="Meat Train" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Meat Train (photo by Emear O'Connell)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/0.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4816 size-medium" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/0.jpeg?w=300" alt="0" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Lex&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/1.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4817" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/1.jpeg?w=200" alt="DD" width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Davie Darko (by ?)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/2.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4818" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/2.jpeg?w=200" alt="FF" width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Firefoxx (by Graeme Willets)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;I believe that the Deaf and Hard of Hearing Derby Skaters Worldwide FB group and community was founded after the incident in during New Zealand's National Team selection involving discrimination against Meat Train for being Deaf. Were you as skaters surprised by this event?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;MT: &lt;span class="s1"&gt;I was very surprised that my hearing loss was taken into consideration and plastered on social media. I was deaf at the start of the year when I got picked for the top 30 and everyone knew that.
I feel that with the mindset that enabled this to happen I never had a hope of making the final team.  This is not ok for New Zealand Roller Derby and this is not ok when picking a national sports team.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;L: &lt;span class="s1"&gt;I felt ill…and then furious. I knew that it was not okay. It has been a very intense 9 months since then and it has been gut-wrenching to see how it has affected Marcia. There has been so much support for her worldwide and our decision to start this page has helped so much with turning this whole thing into something positive.  We have worked tirelessly on the Deaf and HoH Roller Derby Skaters Worldwide page, all with the aim of making sure that this does not happen again to anyone.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What has the community been doing to make things better for D/HoH skaters in the months since it was founded?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;L: &lt;span class="s1"&gt;There are so many things! From derby promo videos in sign language to how much love we see coming to each and every person we profile on the page from their teammates… We have had MANY people contact us saying “we have a Deaf or HoH person in our League – how can we support them?” – it’s wonderful &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The impetus for this interview was the discovery that Doonhame's Firefoxx was representing Scotland and the Deaf community in Bristol, to be filmed by See Hear. Can you talk a little about how you got involved in this, and what the experience was like?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;MT: &lt;span class="s1"&gt;Firefoxx was one of the 1st skaters profiled on our page. When we were contacted by the BBC looking for a Deaf/ HoH skater in the UK we put them in contact with her as her profile had been very popular and she was one of the only UK-based derby people we knew at the time.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;L:  &lt;span class="s1"&gt;As Marcia said, the BBC got in contact with us and we pointed them in Firefoxx’s direction  It was very exciting in the few days leading up to the filming as we decided to pull together a ‘good luck video’ for her and her teammates (as it was their cherry popper!) from derby people from all around the world! We spent a crazy few days calling in favours, filming our own message, editing and getting the vid to the BBC in time to surprise the Doonhame Derby Dolls before the bout. It was bloody intense but so worth it!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;There are, of course, many sign languages, which are very different in vocabulary and grammar. Do any of you know more than one Sign Language, and if so, are any better suited to derby than others? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;MT:New Zealand Sign Language is very similar to British Sign Language. I find NZSL easy to use on the track as we’re not signing whole sentences, just signs for different plays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;L: No, only basic New Zealand Sign Language but we really need to learn some American Sign Language to be better able to Skype call with the ASL users we meet through our page!!!!!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;D: Unfortunately I don't know any sign language, but I'm seriously considering ASL, given my deteriorating hearing and of course where I live.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;FF: [I'm] currently learning [British] sign language and enrolling in advanced classes soon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;As with any language which the majority do not speak, are there advantages to having a Sign Language as a language (and teaching your teammates it)?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;MT: &lt;span class="s1"&gt;I’m still learning sign as I’m going deaf and it is now my second language. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Using sign is an advantage as the other team have no clue what you’re about to do. It helps make sure everyone knows what play we are about roll out, without telling the opposition. And at a derby game it’s so loud who can hear much anyway? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;New Zealand Sign Language is very similar to British Sign Language. I find NZSL easy to use on the track as we’re not signing whole sentences, just signs for different plays.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;L: Absolutely. Sign Language can be seen from a distance so you can communicate across a track, even in the middle of a drill or from the bench. As someone in the audience I often get signed at from the bench (can you fill my water bottle/ I’ve hurt my _________ or what was that penalty for? LOL)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;There's a lot of advice on the FB page for skaters and officials concerning support of Deaf and Hard of Hearing skaters, including the provision of signing translators for bench teams, and dealing with insubordination calls. What've been the most common issues, and the best responses to the issues that you face as D/HoH skaters?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;MT:  &lt;span class="s1"&gt;There are Leagues around the world trying to understand, trying to help and holding events that are inclusive but like anything it takes time and a willingness to try.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;D: In my experience as an official (and from that point of view), the most common issues I've seen are skaters knowing when they are receiving a penalty or penalty warning from a referee, or receiving instructions from penalty box staff. However, these are well-known issues, and for teams that have a Deaf or HoH skater, they usually already know how to handle it. It is brought up early before the game starts, and procedures are put in place to better enable communication between skaters and officials.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;FF: The biggest barrier I've faced is the communication between myself and officials. Being on track, not being able to hear what is happening around you and having that inner panic incase you miss a ref call or something is a really isolating feeling. It's literally like skating around in your own little bubble. I rely heavily on the officials to immerse me fully into the game. The biggest challenge we face is educating all the officials out there on how to communicate effectively with the deaf and HOH.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Is it easier, do you think, to be HoH or deaf when playing derby, and are there more similarities than differences?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;MT: I think so, yes, but then I don’t have anything to compare it to. It’s what I know, my way of being in the world…
I don’t get distracted by other stuff like the crowd, people talking smack talk, the commentary. On the other hand if there is music when I’m jamming it puts me at a disadvantage as I can’t hear the whistles and end up starting later than the other Jammer (I always have to watch the hand signal of the Jam Timer). The music is what I hate the most. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;L: I can’t speak FOR the Deaf or HoH people involved in derby as I am not one of them.  I can say that one of the most common things that comes through the page is that people who are hard of hearing are often struggling with where they fit in derby.  We have seen some amazing improvements in people’s confidence to ‘come out’ to their Leagues and speak up for what they need. This doesn’t always happen though and we have seen some people walk away from derby because it’s just too hard to keep asking for a few accommodations that would make all the difference. That always breaks our hearts and this is one of the main reasons why we created our resources (for skaters, for officials, for leagues and for fans).
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;D: I can't speak to what is easier or harder, but as a HoH official, I can certainly attest to the challenges that are faced. For us, audible signals are a must for certain things. For example, as a Jammer Referee, there are decisions you have to make that depend upon the state of the pack and where the Engagement Zone is, and if you have trouble hearing the pack definition or in/out of play status from the Inside Pack Referees, you could be missing critical information and make the wrong call. Luckily my hearing aid has helped me in this regard.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;FF: I honestly completely underestimated how hard this game would be as a deaf skater. Not only do we have to use our individual talent on talent and perform exceptional teamwork - we have to essentially find a way to bring that all together; but without any hearing. I think if people could truly understand how it feels to be a deaf person in a hearing sport; they'd quickly change the way of the game. It's hard, but my love for the sport makes it worth it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;If you could pick one thing which is the most important aspect to do right to support D/HoH skaters in derby, what would it be?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;MT: Facing the Deaf/ HoH person when you are talking to them.
The hardest part of derby is the training, not so much the games. It’s in training that coaches roll around to talk so you can’t always see their face and what they’re saying. At the same time other skaters are often fixing their gear up (velcro, stomping their skates) or talking over top of the coach or just chatting to their friends and that makes it hard (or impossible) to hear what the coach is saying. Facing us means we have a much better (but not 100%!) chance of lip-reading or hearing what you are saying!
Also, it’s nice to know you’re not alone when you feel like you don’t fit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;L: Be welcoming to them. Don’t make them feel like a burden or too-hard to deal with. You could be missing out on your next star Jammer or Blocker/ an amazing new friend xx
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;D: Derby is the people. As such, I think the most important thing is to learn how we can best understand and support each other through inclusivity and open, honest, and patient communication.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;FF: Be patient. We're trying really hard to keep up with you. If you give us a little time, we'll be a true asset to your team. We may not be able to hear you but we'll make up for it with our incredible determination.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>deaf and hard of hearing</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/19/an-interview-with-the-deaf-and-hard-of-hearing-roller-derby-skaters-worldwide-community-group/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 10:04:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Future of Derby: Junior Roller Derby, Part Two</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/10/the-future-of-derby-junior-roller-derby-part-two/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the second of our interviews on the current and future state of junior roller derby in the UK, we spoke to Debz "Dread Alert" McDowall of the Doonhame Derby Dolls, currently in the process of setting up a junior league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was behind your decision to set up a junior league?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Youth &amp;amp; Community worker I could see the massive benefit that derby could bring to the life of young women, in terms of self esteem, empowerment, health and wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the actually the original reason I got involved in helping establish the Doonhame Derby Dolls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is your league aimed at? Gender, age group etc?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;League is still in its embryonic stages - we have been delivering in one of our local high schools (Maxwelltown High School) since August 2014 as part of their curriculum, targetted at the Senior Girls PE sessions which are 16-17yrs old. We aim to kick start our generic (out of school) juniors in the new year and we will be working with mainly young women / girls aged 11-17 (split into Under 13s, and then 13-17yrs). We will keep our minds open to co-ed but our focus will be on young women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What obstacles have you faced in setting up your league?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our biggest obstacle has been getting insurance, it is super expensive given that they see Derby as an extreme sport and add to that the fact we are working with under 18s, and it makes it an expensive insurance quote, even if you can actually get someone to consider insuring it. Given that we are all volunteers and need insurance as individuals it makes it costly for us as coaches / youth workers to cover this personally, as although we are working hand in hand with the Doonhame Derby Dolls the juniors side of things is being run separately so doesnt fall under their insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you received much support from your local community and the derby community?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have received tonnes of support from our local community (especially from the derby community ie local derby mums who are loving getting the chance to share some physical activity and an obsession with their daughters), we have sooo many people desperate to send their kids along once we get launched, we have had amazing support from the local Community Sport Hub Development Officer, and Active Schools Co-ordinators, and indeed from Maxwelltown High School who were eager and willing to pilot our project, and other schools are lining up locally for us to roll it out across their Senior Girls aswell now that they have seen the success of it for working with young women who dont normally participate in physical activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you do any research into interest in junior derby?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I researched the physical and mental health and the generic wellbeing outcomes for derby, and applied that to a youth work setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also researched what other leagues were out there, and the way that other junior derby clubs run with regards to health and safety etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We posted out via our social media, and consulted with young women we knew to gauge interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you affiliated to any groups/organisations, either derby related or otherwise?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are affiliated with our league (Doonhame Derby Dolls) who are in the process of being affiliated with UKRDA. And the local Sports Hub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is your overall aim for your league?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To increase the health and wellbeing, self esteem / confidence, empowerment and sense of community/belonging for local young women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide a supportive and safe space for these young women as they develop into adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where would you like to be in a year, and in 5 years?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In One Year: We would like to be running a weekly out of school session for 10-13year olds, another weekly session for 13-18 year olds, and running at least one session per week as part of one of our local schools' curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be well established, well attended, have well informed adult volunteers who are skilled and confident in their youth work as well as their derby, and be having a great time with our juniors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 5 years time: all of the above plus I would like our juniors to be a strong team who are regularly bouting, travelling the country and having a blast! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you see as being important in the future of junior Derby in the UK?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To have a regulated body (something via UKRDA maybe?) which ensures all junior teams / leagues have robust policies and guidelines in place to ensure the safety of the juniors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A strong network of junior leagues across the country, and some way of ensuring Insurance is easy and accessible and doesnt create the barrier that it currently is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you think it's important to have a junior Derby infrastructure in the UK, i.e. For setting up tournaments etc.?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See my previous answer, yes I do!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>future derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/10/the-future-of-derby-junior-roller-derby-part-two/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 09:43:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Doonhame Derby Dolls: Dollfest</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/14/doonhame-derby-dolls-dollfest-2/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/dollfest.png"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/dollfest.png" alt="Image courtesy of Doonhame Derby Dolls" width="614" height="877" class="size-full wp-image-3572"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Doonhame Derby Dolls
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.doonhamederbydolls.co.uk/"&gt;Doonhame Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; present Dollfest, a series of events over the weekend of 15/16/17 August. 
For DDD members there are open forum discussions and a boot-camp featuring guest coaches from &lt;a href="http://windsorrollergirls.com/"&gt;Royal Windsor Rollergirls&lt;/a&gt;. 
For non members, a chance to meet the guest coaches, and find out about volunteering with the Doonhame Derby Dolls in a more social setting, with live music and dj's.
&lt;a href="http://www.doonhamederbydolls.co.uk/index.php/ct-menu-item-3"&gt;Contact the Dolls&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>roller derby bootcamp</category><category>roller derby bootcamps</category><category>royal windsor rollergirls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/14/doonhame-derby-dolls-dollfest-2/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 23:15:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Review 2014: Non-bouting Leagues Roundup</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/09/derby-review-2014-non-bouting-leagues-roundup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While many of our Scottish leagues have held bouts in the past year, that doesn't make the newer, or relaunching, members of the Scottish Roller Derby community any less important. New leagues are an important part of the derby community, spreading skating to places that it hasn't been before. So, let's spend a little time catching up on what the non-bouting leagues have been doing in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013, Scotland continued to gain new leagues at an impressive pace. Leaving aside Voodoo Roller Dollies (who will be covered in a different article), women's derby leagues sprouted up in Dumfries and Galloway, and in Ayrshire. As is traditional, both the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Doonhame-Derby-Dolls/161632670699789"&gt;Doonhame Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ayrshirerollerderby"&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; were founded by women who wanted to skate, but found themselves too far from the existing leagues to join one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/doonhameandfriends1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3255" alt="Doonhameandfriends1" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/doonhameandfriends1.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="408"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Doonhame Derby Dolls, and friends from GRD and Mean City Roller Derby (Sourced from DDD Facebook page.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;The Dolls have been particularly successful, as skater Claire Warner noted "Our first meet saw 50+ in attendance and that number has grown since (with over 70 paid up members now on the books)!"
As with any new league, that success was supported by the wider derby community, as Claire told us "Our first night was led by Jodie from Glasgow Roller Derby (the woman who had inspired [founders] Debz and Grace) and Cat, a Windsor Rollergirl who luckily for us had just moved to the area, and who has been coaching us ever since. We have had other guest skaters joining in and sharing their skills too, Bruisedog from Mean City, and Turbolinz from GRD came for a visit, Tessington World of Adventures from Granite City Roller Girls and Hazzard from LRG have all dropped in to share their skills, knowledge and love of derby with us, the freshest of fresh meat."&lt;/p&gt;
Doonhame have been exceptionally organised in themselves, as well. In the last four months, they've managed to set up their league branding and management structure, gain sponsorshop, and also garner a huge amount of local media attention, including a spot on ITV Borders News. They've even managed to hold two RollerDisco fundraisers, the funds from which they are planning on using to subsidise costs for skaters on low incomes.
From all of that, you would not be wrong in guessing that their plans for 2014 are.. expansive.
"There is sooo much more planned for this year too (we have just been away on a Dolls development planning weekend)!", Said Claire, "Not only do we plan to gain affiliation, sponsorships/funding to improve access opportunities for other local women, we aim to hold our own local bootcamp to help us work towards passing minimum skills, put on a demonstration bout and hopefully be scrimmaging by the end of the year. In addition to all this we are also looking to take part in local charity fundraisers, spreading the Derby Love and helping those in need in our local community. we will also be running roller disco's on a regular basis throughout the year and hopefully we are about to start organising our own junior derby league!!"
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/ayrshire2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3257" alt="Ayrshire Roller Derby's earliest skaters." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/ayrshire2.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="411"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Ayrshire Roller Derby's earliest skaters. (Sourced from ARD Facebook page)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Dolls were inspired by one Glasgow Roller Derby skater, Ayrshire Roller Derby was inspired by another. As Lorna McIlvanney told us: "We wanted to start up an Ayrshire league but thought it would be difficult and never had the time to do it. Then at Rollerstop, we spotted Sylk from GRD and approached her to see if she might be able to help us set up. She said she would give advice and help with training as and when. [...] We have had massive amounts of help from Sylk, along with various Mean City skaters. We have been invited to scrim with other leagues (once we are mins passed) and have had messages of support and offers of help from many, which has been awesome."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARD have exciting plans for 2014, as well, as Lorna explained, "We are planning on getting to as many bouts as possible and getting involved where we can e.g. as NSO's etc. Our sights are set on passing mins shortly. We have fundraising plans and recruitment drives coming up. Then, scrims for experience and hopefully we'll be ready for our very first bout. We hope to one day base ourselves in the three Ayrshire (North, East, South) and maybe have our home teams structured that way. That's further down the line obviously, but it nice to have goals."
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;⁂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;As well as the brand-new leagues of 2013, leagues founded from 2012 and earlier still continued to develop over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
In Glasgow, the &lt;a href="http://deadlydivasrollerderby.webs.com/"&gt;Deadly Divas&lt;/a&gt; experienced a hiatus for various personal reasons. A spiritual-successor league, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/renfrewshirerockinrollers"&gt;Renfrewshire Rockin' Rollers&lt;/a&gt;, also appeared, with similar stated aims, but is also currently static. RRR Co-founder, Juggs Knock'her said "At the moment due to a lot going on in our personal lives things are on hold. We plan to have a fairly relaxed approach to skating, as well as training to WFTDA rules and Renegade. We are looking to recruit both women and men. Basically derby is about fun and we hope to keep it that way."
With the Deadly Divas also hinting that they might be waking up, it remains to be seen what happens in the space of second-leagues in Glasgow.
&lt;p&gt;Moving northwards, the resurgence of Perth's &lt;a href="http://www.faircityrollers.com/"&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; continued apace in the past year. League chair Pistol Panties was excited about their continued growth, "Initially, we were holding open sessions and just trying to build our numbers up, with the rec sessions, and we have achieved that. We had a big fresh meat intake in August, funded by a local charity geared towards increasing attendance at women's sports, which was a great success and we had a great response from everyone. That really was a stroke of genius, because it allowed us to invite all Scottish leagues along to an open scrimmage, which not only meant we got to see our friends, but it allowed the girls to get a real flavour of what Roller Derby is really about. We now have good numbers of regular attendees, and a team of (very nearly) mins passed skaters."
The league even managed to one-up most of the rest of Scotland, organising a guest coaching session from Steel City Rollergirls' Shrinking Violet in June. "We worked on basic skills, which was really useful even for the more experienced skaters, we all wanted longer with her, so we did a bit of off-skates afterwards too!".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City are now holding regular fresh meat sessions, with the last one being on the 27th of January, and regular training sessions are up to 3 hours a week. "We feel excited about this year," said Pistol, "and to be in a position to be thinking about getting back to competing in the near future. Basically, the only way is up!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/icrdlogo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-3250 " alt="Inverness City Roller Derby's new, striking, logo." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/icrdlogo.jpg?w=614" width="368" height="362"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Inverness City Roller Derby's new, striking, logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inverness' Nasty Nessies Roller Girls underwent a few changes over 2013, not least a change of name and branding. The newly styled "&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/InvernessCityRollerDerby"&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;" will retain the "Nasty Nessies" name and logo for their travel team. While ICRD has not yet bouted, their skaters continue to make appearances in exhibition and cherry popper bouts hosted by other leagues, and travel to open scrims in the rest of Scotland. They've also been working on an interesting outreach project, as Scarlett O'Horror told us: "We've just completed a collaboration with &lt;a href="http://www.fixers.org.uk/"&gt;Fixers&lt;/a&gt; - a group that helps promote community participation and challenge stereotypes. We made a film with them, featuring our own lovely skaters, which will be premièred in Inverness - very exciting!"
2014 looks like being the year for roller derby in Inverness, however, "We have a lot planned for this year! We will hopefully move into a new training venue this year, and have a few more mixed bouts lined up, including participating in a bout in April, which is really exciting for us. Some very lucky members are also off to Texas to watch the World Cup in December - picking up tips and training ideas, no doubt! And t-shirts. Always t-shirts."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, at the northernmost point of Scotland, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ShetlandRollerDerby"&gt;Shetland Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; has continued to hold both derby and open skate sessions throughout the year. Men and women are welcome, and the Open skates in particular have been popular.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;⁂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;As you can see, it's been an eventful year with the growing leagues of Scotland, and 2014 promises to be even more interesting!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>deadly divas roller derby</category><category>derby review 2014</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>renfrewshire rockin' rollers</category><category>shetland roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/09/derby-review-2014-non-bouting-leagues-roundup/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 15:22:11 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>