<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about doonhame roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/doonhame-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:33 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Doonhame Roller Derby show collaboration is the way to victory.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/10/03/doonhame-roller-derby-show-collaboration-is-the-way-to-victory/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst one of the prevailing narratives in Roller Derby is that the sport is the "fastest growing female sport in the world", it's worth noting that even when this was unarguably true, growth is always unevenly distributed. In order to keep growing, a league needs enough skaters to form good bouting team, in order to get those games which build visibility and retain ambitious players. If you're a smaller team, this can be challenging!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-24847" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/10/doonhameunicorn.jpg?w=596" alt="Doonhameunicorn" width="298" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dumfriesshire's Doonhame Roller Derby have found that collaborating with other leagues is a profitable way to enable more derby, more of the time, and help grow both themselves and their collaborators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more long-term collaboration is with fellow-West-of-Scotland league, Ayrshire Roller Derby - the resulting "Doonshire" train together and have even played a closed bout, with perhaps more fixtures in the future. Doonhame's Suze MacBruise told us, "Ayrshire Roller Derby are in a very similar situation to us: they had a big shake up when they lost their regular training hall, moving them to actually training in Kilmarnock rather than Ayr. We find that, with smaller towns like ourselves and Ayrshire, that we almost get up to full team numbers, and then when the slightest thing happens we're pushed back to training again."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it's another collaboration which is providing a bigger event, as Doonhame are joining forces with Durham City Rolling Angels to take over Newcastle's &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Walker+Activity+Dome/@54.9687347,-1.5582393,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487e7068944e76d1:0xe1a6394d9f25325!8m2!3d54.9687316!4d-1.5560506"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for a special Triple Header event for Halloween.
Whilst Durham might not be the obvious collaboration, Suze told us "we also have always got on really well with DCRA, and myself and [Durham's] Clairely Psycho hatched this plan to get a game together... we got far too excited and now it has turned out to be this marvellous Halloween event, focusing on players stuck in the 'twilight zone', who've played too many games for a cherry popper, but are not quite confident enough to play advanced."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as an opening Cherry Popper bout, the remaining bouts will both be previously-unseen collaborations:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Doonhame and Durham forming the "Doom Angels" to take on an exhibition team of low/intermediate skaters&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Newcastle's Tyne and Fear joining with Teeside Skate Invaders (as the "Tyne Invaders") to take on an advanced, open/coed exhibition team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Durham and Doonhame's Halloween Triple Scrim is on Saturday&lt;strong&gt; October 28th&lt;/strong&gt; , with tickets for skaters who wish to play in any of the games available from EventBrite (&lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/halloween-triple-header-scrim-tickets-37317907867?aff=efbeventtix"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;link&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The same link also allows spectators to get a ticket to see all the lovely games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event is also in need of lovely NSOs and Referees in order to support all three bouts: if anyone is interested in joining the Officiating team, they should &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/805242299645606/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;look here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event Facebook page is: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/111674759544178/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/111674759544178/&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;for updates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>doonhame roller derby</category><category>durham rolling angels</category><category>teeside skate invaders</category><category>tyne and fear</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/10/03/doonhame-roller-derby-show-collaboration-is-the-way-to-victory/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 18:56:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2017: the year of (more) Scottish Derby?</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/08/2017-the-year-of-more-scottish-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we previously flagged, while the number of Scottish Leagues had been growing recently, the conversion of those leagues into bouting leagues had been a little slower... until 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most prominently, Perth's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/FairCityRollers/"&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (who are effectively a new league after their hiatus led to a large changeover of members) and Scotland's second-northernmost league, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://helginrollerderby.wordpress.com/"&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, will be joining forces to take their first bout together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-15876 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/packfromthedead.jpg" alt="PackFromTheDead" width="1702" height="630"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;April 16th&lt;/strong&gt;, in Perth's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Live+Active+Bell's+Sports+Centre/@56.4029941,-3.437384,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48863b152b41b60b:0x2b806df2e1d11749!8m2!3d56.4029912!4d-3.43519"&gt;Bells' Sport Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (famous for its domed roof and exceptionally shiny floor surface), &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/254873508256762/"&gt;the event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, going by the name "Pack from the Dead", will kick off as doors open at &lt;strong&gt;1pm &lt;/strong&gt;for a&lt;strong&gt; 1.30pm &lt;/strong&gt;start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking to us, Fair City said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce FCR’s comeback bout will take place in Perth on Sunday 16th April. After having a break of almost 5 years from competing, we’re back! We’ve created a brand new team of dedicated players, who’ve worked their butts off to get bout ready. FCR will be playing against Elgin’s team ‘Helgin’ at Bells Sports Centre and we want to welcome them to Perth for what will be a fantastic game. We’ve trained hard and played friendly matches against some fantastic teams, all with the aim of getting us bout ready…and now we want to shout out ‘bring it on’! 'Pack From The Dead' was the perfect name; FCR have been resurrected. Everyone is welcome, under 12s are free, please get your tickets now. Looking forward to seeing you all there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helgin Roller Derby are equally excited, with their Mane-iac telling us: "I'm very proud of how far Helgin has come as a club over the last two and a half years. We've come a long way from our very first days as a group of 4 girls attempting to skate in a small hall, to having a team of mins-passed skaters and preparing to play in our first game. Just thinking about playing in this game gives me butterflies, it's such an achievement for the club, and an exciting and momentous day for all the skaters. I can't wait to put on my Helgin uniform, skate on track as a team and show everyone what Helgin's made of!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fellow skater Bruteyvicious agrees, "It's a pretty momentous occasion. It was just a fantasy for us a year ago, but we moved steadily and grew together until we reached this point. We've played in many scrims between us but actually playing as a team together is really going to feel special! This is why I joined Derby, to play alongside my team in a sport I love. We will give 100% and will continue to do so and strive to keep playing and improving. I'm confident we can hold our own in our first bout. I can only imagine the adrenaline I'll feel on the day, I really can't wait."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it's not just Helgin and Fair City who are planning to hold their first bouts this year.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.invernessrollerderby.com/"&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are also planning to bout before 2017 is out, with a date scheduled for 19th August. Whilst we know ICRD will be hosting the bout, almost everything else (including their opponent) is not public at this time - as soon as there is an official announcement to be made, we will be highlighting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the other end of the country, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DoonhameDerbyDolls/"&gt;Doonhame Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, of Dumfries, are also planning their first public bout, although even less details are available than for ICRD. We hope to bring you details in the second half of the year!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>doonhame roller derby</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/08/2017-the-year-of-more-scottish-derby/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 14:01:15 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>