<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about drg)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/drg.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Rising Stars and Bs at Aberdeen!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/05/rising-stars-and-bs-at-aberdeen/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Granite City Roller Derby's Northern Fights have been a little distracted by British Champs in the first half of this year, leaving GCRD B, the Fight Hawks to play their home games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7236" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/4627878756.jpg" alt="4627878756" width="757" height="1069"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.granitecityrollerderby.co.uk/blog/4584694771"&gt;This weekend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; sees the trend for Scottish Double Headers with Rising Stars bouts continue as Aberdeen's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Beach+Leisure+Centre/@57.155602,-2.082094,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48840e4028217933:0x30c6b9176815da5b!8m2!3d57.155602!4d-2.0799"&gt;Beach Leisure Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; hosts the Fight Hawks taking on Dundee's B team, the Bonnie Colliders, introduced by two teams of newer skaters from around the country demonstrating their talent (and getting experience to boot).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With doors opening at &lt;strong&gt;12:30pm, May 7th&lt;/strong&gt;, this is an ideal opportunity to see these skaters, many of whom are from the several new Scottish leagues which are still working towards their first bouts, on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second bout is an unpredictable&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt; match up between Scotland's newer B teams, which should be an unmissable event. Both the Bonnie Colliders and the Fight Hawks have been working hard to develop themselves over the past year, and, while the Fight Hawks are probably the underdogs, the home team advantage could well give them the edge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that isn't enough incentive, the refreshment stall will be raising money for&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.justgiving.com/fundraising/ChristophersCLANChallenge"&gt; Christopher's CLAN Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a 12 month fundraising effort to raise £20k for teenagers and their families affected by cancer in the NE of Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always with GCRD's home games, entry is completely &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;literally, FlatTrackStats can't compare the teams, and has incomplete entries for GCRD B!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>gcrd</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>rising stars</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/05/rising-stars-and-bs-at-aberdeen/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 11:29:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs T3 North: Gameday 1</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/02/british-champs-t3-north-gameday-1/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;Of the six leagues that make up Tier 3 Regional North of this year’s British Roller Derby Championships – Dundee Roller Girls, Fierce Valley Roller Girls, Hallam Hellcats Roller Derby, Hull’s Angels Roller Dames, Manchester Roller Derby and Preston Roller Girls – only one competed at the same level last year: Dundee Roller Girls, who finished third in the table, with a record of three wins to two losses.  H.A.R.D. and Manchester Roller Derby both took part in Tier 2 National North, where Manchester beat H.A.R.D. in their encounter.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;Each of the other leagues moved up from Tier 4, Fierce Valley Roller Girls and Preston Roller Girls from T4 Local North as winners and runners up, and Hallam Hellcats from T4 Local Central North, as runners up.  The three teams faced off in the T4 North play-offs in November, where Hallam Hellcats beat Fierce Valley and Preston overcame Wolverhampton Honour Rollers to make the play-off final.  Hallam Hellcats took the victory on the day, and both leagues were promoted by making the final.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6023" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/fvrg1.jpg" alt="fvrg1" width="960" height="640"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;For Fierce Valley Roller Girls, T3 North contains some very familiar foes: both Dundee Roller Girls and Preston Roller Girls have faced FVRG on three occasions.  Dundee currently hold the edge with two victories to one, while FVRG have won each of their games against Preston.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6024" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/fvrg2.jpg" alt="fvrg2" width="960" height="640"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;Gameday 1 took place on Saturday 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; of February, in Preston.  The first game of the day saw FVRG take on H.A.R.D. before Dundee faced the host team.  From the first whistle, the game was very competitive, with neither team giving much ground.  H.A.R.D. took an early lead with some controlled offensive play before FVRG began to gain a foothold in the game.  Despite H.A.R.D.’s rock solid walls and good offensive play from both teams, FVRG’s jammers were finding a way through, and the first half ended with FVRG in the lead.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;H.A.R.D. started the second half very strongly, living up to their name with strong offensive play and big hits, to narrow the points gap.  Both teams fought hard and were fairly evenly matched through the second half, with the result that the score was tied at 171-171 heading into the final few jams.  Just when we thought the tension couldn’t get any higher, FVRG took the lead by one point and the jam ended with just 3 seconds on the clock.  With a time-out called by H.A.R.D., one final jam was played and a final lead change occurred, H.A.R.D. eventually winning the game by 182-178.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6022" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/drg2.jpg" alt="drg2" width="960" height="598"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span id="ecxyui_3_16_0_1_1456924961619_4040"&gt;Dundee's Silvery Tayzers travelled to Preston for their first Champs game of the season, having never met the home team before. Both teams set up in a very similar fashion using strong defensive walls and some useful offense for their jammers to take. Dundee started the game well with Preston giving away a powerjam in the first jam, allowing Dundee to move into a quick lead. Dundee were able to build on this with some good defence and recycling from their blockers allowing the jammers to score valuable points and extend the lead into halftime with the score 53 - 158 in Dundee's favour. The second half followed in the same fashion with both teams playing some great offense and Preston picking up some more points, but Dundee were able to see out the game with a 111-262 victory. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6021" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/drg1.jpg" alt="drg1" width="960" height="640"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;The next date in the T3 calendar is 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; March, when Dundee will travel to Manchester to take on the hosts, and Preston will face H.A.R.D.  The all-Scottish clash is next up at the FVRG-hosted double header on 23&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; April, which will also feature Manchester against Hallam Hellcats.  Dundee welcome H.A.R.D. at home on 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; May, when FVRG will also face Hallam Hellcats.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;Photos courtesy of Johannes von Voges&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bout reports</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/02/british-champs-t3-north-gameday-1/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 16:40:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lothian Derby Dolls Vs Dundee Roller Girls Bonnie Colliders 13 Feb 2016</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/02/19/lothian-derby-dolls-vs-dundee-roller-girls-bonnie-colliders-13-feb-2016/</link><dc:creator>kj782</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bout review by Fully Harmed &amp;amp; Killah Jules of Lothian Derby Dolls.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;57&lt;/strong&gt; v’s DRG &lt;em&gt;Bonnie Colliders&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;414&lt;/strong&gt;
13 Feb 2016, Jack Kane Sports Centre, Edinburgh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5808" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/12751972_10153290311725025_1687578989_o.jpg" alt="12751972_10153290311725025_1687578989_o" width="1080" height="720"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5807" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/12765729_10153290313055025_364153108_o.jpg" alt="12765729_10153290313055025_364153108_o" width="1080" height="720"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photographs by Laura MacDonald&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the first bout of the year for LDD and we fielded a team with mixed levels of experience, with a few skaters injured or away having babies. We felt this was a good opportunity to give our newer skaters some experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt; The Bonnie Colliders dominated the game with strong blockers making holes in the LDD walls for nippy jammers to take advantage of.  LDD had a hard time reforming their defensive walls and then lost three skaters from the game due to penalties. The second half was more positive for LDD with Fi-Nix taking an epic star pass from Jugz and Tea Wrecks hitting out her first jammer in competitive play.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;LDD's heads never went down despite getting beaten by such a wide margin. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5806" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/12755250_10153290315560025_1787426263_o.jpg" alt="12755250_10153290315560025_1787426263_o" width="1080" height="720"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photograph by Laura MacDonald&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;In roller derby things change quickly and we will be training hard until our next bout on the &lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt;th of &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt; against Mean City in Glasgow.  &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1555212058123782/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1555212058123782/ &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout reports</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>ldd</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/02/19/lothian-derby-dolls-vs-dundee-roller-girls-bonnie-colliders-13-feb-2016/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 17:43:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls - Review of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/20/dundee-roller-girls-review-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>julezw</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year was set to be one of the busiest for DRG with their involvement in British Championships meaning a lot of travel around the north, as well as a few home games and a full Home Teams tournament. &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/hubs.png" rel="attachment wp-att-5255"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-5255 alignright" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/hubs.png?w=300" alt="Hubs" width="220" height="218"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
What followed was a hectic season with the Tayzers playing more games both home and away than ever before.
First up was a repeat of the first game of the previous season against Granite City, but this time as part of Tier 3 North for British Championships. This was a slightly surreal game, playing one of our closest neighbours in Rainy City’s Thunderdome in Oldham. DRG’s Tayzers again took the win, 366-58.
The following game against Halifax was forfeited by Halifax, giving DRG a 300- 0 victory.
The next few months saw the Tayzers take on Liverpool, Sheffield and Furness in the final three champs fixtures. Two losses (Liverpool 152-115 and Furness (173-108) and one victory (Sheffield 190-135), meant that DRG finished a very respectable 3rd in the first champs season, only narrowly missing out on a playoff place.
With the tiers having been rearranged for next season DRG will be looking to progress from this and aim for promotion.
The autumn began with the Tayzers and Bonnie Colliders playing some home games. The Colliders team was all change from last season, with the game being the first for many. Their first opponents were the Dollie Mixtures (a mix of skaters from leagues across Scotland). The Dollie Mixtures experience showed and they came out on 185-110. The second game of the day saw the Tayzers take on another DRG in the form of Dorset Roller Girls. The home DRG took the win 195-104.
Following on from this in October, the Colliders took on Newtown, winning 234-76 and the Tayzers victorious in a very tense and close game against Dublin B team 238-195.
November held the final games for the Bonnie Colliders and Silvery Tayzers. The Colliders were taking on BCR’s Central Belters with the visiting team taking the win 171-95. The Tayzers then had their first experience of European opposition with the visit of Kallio Rolling Rainbow’s B team the Kinapori Fistfunkers all the way from Helsinki. This was a really exciting game to watch with a different style of play from the Finns who ultimately came out on top with a 261-134 win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/colliders.png" rel="attachment wp-att-5254"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-5254 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/colliders.png?w=300" alt="colliders" width="361" height="131"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The season ended with the second full Home Teams tournament. This provided a great opportunity for some of our newer skaters to take part in full games and gain some experience before the start of the new season. Again all three teams played against each other, with the final ending in a nail-biting finish. The Press Gangsters held on to their trophy from last season, edging the win over the Jutes of Hazzard (131-128).
This year, Dundee’s officials have continued to grow both in number and experience - DRG now have nine on-skates officials and have officiated numerous tournaments and events in the last year. DRG officials have staffed games in almost all of the British Champs tier levels for both men and women (including a divisional head referee for women's tier 2), dozens of games around Scotland, many in England and several in Europe. The officials have also been to several tournaments, including Furness Firecracker's Sur5al bonanza in Blackpool, BEARDi in Cannock, 4Nations in Birmingham and Beach Brawl in Fort Lauderdale (USA). Officials' training continues in strength with both monthly on skates and off skates sessions. Several of the officials recently sat the infamous "Hellahard" rules test for WFTDA certification (some of which even passed!) and refs will be testing their skate skills out for certification at the last training session of the year thanks to Auld Reekie Roller Girls. Righteous Oxide also recently featured in the local newspaper as part of their 20 questions section in the sporting post.
2015 was a fantastic season for DRG with all skaters and officials gaining valuable experience to take into 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos courtesy of Dave McAleavy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>drg</category><category>home season tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/20/dundee-roller-girls-review-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 11:20:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Final Champs game for DRG</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/04/final-champs-game-for-drg/</link><dc:creator>julezw</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girls Silvery Tayzers will travel to Sheffield this Saturday (8th August) to compete in the final triple header of the British Championships T3 Regional North. After securing victory against Sheffield Steel Roller Girls in July, Dundee have left themselves in a great position to secure a play-off spot. Victory against Furness Firecrackers will see Dundee progress but with three teams still in with a chance (Furness Firecrackers, Liverpool Roller Birds and Dundee), it’s all to play for. Last time the teams met, Dundee emerged victorious and will be looking for a similar outcome this time round.
In the days other games, GCRG take on Halifax Bruising Banditas and hosts Sheffield take on Liverpool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ssrg.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4836" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ssrg.png?w=214" alt="SSRG" width="214" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come down and join the fun!
Concord Sports Centre, Shiregreen Lane, Sheffield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors 9.30am.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/04/final-champs-game-for-drg/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 16:32:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls: Roundup of 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/28/dundee-roller-girls-roundup-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We caught up with &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee&lt;/a&gt;'s Julia "Crown Julez" Wright to get the story of the league's 2014:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/735097_492237780841642_237571758_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4501" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/735097_492237780841642_237571758_n.jpg?w=300" alt="Dundee Roller Girls logo." width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Dundee Roller Girls logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girls' Silvery Tayzers started the year with their first game against old rivals Granite City Roller Girls Northern Fights in Aberdeen. The Tayzers had never beaten GCRG in their previous games but after an almighty comeback by GCRG in the second half the Tayzers finally came out winners with a 182 – 83 victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What followed was a hectic season with the Tayzers playing more games both home and away than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An away win against Newcastle’s Whippin Hinnies (131 -163), was closely followed by home defeat to Hulls Angels Roller Dames in the most dramatic of overtime jam finishes. Furness Firecrackers were the next team to make the trip to Dundee and were defeated 178 – 157 in a thrilling match-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May saw one of the most exciting developments in DRG history, with the launch of our Home Teams Season. Assisted by the Big Lottery Fund, DRG were awarded £2000 to develop the Home Teams brand. Sticking close to Dundee’s Jute, Jam and Journalism history, three teams were created; The Jutes of Hazzard, Jammin’ Dodgers and the Press Gangsters. After a summer season of Home Teams games, the Jutes and Press Gangsters fought it out for the trophy with the Press Gangsters triumphing in the final 163 - 108.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10628596_10100312218540564_7362283630468818259_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-4500" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10628596_10100312218540564_7362283630468818259_n.jpg?w=614" alt="Dundee's Rising Stars, post Bairn City bout (Photo: Laura MacDonald)" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Dundee's Rising Stars, post Bairn City bout (Photo: Laura MacDonald)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late summer also saw the first game for DRG’s B team with the Rising Stars defeating Durham Roller Derby by a single point in nail-biting game (172 – 171). The Silvery Tayzers were also in action on this double-header day being defeated by a hard-hitting Roller Derby Leicester team (107 – 228).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second double header pitted the Rising Stars against Team White and the Tayzers playing Halifax’s Bruising Banditas, with both teams securing victories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The autumn began with the Tayzers playing two away games to FVRG and their furthest away trip to Swansea. Both games ended in defeat for the Tayzers but they left with a great deal of experience gained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tayzers final game of the season was another against an old rival; Glasgow Roller Derby’s Maiden Grrders, a team the Tayzers had yet to record a win against. After a brilliant match-up between the two teams, the Tayzers managed to pull off a memorable victory defeating the Maidens 181 -143.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;November held the final games for the Rising Stars who were trying to maintain their 100% record in their debut season. Two victories against Voodoo Roller Dollies and Bairn City’s Central Belters saw the Rising Stars achieve this record and with it brought the end of a memorable season for DRG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five of DRG headed off to Dallas in December for the Blood and Thunder Roller Derby World Cup in Dallas, Texas. Representing the league were; Milky (Team Scotland Skater), Jill Antonic (Team Scotland Manager), Righteous Oxide (member of referee crew), Crazily InSanne (Team Netherlands Skater) and Twiggy Ramirez (Volunteer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2014 was a fantastic season for DRG with some tense victories, heart-breaking losses and masses of experience gained. With the development of the British Championships, DRG are looking forward to 2015 with a positive outlook and great expectations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 in review</category><category>articles</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/28/dundee-roller-girls-roundup-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 09:33:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Parma Violents vs. Silvery Tayzers</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/26/parma-violents-vs-silvery-tayzers/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Saturday 6th September, FVRG's Parma Violents will take on DRG's Silvery Tayzers in Grangemouth Sports Complex. Doors open at 3:30pm, with the game starting at 4pm.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;The two teams first met in February 2012 in the Parma Violents first public game. Although the Silvery Tayzers took home the victory, the Parma Violents jumped at the chance for a rematch in November 2013, and again for the chance to play them again next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Tickets are available online from &lt;a title="Buy Tickets Online" href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/836544" target="_blank"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt; for £5 (+ admin fee), or £7 on the door. Under 14s go free with a paying adult.  Join FVRG's &lt;a title="FVRG Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1515534441994379/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt; for more information - and details on their ticket give-away competition!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/header.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3632" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/header.jpg" alt="Image courtesy of Fierce Valley Roller Girls" width="614" height="292"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Fierce Valley Roller Girls
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>parma violents</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/26/parma-violents-vs-silvery-tayzers/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 18:50:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls: Home Season Final</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/22/dundee-roller-girls-home-season-final/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/10265400_685889494809802_8521628737669787681_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/10265400_685889494809802_8521628737669787681_o.jpg" alt="Image courtesy of Dundee Roller Girls" width="511" height="720" class="size-full wp-image-3604"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Dundee Roller Girls
&lt;p&gt;A little part of &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; history will be made with the conclusion of their first Home Season this weekend.
Taking their cues from the history of the City, DRG named their Home Teams after three of the most iconic Dundee exports, jute, jam and journalism. The Jutes of Hazzard, Jammin' Dodgers and Press Gangsters battled it out over the last few months, in a series of fairly balanced games, each team taking a win.
The season kicked off back in May, the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Press-Gangsters/246335275570905?fref=ts"&gt;Press Gangsters&lt;/a&gt; won in a hard fought game, in which they gradually asserted their authority, particularly so in the second half, over the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Jutesofhazzard?fref=ts"&gt;Jutes Of Hazzard&lt;/a&gt;, final score 198-126.
The debut of the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/jammindodgers?fref=ts"&gt;Jammin' Dodgers&lt;/a&gt; in game 2 saw them lose in the biggest point differential of the season, with the Jutes Of Hazzard making up for their loss in their first outing with a final score of 234-134.
The last game came right down to the wire in the last jam, but the Jammin' Dodgers edged the Press Gangsters by a single point, 148-147.
The final will be a double header, with the first bout featuring the third place Jammin' Dodgers against an exhibition team comprised of skaters from Auld Reekie Roller Girls, Bairn City Rollers, Glasgow Roller Derby, Granite City Roller Girls and New Town Roller Girls. The second bout, the first ever Dundee Roller Girls Home Season final, will see the Jutes of Hazzard take on the Press Gangsters. 
More information on the Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1526146167612767/"&gt;event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>jammin' dodgers</category><category>jutes of hazzard</category><category>press gangsters</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/22/dundee-roller-girls-home-season-final/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 00:34:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hinnies Head for Scotland - Newcastle Roller Girls on their Month of Scottish Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/05/27/hinnies-head-for-scotland-newcastle-roller-girls-on-their-month-of-scottish-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Up in Scotland, we're no strangers to &lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.org.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;; they've played most of our established leagues over the last few years. This year, however, they've made slightly more of an impression, scheduling 4 bouts against Scottish leagues all within the month of May!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we approach the last of those dates, which sees Newcastle's B-team (The Whippin' Hinnies) take on &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie&lt;/a&gt;'s B Cannon Belles in Edinburgh on the 31st, we thought we'd have a chat to Newcastle's A and B teams about their experience so far, and some other exciting things that have happened in the last few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/theasaurus-wrecks.jpg"&gt;&lt;img id="i-3456" class="size-full wp-image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/theasaurus-wrecks.jpg?w=615" alt="Theasaurus Wrecks"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big event was always planned to be the one Newcastle hosted, a double-header at their usual venue, the Walker Activity Dome, featuring the Whippin' Hinnies taking on &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee&lt;/a&gt;'s Silvery Tayzers, followed by Newcastle A, the Canny Belters, facing off against &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; B, the Maiden Grrders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hinnies had previously taken on Dundee at the Into The Nitemare organised tournament, Battle of Britain, in November last year. Battling for the title, the Hinnies won with 60 points to Dundee's 51, in an extremely low scoring bout.
Theasaurus Wrecks, Hinnies Captain both for that bout and this year, remembers it fondly: “Battle of Britain was amazing. We were the underdogs, and I always think we perform really well as underdogs. ... we had a fantastic bench who knew the rules very well, and that worked incredibly well to our advantage. We also had a really strong team at the time with a lot of great crossovers [skaters who are on the 20 player pools for both the A and B teams, and thus eligible to roster for either].”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming into the Dundee bout this year, the team composition was a little different, the Hinnies roster having collected newer, less experienced skaters in the interim. In addition, Dundee's Tayzers had already demonstrated a very powerful team for the new year, with an impressive win over &lt;a href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/"&gt;Granite City&lt;/a&gt; at the end of March. So, it should not, perhaps, have been surprising that the first game of the double header went to Dundee Roller Girls, 163 to 131.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That the score was that close was a testament to the Hinnies' grit and determination, “In the first section of the 2nd half, the Hinnies were quite battered and feeling a bit down about it, but we kinda escalated away and picked up 70 pts in 15 minutes or so. So we sort of really brought it back in,” Thea told us, adding, “[it] shows what a psychological game roller derby is as well. Quite often if you start to think that you're losing it, then you kind of lose your psychological game and sort of give up. If you're willing to battle through to the end, then you can bring it back 'round to your favour.” While the Hinnies didn't quite manage that this time around, Dundee certainly felt the need to work hard, “They said to us afterwards that it was one of the best games they'd played in a long time, because they'd felt really challenged by it as well.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/gin-jamming-close-up.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3458" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/gin-jamming-close-up.jpg?w=614" alt="Gin and Sonic, on track." width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Gin and Sonic, on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the second bout of the day was not to happen, as a leak in the roof of the Walker Activity Dome began to let water on to the track during the inter-game break. With the referees ruling the track unsafe as long as water continued to fall, there was no choice but to call off the game. The Belters' Gin and Sonic was not alone in feeling extremely frustrated by the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So, you think when you play an &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;indoor &lt;/span&gt;sport that it will go ahead rain or shine... Our home venue is in many ways the perfect space for roller derby, and it’s not long since it was refurbished, so to say we were gutted when our GRD bout was rained off after a leaky roof issue is a MASSIVE understatement. We have so much love for GRD, they were really understanding (not to mention incredibly patient on the day while we waited to hear if the bout could go ahead safely...) and we’re hoping to reschedule very soon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently Newcastle are in negotiations with Newcastle City Council to resolve their venue issues – either by fixing the roof or getting a new venue – but they are determined not to let it affect their schedule at all. (Their next home fixture, seeing the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/486333931501291/?ref=5"&gt;Belters take on Birmingham Blitz Dames (in a double header with Tyne and Fear v The Inhuman League)&lt;/a&gt; is still on for the 7th of June, in the Centre for Sport, on the West Road, and has been rescheduled to a later time (but the same date) as a result.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Breaking News, added to this document after publication: The cancelled Glasgow Roller Derby bout has been rescheduled for June 28th, and will be hosted by &lt;em&gt;Glasgow&lt;/em&gt; at their usual venue, the ARC, as a replacement to the previously scheduled Glasgow A v Hot Wheels game (which is now cancelled).]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/theasurus-jamming.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3459" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/theasurus-jamming.jpg?w=614" alt="Theasaurus, pushing past the final blocker." width="614" height="614"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Theasaurus, pushing past Dundee's Milky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the loss of their venue is a setback, it didn't affect the next Scottish bout for the Hinnies, as they travelled up to Stirling to play &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' Parma Violents. This was a return bout, as Fierce Valley had travelled down to Newcastle in April 2013, and while a Newcastle win was expected, the Hinnies weren't going to relax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thea noted “the Hinnies, being a B-Team, being dynamic, is always changing, so we had a completely different lineup to the Dundee game. ... I'm one of the few people who's been with the Hinnies all this time, as the Team Captain, so yeah, we had a great opportunity with FVRG that we could try out lots of new players. So we had 1 brand new player, and 3 or 4 players who'd only played 1 or 2 games before, that was a really good learning curve for a lot of the newer people in the team.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And indeed, taking the opportunity to gain experience for the newer skaters still paid off, with the Hinnies pulling out a close (201 to 169) win – less than predicted, but nothing to sneeze at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we look ahead to the final bout in Newcastle's packed Scottish schedule (and it is exciting for multiple reasons), we should note that Scotland is not the &lt;span style="font-weight:bold;"&gt;only &lt;/span&gt;place that Newcastle Roller Girls have been involved with recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/gin-sonic-high-fives.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3460" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/gin-sonic-high-fives.jpg?w=614" alt="Gin and Sonic, taking high-fives post bout." width="614" height="345"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Gin and Sonic, taking high-fives post bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a start, three of the Canny Belters have made the roster for Team Wales Roller Derby, and will be playing for the Valleys in the Blood and Thunder World Cup in December. Gin and Sonic was one of the three, and was happy to talk to us about her choice of Wales over England:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was eligible to try out for both England and Wales. I tried out for England on a bit of a whim and really steeled my resolve to try out for Wales and gave it everything I have. I’m so glad I did as we have a really great team and they make me really proud of my Welsh side. It’s been brilliant sharing the try out process with [fellow Belters] Hit One Purl One and Marie Bayonet as we’ve been each other’s cheerleaders and it’s great having travel buddies for long trips to training! NRG have been so supportive of us and I know we’re going to learn lots from the experience and bring it all back to Newcastle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Belters have been getting skaters onto National teams, the Hinnies have gone the international route, playing their first European away bout against Eindhoven's Rockcity Rollers in January. Winning by a single point, the experience has whetted the Hinnies' appetite for Euroderby, in Thea's words: “That was one of the most Emotional games [she laughs] that I've ever played. It was really close.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While normally it would be the A team that gets into International derby first, in this case it was an existing connection that brought the Hinnies to the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It came about because we had a skater from &lt;a href="http://www.domcitydolls.com/"&gt;Dom City&lt;/a&gt; which is in Utrect. She came over and skated with NRG for three months, and we kind of just built up a really good friendship. So she said that since they were kind of an up and coming league, they would love to have us come over and do some coaching.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanting to get as much our of the trip as possible, the Hinnies found &lt;a href="http://rockcityrollers.nl/"&gt;Rockcity Rollers&lt;/a&gt;, ranked very closely to them, in Eindhoven, and managed to arrange a bout for the dates they were over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thea is still emotional about the event “we'd been travelling for ages, and it was a covered outdoor venue, and it just... it just was so close.
In final jam, we had our jammer, Torville and Scream, up and I saw her calling it off, and I didn't even know if she'd made the points, but she just was absolutely shattered, so she had to call it off and we were all there holding our breath just hoping that she'd picked up the points, and she had, so it was amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that was the first game that my parents had ever seen me play, so they said they kind of got how exciting roller derby could be from that game.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And more international bouts might be on the cards:
“I think it's all about funding and finances. I think I'd really like to play Amsterdam. One Love is really good as well, I would like to play a lot more teams of similar to us in the rankings, cause the games that we've had recently with Scottish teams have all been so challenging, and so exciting, and really pushing us to our limit. And that's really .. when you learn a lot about your team.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Canny Belters, meanwhile, are focussed on the American side of International derby, as Gin and Sonic revealed: “we’re dead proud of our Hinnies flying the NRG flag in Europe earlier this year and the Canny Belters have big aspirations for the next year! We became WFTDA apprentices earlier this year and we’re hoping to graduate as full members very soon. We’ll be focussing on the Northern Series which is a round robin of UKRDA/WFTDA games between Leeds Roller Dolls, Rainy City Roller Girls and Middlesbrough Milk Rollers. Hopefully our first round of WFTDA sanctioned bouts will put us in a good ranking position to go further afield in 2015. We’re itching to go a big international tournament like ARRG and Glasgow!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it's only an hour and a half from Newcastle to Edinburgh, the Belters will surely be discussing how to dominate America with Auld Reekie's Twisted Thistles, as both watch their B team sistren play this coming weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This looks like being a particularly close fought bout, with the rankings very close between the teams. Theasaurus Wrecks agrees, “
[I'm] Really excited. This is going to be the highlight of the year, I think. I think it's going to be the toughest challenge that the Hinnies have had; obviously ARRG are a really strong team, they've got a fantastic foundation, fantastic coaching from their A Team, they're in a really strong position on the table. So I'm really looking forward to us having that real focused challenge, and trying to achieve the best that we can for that. Having a battle - it's going to be very tough.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is not all, as Fierce Valley's junior derby league, the &lt;a href="http://www.fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs&lt;/a&gt;, are making a debut appearance at half-time, with a demonstration scrim. The Cubs are all big derby fans as Thea has already discovered, “I'm really excited to see that! They sent a really nice email to us, asking if we could do a photo with them at the end. I'm looking forward to that one :D”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe she'd sign an autograph or two as well (as the Cubs have been known to collect in the past)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;laughs&lt;/em&gt; Oh, I'm looking forward to it.
I feel like a minor celebrity(!)”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hinnies won't be the only celebrities present, either. Recently, Auld Reekie revealed that (known derby fan) Phill Jupitus will be co-announcing the bout, alongside long-standing ARRG announcer Stephen Tawking.
“I have noticed, that on QI, he's worn Kent Roller Girls t-shirts quite a bit, so I'm hoping that he'll wear ARRG and Newcastle shirts after this bout,” said Thea. We're pretty sure that Phill will end up getting freebie tshirts from all the leagues present after this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to see the Whippin Hinnies take on Auld Reekie Roller Girls on Saturday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;31 May, doors open at 2pm, for skateout at 2:30. Tickets can be bought at
&lt;a href="http://m.bpt.me/event/643612"&gt;http://m.bpt.me/event/643612
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Newcastle Roller Girls' Theasaurus Wrecks, Gin and Sonic, and PR Pretty Skate Machine.
All photographs from Newcastle Roller Girls - photographers please contact me for attribution!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was edited after publication to include details of the rescheduling of the GRD v NRG bout, and to improve cross-linking to league pages.
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>cannon belles</category><category>canny belters</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>interviews</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>nrg</category><category>parma violents</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>whippin hinnies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/05/27/hinnies-head-for-scotland-newcastle-roller-girls-on-their-month-of-scottish-derby/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 18:55:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Review 2014: Dundee Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/14/derby-review-2014-dundee-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another day, another league Review for 2013. Moving a little further North than the last few, Silvery Tayzers Captain Psychomilly was happy to talk about &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/img_0341-copy.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3158" alt="Dundee Roller Girls taking on Lothian Derby Dolls at Battle of Britain (Photo: Laura MacDonald)" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/img_0341-copy.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Dundee Roller Girls taking on Lothian Derby Dolls at Battle of Britain (Photo: Laura MacDonald)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compared to 2012, 2013 has been a slightly more mixed year for the Silvery Tayzers; a couple of losses at the start of the season against Rainy City and Glasgow's Maiden Grrders, followed by an improving streak (a narrow loss against Newcastle's Whippin' Hinnies, and an almost unbroken winning streak since). You said last year that Dundee were aiming higher for their competition in 2013; how did you work to raise your game and fight back over the year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team has worked really hard this year to push our skills and to keep our tactics current with the new rules set introduced. We saw more losses this year than last, but we really were playing with the big girls this year! Over the year I think we settled into our new roster and became more comfortable working together as a team. In the latter half of the year, we took our tactics back to basics and worked on developing our skills together, which definitely paid off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There's also been several changes to the roster over 2013, starting the season with several regulars missing or moved to other locations, and then Suffra-Jet moving to Glasgow to join GRD in the middle of the year, and Cult Friction moving to Edinburgh to join ARRG (and changing her skatename!), ending with Dr Carnage's last bout You've also picked up a bunch of new (or returning) skaters, who we saw in the last few bouts of the year. How are you adapting to the changing makeup of Dundee this year? Do you think this kind of cyclic mutability is good for the team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DRG have always had a pretty fluid roster as we're a university team - there's two universitys in Dundee, but it's a small city when it comes to finding a job, so a lot of our veteran skaters have moved for the sake of their careers. It's always hard to see someone you've trained with leave, but we're so, so proud of everyone who has moved on and become even more skilled.
This season, we've had some absolutely inspirational skaters move from newbies to Tayzers almost seamlessly. Having so many new skaters get on the Tayzer's roster has meant that as a team we've worked even harder to bond on track and to support each other. BoB and our home game against FVRG were the most 'together' I felt the team all year and it's a total pleasure to skate with so many committed new skaters. I think having new skaters move up to the Tayzers is good for us as a team - they bring fresh ideas and their enthusiasm and motivation is infectious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With all the preparation for the second ever (Women's) Roller Derby World Cup in 2014, several of Dundee's skaters have been trying out for national teams. Crazily InSanne got into Team Netherlands, and there's a few of your skaters who attended the Team Scotland first round tryouts. It's a great thing for Scottish derby to have skaters featured in potentially multiple national teams… do you see more of this and other international involvement in Dundee's future?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm so excited to see DRG represented at the World Cup. Sanne has gone from strength to strength this year and I think you'd struggle to find someone more committed to the sport. Her behind the scenes work to keep our team running as well as the time she spends honing her skills, fitness and knowledge is outstanding. It'd be a total dream to represent DRG as part of Team Scotland, but the competition is so, so high!
I'd love to see Dundee more involved in international derby, particularly now that there's more and more leagues in Europe visiting Scotland. Hopefully this year we can experience our first international bout!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking outside of Dundee, there's been a continuing growth in Scottish Roller Derby over 2013, with Bairn City Rollers, Lothian Derby Dolls and New Town Roller Girls all holding their first bouts this year. Dundee played two of those league already, and donated a skater or two to New Town's cherry popping bout roster. Now that Dundee is firmly in the upper-half of Scottish teams in terms of experience, do you feel you have a responsibility to newer teams? How does the increasing breadth of derby spread interact with how you see DRG placing itself in Scotland?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expansion of derby in Scotland this year has been amazing. We've found the newer leagues have provided a great opportunity for some of our newer skaters to get involved with scrimmages and bouts with skaters of their level. We've also seen skaters from a lot of the newer leagues in Scotland visiting us for our open scrimmages, which is a really good way of sharing learning and techniques, as well as getting to know the leagues better. In the beginning, DRG received so much training and advice from the larger leagues at the time, we realise how important it is to be supported by more experienced teams. We love to help out other leagues in any way we can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This was the first year Dundee Roller Girls played in a tournament, signing up to IntotheNitemare's Battle of Britain at the last minute due to cancellations. Despite Newcastle pipping you to the top spot, Dundee did very well - are you planning on more tournaments after this experience? How did the tournament compare to the usual single-bout context?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd love to take part in more tournaments. It's a fantastic way of bonding as a team and I think we kept the momentum going throughout the day. I couldn't have been any more proud to captain DRG at the tournament. We worked together so well as a team - particularly with 6 skaters new to the Tayzers. BoB was one of my favourite experiences in derby.
I think tournaments differ to single bouts in that it's over just as you get into your stride. Keeping the motivation and morale up through the day was really important to us - we had a team quiz, a poster of the roster made up of pugs and a gold-star system of goals to keep us all focused and smiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For much of this year, Dundee have continued their support of Co-ed Derby with the Dundee Co-ed Scrims continuing to be extremely popular for skaters across Scotland, and the Jakey Tayzers returning to play more co-ed derby on track. How's Dundee's relationship with Co-Ed developed over the year? Will the Jakey Tayzers remain a more exhibition team, or is there possibility of a more formal arrangement?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dundee have always supported co-ed derby and will continue to do so. This year we've moved to having monthly co-ed scrimmages. Co-ed is a great way to challenge ourselves, as skating with men means we have to skate that little bit smarter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the Jakey Tayzers...I think we already see ourselves as more than an exhibition team. Still unbeaten!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On a personal note, you’ve had a busy year: referreeing at as many bouts as you’ve played in, appearing on Team Steve for Scotland’s first Men v Women bout against the Jakey Bites, as well as regaining the captaincy of Dundee for the last bouts of the season (and trying out for Team Scotland(!)). How do you fit it all the derby in? Is there a temptation to choose one or other of refereeing or bouting?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been really lucky over the past few years, with ARRG and GRD giving me the opportunity to officiate loads of their bouts, including my first WFTDA Sanctioned bouts, which was a total honour. I also loved reffing the Men's European Roller Derby Champs. It was an incredible experience and I met loads of really inspirational officials. I'm also lucky to have such a supportive home league who've given me the opportunity to captain them again and help build the team and I've had the most fun bouting with them this year, especially at Battle of Britain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart is definitely still in bouting, I love DRG, though I do often get told that I'll have to choose either skating or officiating eventually. I find that a really strange idea and one that I think only female officials seem to be pushed into - I can think of a number of male skaters who skate high level derby who also officiate, but women in the same situation seem to be expected to choose one or the other. Until my schedule means I can't manage both, I'm happy sharing my time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, can you let us in on any of Dundee Roller Girls' plans for 2014?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm...well, we have a massive year planned for the team, but sadly I can't reveal too much just yet! It's safe to say we're working hard to expand and develop our wee team, so watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>derby review 2014</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>review</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/14/derby-review-2014-dundee-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 11:49:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>