<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about dubai roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/dubai-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:36:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>UAE All-Stars: A National Team for the Emirates</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/03/20/uae-all-stars-a-national-team-for-the-emirates/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst we often talk about Roller Derby in North America, and Europe and Australasia, and somewhat less about Latin America (at least, in English - &lt;em&gt;en español,&lt;/em&gt; a lot is said) we speak much less about Roller Derby in the rest of the World. Part of this is because of a similar tendency to only talk about teams which compete internationally... of which there are much fewer outside of those above regions. This is a self-fulfilling prophecy, of course, since isolated teams, inherently, find it hard to find any local opponents: and they can't find international opponents if people don't talk about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United Arab Emirates has had two Roller Derby leagues: Dubai Roller Derby, and Abu Dhabi Roller Derby, for more than 6 years, the two forming within a few months of each other in late 2012. It's been hard for them to find opponents elsewhere, however, especially given the roster sizes for the two. 
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this year, members of both teams decided to collaborate on a bigger thing: a Emirates-wide Travel Team, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/UAERollerDerby/"&gt;UAE Roller Derby All-Stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, representing the country on the international stage. (Between them, Dubai and Abu Dhabi represent about 2/3s of the population of the UAE, but there are 5 other Emirates which could still develop teams.)
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spoke to two of the main agents of this initiative, Mean Curls and Inga Knee’her, about how this got organised, and what their plans are.
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27922} --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="UAE Roller Derby Logo (&amp;amp;quot;UAE All-Stars&amp;amp;quot; forming part of a circle in grey, with the Arabic name in green on top, designed to include the image of a roller skate in the negative space)" src="https://scottishrollerderby.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/52672994_267004467546689_505072778026680320_n.jpg" title="UAE Roller Derby Logo ('UAE All-Stars' forming part of a circle in grey, with the Arabic name in green on top, designed to include the image of a roller skate in the negative space)"&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As long ago as 2013, Dubai and Abu Dhabi Roller Derby had discussed the possibility of forming a national, potentially WFTDA-sanctioned, joint team. However, with both leagues also organising their individual affairs, it wasn't possible to achieve this until recently: there wasn't enough time, or experience, in the teams to build the bigger plan.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018, however, Inga Knee'her became one of the most experienced new members of Dubai Roller Derby - transferring to the team after 10 years of experience in Steel City Roller Derby (at the time WFTDA D 1 team), and Tokyo Roller Derby. As well as spearheading the adoption of Rolla Skate Club's Short Track Roller Derby ruleset to enable Dubai to play more derby in more places, she's also become part of the trio behind the UAE All-Stars.
With Spinky (president of Abu Dhabi Roller Derby) and Mean Curls, the plan has gone from a discussion over ice-cream to reality.
As Inga and Mean Curls tell it: "In less than two months, we [] created the team, organized weekly practices focusing on Short Track coached by Inga, and played our first international game in Hong Kong as part of Pan Asian Spring Rollers (prompting the self-proclaimed name of the “Get Sh*t Done Team” :D)."
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Dubai and Abu Dhabi also the most populous cities in the UAE (and their eponymous emirates), and fairly closely located, the All-Stars can alternate training between the two easily, helping to build a sense of equal partnership in the national team.
At present, the team is working on helping to develop visibility and interest in Roller Derby - and Roller  skating - in the UAE, where historically there hasn't been much. (At present, all of Dubai and Abu Dhabi's kit comes from abroad via international shipping.)
One aim of this increased visibility is towards developing the skill levels for their member skaters, by providing opportunities for higher level play that would otherwise be inaccessible. 
Inga's contacts with the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers (the Roller Derby collaboration between Beijing, Shanghai, Hong-Kong and Bangkok &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderby.wordpress.com/2017/06/07/east-asian-derbys-new-spring-rollers/"&gt;we've covered previously&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) immediately paid off in this sense. Having played against the Spring Rollers as part of the Women's Roller Derby Japan team at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderby.wordpress.com/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/"&gt;Tomodachi Roller Derby tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Okinawa (2017), she was hoping for opponents to play Short Track derby with.
As it happens, the timing of the Spring Rollers bout against Hong-Kong was too good to pass up: Mean Curls, Spinky, and Inga were able to make the trip to join Pan Asia v. Hong Kong as members of the Spring Rollers team.
(Their team ended up winning too, 159 to HKRD's 127.)
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That bout also helped to build even more contacts: Derby Without Borders' founder Mae Dae has recently relocated to Bangkok, and was present as part of the Hong Kong event. We're promised future collaborations with Derby without Borders, supporting their mission in the Middle East and Asia so watch this space! (Mae themself has also been busy since moving to Bangkok, and we'll be catching up with them in a future article.) 
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27923,"width":561,"height":842} --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Two of UAE All-Stars' skaters (Mean Curls, Spinky) in blue as part of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers team against hosts Hong Kong Roller Derby. Photograph by Teddy Tse" src="https://scottishrollerderby.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/dsc_5798-2.jpg" title="Two of UAE All-Stars' skaters (Mean Curls, Spinky) in blue as part of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers team against hosts Hong Kong Roller Derby. Photograph by Teddy Tse"&gt;Two of UAE All-Stars' skaters (Mean Curls, Spinky) in blue as part of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers team against hosts Hong Kong Roller Derby. Photograph by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teddy.tse.12"&gt;Teddy Tse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At home, they're focusing on Short Track Roller Derby as it makes practice much more accessible: not only is it easier in terms of numbers, the smaller space needed (the Short Track track fits inside a standard basketball court) makes it much easier, and cheaper, to find spaces to practice in. 
With the UAE's regulations limiting other opportunities (public events need licenses, for example), having more options in hosting always helps. 
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, UAE All-Stars aren't limiting themselves to a single ruleset for future games. Inga and Mean Curls emphasised "we are interested in any and all roller derby opportunities for our skaters. We are lucky to live in a place with direct flights to so many cities, making it relatively easy for us to visit other teams as well as to host events in the future."  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, whilst the team has not ruled out applying to join the WFTDA in the future, they're also setting their sites on the most international of competitions. 
"Our ultimate goal is to represent the UAE at the next Roller Derby World Cup," the team told us, adding "Mean Curls is the only current Emirati roller derby skater (that we know of) and will represent us on the Nations Committee".
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>abu dhabi roller derby</category><category>articles</category><category>dubai roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><category>short track roller derby</category><category>uae all-stars roller derby</category><category>uae roller derby all-stars</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/03/20/uae-all-stars-a-national-team-for-the-emirates/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 12:27:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Short Track Worldwide Update (2019 Feb)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/03/01/short-track-worldwide-update-2019-feb/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderby.wordpress.com/2018/10/26/short-track-roller-derby-a-first-scottish-test/"&gt;first article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://rollaskateclub.com/lets-rolla/"&gt;Short Track Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, back in 2018, the new ruleset has continued to spread, in almost all the places in the world where Roller Derby is played.
As such, we thought we’d follow up, just 4 months later, with some of the exciting developments in Short Track worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, as readers of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://whataboutmagazine.com/"&gt;What A Bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; magazine will already know, Short Track Roller Derby has spread further-and-wider than we could have hoped: to Russia, and Dubai, in the United Arab Emirates, already. You should read the full article in WAB &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://whataboutmagazine.com/2019/01/20/what-a-bout-issue-3-winter-2019/"&gt;Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for full details, but look out for several Short Track tournaments in Moscow, and other Russian cities later in the year. Dubai’s interest in Short Track has also led to bigger things which we’ll get to later in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short Track is continuing to enable more teams to play derby, even now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Poland, Gdańsk’s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/551140512034275/"&gt;Chrome Sirens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are playing their first ever public game, thanks to Short Track rules enabling them to put together two competitive teams (and use more accessible venues). This double-header event will be coming to the city in the middle of next month - March 16th!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Americas, Short Track Derby is also taking off: ruleset creators Rolla Skate Club having provided initial impetus with a comprehensive series of trial sessions across Canada and the North-west of the USA. In Latin America, meanwhile, there is interest in Buenos Aires, Argentina, in exploring the ruleset, as it solves several of the challenges of the many teams in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27916,"width":600,"height":426,"linkDestination":"custom"} --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Illinois Valley Vixens Roller Derby during their first public bout under Short Track Rules.(Photo used by permission of Dave Schrader under license. [not covered by site CC license] )" src="https://scottishrollerderby.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/img_6131-crop-1.jpg" title="Illinois Valley Vixens Roller Derby during their first public bout under Short Track Rules.(Photo used by permission of Dave Schrader under license. [not covered by site CC license])"&gt;Illinois Valley Vixens Roller Derby during their first public bout under Short Track Rules.(Photo used by permission of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/korfan/collections/"&gt;Dave Schrader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; under license. [not covered by site CC license] )
&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the USA, though, public bouts have already started, with the ruleset enabling teams to play their first games in years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/IVVRD/"&gt;Illinois Valley Vixens Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, who played their first public bout for 3 years thanks to Short Track back in February, the ruleset has been a revelation. Whilst some venue issues meant that they had to modify the track slightly, the bout was a complete success - despite only using word of mouth and social media for advertising, they managed to fill all the available seating. Speaking for the league, Lemon Squeezer told us : “We now know that a smaller track definitely does not mean less exciting or intense, quite the opposite! I can't remember a time I have heard a crowd this engaged before and the feedback from spectators was that they are looking forward to the next one and bringing friends. We also had several former skaters come to check it out that are now interested in coming back.”. 
I.M.GROOT added, “The fact that all players have to both jam and block really takes you out of your comfort zone. It pushes you to use all the skills you have learned, not just the ones you prefer. Short Track has the ability to really push skaters to be stronger, better and more adaptable in game play.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an even more striking mode, the USA has also brought us the first ever “Short Track” league: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pstrollerderby.com/"&gt;Pittsburgh Short Track Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, founded by a group of skaters who retired from “competitive” Roller Derby, but still wanted to play a friendlier version of the sport. Their league aim, as expressed on their website and Facebook page, “We are a group of friends who wanted to create a safe, stress free environment to get together and skate. Community over competition.” encapsulates the entire point of Short Track as a ruleset and community. (You can find out more about them on social media and their website.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further in the future, there’s also exciting news of potentially the first ever international Short Track Roller Derby Tournament.  The newly created &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/UAERollerDerby/"&gt;UAE All-Stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the United Arab Emirates’ official travel team, are exploding onto the scene, and one of their first public plans is to play Short Track Derby! Formed of skaters from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DubaiRollerDerby/"&gt;Dubai Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ADRollerDerby/"&gt;Abu Dhabi Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the team plan to play all kinds of Derby, but Short Track is definitely a solid component of their goals. [We have more about UAE All-Stars themselves in another new article here, which we’re going to publish soon - and their first ever public game &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/495068457564329/"&gt;will be this weekend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, 2nd March, in Hong Kong, as part of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27917,"width":576,"height":384} --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="UAE Roller Derby All-Stars practising on the Short Track [courtesy of UAE All-Stars]" src="https://scottishrollerderby.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/53180456_272367973677005_4491993895592263680_n-e1551445852446.jpg" title="UAE Roller Derby All-Stars practising on the Short Track [courtesy of UAE All-Stars]"&gt;UAE Roller Derby All-Stars practising on the Short Track [courtesy of UAE All-Stars]
&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the support of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gogogent.be/en/home-default/"&gt;GO-GO Gent Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, who had been investigating hosting an experimental Short Track clinic for several months, UAE All-Stars will be travelling to Belgium on the 1st and 2nd of June. The first day will be a Short Track Roller Derby training workshop, allowing the experienced skaters from Dubai’s testing of the rules (and potentially other skaters who’ve tried Short Track from the rest of Europe) to explain and demonstrate the potential of the ruleset to attendees.  
The second day will be a tournament event: the structure of which is still under development. Teams are welcome to participate from across Europe, and we know that there’s been interest from several regions already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even further in the future, there’s the possibility of Short Track bootcamps in other parts of Europe, including the UK, and other plans afoot about which we can’t speak at this time. Stay tuned for further updates as they occur!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dubai roller derby</category><category>in the news</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><category>polish roller derby</category><category>short format tournaments</category><category>short track roller derby</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/03/01/short-track-worldwide-update-2019-feb/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 13:12:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Future of Derby: The Middle East</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/19/the-future-of-derby-the-middle-east/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next up in our series on the Future of Derby is another geographical region where the growth and development of the sport is pushing new boundaries: North Africa and the Middle East. Egypt's &lt;a href="http://www.cairollers.com/"&gt;CaiRollers&lt;/a&gt; swept to some fame a few years ago when they were first founded, getting attention in some major newspapers, but since then other leagues have begun emerging, in the UAE and in Lebanon...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Middle-East has, perhaps, particular challenges for Roller Derby, as it (and Asia) have less Western ideas of women and sports in popular culture. As Derby develops into a truly International sport, encountering and adapting to non-Western cultural ideals will be a key test of the sport and its leadership (as will the ability to decentralise the core of the sport itself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to all three Middle-Eastern leagues we are aware of, to find out how they see the sport developing in their region. &lt;a href="http://www.dubairollerderby.com/"&gt;Dubai Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s The Killer Purple answered questions for them, while the CaiRollers had their Nofearteti respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Roller-Derby-Beirut/763063127094159"&gt;Roller Derby Beirut&lt;/a&gt; is currently just a work in progress, and their founder provided us with the following statement: &lt;em&gt;Women of the Middle East face challenges that cannot compare in any way to the reality we know where I live, in the cold Northern Copenhagen. I've been following the amazing ladies of the CaiRollers, and the way Roller Derby enables them to claim their space in the public sphere. This is not about religion, Orientalism or naïve good-doing; it's about sharing our amazing sport and community with women around the world. It makes me happy and proud to feel the derby community reach out and help in any way they are able to; that's why Derby is so unique. I hope the ladies of Beirut will find this together whilst turning left. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[You can help Roller Derby Beirut with donations at the World Cup or otherwise via this event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/599390206837488/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/599390206837488/&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dubai:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Although Roller Derby in Dubai (and the U.A.E. in general) is young, have you considered a national team submission for the next &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;World Cup&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely. We would definitely consider submitting a National Team, and have already discussed it. The issue, however, is that few of our skaters, if any, are from Dubai/the U.A.E. This is not because we have any kind of restrictive or exclusionary policies but because of the U.A.E.’s demographics. Roughly 80% of the population is expatriate. Local women also tend to be from more protective family backgrounds. Athletic local women are certainly the exception to the rule although this is slowly changing. As it stands, the World Cup’s eligibility rules need to be modified to be able to include places like the U.A.E., Singapore, Hong Kong, Qatar, Egypt, etc. and our particular social make-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Middle-East has perhaps unique problems for the growth of derby, but some issues are common to leagues across the World. What have been your issues to date with growing and spreading derby across the U.A.E?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Possibly the primary factor that limits the growth of derby in Dubai &amp;amp; the U.A.E. is the transient nature of the population. Most people come here early on in their careers, at a time when their lives are changing rapidly, stay for a few years to benefit from the tax-free laws, and then return to their native countries to establish more permanent homes. While they’re here, they take advantage of Dubai’s proximity and ease of access to many tourist destinations, and travel frequently. This constant turnover of people, and serial absence of skaters makes it difficult to plot and monitor progress of an individual skater, and of the league. Expatriates also tend to take long breaks from work in the summer to escape the scorching, draining temperatures. This discontinuity certainly slows our progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another factor that has severely hampered our growth is the lack of infrastructure to support us. At the peak of the quad skate fashion, the U.A.E. was little more than a desert, and as such, has no old roller rinks, no old skates, no former wheely-disco-divas. What we do have is an indoor ski slope, which has that excessive appeal that Dubai prides itself on. The roller derby “story” of grassroots, female empowerment, alternative living, community driven success is not one that might appeal to decision-makers here – people that have the money, resources, and permits to build. This is Eden for big business-big government. Unless a direct monetary advantage can be leveraged, the project is dead in the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Culture probably does play a significant factor as the athletic development of girls and women is considered secondary to their moral well-being. Athletic facilities that women use are primarily built for men. We know that many derby leagues began in parking lots, etc. but try skating in 99% humidity, and 50°C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, finding a decent sports hall, with skateable flooring, has given our league a much-needed boost. With a consistent practice location and times, we’ve gained a good reputation, garnered a lot of media attention, and gotten a lot of new skaters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any hopes for development in the Derby community which would make the sport more successful in the Middle East, and Dubai in particular?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) To be perfectly honest, the only way in which we hope derby develops is in being able to include us to play in the World Cup. It could be a concern that as the sport grows, people jump on the bandwagon and beat the horses. Right now, We like that there isn’t a fat-cat commission setting rules for me to make them money. We like that derby isn’t about money. We like that we've got an international sk8rhood. We like that we’re fierce and I like that we have to fight for our right to party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Egypt (Cairollers):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The CaiRollers have been growing for about 2 years now. What challenges (and support/unexpectedly easy things) have you encountered on the way? (Are any unique to Egypt?)&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenges today remain similar to what they were when we first started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) the gear is not available in Egypt and it's not easy to get it shipped here without paying hefty fines and/or guaranteeing that something will get lost along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) Practice locations - it's difficult to find a suitable surface for us to play on, and when we do it's either too expensive. We don't have any sponsors yet and we pay for all practice venues out of dues which we try to keep to a reasonable amount so that players from all walks of life can play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) Drumming up awareness of what derby us and support and interest from women to play. In addition to which many of our founding players were expats, so in our second year we lost about 80% of the team and had to kind of start from scratch. However, we have managed to build a more local base and now the team is majority Egyptians or women who are living in Egypt for the long term, so turnover won't be as high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unexpectedly easy and awesome thing which has helped with all of the above challenges is the international support that we have received. So many teams from all over the world have supported us by talking us up, donating a ton of gear and even making financial donations to our paypal account. the amount of derby love that has come our way from ALL over the world has been overwhelming and incredible. At the end of our 1st birthday &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/video.php?v=10101801428504640&amp;amp;set=vb.320558514691079&amp;amp;type=3&amp;amp;theater"&gt;slideshow&lt;/a&gt; we had such a long list of leagues to thank and send out love to and that was an amazing thing.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Has the English-language focus of derby, especially with rules + best practice, caused any problems?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Yes, it has caused some issues in terms of teaching our own players the rules, but also in terms of drumming up interest in the game. There is no direct translation for the word Jammer in Arabic. How do we explain roller derby without being able to explain what a jammer is? [In almost all other languages, Jammer remains untranslated, or becomes something like "star" in the destination language - Ed] But we've made do. Recently we've been talking about translating our fresh meat package into Arabic. We've got parts of it translated now, but we want all the details to be available in Arabic so we can sort of be a resource for derby in Arabic.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;If there is a World Cup in 2016/17, would you consider forming a Team Egypt? (Eligibility for national teams tends to be decided by nationality, not domicile.) Have you thought about this already?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would definitely consider it but there's a lot that would go into that consideration. We don't have any sponsorship, though we've been trying to drum up some big name sponsors for a year now. We would need some serious sponsorship in order to be able to go, as many of the women on our team cannot afford to contribute much, if anything towards travel abroad. We would also like to have a couple of bootcamps and play a couple of international bouts if possible prior so that the World Cup is not our first time encountering that level of play. But as a pipe dream, it's definitely something we've talked about from time to time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;As derby grows outside the "Western" cultures of North America and Western Europe, do you see any changes either being required to grow in those new areas, or being fed back into the community from those new cultures?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
I don't think there need to be any real, fundamental changes to the game of derby in order for it to grow, but there has to be perhaps a widening in the scope of what is meant by derby culture. We've been able to adapt the 'badass' tough chick image of derby to our situation here in Egypt. We've got Egyptian women from various social classes and religious backgrounds playing together, some are veiled, some are not. When the veiled women first showed an interest in derby some of them asked if it would be possible to play with their hijab. We of course told them that there is no requirement that they wear racy clothing or have tattoos or any of these other things that they might have picked up from some of the popular media around derby (The movie Whip It is shown on a regional satellite network quite often, and I think this is where a lot of people might be getting their ideas about derby...) In any case, we've adopted a very 'come as you are' attitude here, and I think we've done a good job of reconciling the different viewpoints of our players about what derby culture is and what it should be. So I guess, that's just a long way of saying that I don't think there need to be any drastic changes to derby in order for it to grow in new areas. I think each league will sort of naturally figure out what works best for them.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>cairollers</category><category>dubai roller derby</category><category>future derby</category><category>future of derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>middle east</category><category>roller derby beirut</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/19/the-future-of-derby-the-middle-east/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 09:59:50 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>