<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about dublin roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/dublin-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Europe's First Continental Cup: the UK's next International Derby fixture in 2018</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/04/europes-first-continental-cup-the-uks-next-international-derby-fixture-in-2018/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By any account, 2018 has been a very good year for Roller Derby's international profile, in both Europe and the UK. From the third Roller Derby World Cup in Manchester this February, and the third Men's Roller Derby World Cup in Barcelona a few months later, we've gone on to host an MRDA Playoffs, in Halifax/hosted by Manchester Roller Derby, and a WFTDA Playoffs, in A Coruña.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pendulum is, inevitably, swinging back again from Spain to the UK, with the last event in this sequence: the first ever &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wftdaecc2018.com/"&gt;European WFTDA Continental Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, bringing up the rear in this inaugural year for the new format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the MRDA Playoffs (hosted by Manchester, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; Halifax), this is hosted by Birmingham Blitz Dames, but physically &lt;i&gt;located&lt;/i&gt; in Telford... but the hosts have done a lot to make the brand of the tournament their own. The distinctive diamond logo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-27531 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/blitzdamesdiamon.png" alt="BlitzDamesDiamon" width="245" height="240"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;has both a general connection to Birmingham's jewellery industry, and to the Blitz Dames themselves - and even references their ex-skater, goldsmith Isabella Day, who made the trophy for the tournament!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27532" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/continental_map_logos.png" alt="Continental_map_logos" width="1562" height="1070"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Continental Cups framework is a response to the increasing spread of Roller Derby, and particularly the increasingly global membership of WFTDA. With more than 400 member leagues, an ever decreasing fraction of travel teams can hope to compete in a WFTDA Playoffs (and travel costs become increasingly prohibitive if you just extend the cut-off for Playoffs, or extend the old Division 2). &lt;i&gt;Regional&lt;/i&gt; "Continental Cups" provide a WFTDA-certified tournament, for every region with enough teams, at a level just below that of Playoffs - but with much less travel costs. (Next year, there will also be a set of regional "Development Cups", providing a WFTDA-certified tournament option for regions who aren't competitive at the old "D2" level, with guest "seed" teams from more "connected" regions to help improve ranking accuracy.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe's Continental Cup, then, has a familiar set of teams (and countries) represented (order from WFTDA announcement):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Kallio Rolling Rainbow (Finland)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dublin Roller Derby (Ireland)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dock City Rollers (Sweden)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers (Wales)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Central City Roller Derby (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby (England)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
The current FTS Europe rankings (which include a different subset of games to WFTDA rankings; excluding games against teams outside Europe, but including unsanctioned games) disagree somewhat with this ordering - FTS thinks that some of these teams were strong enough to make Playoffs ahead of some of the European representation there! - but predict a rather close set of games, regardless. In fact, FTS currently rates the two "local" teams - hosts Birmingham Blitz Dames, and Central City Roller Derby - as being exceptionally close in strength - sadly, the bracket prevents them from meeting unless they both lose their first games, or meet in the final.
Similarly, FTS expects some surprisingly close matches in the first round of the elimination bracket, despite WFTDA's usual slaughter pairing setup: Kallio versus Middlesbrough should be a near-draw by European data; although WFTDA sanctioned ratings place Kallio much higher than the UK team. If you're playing the Bracket Challenge for this contest, that's your best chance for an early upset...
&lt;p&gt;Despite, or perhaps causing, of the possibility of so many upsets and ranking disparities, the European Continental Cup should continue the example of the two North American CCs, in having a higher than "usual" number of close bouts, despite the tendency of elimination tournaments to start with a round of blowouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bracket is available here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.wixstatic.com/ugd/590519_be81975ec1304fcf96b32590ddbe2d8a.pdf"&gt;BRACKET PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (note for those not in the UK - this event is on the weekend that the UK changes over from Daylight Savings Time, so be careful checking timings for the Sunday, in particular).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-27324" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/officials_eur_map.png?w=2048" alt="Officials_EUR_map" width="1024" height="768"&gt; Geographical distribution of European Officials at the ECC! Stars may represent more than one official from a given location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as for the competition, the Continental Cup is also a great chance for more representation for our highly skilled European Officiating community. Just at the Tournament and Crew Head levels, we have officials from Karlsruhe, Newcastle, Dublin, Nottingham, Paris/Lutece, London/Southern Discomfort, (and Michigan...) - including all of the other crew positions adds (deep breath) Amsterdam, Antwerp, Bath, Belfast, Birmingham, Brussels, Cambridge, Cardiff, Chelmsford, Copenhagen, Darmstadt, Devon, Dresden, Dundee, Essex, Falkirk, Frankfurt, Gothenburg, Kallio/Helsinki, Manchester, Metz, Mons, Nantes, Northampton, Oxford, Riems, Ruhrpott, Southend, Southampton, Vicenza, Vienna, Wiltshire, Wuppertal,  (and Rochester, NY; Monterrey County, CA; St Louis, MO; Boston, MA; USA... and Adelaide, SA, Australia)! Just as with the other international events in Europe this year, this kind of exposure, and opportunity to both officiate at a high level, and meet up with a wider-flung segment of the Derby Community is fantastic for Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not all, as there's also fantastic line-up of (mostly...) European announcers, from Head Announcer Biertrix (Rainy City Roller Derby), through a host of UK announcers from London through Manchester to Durham and Newcastle; and from Germany, Denmark, as well as the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, as with all WFTDA post-season events this year, there will be a genuine chance for all members of the community (WFTDA-members or no) to connect with WFTDA Membership via the co-hosted "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/772801099579539/"&gt;WFTDA World Summit Satellite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" event. We're very impressed by WFTDA's increased commitment to listening to the voices of the whole community, and would encourage the community to also make use of these opportunities in return: listening should be rewarded with dialogue. (On that note, WFTDA are also surveying every league which does derby and are not WFTDA-members - regardless of their gender policy etc - and we'd encourage everyone eligible to respond to this too, here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.org/surveys"&gt;WFTDA.org/surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The European Continental Cup will run from &lt;strong&gt;October 27th to October 28th&lt;/strong&gt; at The International Centre, Telford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WFTDA Continental Cup page: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/events/wftda-continental-cups/"&gt;https://wftda.com/events/wftda-continental-cups/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Facebook Event for European Continental Cup: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>birmingham blitz dames</category><category>central city roller derby</category><category>continental cup</category><category>dock city rollers</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>kallio rolling rainbow</category><category>middlesbrough roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>tournament</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/04/europes-first-continental-cup-the-uks-next-international-derby-fixture-in-2018/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 15:54:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash 2018: Newcastle Roller Girls' tournament expands beyond the "Euro".</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/26/euroclash-2018-newcastle-roller-girls-tournament-expands-beyond-the-euro/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Readers of the blog will remember our coverage of Newcastle Roller Girls' first European Tournament, &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/365884340424845/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, back in 2017. Newcastle's first WFTDA Recognised Tournament brought together teams across Europe for some high level action, and prefigured performances as far ahead as WFTDA Playoffs; as well as presenting a sneak peak at two of the National teams (Scotland and Ireland) as they worked towards the 3rd Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the ridiculously tournament-filled start of this year has delayed us, we're also going to be bringing you as much coverage as we can of the return of EuroClash this year... although, given one of the attendees this time, the tournament has already outgrown its name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this initial article, we're just going to introduce you to the competitors, and their current placements in the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst 2018's edition is slightly smaller than 2017's - 9 attendees (6 returning from last time), rather than 11 - their geographic distribution is &lt;em&gt;substantially&lt;/em&gt; wider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning from 2017's inaugural event are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls (hosts)
Auld Reekie Roller Girls (soon to &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/25/auld-reekies-10-anniversary-rebrand-with-your-help/"&gt;rebrand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; to Auld Reekie Roller Derby) [Edinburgh]
Central City Roller Derby (competed last year as Central City Rollergirls) [Birmingham]
Dublin Roller Derby
Middlesbrough Roller Derby (EuroClash2017 was their first fixture after rebranding)
Tiger Bay Brawlers [Cardiff]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joining them to make up the full nine are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames
Dock City Roller Derby [Gothenburg]
Steel City Roller Derby [Pittsburgh]!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-26639" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/euroclash2018.png?w=2048" alt="EuroClash2018" width="1024" height="768"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, EuroClash served as the first step for several of the attending teams' campaigns to get into WFTDA Playoffs - Auld Reekie, Bear City, Paris and Dublin all gaining valuable ranking points from their attendance, as all bouts are WFTDA Sanctioned games.
Whilst EuroClash itself is not arranged to provide a final ranking, or a tournament cup, we did analyse the tournament itself &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Our analysis was good enough to predict the results of Paris Rollergirls' subsequent two games against other attendees, so it's probably as good as any other attempt at rating the teams...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since last year, the returning teams have played a lot of Roller Derby, with varying stories; so we can expect some changes in the matchups this time around. [We're using the FTS "WFTDA" ratings here, as not all the teams can be rated with the usually-more-accurate Europe ratings.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the time of writing, the attending EuroClash 2018 teams span a 41 position zone within FTS's rankings - but a fairly closely rated one. (FTS's built in predictor tool expects only a 2:1 score ratio between the highest rated - Dublin - and lowest rated - Auld Reekie - teams if they played today.) We've also included, in parenthesis, the WFTDA Official ratings and rankings for the teams - despite the different ordering, the "range" in strengths is about the same for WFTDA's own ratings, perhaps slightly larger.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="3" rowspan="1"&gt;FTS "WFTDA" Ratings 23 April 2018 (WFTDA Rating 31 March)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rank&lt;/strong&gt; (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Rating (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;53&lt;/strong&gt; (46)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7775/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;745.2 (391.51)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;62&lt;/strong&gt; (65)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/29732/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dock City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;732.4 (318.9)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;63&lt;/strong&gt; (68)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7948/rankings/wftda"&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;729.4 (307.57)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;70&lt;/strong&gt; (94)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7763/rankings/wftda"&gt;Central City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;713.3 (242.58)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;83&lt;/strong&gt; (62)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7949/rankings/wftda"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;691.7 (323.67)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;86&lt;/strong&gt; (95)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/3417/rankings/wftda"&gt;Steel City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;683.0 (241.15)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;88&lt;/strong&gt; (88)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7736/rankings/wftda"&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;682.2 (259.63)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;93&lt;/strong&gt; (85)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7953/rankings/wftda"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;676.0 (262.62)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;94&lt;/strong&gt; (87)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/5912/rankings/wftda"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;674.9 (259.86)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
Auld Reekie and Middlesbrough both suffered ratings reductions against 2x4 Roller Derby during the latter's Jan-Feb tour of Europe, where the Argentine team outperformed expectations against almost &lt;i&gt;everyone&lt;/i&gt;. The jury is out as to how much of this is due to 2x4's general under-ranking, and how much is due to over-ranking of the teams they played - in general, we'd expect better-than-ranking performances from both teams at EuroClash.
Middlesbrough could potentially surprise the current #1 seeds, Dublin; the gap between their WFTDA ratings is entirely due to that loss to the under-ranked 2x4, and their European rating, by comparison, places them above the Irish team (and only just below Paris)!
Similarly, Auld Reekie's European rating places them in the middle of the field, rather than at the bottom, although their trajectory is in the same direction - however, some of this is due to their bout against Leeds Roller Derby, who are almost certainly under-ranked at this point in the year.
&lt;p&gt;Hosts Newcastle have also had difficult bouts, against EuroClash 2017 returnees Central City Roller Derby - given CCR's stronger-than-previous performance against other recent opponents, we consider this to be more of a reflection on CCR than Newcastle - and Leeds Roller Derby (who, again, are simply improving themselves, as they knit together as a team after their first year). We suspect Newcastle are somewhat underranked due to their choice of opponents, and as the hosts they'll be wanting to show that at EuroClash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remaining steady, Tiger Bay Brawlers have still had a pretty good year - and even their recent loss to Central City is not a bad sign, as their performance was near identical to that at EuroClash 2017; if CCR show signs of being back on the up, then this is actually good for the Cardiff team too. The recent transfer of Kid Block back to TBB from London can only improve their strength further - we expect strong performances from the team, beyond what their current rating implies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dublin Roller Derby have also had a pretty good 2017, continuing their upward trend in the FTS European ratings, and remaining steady in the WFTDA rating. Their current placement at the top of EuroClash 2018's rankings seems solid, barring improvements from Dock City, or Middlesbrough. This could all change this weekend, however, as Dublin play some competitive sanctioned games over in the USA at Southern Discomfort 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also remaining steady for the past year, Steel City Roller Derby - after losing around 100 rating points in 2016, the team had a very stable 2017, sticking around the 680-690 rating they still reside at entering EuroClash. A return to their 2016 high would make them easily the strongest team in the tournament, but we suspect their middle-table ranking is more likely, especially given the effects of trans-Atlantic travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gothenburg's second league, Dock City Rollers, continued their generally upwards climb over 2017 (and 2016), and show no particular signs of stopping this progress in WFTDA bouts. They're one of two teams which could challenge expected #1, Dublin if they play against them. Looking at the more plentiful data in the European FTS rankings, they've suffered a "correction" to their ranking as a result of their performance in last year's Swedish national tournament, but their trend is still upward - if we believe the European values, however, they'll be better matched against Auld Reekie than Dublin's finest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representing Birmingham, we have both Birmingham Blitz Dames and Central City Roller Derby, and both seeing upwards movement in the rankings over the past year - Central City in the past month or two, and BBD earlier in 2017 - although the more detailed European ratings show signs of a correction in the Blitz Dames rating at the start of this year, albeit again against the probably-underranked Leeds Roller Derby.  We'll see if the Blitz Dames still have more rating gains to come in the WFTDA rating, as they play in the 2018 K Town Shakedown this weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be back with some more articles, and a guide to the schedule when its published, closer to the event...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash 2018&lt;/a&gt; will be hosted at the &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/6NHQpKxP5Em"&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; on the &lt;b&gt;19th&lt;/b&gt; and&lt;b&gt; 20th May&lt;/b&gt; 2018 - less than a month away! Tickets are on sale, for &lt;b&gt;£30&lt;/b&gt; in advance (£35 on the door), or at a limited special group discount price of&lt;b&gt; £100 for 4&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>birmingham blitz dames</category><category>central city roller derby</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>dock city rollers</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>euroclash</category><category>middlesbrough roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>steel city roller derby</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/26/euroclash-2018-newcastle-roller-girls-tournament-expands-beyond-the-euro/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 13:04:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: A Chat with... Dublin Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/03/euroclash-interviews-a-chat-with-dublin-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, we covered one half of the Irish contingent to Newcastle Roller Girls' &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/365884340424845/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EuroClash&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;tournament in March, with the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/02/02/euroclash-interviews-team-ireland-roller-derby/"&gt;Irish National Team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we're following up with an audio podcast recorded with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dublinrollerderby.com/"&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s Snowy. Dublin Roller Derby had a very exciting and packed 2016, with both a US trip (to Beach Brawl, hosted by Gold Coast Derby Grrls in Florida) and plenty of European bouts as well... and their 2017 schedule looks equally busy, with their A team's first bout only a week away on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1743272762668788/"&gt;11th&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;over in Toulouse!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dublin will be competing at EuroClash, and we also expect several of their skaters to be on the Team Ireland roster that competes with Team Scotland there as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13744 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/drd-logo.png" alt="drd-logo" width="200" height="213"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can listen to the interview here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[soundcloud url="https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/305749218" params="auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true" width="100%" height="450" iframe="true" /]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>euroclash</category><category>team ireland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/03/euroclash-interviews-a-chat-with-dublin-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 12:52:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash 2017 - The Teams</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/12/euroclash-2017-the-teams/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;When Newcastle Roller Girls announced their intent to host a women's derby equivalent of the Men's European Cup (hosted by their sibling league, Tyne and Fear), there was understandable excitement... but the hosts have been remarkably secretive about the leagues involved, with the only hints being that the attendees were amongst the best teams in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Now, finally, the roster of competitors is announced, so we've made this quick guide to the teams (and will have individual features later on). EuroClash will be March 25th to 26th, at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Walker+Activity+Dome/@54.968707,-1.558266,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487e7068944e76d1:0xe1a6394d9f25325!8m2!3d54.968707!4d-1.556072"&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Newcastle. Tickets available &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.org.uk/buy-tickets/euroclash-2017"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-13774" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/euroclash.jpg" alt="euroclash" width="851" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, who are the teams competing in the first ever &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/365884340424845/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13711 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/newcastlerg_1.png" alt="newcastlerg_1" width="122" height="250"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Starting with the hosts, we have &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;. British Championships 2016 Premier Tier Winners, and currently ranked 76th by WFTDA (13th in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/europe"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and 13th by &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;*), the Canny Belters have had a strong 2016 - competing in the USA for the first time, at Beach Brawl in Florida (losing only to the mighty Rainy City) almost immediately after taking that British Championships win. In fact, the Belters have only lost to two teams in the last year - Rainy City and Edinburgh's Auld Reekie (who they also defeated in a rematch). As the hosts, home team advantage will also help their performance, and it would be a mistake to underestimate their chances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13716 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/leedsrollerderby-09.jpg" alt="leedsrollerderby-09" width="200" height="200"&gt;Staying within the UK, &lt;strong&gt;Leeds Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; are "technically" a new league, formed by merger of Hot Wheel Roller Derby and Leeds Roller Dolls at the end of 2016. Leeds Roller Dolls were ranked 65th by WFTDA, and their European Rankings were 23rd FTS, 22 SRD Rank; whilst Hot Wheel had Euro rankings of 31 and 25 respectively. We &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/19/by-their-powers-combined-they-are-leeds-roller-derby/"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on their merger at the time, and are excited to see what the combined pool of talent can accomplish in a single roster. Leeds Roller Dolls had their second trip to the USA in 2016, performing significantly above expectations; after placing solidly in the middle of the Champs Premier Tier rankings. Hot Wheel, by contrast, played their first European tournament in 2016, attending A Skate Odyssey, where they met surpassed expectations (beating their seeding by 4 places); they also managed to come second-from-top in British Champs Tier 2, clearly on the up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13765 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/mmr1.jpg" alt="mmr" width="222" height="200"&gt;Middlesbrough Milk Rollers&lt;/strong&gt; are possibly the highest ranked English team attending Euro Clash, with an impressive 56th position on the WFTDA rankings (9th in Europe by FTS, and 4th by SRD Rank)! MMR declined to participate in British Champs in 2016, but had an absolutely impressive year of competition, defeating almost all comers (including Connecticut and New Jersey) despite playing away for each and every bout. The only team to defeat them was London B, the Brawl Saints, which is not a bad record at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13730 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/central-city.png" alt="central-city" width="200" height="200"&gt;Central City Rollergirls&lt;/strong&gt; are the 83rd WFTDA ranked team (16th in Europe by SRD, and 20th by FTS), and one of the first Roller Derby leagues in the UK, representing Birmingham. CCR are the second team in this list to have spent their 2016 breaking into the USA via Beach Brawl, where they won more than they lost. They also defeated London B earlier on in the year, still a rare accomplishment for a UK team. The Birmingham team had quite a quiet year by comparison with the hectic adventures of some of the others in this list, and will have a lot of energy for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13735 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tigerbay.jpg" alt="tigerbay" width="200" height="183"&gt;Moving outside England, Wales' &lt;strong&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/strong&gt; are the best that their country has, ranked 75th by WFTDA (14th FTS, 12th SRD Rank in Europe). Declining to compete in British Champs in 2016, TBB instead competed against a wide range of European opponents, defeating London B, but narrowly failing against the mighty Rainy City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;After a lull in 2015, the general feeling is that Cardiff's all-stars have regained their best performance and are ready to go further in 2017; they're also a strong component of the current, and very strong, Welsh National Team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13740 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/arrg-logo.png" alt="arrg-logo" width="200" height="89"&gt;And representing the northern part of the UK, Edinburgh's &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; are the strongest team in Scotland, placing 60th in WFTDA (16th FTS, 20th SRD Rank in Europe). Auld Reekie made some waves last year by declining the offer to compete in WFTDA Playoffs, using the time to work more on their own performance - and they also declined British Champs 2016 as well. They did spend some time in the USA earlier in the year, competing at The Big O 2016, but had perhaps a more impressive start to 2016 where they defeated both our hosts Newcastle and Ireland's finest, Dublin. They'll be wanting to recapture that energy for the start of 2017... and will have a boost from their significant presence in the Team Scotland training squad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;For our remaining teams, we have to head outside the UK, so by distance, we first have...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13744 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/drd-logo.png" alt="drd-logo" width="200" height="213"&gt;...&lt;strong&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;, ranked 86th by WFTDA (but 11th in Europe by FTS and SRD Rank). Dublin have had a very exciting 2016, playing their first bouts in the USA at (yes!) Beach Brawl and winning against everyone except Newcastle Roller Girls! This performance didn't slow them down at all, as they also had one of the busiest schedules of 2016 as well, playing 15 bouts over the year, 10 of them away! With strong representation in Team Ireland, the Dublin team is definitely a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13749 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/paris.png" alt="paris" width="200" height="200"&gt;Moving a little further into Europe, &lt;strong&gt;Paris Rollergirls&lt;/strong&gt; are one of the two most exciting teams in France, ranked 71st by WFTDA, but 8th (or 9th) in Europe by FTS (SRD Rank). Hotly tipped for greatness in 2017 by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://thederbyapex.com/trending-french-roller-derby-56c5e691b036"&gt;The Derby Apex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the potential strength of Paris is also reflected in the performance of the French National Team, which they are a significant contributor to - Equipe de France is yet to lose a game with their current roster! Paris also burst onto the USA scene in 2016 at... (you've guessed it!) Beach Brawl, losing only the single bout. Much of the rest of their busy 2016 schedule was consumed by the French Nationale Elite Tier, which they topped, winning each and every bout in the 2015/6 season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13756 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/bcrd-bear-city-roller-derby_0.png" alt="bcrd-bear-city-roller-derby_0" width="200" height="200"&gt;From Berlin, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;Bear City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; are also one of the older teams in Europe, established back in 2008 . Ranked 50th by WFTDA (and 12th in Europe by FTS, 14th by SRD Rank), the Berlin Bombshells are the only team in this competition to have competed in WFTDA (Division 2) Playoffs in 2016, placing a strong 5th out of the 10 competitors, and defeating 4th seed Cincinnati on the way. In fact, Bear City spent more time competing in the USA than anywhere else in 2016, as the majority of their remaining bouts were at the Midwest BrewHaHa, with only two bouts in Europe (against Kallio Rolling Rainbow and Glasgow Roller Derby). Whilst Bear City the league also won the German Nationals (the Bundesliga), we believe this was strictly an exhibition team which differed from BCRD's normal A roster...
EuroClash sees the Bombshells return to Europe to take on the other rising stars of the continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;But that's not all, as we also have the excitement of a National Teams bout as well!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13777 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/ireland.jpg" alt="ireland" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13779 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/scotland.png" alt="scotland" width="200" height="200"&gt;Teams &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; met at the Road to TBC in Cardiff this November, with the Irish taking the win... but neither team had finalised their roster at that point. This rematch is taking place after final selections for Team Scotland [their selection bout is February 11th], and the Scots will be keen to show what they can do with the team that will be heading to the World Cup in Manchester. Meanwhile, Team Ireland were exceptionally green at the Road to TBC, and they will be that much more experienced as a squad by March...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We will be posting interviews with each of the teams competing at EuroClash over the next few weeks, to get into more depth about each of the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;* European rankings on SRD Rank computed from the set of all Women's Travel Teams in Europe known to the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bear city roller derby</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>euroclash</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>middlesbrough milk rollers</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>paris rollergirls</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/12/euroclash-2017-the-teams/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 19:15:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow cross the Irish Sea: Dublin v Irn Bruisers</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/25/glasgow-cross-the-irish-sea-dublin-v-irn-bruisers/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dublin Roller Derby have been a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; busy league this year - earlier on, as we &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/01/europe-goes-to-beach-brawl/"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, they joined Auld Reekie and Newcastle at Gold Coast's Beach Brawl in Florida. Last weekend, they went across to play Middlesbrough Milk Rollers and Hot Wheel Roller Derby [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/21/european-roller-derby-22-october-update/"&gt;as we reported in our roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]. This weekend (as we will be reporting), they're hosting a triple-header for their B-team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And on &lt;strong&gt;November&lt;/strong&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;5th&lt;/strong&gt;, they're &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/299480537069476/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; again, as Glasgow Roller Derby travel across to Ireland to take them on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-10493" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14724154_1255954684466870_1555950462_o.jpg" alt="14724154_1255954684466870_1555950462_o" width="1284" height="2048"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow have had a difficult year, and Dublin Roller Derby are flush with increased confidence after their performance in the US: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85892/rankings"&gt;predicts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; a 90% win probability for the home team. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/08/ranking-the-world-and-other-fts-visualisations/2"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (using the 1 October rankings*) agrees, and also concurs with FTS's approximate prediction that Dublin should score about 70 to 75% of the total points. That said, Glasgow's Irn Bruisers have been working hard to rebuild, and they may still surprise us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;12pm&lt;/strong&gt; for 1pm start. Hosted at Dublin Roller Derby's usual venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Shoreline+Leisure+Greystones/@53.136466,-6.067257,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4867af24e2419651:0x45f0195e8da6d900!8m2!3d53.136466!4d-6.065063"&gt;Shoreline Leisure Greystones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Dublin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets: &lt;strong&gt;€7&lt;/strong&gt; (under 16's free, accompanied) on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Our next ranking calculation will use the 1 November data, but it obviously can't exist yet. We'll update our prediction here before the bout!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/25/glasgow-cross-the-irish-sea-dublin-v-irn-bruisers/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 18:07:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Europe goes to Beach Brawl</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/01/europe-goes-to-beach-brawl/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Despite the strong growth of Roller Derby internationally, the couple of years head start that the USA had during the revival means that the strongest Roller Derby is still found in that country. As a result, increasingly more European teams are making the step of attending the big American WFTDA Sanctioned tournaments, hoping to both further their WFTDA Rankings (which, being influenced by Strength of Schedule, are much harder to develop without a large number of Sanctioned games against high level opponents) and their own skill.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/01/europe-goes-to-beach-brawl/screen-shot-2016-03-30-at-13-10-27/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-6892"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6892" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/screen-shot-2016-03-30-at-13-10-27.png" alt="Screen Shot 2016-03-30 at 13.10.27" width="700" height="528"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most popular destination for visiting teams this year seems to be the &lt;a href="http://www.beachbrawlrollerderby.com/home"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beach Brawl&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;May 13-15&lt;/strong&gt;, hosted by Gold Coast Roller Grrls in Fort Lauderdale, Florida.  (We are covering Auld Reekie Roller Girls' own plans for USA travel in a separate article, coming soon!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current top-of-the-British-Champs leaderboard, &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; have set their sights on the tournament as the next step in their development as a league. This will be their first ever US roller derby tournament, although not their first ever WFTDA tournament; in common with many Beach Brawl attendees this year, Newcastle attended the 2015 Skate Odyssey, hosted by Gent Go-Go Rollergirls, coming second overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Newcastle's Co-Captain, Missy Pow-Pow, told us: "Since July 2014 when we graduated as a full WFTDA league, our aim has been to improve our ranking. We’ve been working hard on and off track, both physically and mentally, to up our game.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Last year our hard work started to pay off when we won the British Champs national Tier 2 division and were promoted to the premier tier. We also only missed out on 1st place by 2 points at our first ever WFTDA tournament - A Skate Odyssey. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Our game has improved so much so quickly that our WFTDA ranking doesn't reflect the real strength of our team and we’re struggling to find the sanctioned games that we need in Europe to be able to improve our ranking. So we’re having to do what other leagues in a similar position to us are doing - going stateside to play roller derby. It wasn't an easy decision to make - the cost to the league, skaters and support staff in both monetary terms as well as time is huge, but we felt there was no other option if we were serious about improving our WFDTA ranking.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We applied for several US WFTDA events with Beach Brawl being our top choice so we were stoked when we got the invite and can't believe it’s now only six weeks left until we fly out! We are continuing to work hard, improving our fitness and performance so that we are ready and prepared as best we can be for this.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;On behalf of all of us at NRG, I want to thank everyone who’s supported our Beach Brawl fundraising campaign so far - we couldn’t do it without you and we hope we’ll do the North East and the UK proud."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also attending for the first time are &lt;strong&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;, who are facing Auld Reekie this weekend. Dublin were also attendees at the 2015 SKOD, where they only narrowly missed out getting to the semi-final, after a 2 point loss against the hosts (just as Newcastle did in the final)! As the highest ranked team in Ireland, it's especially the case that DRD have to travel overseas to compete against better teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dublin's Co-Captain, Snowy, said: "&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Dublin Roller Derby are about to achieve the ultimate derby dream by becoming the first Irish league to compete in an International Tournament in the United States. This May, we’re off to Beach Brawl, Florida, for our first taste of US roller derby.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We’re unbelievably excited to play in the country that invented this wonderful, mad sport of ours and to see what challenges we’ll face stateside. We might also be a little excited by the prospect of a week in a sunnier clime than Dublin, but needless to say we’ll be packing factor 50 sunscreen."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls and Dublin Roller Derby are both raising money for the travel to the tournament via GoFundMe.
Newcastle's GoFundMe is here &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gofundme.com/nrgtobeachbrawl"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/nrgtobeachbrawl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with a series of rewards for donators including new limited edition Beach Brawl themed merch. They also have several other fundraising initiatives in hand, including a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/540135629522203/"&gt;Pub Quiz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the 10th of April (with some big prizes, including show tickets and first class train travel!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dublin's GoFundMe is here &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gofundme.com/dublinrollerderby"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/dublinrollerderby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; , where they also have a range of limited edition (Miami-Vice themed) merch as donator rewards. In common with Newcastle, Dublin are also running a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1007331919339066/"&gt;Table Quiz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, with a Father Ted theme (!) on the 26th of April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The schedule for Beach Brawl is not public quite yet. When it is,  our localised and translated &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/29/beach-brawl-viewing-guide-timezone-adjusted/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;viewing guide will be here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It will link to FlatTrackStats for each match up, and will have livestream links as soon as we are aware of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>beach brawl</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/01/europe-goes-to-beach-brawl/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 16:04:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>International Derby at Glasgow and Edinburgh</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/29/international-derby-at-glasgow-and-edinburgh/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Scottish Roller Derby season is hotting up, and that means more International fixtures to add to your diary.
As well as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/23/international-roller-derby-in-the-forth-valley/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls taking on the cream of Swiss Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, both Auld Reekie Roller Girls and Glasgow Roller Derby have international bouts planned for the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/29/international-derby-at-glasgow-and-edinburgh/883965_10156639729380224_7285447541727594878_o/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-6881"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6881" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/883965_10156639729380224_7285447541727594878_o.jpg" alt="883965_10156639729380224_7285447541727594878_o" width="700" height="259"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/arrg-v-dublin/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;this weekend&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; sees Auld Reekie Roller Girls' All-Stars take on Ireland's Dublin Roller Derby, for the first time. Dublin are the highest rated team in Ireland, and previously defeated ARRG's B team (back when they were called the Cannon Belles).
This bout is a change of the usual for ARRG in another sense, too, as it is scheduled for an evening timeslot, beginning at &lt;strong&gt;17:10, &lt;/strong&gt;in their usual venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Meadowbank+Sports+Centre/@55.9567319,-3.160204,16.61z/data=!4m2!3m1!1s0x4887b86eb150070f:0x6955a8c9b9a10cc5"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/5912/7775"&gt;FlatTrackStats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; predicts a fairly strong win for the Edinburgh team, with a 1:2 score ratio. Auld Reekie will be wanting to keep FTS true for this one, as their momentum after defeating a very strong Newcastle Roller Girls earlier this year is strong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/02/glasgow-roller-derby-next-level-bootcamp-guest-coaching-available/grd/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-4565"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4565" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/grd.jpg" alt="grd" width="700" height="254"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks later, &lt;strong&gt;April 23rd&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;midday&lt;/strong&gt;, Glasgow Roller Derby's Irn Bruisers are playing their first home International of the season (having been abroad themselves already, at European Smackdown). &lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/events-calendar/2016/4/30/irn-bruisers-vs-berlin-rollergirls"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In their first bout in a new venue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Glasgow+Club+Bellahouston/@55.8470224,-4.3307299,14.97z/data=!4m2!3m1!1s0x4888461a8453bc9f:0xb647f258023c5070"&gt;Glasgow Club Bellahouston&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; , the Bruisers will be taking on Bear City Roller Derby's Berlin Bombshells. The two teams have faced off several times before, but this will be a particularly unpredictable contest; Glasgow's roster has changed a lot from last year, and Berlin have lost their star double-thread, Master Blaster, to London.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/7929/7734"&gt;FlatTrackStats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; predicts a win for the away team, with a 17:10 score ratio in Berlin's favour. However, while Glasgow have played enough games this season for FTS to have a handle on their current strength, Berlin have no bouts on record this season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This event will also be a double-header, with a "newbies" bout as warm-up to the main event. New skaters from Glasgow, as well as Auld Reekie, Ayrshire Roller Derby, Granite City Roller Derby, and more, will be forming two mash-up teams, to get experience on track. This is an ideal opportunity to see the next Scottish roller derby stars as they begin their journey in public competition.
For those who feel inspired to give Roller Derby a try themselves afterward, Glasgow are also hosting a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/events-calendar/2016/3/19/oeu1rzh6k77jmbol8c5xofw0cwnsel"&gt;Recruitment event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the very next day, &lt;strong&gt;April 24th&lt;/strong&gt;., at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Glasgow+Club+Drumoyne/@55.8597633,-4.334637,15.48z/data=!4m2!3m1!1s0x488845fd9321ec39:0xcf01f9e4e5ae65e0"&gt;Glasgow Club Drumoyne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;12:30&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>berlin bombshells</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/29/international-derby-at-glasgow-and-edinburgh/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 11:29:17 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>