<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about ecdx)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/ecdx.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:34:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>An (ECDX) Interview with... Hot Pants, Cold Beer</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/07/13/an-ecdx-interview-with-hot-pants-cold-beer/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As something of a teaser for our series of ECDX interviews, I caught up with Pennsylvania based Derby Spectating Team "&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HotPantsColdBeer"&gt;Hot Pants Cold Beer&lt;/a&gt;", who are ECDX regulars. After Auld Reekie's Alma Geddon made contact with them pre-ECDX, the Hot Pants Cold Beer team made sure to catch the Scottish bouts and cheer on the foreigners!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was talking to group founder Heather Harlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/920065_488054554599481_999665459_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-2819" alt="The core Hot Pants Cold Beer group, Heather Harlin giving the thumbs up." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/920065_488054554599481_999665459_o.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="359"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The core Hot Pants Cold Beer group, Heather Harlin giving the thumbs up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We'll start with some background, I think. So, how did you get started as a group?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Well I'm an official in the sport and only ever get to be a fan during ECDX each year. I was with other friends and joked about creating a spectating/drinking team. So our original group include a skater from Lehigh Valley Rollergirls, her husband, and 4 roller derby officials based out of Lehigh Valley. We decided to get shirts made up and a bunch of people hopped on board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long have you been going for, and how did you make your connection to our Scottish teams?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is our second year and our philosophy is that we cheer for the teams that come from the furthest away. They're the least likely to have fans there and so we are their surrogate fans. Last year, Portland, Oregon's team Rose City Roller Girls and Denver, Colorado's team Denver Roller Dolls were the teams we worked hard to cheer for last year. When we found out that Auld Reekie and Glasgow were making the trip we knew immediately that they would be "our teams". Also, a skater for Lehigh Valley and a HPCB member Holly Floyd, "Double Barrel Hot Gunz" lived in Glasgow for a year so it was destiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, before ECDX proper, Auld Reekie came over to play LeHigh. How was that bout - were you surprised by ARRG's performance, and did it change your expectations for ECDX itself?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an official for that game, I actually didn't pay attention to much of the game. I did notice on Thursday and through the rest of the weekend that Auld Reekie is a second half team, meaning they learn quickly from the first half of play and make adjustments successfully. Those teams are always fun to watch and officiate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; So, coming to ECDX proper: what were the highlights for you? There were plenty of tense games and great derby to choose from...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, personally, make a point to see teams I wouldn't be able to see within a 3 hour drive. The Scottish teams of course were my favorite - especially Glasgow v. Long Island. I don't think my heart could handle much more that 60 minutes of that game. It was so close and back and forth. The Windy City v. Philly game was intense, I hear, but I only saw the overtime jam from behind what seemed like a billion people and the energy from the fans was contagious!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From all of the games, I know at least 3 or 4 of us lost our voices from all of the cheering. I know mine came back just two days ago. It was such a great weekend&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Having seen both Glasgow and Auld Reekie significantly surpass expectations in all of their bouts, do you think there's been a tendency in the US to be a little complacent about the International game? Could you see more European teams coming to ECDX in future (flights permitting)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since no one really knew what to expect I think it was a pleasant surprise to see them both. I don't think its complacency, necessarily, just lack of exposure. I can't speak on what ECDX does in terms of team invitations or lottery, but I can say I want to watch more international derby because all derby is wonderful. It's just hard to do when the sport is not main stream and rarely broadcasted in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; With respect to derby video and broadcasting, it's true that the US has an advantage in livestreams (as DNN shows). But the Swedish National Rollerderby tournament was filmed by their national TV! Do you think ubiquitous bout footage is important to the sport, or just to spectators? (Lacking online footage, would HotPantsColdBeer consider flying to Europe for a big tournament here?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be the DREAM to fly out and catch all the derby. I think video is important to the sport because its important to the fans/spectators. Not everyone has access to multiple leagues so having it broadcast is a great way to watch your favorite teams even from far away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And of course, to see new ones!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but of course!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks for your time!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>ecdx</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/07/13/an-ecdx-interview-with-hot-pants-cold-beer/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 14:36:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ECDX Schedule</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/06/27/ecdx-schedule/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The wait is over and The East Coast Derby Extravaganza is finally here.Viewing parties have been organised and i dare say a few beers may well have been purchased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly,you can watch it via &lt;a href="http://wftda.tv/"&gt;WFTDA.tv&lt;/a&gt; and secondly,please remember that the times shown below are UK/GMT and are subject to change.Another point to think about is that these times are the actual bout start times,not when the teams take to the track to warm up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday 28th June&lt;/strong&gt;
On &lt;a href="http://www.phillyrollerderby.com/friday-schedule"&gt;Friday&lt;/a&gt; there are only four bouts.
On rink 2..
11PM - Philly Independence Dolls vs. Gotham Girls Wall Street Traitors (WFTDA Regulation)
00:45AM - Jersey Junior Derby vs. 4H Barnyard Bruisers &amp;amp; Red Bank Riot Girls Mixed Team
1:30AM - Texas Rollergirls vs. Gotham Girls Roller Derby (WFTDA Sanctioned)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and on rink 3..
12:00PM - New York Shock Exchange vs. Mass Maelstrom (MRDA) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there is really only one difficult choice to make on Friday,do you switch feeds to watch the MRDA bout and miss part of Gotham V Philly &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; part of the Junior Derby bout?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday 29th June&lt;/strong&gt;
Moving onto &lt;a href="http://www.phillyrollerderby.com/saturday-schedule"&gt;Saturday&lt;/a&gt;.From this point on in the event,it's worth remembering that nothing from rink 1 will be streamed,which removes some difficult viewing choices but leaves quite a few more.
The action kicks off for the day at 3:30pm with Dutchland V Roc City and of particular interest to readers of this blog will be the bouts featuring the Scottish contingent.Sadly though,this is one of those difficult viewing decisions.
at 7:30pm on rink 2-Glasgow Vs Columbia
at 8:00pm on rink 3-Auld Reekie Vs Dominion
Later,there is some amazing stuff on,Gotham Vs Atlanta,Montreal Vs Charm City and Philly Vs Texas amongst many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday 30th June&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.phillyrollerderby.com/sunday-schedule"&gt;Sunday&lt;/a&gt; has the Scottish bouts on the same track,in fact,Glasgow kick the day off and are followed by ARRG.
at 3:30pm on rink 2-Glasgow Vs Long Island
at 5:30pm on rink 2-Auld Reekie Vs Ithaca
Like the Saturday,there are some stellar bouts later in the day,Philly Vs Windy City,Atlanta Vs Charm City and the last bout of the event,Team USA Vs Team Canada.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>ecdx</category><category>grd</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/06/27/ecdx-schedule/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 21:26:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Slew of Glasgow Roller Derby ECDX Fundraising Events.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/05/16/a-slew-of-glasgow-roller-derby-ecdx-fundraising-events/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It looks like Glasgow Roller Derby have been a bit busy building up fundraising events for ECDX, only to release them in a fusillade of money-making goodness today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, and very soon indeed,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/harshtugimage.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2612" alt="harshTugimage" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/harshtugimage.jpg" width="419" height="594"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/content/harsh-tug-fundraiser"&gt;Harsh Tug @ The Flying Duck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The night of the 24th of May sees The Notorious B.A.G. provide a night of hip-hop, gangsta rap, and other musical genres which this correspondant is too old to properly appreciate, hosted at The Flying Duck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All proceeds go to the ECDX fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/facebook_65874.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2613" alt=".facebook_65874" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/facebook_65874.jpg" width="453" height="640"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're still up for more Glasgow Roller Derby related musical goodness, GRD-skater-based-duo SummerSlams are DJing an event, &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/335576776567980/"&gt;"Bitch, Please!"&lt;/a&gt;, at Nice N Sleazy on the night of the 31st of May, promising an eclectic mix of musical genres, and specially featuring Glasgow-based Grime artist Patricia Panther.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, all proceeds go to the ECDX fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of the above events start at 11pm, and are £3 entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you're not one for late nights and music, the long promised GRD Fundraising Auction has launched, with "items" up for bidding including tickets to various events, custom art works, cupcakes and one day's time from a GRD skater. You can check out all of the possibilities on the special &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/auctions"&gt;GRD Auction&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>ecdx</category><category>fundraiser event</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>grd</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/05/16/a-slew-of-glasgow-roller-derby-ecdx-fundraising-events/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 16:03:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow Roller Derby and Auld Reekie Roller Girls Go Global!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/05/10/glasgow-roller-derby-and-auld-reekie-roller-girls-go-global/</link><dc:creator>paingrrl666</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/glasgow-team-shot2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-2582" alt="Image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/glasgow-team-shot2.jpg?w=487"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, ECDX is now less than 8 weeks away! How ready is the team?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; Cider (ARRG):&lt;/strong&gt;  We bout all year round, so we're always ready to play Roller Derby.  We just need to remember to pack party hats and sun block and we're there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rogue (GRD): &lt;/strong&gt; As ready as we’ve ever been, I reckon! It was important to us to plan and train far in advance for this event so we’ve been working very hard at playing as a solid unit for a while now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there any specific training that your team have been doing to prepare, eg extra scrimmage/off skates training/teambuilding?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Rogue (GRD): &lt;/strong&gt; Yes, everyone on the team has taken on some sort of off skates training. This has taken many forms. Some people are going to the gym, some do Cross-fit, running, strength training or even Parkour! This means that everyone has been making a huge commitment, as the team already train 3-4 times a week. It’s a lot of work and time for everyone. This team is dedicated!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crazy (ARRG): &lt;/strong&gt; Yes - lots of intense off skates, focus on team work and a lot of work on our technical skating skills lately -  we jumped at LRG's invite to go play at Anarchy in the UK III because we knew that would give us a couple of really challenging games and bring the team together just before ECDX.  And the lovely Hot Wheels invited us down for a bout the week afterwards, which was great in consolidating our team work a bit more. For the next few weeks we have booked in a lot visiting teams to scrimmage against us, so that we can do as much as we can to raise level of the ARRG teamwork dream work!  We also have an exciting scrimmage with Gotham, and a pre ECDX bout with another WFTDA league organised for when we get to the States to acclimatise us before ECDX starts. Bouting in New York AND Philly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/arrg11.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-2585" alt="Image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/arrg11.jpg?w=487"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the team/wider league doing to help with finances for this international opportunity?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rogue &lt;/strong&gt; (GRD): &lt;/strong&gt; The whole league, as well as our families and friends, have been amazing in helping us to raise funds for this. To try to list the ways that people have helped would be to miss something out. Fundraising efforts have been as diverse as bag-packing at a local supermarket;  a photo exhibition at a local café run by our own Phoenix; and a Grd Auction.  I’m grateful to everyone who has helped us and I hope we can make them proud.    Click here if you’d like to help out!  &lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/get-in-touch/donate"&gt;http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/get-in-touch/donate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cider (ARRG): &lt;/strong&gt; So much! It's unreal -  I think everyone in the league has helped in some way which is a bit single teary for us as a team.  We feel really supported, and a bit overwhelmed by the sacrifices people have made for us.  Our limited edition merch, designed by Admiral Attackbar, has been a huge bonus because not only does it raise money for us, but it's also amazing quality.  We love the designs! You can buy them here:   &lt;a href="http://auldreekierollergirls.bigcartel.com/products"&gt;http://auldreekierollergirls.bigcartel.com/products&lt;/a&gt;.       Our Sponsorship and Advertising Committee have pulled off some brilliant and fun fundraising events for us this year too – like our huge 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; birthday party which will be happening this Saturday, which has lots of lovely surprises happening on the night. This will help us raise further travel funds.  You can find our more here:          &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/193068510841007/" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.facebook.com/events/193068510841007/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you know anything about the teams you’re up against?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; Crazy (ARRG):&lt;/strong&gt;  Of course! We did some fairly intensive research as soon as the sanctioned teams were announced by ECDX Organisers - it's frightening how organised our team was at online research or &lt;em&gt;creeping&lt;/em&gt; as we call it.  There was a 12 hour overnight 'ARRG mass creep' period where the whole team did this massive impressive feat of internet stalking and voting to suss out who we wanted to play!  We've been keeping an eye on both teams - Ithaca and Dominion - and where they are appearing in rankings; who they're playing and who they're beating; but I guess it's really only when we get there that we'll get a real sense of the level of play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rogue (GRD):&lt;/strong&gt;  Long island are ranked 93rd, and Columbia 39&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, in the WFTDA rankings but who knows what that means? Teams don’t tend to give much away and it’s hard to find recent footage online. However Columbia are playing against Charm City (17th) this weekend and I’ll be watching the results of that one very closely! I also know from being in touch with members of both teams that they will play hard and play to win, but that they are lovely people and I can’t wait to meet them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/grd-brrd1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-2586" alt="Image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/grd-brrd1.jpg?w=470"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you think the team will perform?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rogue&lt;/strong&gt; (GRD):&lt;/strong&gt; The team have all been reminded to pack our A game. We’ll be playing to win!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cider (ARRG):&lt;/strong&gt;  I think that we've been performing well lately as a team and consistently improving with each bout or tournament, so if we keep our focus I know we can perform well.  It just all depends on how well the other teams perform against us I guess.  We've trained hard and we'll go in with the usual 100% and see where that gets us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you most excited about?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crazy (ARRG):&lt;/strong&gt;How long have you got?! It's ECDX!!! Roller Derby in America! Food in Philly! Rocky steps! Team Sauna! And most exciting, is knowing the rest of ARRG will be watching and cheering for us. We want to make them all proud. Hopefully squeeze a bit of shopping in also...  And also, just to say it is such a great chance for two Scottish teams to represent themselves in the States … and if the Team Scotland after-party was anything to go by (from the World Cup) we should have fun doing it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rogue (GRD):&lt;/strong&gt;  Oh, so many things! I’m excited to get there and play with the team and see all of our hard work pay off. I’m excited about the opportunities that this could create for us. I’m excited about the future of GRD. I rarely stop being excited about roller derby!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/group-2-21.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-2588" alt="Image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/group-2-21.jpg?w=487"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>ecdx</category><category>grd</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/05/10/glasgow-roller-derby-and-auld-reekie-roller-girls-go-global/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 08:33:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Scotland heads to ECDX</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/07/scotland-heads-to-ecdx/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/ecdx13sm.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2467" alt="ECDX won't know what's hit it..." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/ecdx13sm.jpg" width="450" height="690"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ECDX won't know what's hit it...
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;For skaters in the North American continent, the &lt;a href="http://www.phillyrollerderby.com/ecdx"&gt;East Coast Derby eXtravaganza&lt;/a&gt; has been an essential fixture since its founding in 2007. Despite initial hiccups (scheduling their first event in the winter led to ice-related chaos, causing the move to the current June 28th to 30th slot), ECDX is now one of the biggest derby meetups in the USA, outgrowing its initial purpose of providing a yearly meetup merely for leagues  on the Eastern seaboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;This year, however, for the first time in ECDX's 7 year history, two of the teams competing in front of thousands of spectators will be from outside the USA and Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
Because, this year, &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/07/scotland-heads-to-ecdx/glasgowrollerderby.com"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s Irn Bruisers and &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/07/scotland-heads-to-ecdx/arrg.co.uk"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' Twisted Thistles are bringing Scottish derby to the East Coast.
&lt;p&gt;If ECDX is such an awesome event (winning Best Regular Season event in the DNN reader awards three years running), then why is it that no European leagues have attended before? The same reason, of course, that London Rollergirls has so many sponsors nowadays: the cost of flying up to 20 excited rollergirls, and supporters, across the Atlantic ocean, is a more than significant outlay for even the biggest European leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, both GRD and ARRG are embarking upon an extensive round of fundraising to pay for their travel and boarding, allowing them to represent not just Scotland but also the UK and Europe in Philadelphia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from augmenting the money made at their regular bouts from raffles and cakes (and face painting in the case of GRD), both leagues have been running a series of derby and non-derby events. For Glasgow, upcoming events include DJ nights at The Flying Duck on May 24th, and at Nice n Sleazy's on the 31st of that month; a gala day and a speed dating evening with dates not yet finalised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/dsc06566.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-2472 " alt="Facepainting at the first Glasgow Roller Derby Home Season of the year." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/dsc06566.jpg?w=614" width="430" height="286"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Facepainting at the first Glasgow Roller Derby Home Season of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie have also been hard at work raising money for their trip, long before their plans were made public. As fundraising chair Skinner Alive notes, “We were in touch with the ECDX organisers just after the summer of last year so our journey to ECDX was always in our 2013 plans, and as such we have been fundraising like mad over these past 8 months.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;ARRG’s first ever hosted bootcamp, School of ARRG Knocks, was one of the first events that the league run to raise ECDX funds, and was so popular that a second bootcamp (subtitled “Even ARRGer!”; perhaps "Skate Free and Die ARRG" was taken?) is already planned.&lt;/p&gt;
ARRG are also running quizzes and music events across Edinburgh, in venues such as The Tron, ElboW, Brassmonkey, Leith Cricket Club and The Breakfast Club, hosting bands such as Shields Up, Trails, Taking Chase, Curators, Bonehouse and Albaroma. Skinner noted that both the hosts' and the bands' support is particularly valued, with the bands often providing their services for free.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;As well as continuing to advertise such events, ARRG is also gearing up for a very special event: their 5th birthday party, which Skinner promises will be an event not to be missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Both leagues have even been driven to sell their possessions to help raise funds. One of the first things that Auld Reekie’s fundraising team (Skinner, Princess Die, Maulibu Barbie and Captain Havoc) did on learning they’d be going to ECDX was to stick all of the league’s old kit at a car boot sale for a starting fund, which “was a great easy money maker, and truly amazing what you can turn into cash with very little effort”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;GRD are also raising money in other ways, with an auction of time and items in planning. This will be hosted by GRD themselves, although the precise format is not available at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/dsc07662.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-2478 " alt="The Auld Reekie Limited Edition Merch stall, at their first Home Season bout of the year." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/dsc07662.jpg?w=614" width="430" height="645"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Auld Reekie Limited Edition Merch stall, at their first Home Season bout of the year.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Finally, both leagues are also producing new merchandise. In Edinburgh, skilled graphic designer, and star ARRG jammer, Admiral Attackbar has developed a range of limited edition clothing with the “Party ARRG” brand. “We decided that we really wanted to give something back to our supporters for helping us out so rather than just donating money, fans can buy themselves a sweet limited edition tshirt instead and know that the proceeds are going to help us get to ECDX,” said Admiral. Asked about the origin of the punny slogans, she revealed that their something that’s been bubbling under for a while: “When we hosted School of ARRG Knocks we were coming up with puns all over the place and Party ARRG arose at some point with regards to the after party. I was really trying to capture the spirit of the league in the new merch designs whilst still keeping things clean, simple and effective."&lt;/p&gt;
Meanwhile, in Glasgow, GRD are sourcing recipes for a  planned cookbook, with a vegetarian and vegan slant, which they are hoping will be successful enough on its initial run to raise funds.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;More prosaically, both leagues will be offering their bag packing skills in the shopping centres of their respective cities, so if you want your purchases packed by a roller derby skater, do watch out in the next few months!&lt;/p&gt;
Of course, it isn't just skaters who are raising money for their trip. Dave McAleavy, possibly Scotland's most well-known derby photographer is running an exhibition in derby-owned Cafe Phoenix to raise money for the GRD’s cause. “Glasgow Roller Derby have had a great couple of years,” said Dave, “and heading to ECDX to take on the world [...] the proceeds from sales will be going to their travel fund.”
&lt;p&gt;If you want to know how important this is to both leagues, all you have to do is to talk to the skaters, all of whom are now considering their next few months in the context of ECDX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/img_0126.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-2475 " alt='New GRD Irn Bruiser Mona Rampage, playing as part of the composite team "The Gavehearts" in Edinburgh.' src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/img_0126.jpg?w=614" width="430" height="359"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; New GRD Irn Bruiser Mona Rampage, playing as part of the composite team "The Gravehearts" in Edinburgh. (Photo: Laura MacDonald)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Speaking for Glasgow Roller Derby, new Bruiser Mona Rampage was luckily enough to graduate to the A-team just in time to join the ECDX crew, and is understandably excited. “Getting selected to be a Bruiser was a massive accomplishment for me”, she said: “I failed my minimums 3 times so was always behind everyone else in my intake skill wise; watching them getting selected for the top 20, NSOing bouts they were playing in, and bench managing their team’s games. To finally go from being on the sidelines to being on the A-team was huge for me. I can't even express how happy I was to be selected. I feel like I really earned my spot though, which makes it so much sweeter! As for ECDX, I am really trying to up my game for the tournament as it will be the hardest thing I have ever done, not to mention the hardest thing the Bruisers have ever done.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/582603_861566419054_309353197_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-2469 " alt="Alma Geddon, jamming against Sheffield Steel in Scotland's first international derby tournament." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/582603_861566419054_309353197_n.jpg?w=614" width="430" height="455"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Alma Geddon, jamming against Sheffield Steel in Scotland's first international derby tournament, in Glasgow
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Auld Reekie’s Alma Geddon has been on their A-team, the Twisted Thistles, for a while, but that hasn’t tempered the excitement of ECDX for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;Both Mona and Alma were especially excited not just to be facing some fantastic American derby opponents, but each to be doing so alongside their counterparts on the other side of the country. “It's massive for Scottish and UK derby and I'm glad we can share the experience with them. We are really lucky that we get on so well with all of the ARRG girls and I'm excited to hang out with them by the pool, cheer them on in their sanctioned outs and I'm sure they will do the same for us" enthused Mona.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Alma was equally pleased to be seeing Glasgow's skaters at ECDX. “It's fantastic that both ARRG &amp;amp; GRD will be a part of ECDX this summer. In 2011 the Scottish national team competing at the first Roller Derby World Cup in Toronto consisted mainly of skaters from these two leagues. In the bout against Team USA, Team Scotland may only have scored the now infamous 'one point', however, I think it's true to say our Scottish pride &amp;amp; tenacity has already left quite an impression on a number of the American skaters. As one of the Team Scotland skaters I know I learned a lot from my World Cup experience &amp;amp; have grown as a skater as a result. The other lovely byproduct of the World Cup is that the two leagues have grown much closer &amp;amp; more supportive of each other than ever before, there was a whole lot of Scottish love at Track Queens tournament last November in Berlin. I'm looking forward to ARRG &amp;amp; GRD showcasing how far we've all come &amp;amp; how hard we've all been working!"&lt;/p&gt;
That said, if it was all about simply hanging out with each other, there’d be no need to fly to Philadelphia to do it. Mona Rampage was all about the challenge,  “really excited to play Columbia as they are the highest ranking team we will be coming up against. I really hope we give them a hard game! I'm going to try my hardest in any case!”  While Team Scotland veteran Alma Geddon has perhaps a few more contacts, and is looking forward to catching up as much as making new friends “Three days of superb derby action to enjoy watching &amp;amp; playing, not to mention rubbing shoulders with some derby heroes/crushes, meeting up with old friends &amp;amp; making new friends …. I stumbled across a roller derby spectating team called &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HotPantsColdBeer"&gt;Hot Pants Cold Beer&lt;/a&gt;, they sound like a great fun bunch of folks.”
&lt;p&gt;Whether those folks can keep up with the cream of Scottish Roller Derby is another matter entirely, and one we look forward to testing on June 28th!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;All of Auld Reekie Roller Girls' events are advertised on Facebook &amp;amp; Twitter (@AuldReekieRG), as well as the ARRG website. The limited edition ARRG merchandise can be bought at: &lt;a href="http://auldreekierollergirls.bigcartel.com/"&gt;http://auldreekierollergirls.bigcartel.com/&lt;/a&gt;  before April 15th, and then at all of the ARRG bouts until the 18th of May. You can also &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/sponsors/donate/"&gt;donate&lt;/a&gt; directly to ARRG via their website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Similarly, Glasgow Roller Derby’s events are also publicised on Facebook and Twitter (@WeAreGRD), and on their website, which also includes a funding thermometer. As with ARRG, you can &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/get-in-touch/donate"&gt;donate&lt;/a&gt; directly to them via their website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>ecdx</category><category>fundraiser event</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>irn bruisers</category><category>twisted thistles</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/07/scotland-heads-to-ecdx/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 21:36:42 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>