<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about end of year)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/end-of-year.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The First SRDB Awards - RESULTS</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/01/srdbawards-awards-2019/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt='The SRDB Award Logo: the Scottish Roller Derby Blog Logo (concentric circles, outer circle containing words "Scottish Roller Derby" all-capitals, separated by five-pointed stars, and an inner ring of stars just outside the boundary of the inner circle; inner circle containing a modification of the "lion of scotland", a heraldic lion, facing right, rampant, with a jammer cover on its head), but with a gold/bronze colour scheme applied.' src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/SRDB-Award.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the AWARDS page for the first ever SRDB Awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ground-rules for the Awards are covered in the launch post &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/srdbawards-nom-2019/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in that link, voting was by &lt;em&gt;approval voting&lt;/em&gt;.
This means that you could, and should, tick boxes for all of the nominees you thought would deserve to win. You could tick all the boxes, if you thought they're all deserving; you could tick no boxes if you think none were deserving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the winners of each award, some statistics on the voting: we let you choose which categories to vote on, so some categories were voted on more than others.
In general, the categories with the longest list of nominees were the ones with the most votes, predictably; the category with the fewest votes &lt;strong&gt;BOOTCAMP&lt;/strong&gt; had about 7.5% of the votes cast on the category with the most, &lt;strong&gt;SKATER&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fraction of voters voting for more than one nominee varied significantly across the categories: with only two nominees, only 1 voter voted for both &lt;strong&gt;BOOTCAMP&lt;/strong&gt; nominees; whilst 38% of voters voted for more than one &lt;strong&gt;HALL OF FAME&lt;/strong&gt; nominee. Overall, (ignoring the &lt;strong&gt;RISING STAR&lt;/strong&gt; category as it had additional voting rules), 17% of votes were cast for multiple nominees, across the categories - this is a little higher than the average for this voting scheme in other deployments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also let you cast a vote for &lt;em&gt;no-one&lt;/em&gt;, if you didn't think any nominee deserved it in a category. Again, ignoring RISING STAR, only 4 such null votes were cast, around 0.2% of votes in total. This is a little lower than the average for systems which let you place null votes, which is encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that statistical interlude out of the way, lets get on with the main matter, the winners in each category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="awards"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;AWARDS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="skater"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SKATER&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Skater award had the largest number of votes of any category in the awards. Despite this, the clear winner, with more than 50% of the voters, was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ELO C RAPTOR&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Harpies Roller Derby Milano&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="coach"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;COACH&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Coaching award was both popular (with more than 200 voters casting opinions), and very tightly contested, with the top 4 by votes all within 7 votes of each other. The winner, pipping the others to the post was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROSIE PEACOCK&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;New Wheeled Order&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="referee"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;REFEREE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Referee award was also very popular, with more than 200 voters, but had a very clear margin for the winner (although still short of an overall majority)...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NICOLA'S RAGE&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Crimson Vipers Roller Derby Bergamo&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="non-skating-official"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NON-SKATING OFFICIAL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NSO award was not quite as heavily voted on, with more than 100 votes cast in total. The runaway winner, just 1% short of an overall majority, and with twice the votes of the next highest placed nominee...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEDROG&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="announcer"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;ANNOUNCER&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With only 3 nominees, the Announcer category had some interesting voting patterns... and a very clear winner. With a majority of the vote, the winning announcer was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GRAEME MCPHAIL&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="photographer"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PHOTOGRAPHER&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Photographer category was the second most voted on category of all in the awards, with almost 250 votes cast in total. Despite this, it was also a very tightly contested category between the top 3, who remained within 10 votes of each other for the entire voting period (and changed position more than once).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, the winning photographer was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VINCIANE PIÉRART&lt;/strong&gt; (NSP189)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="volunteer"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;VOLUNTEER&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Volunteer category, with only 3 candidates, was another with interesting patterns of voting. The overwhelming winner, with a supermajority of votes, was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AUDREY&lt;/strong&gt; ... ex-Dundee Roller Derby, and sort of semi-retired volunteer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="league"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LEAGUE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;League was another popular category, with more than 200 voters casting overall. It was also a very convincingly won category, with the margin between 1st and 2nd place being larger than the total votes cast for 2nd. Despite this, winning by a plurality:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE ANGUANAS&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Vicenza, Italy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tournament"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TOURNAMENT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tournament category saw only just shy of 200 votes cast... and the overall winner had the support of a supermajority of those! It's...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SKATE IM RING 2019&lt;/strong&gt; hosted by &lt;strong&gt;Alp'n Rockets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="non-regulation-tournament"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NON-REGULATION TOURNAMENT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Non-Regulation Tournament category should probably have been called the "Roller Derby Sevens" category, as all three candidates used that ruleset. This was a pretty tight contest between all three, with the winner by plurality:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KRUSTFEST 2019&lt;/strong&gt; hosted independently, in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bootcamp"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;BOOTCAMP&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With only two candidates this category went, convincingly, to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"LILY GASKELL AND FAIRY QUAKE'S BOOTCAMPS"&lt;/strong&gt; hosted by &lt;strong&gt;Rainy City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="media"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MEDIA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Media award was one of our less voted on categories, despite having a bunch of nominations, and the winning candidate changed over the course of voting... taking a win with a majority of voters when voting closed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The MRDA EUROPEAN QUALIFIERS LIVESTREAM&lt;/strong&gt; hosted on &lt;strong&gt;YouTube&lt;/strong&gt;, run with &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="hall-of-fame"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;HALL OF FAME&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hall of Fame category is something of a wildcard category, and had an eclectic range of nominees. This might explain why almost two-fifths of voters voted for more than one candidate in this category! Despite this, there was a clear winner, only just shy of an overall majority...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first Hall of Fame member is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5TH BLOCKER SKATES&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;'s own Roller Derby shop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rising-star"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;RISING STAR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we come to the Rising Star category, for junior skaters, or up-and-coming younger skaters in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to some anomalies in the nomination process, and also to especially encourage voters in this category to vote on the basis of deserving, rather than just popularity, this category required you to vote for 2 or more nominees. (Votes for a single nominee were considered the same as a vote for no-one.) Despite this being clearly described on both the Nominees page, and on the actual voting form (in two places on the latter), a number of voters still voted for a single candidate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, including these single votes would not have changed the overall winner (although it would change the margin of win, and the ordering of all the other positions). The Winner, with a significant margin in terms of valid votes, was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;red OWEch (Owen Squires)&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Junior Roller Derby (Australia)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst there's no official prize for winning an SRDB Award (and we consider being Nominated to be the real point), we'd be happy to work with any of the winners on a "Winners Profile" to be published later in the month or year. Please get in touch with us if you are a winner (or the nominee of a winner) if you want to work with us on this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>announcer</category><category>awards</category><category>bootcamp</category><category>coach</category><category>end of year</category><category>hall of fame</category><category>league</category><category>media</category><category>non-regulation tournament</category><category>non-skating official</category><category>photographer</category><category>referee</category><category>rising star</category><category>scottish roller derby blog</category><category>skater</category><category>tournament</category><category>volunteer</category><category>votes</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/01/srdbawards-awards-2019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 11:26:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The First SRDB Awards - HUB</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/12/srdbawards-hub-2019/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt='The SRDB Award Logo: the Scottish Roller Derby Blog Logo (concentric circles, outer circle containing words "Scottish Roller Derby" all-capitals, separated by five-pointed stars, and an inner ring of stars just outside the boundary of the inner circle; inner circle containing a modification of the "lion of scotland", a heraldic lion, facing right, rampant, with a jammer cover on its head), but with a gold/bronze colour scheme applied.' src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/SRDB-Award.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the HUB page for the first ever SRDB Awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ground-rules for the Awards are covered in the launch post &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/srdbawards-nom-2019/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in that link, voting is by &lt;em&gt;approval voting&lt;/em&gt;.
This means that you can, and should, tick boxes for all of the nominees you think would deserve to win. You can tick all the boxes, if you think they're all deserving; you can tick no boxes if you think none are deserving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone gets &lt;em&gt;a single submission&lt;/em&gt; per category (with as many boxes ticked as they want); we have enabled detection of multiple submissions on these forms, and will also be taking action against unusual voting patterns which get past this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The individual links for each nomination are below: Each Nomination is listed along with the reasons for their nomination, as supplied by their nominator. For submissions in a language other than English, we've supplied a translation into English (errors are ours). For multiple nominations for a single nominee, we've combined the reasons together (we've edited where needed, and removed repetition that results).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-skater-2019/"&gt;[SKATER]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-coach-2019/"&gt;[COACH]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-referee-2019/"&gt;[REFEREE]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-nso-2019/"&gt;[NON-SKATING OFFICIAL]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-announcer-2019/"&gt;[ANNOUNCER]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-photographer-2019/"&gt;[PHOTOGRAPHER]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-volunteer-2019/"&gt;[VOLUNTEER]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-league-2019/"&gt;[LEAGUE]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-tournament-2019/"&gt;[TOURNAMENT]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-nonregtournament-2019/"&gt;[NON-REGULATION TOURNAMENT]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-bootcamp-2019/"&gt;[BOOTCAMP]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-media-2019/"&gt;[MEDIA]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-halloffame-2019/"&gt;[HALL OF FAME]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-risingstar-2019/"&gt;[RISING STAR]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>announcer</category><category>awards</category><category>bootcamp</category><category>coach</category><category>end of year</category><category>hall of fame</category><category>league</category><category>media</category><category>non-regulation tournament</category><category>non-skating official</category><category>photographer</category><category>referee</category><category>rising star</category><category>scottish roller derby blog</category><category>skater</category><category>tournament</category><category>volunteer</category><category>votes</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/12/srdbawards-hub-2019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 09:46:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The First SRDB Awards - Nominations Open!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/srdbawards-nom-2019/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;End of Year awards are a tradition in a lot of communities, and they're one way to highlight and recognise contribution within that community. For the last several years, the Talk Derby To Me podcast ran them for Roller Derby. With TDTM in a quiescent state currently, we reached out to the podcast's founder to get permission to take on the mantle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you might guess from this post existing, he agreed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this article will introduce the ground-rules for the first ever &lt;strong&gt;SRDB Awards&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="srdb-awards-2019"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SRDB AWARDS 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt='The SRDB Award Logo: the Scottish Roller Derby Blog Logo (concentric circles, outer circle containing words "Scottish Roller Derby" all-capitals, separated by five-pointed stars, and an inner ring of stars just outside the boundary of the inner circle; inner circle containing a modification of the "lion of scotland", a heraldic lion, facing right, rampant, with a jammer cover on its head), but with a gold/bronze colour scheme applied.' src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/SRDB-Award.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SRDB Awards, as with the TDTM Awards before them, are entirely delivered by the &lt;strong&gt;community&lt;/strong&gt;, and provide a chance to recognise contributions to Roller Derby in a range of categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anyone can nominate&lt;/strong&gt; any number of candidates for each and any of our categories: you must, however, provide a suitable reason for why they should win. This reason will be shown to voters when voting, so try to make it convincing! You can nominate for any reason, as long as you explain it. You may nominate in any language, and we will translate [but we may need to talk to you to confirm - please specify your contact details if you want to be contacted].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Even being nominated will give your nominee visibility, so please do nominate even if you are worried about them &lt;em&gt;winning&lt;/em&gt; - winning isn't everything, and being nominated is really the core thing here.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(SRDB reserves the right to remove obviously trolling nominations, but we promise to have a light touch here; we will also remove or recategorise nominations which don't match their category.) SRDB will &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; nominate anyone for any categories themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/srdbawards-nom-2019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>awards</category><category>end of year</category><category>nominations</category><category>scottish roller derby blog</category><category>talk derby to me</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/srdbawards-nom-2019/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 09:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>