<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about euroclash)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/euroclash.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>EuroClash 2018: Two Weeks To Go (Schedule + Updated Predictions)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/05/09/euroclash-2018-two-weeks-to-go-schedule-updated-predictions/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/26/euroclash-2018-newcastle-roller-girls-tournament-expands-beyond-the-euro/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;written once already&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about the return of the, now International, Roller Derby tournament to Newcastle Upon Tyne...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26639" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/euroclash2018.png" alt="EuroClash2018" width="1920" height="1440"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...but, with the publication of the official Schedule, and a lot of activity from many of the competing teams, we thought it was worth a quick update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, to the schedule: the official schedule in UK time is below, but we've also prepared a fancy multi-time-zone version &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/EuroClash2018/"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for anyone expecting a livestream and wanting to follow their favourite team from abroad.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Saturday 19 May&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;9am&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="profileLink" href="https://www.facebook.com/TigerBayBrawler/?fref=mentions"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/a&gt; vs &lt;a class="profileLink" href="https://www.facebook.com/SteelCityRollerDerby/?fref=mentions"&gt;Steel City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11am&lt;/strong&gt; Newcastle Roller Girls vs &lt;a class="profileLink" href="https://www.facebook.com/birminghamblitzdames/?fref=mentions"&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="profileLink" href="https://www.facebook.com/dublinrollerderby/?fref=mentions"&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; vs &lt;a class="profileLink" href="https://www.facebook.com/DockCityRollers/?fref=mentions"&gt;Dock City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;3pm&lt;/strong&gt; Birmingham Blitz Dames vs Steel City Roller Derby
&lt;strong&gt;5pm&lt;/strong&gt; Newcastle Roller Girls vs Tiger Bay Brawlers
&lt;h3&gt;Sunday 20 May&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;9am&lt;/strong&gt; Newcastle Roller Girls vs Steel City Roller Derby
&lt;strong&gt;11am&lt;/strong&gt; Dublin Roller Derby vs &lt;a class="profileLink" href="https://www.facebook.com/middlesbroughRD/?fref=mentions"&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt; Dock City Roller Derby vs &lt;a class="profileLink" href="https://www.facebook.com/auldreekierollergirls/?fref=mentions"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;3pm&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="profileLink" href="https://www.facebook.com/CentralCityRollerDerby/?fref=mentions"&gt;Central City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; vs Steel City Roller Derby
&lt;strong&gt;5pm&lt;/strong&gt; Middlesbrough Roller Derby vs Auld Reekie Roller Girls
&lt;strong&gt;7pm&lt;/strong&gt; Dock City Roller Derby vs Birmingham Blitz Dames
&lt;p&gt;Also, since our first update, several of the teams competing have played at significant tournaments: Birmingham Blitz Dames playing exceptional derby at the K-Town Shakedown in Kalamazoo, Michigan, winning 2 out of 3 games, and only losing the last, against Royal City (Guelph) by 9 points (against a predicted loss of around 150!). We predicted that Birmingham might well be underranked in our last update, and this proves us very right...
Similarly, a great performance by Dublin at Southern Discomfort 2018 in South Carolina, beating expectations in every single bout by huge margins - only losing one bout (against Ann Arbor) by 3 points (against a predicted loss of around 90), and winning every single other - has pushed their expected rating up significantly, although as they already top the expected teams at EuroClash, this doesn't really change our prediction for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, for Dock City Rollers and Newcastle Roller Girls over in Tri-City's Put Up Your Toques in Ontario, it was also a very good weekend. Dock City beat expectations against Winnipeg, and Newcastle both won, and beat expectations, against each of their opponents, giving both of them a substantial boost - but not enough for Dock City to gain on Dublin at the top of the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steel City played a single game since our last update, against the Chicago Outfit, where they also out-performed expectations, by a good 50 points or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By comparison, Middlesbrough and Central City have had a relatively quiet time of it, with no further bouts since our last writeup. Central City will play one game, this weekend, as they take on London Rockin' Rollers up in Glasgow for British Champs Tier 1, where their current rating expects a 3:1 score ratio in victory! Nevertheless, games dropping out of consideration, and teams moving around them, have caused ranking changes in WFTDA for both teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Auld Reekie's position is not affected by their own games played since our last update - their closed bouts away against Kallio and Bear City are not marked as Sanctioned on FTS, and so don't count towards their WFTDA ratings there. Whilst they lost a bit of rating compared to last time, their predicted performance seems to have now stabilised, so a rating including these games should be more accurate.
Similarly, Tiger Bay Brawlers' bout against Rainy City B can't count towards WFTDA ratings, as only A teams can contribute ratings. The Cardiff team significantly improved on expectations - narrowly defeating a team which "should have" easily defeated them with a 100 pt margin - so it's unfortunate that this bout is not included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, we have our own rating system - SRDRank - which draws from the full set of FTS bout records, ignoring WFTDA Sanctioning, to produce a rating which takes into account every single game played by a team, including B teams. We've not had time to update the full rating page for this, but just for EuroClash, we've run a special iteration of the rating just for the tournament, and added a column for it here.
(&lt;span style="background:darkseagreen;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Green&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; rows are teams which have gone up in the expected "finishing order" for EuroClash, according to FTS, and &lt;span style="background:indianred;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; rows are those which have dropped. We mark ranking changes in FTS and WFTDA with + and - signs in the Ranking row.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="3" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt; "WFTDA" Ratings 09 May 2018 (WFTDA Rating 30 April)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rank&lt;/strong&gt; (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Rating (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;SRDRank (09 May)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;34 ++&lt;/strong&gt; (38 ++)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7775/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;800.4 (443.76)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.50&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;48 ++&lt;/b&gt; (66 -)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/29732/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dock City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;757.3 (311.87)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.16&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;62 +&lt;/strong&gt; (71 -)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7948/rankings/wftda"&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;729.4 (307.57)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.26&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background:darkseagreen;"&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;65 +&lt;/strong&gt; (50 +++)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7736/rankings/wftda"&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;724.5 (373.88)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.06&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;67 ++&lt;/strong&gt; (64 -)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7949/rankings/wftda"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;717.7 (315.71)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.80&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background:indianred;"&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;68 + &lt;/strong&gt;(81 ++)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7763/rankings/wftda"&gt;Central City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;713.3 (278.36)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.99&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background:indianred;"&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;82 +&lt;/strong&gt; (92 -)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/3417/rankings/wftda"&gt;Steel City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;692.5 (259)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.53&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;93&lt;/strong&gt; (90 -)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7953/rankings/wftda"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;676.0 (262.62)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;94&lt;/strong&gt; (82 +)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/5912/rankings/wftda"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;674.9 (277.65)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.97&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
Interestingly, despite WFTDA, FTS and SRDRank all disagreeing about the relative ordering of the teams, all of the rankings place Dublin clearly at the top. We also all generally agree about the "range of skill" at EuroClash 2018, despite disagreeing about which team is at the bottom: WFTDA expects Dublin to be able to beat Steel City (their lowest rated team) by about a 3:1 ratio - and SRD Rank puts the same contest at about 13:5, whilst FTS thinks that the lowest strength team is Auld Reekie, but also expects Dublin to be able to beat them by about 3:1.
&lt;p&gt;We won't get either of those games at EuroClash 2018, though, as almost all of the scheduled bouts are against teams which are closely matched in one or other of the ratings.
All of our rating schemes expect &lt;em&gt;Dublin's&lt;/em&gt; games to be closely fought - Middlesbrough and Dock City are in 2nd to 4th place in all of the rating schemes we have here, and both have a chance at unseating the expected tournament top dogs from Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie have some difficult games - if you believe FTS, all of their games will be very difficult - but SRDRank has a lot more faith in them. Expect the Edinburgh based team to beat expectations against very tough opponents in Dock City and Birmingham, if we're right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ascendant Birmingham will be counting on the WFTDA rating being accurate when they take on Dock City - both other ratings place them slightly below, not above, the Swedish team - but everyone agrees that they should have an easier time against the Americans from Steel City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steel City will be wanting to bring upsets to both their games - again, going by their ratings from a little more than a year ago, they should win both of their bouts, against Birmingham and Central City... and their current rating has been steadily climbing in recent months. EuroClash could be the place where an American team does to Europe what European teams traditionally do in the Americas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day Tickets (and Weekend Tickets) for EuroClash are available here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/ticketshttps://www.euro-clash.com/tickets"&gt;https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash 2018 will be held at the &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/KwjQQaZfuNF2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;19th&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;20th&lt;/strong&gt; May 2018, by Newcastle Roller Girls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>euroclash</category><category>flat track stats</category><category>international derby</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/05/09/euroclash-2018-two-weeks-to-go-schedule-updated-predictions/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 19:24:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash 2018: Newcastle Roller Girls' tournament expands beyond the "Euro".</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/26/euroclash-2018-newcastle-roller-girls-tournament-expands-beyond-the-euro/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Readers of the blog will remember our coverage of Newcastle Roller Girls' first European Tournament, &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/365884340424845/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, back in 2017. Newcastle's first WFTDA Recognised Tournament brought together teams across Europe for some high level action, and prefigured performances as far ahead as WFTDA Playoffs; as well as presenting a sneak peak at two of the National teams (Scotland and Ireland) as they worked towards the 3rd Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the ridiculously tournament-filled start of this year has delayed us, we're also going to be bringing you as much coverage as we can of the return of EuroClash this year... although, given one of the attendees this time, the tournament has already outgrown its name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this initial article, we're just going to introduce you to the competitors, and their current placements in the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst 2018's edition is slightly smaller than 2017's - 9 attendees (6 returning from last time), rather than 11 - their geographic distribution is &lt;em&gt;substantially&lt;/em&gt; wider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning from 2017's inaugural event are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls (hosts)
Auld Reekie Roller Girls (soon to &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/25/auld-reekies-10-anniversary-rebrand-with-your-help/"&gt;rebrand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; to Auld Reekie Roller Derby) [Edinburgh]
Central City Roller Derby (competed last year as Central City Rollergirls) [Birmingham]
Dublin Roller Derby
Middlesbrough Roller Derby (EuroClash2017 was their first fixture after rebranding)
Tiger Bay Brawlers [Cardiff]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joining them to make up the full nine are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames
Dock City Roller Derby [Gothenburg]
Steel City Roller Derby [Pittsburgh]!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-26639" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/euroclash2018.png?w=2048" alt="EuroClash2018" width="1024" height="768"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, EuroClash served as the first step for several of the attending teams' campaigns to get into WFTDA Playoffs - Auld Reekie, Bear City, Paris and Dublin all gaining valuable ranking points from their attendance, as all bouts are WFTDA Sanctioned games.
Whilst EuroClash itself is not arranged to provide a final ranking, or a tournament cup, we did analyse the tournament itself &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Our analysis was good enough to predict the results of Paris Rollergirls' subsequent two games against other attendees, so it's probably as good as any other attempt at rating the teams...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since last year, the returning teams have played a lot of Roller Derby, with varying stories; so we can expect some changes in the matchups this time around. [We're using the FTS "WFTDA" ratings here, as not all the teams can be rated with the usually-more-accurate Europe ratings.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the time of writing, the attending EuroClash 2018 teams span a 41 position zone within FTS's rankings - but a fairly closely rated one. (FTS's built in predictor tool expects only a 2:1 score ratio between the highest rated - Dublin - and lowest rated - Auld Reekie - teams if they played today.) We've also included, in parenthesis, the WFTDA Official ratings and rankings for the teams - despite the different ordering, the "range" in strengths is about the same for WFTDA's own ratings, perhaps slightly larger.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="3" rowspan="1"&gt;FTS "WFTDA" Ratings 23 April 2018 (WFTDA Rating 31 March)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rank&lt;/strong&gt; (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Rating (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;53&lt;/strong&gt; (46)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7775/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;745.2 (391.51)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;62&lt;/strong&gt; (65)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/29732/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dock City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;732.4 (318.9)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;63&lt;/strong&gt; (68)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7948/rankings/wftda"&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;729.4 (307.57)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;70&lt;/strong&gt; (94)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7763/rankings/wftda"&gt;Central City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;713.3 (242.58)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;83&lt;/strong&gt; (62)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7949/rankings/wftda"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;691.7 (323.67)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;86&lt;/strong&gt; (95)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/3417/rankings/wftda"&gt;Steel City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;683.0 (241.15)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;88&lt;/strong&gt; (88)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7736/rankings/wftda"&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;682.2 (259.63)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;93&lt;/strong&gt; (85)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7953/rankings/wftda"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;676.0 (262.62)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;94&lt;/strong&gt; (87)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/5912/rankings/wftda"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;674.9 (259.86)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
Auld Reekie and Middlesbrough both suffered ratings reductions against 2x4 Roller Derby during the latter's Jan-Feb tour of Europe, where the Argentine team outperformed expectations against almost &lt;i&gt;everyone&lt;/i&gt;. The jury is out as to how much of this is due to 2x4's general under-ranking, and how much is due to over-ranking of the teams they played - in general, we'd expect better-than-ranking performances from both teams at EuroClash.
Middlesbrough could potentially surprise the current #1 seeds, Dublin; the gap between their WFTDA ratings is entirely due to that loss to the under-ranked 2x4, and their European rating, by comparison, places them above the Irish team (and only just below Paris)!
Similarly, Auld Reekie's European rating places them in the middle of the field, rather than at the bottom, although their trajectory is in the same direction - however, some of this is due to their bout against Leeds Roller Derby, who are almost certainly under-ranked at this point in the year.
&lt;p&gt;Hosts Newcastle have also had difficult bouts, against EuroClash 2017 returnees Central City Roller Derby - given CCR's stronger-than-previous performance against other recent opponents, we consider this to be more of a reflection on CCR than Newcastle - and Leeds Roller Derby (who, again, are simply improving themselves, as they knit together as a team after their first year). We suspect Newcastle are somewhat underranked due to their choice of opponents, and as the hosts they'll be wanting to show that at EuroClash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remaining steady, Tiger Bay Brawlers have still had a pretty good year - and even their recent loss to Central City is not a bad sign, as their performance was near identical to that at EuroClash 2017; if CCR show signs of being back on the up, then this is actually good for the Cardiff team too. The recent transfer of Kid Block back to TBB from London can only improve their strength further - we expect strong performances from the team, beyond what their current rating implies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dublin Roller Derby have also had a pretty good 2017, continuing their upward trend in the FTS European ratings, and remaining steady in the WFTDA rating. Their current placement at the top of EuroClash 2018's rankings seems solid, barring improvements from Dock City, or Middlesbrough. This could all change this weekend, however, as Dublin play some competitive sanctioned games over in the USA at Southern Discomfort 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also remaining steady for the past year, Steel City Roller Derby - after losing around 100 rating points in 2016, the team had a very stable 2017, sticking around the 680-690 rating they still reside at entering EuroClash. A return to their 2016 high would make them easily the strongest team in the tournament, but we suspect their middle-table ranking is more likely, especially given the effects of trans-Atlantic travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gothenburg's second league, Dock City Rollers, continued their generally upwards climb over 2017 (and 2016), and show no particular signs of stopping this progress in WFTDA bouts. They're one of two teams which could challenge expected #1, Dublin if they play against them. Looking at the more plentiful data in the European FTS rankings, they've suffered a "correction" to their ranking as a result of their performance in last year's Swedish national tournament, but their trend is still upward - if we believe the European values, however, they'll be better matched against Auld Reekie than Dublin's finest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representing Birmingham, we have both Birmingham Blitz Dames and Central City Roller Derby, and both seeing upwards movement in the rankings over the past year - Central City in the past month or two, and BBD earlier in 2017 - although the more detailed European ratings show signs of a correction in the Blitz Dames rating at the start of this year, albeit again against the probably-underranked Leeds Roller Derby.  We'll see if the Blitz Dames still have more rating gains to come in the WFTDA rating, as they play in the 2018 K Town Shakedown this weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be back with some more articles, and a guide to the schedule when its published, closer to the event...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash 2018&lt;/a&gt; will be hosted at the &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/6NHQpKxP5Em"&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; on the &lt;b&gt;19th&lt;/b&gt; and&lt;b&gt; 20th May&lt;/b&gt; 2018 - less than a month away! Tickets are on sale, for &lt;b&gt;£30&lt;/b&gt; in advance (£35 on the door), or at a limited special group discount price of&lt;b&gt; £100 for 4&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>birmingham blitz dames</category><category>central city roller derby</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>dock city rollers</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>euroclash</category><category>middlesbrough roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>steel city roller derby</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/26/euroclash-2018-newcastle-roller-girls-tournament-expands-beyond-the-euro/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 13:04:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash, Tomodachi and Quad Wars, Three Tournaments, One Weekend (stats)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outside of the USA, there were arguably three big "single date" tournament events last weekend:
Newcastle Roller Girls' &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;EuroClash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, hosting European leagues, a WFTDA Recognised Tournament
Okinawa and Japan's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, hosting East-Asia/Pacific and Alaskan leagues, with a WFTDA Sanctioned Tier
Mendoza, Argentina's Lado Oscuro Roller Derby's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quad Wars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, hosting B/C level Latin American leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of games in all of them, so there's plenty of meat for statistical inference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's start with EuroClash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-13774" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/euroclash.jpg" alt="euroclash" width="851" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash was arranged as a pure invitational tournament, with structure set mostly by the participants' desires for opponents. As a result, EuroClash did not post a "winner" of the tournament. All bouts were WFTDA Sanctioned, as befits a WFTDA Recognised Tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participating teams for all but the last fixture were: Newcastle Roller Girls, Leeds Roller Derby, Middlesbrough Roller Derby, Tiger Bay Brawlers, Central City Rollergirls, Bear City Roller Derby (Berlin), Paris Rollergirls, Auld Reekie Roller Girls (Edinburgh) and Dublin Roller Derby. (Interviews with the teams can be found on this very blog here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/tag/euroclash/"&gt;https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/tag/euroclash/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scores (from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/89165"&gt;FlatTrack Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) are:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;TBB [Tiger Bay Brawlers]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;161&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;CCR [Central City]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;167&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BCRD [Bear City]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;228&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NRG [Newcastle]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;94&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARRG [Auld Reekie]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;194&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MRD [Middlesbrough]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;99&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;LeedsRD [Leeds]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;94&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;DRD [Dublin]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;312&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;238&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;BCRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;177&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;ARRG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;176&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;PRG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;192&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;DRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;85&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;ARRG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;301&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;LeedsRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;93&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TBB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;117&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;203&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;135&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CCR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;177&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MRD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;238&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BCRD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;89&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
As commentators have noted (including The Derby Apex), there's some significant departures from prediction here, which we've highlighted in two different ways. Bolded results are surprising in both European and WFTDA rankings terms, whilst Italic are surprising in terms of WFTDA rank only [in this sense, we mean explicitly "from the WFTDA rankings, not from FTS's ranking based on WFTDA Sanctioned play].
&lt;p&gt;It's pretty clear that there are several patterns here: two ranking errors in WFTDA (Leeds Roller Derby inheriting the ranking from Leeds Roller Dolls, and Paris Rollergirls' known underranking) are responsible for the majority of the `surprises' between them. Anyone who had seen LeedsRD play in British Champs would have expected the same high individual-skill, but teamwork needing more time to gel playstyle we saw in EuroClash - which is to say that there were moments of brilliance, particularly from their jammer rotation (Killaroo, Shin Pain and Little Dark One standing out for us, and in the stats), but there's still some place to go with the cohesion.
And Paris Rollergirls' determination to reach Division 2 playoffs this year is backed by considerable skill and effort in training over the last year - and a consciously constructed schedule of fixtures designed to gain them WFTDA ranking as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this context, then, the real surprises are: Tiger Bay Brawlers holding Paris Rollergirls to their expected performance [including holding them to zero points for the first half of the first period], Central City, in turn, 's surprising win over TBB in the first bout of the tournament, Auld Reekie Roller Girls matching their European expectations of tying Bear City to a 1-point win...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and the curious case of Middlesbrough Roller Derby. The MRD bouts are the only bouts which are a really surprising result in terms of FTS - in the one case, MRD massively underperforming versus Auld Reekie, and in the second MRD massively overperforming against Bear City! (And we mean massively in both cases - Middlesbrough might have been expected to beat Auld Reekie with that kind of points margin, not lose to them by it!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibility, exists, of course, that it was the other teams which were unpredictable... but we can test that with the power of statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We performed a standard linear regression against the results from EuroClash, using score ratios as our measure of performance. As we've explained before, this assumes that the strengths of each team are simply related to each other by their performance - so if Team A is twice as strong as Team B, and three times as strong as Team C, then Team B versus Team C should give a 2/3 ratio win for the B team. Of course, performance varies from game to game, but we can use an "R-squared" value to measure just how good the approximation is for our results. A value close to 1 indicates that the results are very well described by this kind of model, whilst a value close to 0 indicates that no such relationship exists at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running the regression against the full set of results above gives an R-squared&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; of &lt;em&gt;0.39&lt;/em&gt;, a disappointingly low value for Roller Derby tournaments in general (which tend to be around 0.7 or higher).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, given that we know that the MRD results are inconsistent, we can rerun the regression on the results, minus one or both of the MRD games. In this case, we get an pleasingly high R-squared of around &lt;em&gt;0.93&lt;/em&gt; - actually very high for a tournament.
This suggests that, whilst the results might have been surprising when compared with WFTDA rankings, the performance of the teams (other than Middlesbrough) across EuroClash was remarkably consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For interest, then, the relative power-rankings (which should be in the ratio of the points scored between two teams) are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;184&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Paris Rollergirls&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;100&lt;/strong&gt;
Middlesbrough Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;76&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/em&gt;
Berlin City Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;69&lt;/strong&gt;
Auld Reekie Roller Girls &lt;strong&gt;62&lt;/strong&gt;
Tiger Bay Brawlers &lt;strong&gt;51&lt;/strong&gt;
Dublin Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;50&lt;/strong&gt;
Central City Rollergirls &lt;strong&gt;47&lt;/strong&gt;
Newcastle Rollergirls &lt;strong&gt;32&lt;/strong&gt;
Middlesbrough Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;31&lt;/strong&gt; *
Leeds Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where the three entries for Middlesbrough represent their performance against Berlin (184), Auld Reekie (31) and the average of the two (76). That average is around where we would expect MRD to actually have performed if they were consistent, which is interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally matching the results against the existing rankings produces the best matches if we assume that Paris, Dublin and perhaps Auld Reekie, are underranked, and LeedsRD are overranked, with smaller shifts for the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also means that, if we were awarding a Championship to any team, it would be the entirely expected Paris Rollergirls!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paris will be competing against Bear City only this coming weekend, so this will be a good test of their true strength...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-
Of course, the final event at EuroClash was the Team Scotland Roller Derby versus Team Ireland Roller Derby bout.
A rematch of the game played at Road to TBC, where both teams were in their training roster (and Ireland had barely selected that), where Ireland won - this time Team Scotland's competition 20 were playing a more-experienced, but still training, Ireland. (Both teams had many skaters from Auld Reekie and Dublin's rosters, respectively, as well as other teams.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's fair to say that there was a significant difference in the result, with Road to TBC's tough-but-convincing Irish victory replaced by a tight even score in at the end of the first period, becoming a strong Scottish victory by the end of the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final result, &lt;strong&gt;209&lt;/strong&gt; Scotland : &lt;strong&gt;128&lt;/strong&gt; Ireland is stronger than the expected result if Dublin had played ARRG, emphasising the importance of the other leagues making up each National Team; however, at half time, the result was a near tie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;For the statistically inclined, this is actually the adjusted R-squared, not the bare R-squared. We're also using the F-statistic for these regressions, but it closely follows adj. R-squared here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click here: for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/2"&gt;Tomodachi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and here: for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/3"&gt;Quad Wars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over in Okinawa, the Tomodachi Derby Tournament had three tiers - a WFTDA sanctioned tier, an unsanctioned women's tier, and the men's tier (with just two competitors). Interviews with all the participants are available here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/tag/tomodachi-derby-tournament/"&gt;https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/tag/tomodachi-derby-tournament/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-14076" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tomodachi.png?w=300" alt="tomodachi" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;WFTDA-Sanctioned Tier&lt;/h4&gt;
Competing in the Sanctioned Tier were: Okinawa Roller Derby, Tokyo Roller Girls, Devil Dog Derby Dames (the 3 Japanese leagues), Pacific Roller Derby (Hawai'i) and Fairbanks Rollergirls (Alaska, USA).
This was a full round-robin, for a total of 10 games between the 5 teams.
&lt;p&gt;The results were [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/88944"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D4 (Devil Dog Derby Dames)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;305&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FR (Fairbanks Rollergirls)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;156&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRG (Tokyo Rollergirls)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;167&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRD (Hawai'i Pacific Roller Derby)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;138&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ORD (Okinawa Roller Derby)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;124&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;232&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;138&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;188&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;164&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;170&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;126&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;127&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;251&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;174&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;167&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;169&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;172&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;108&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;212&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
The most surprising result is highlighted - Okinawa Roller Derby (which renamed from Kokeshi Roller Dolls just before the tournament) are usually ranked around the same as their fellow Okinawans in Devil Dog Derby Dames.
&lt;p&gt;Running our statistical regression on the tournament, we get an R-squared value (our measure of how "consistent" the games all are) of &lt;em&gt;0.44&lt;/em&gt;, which suggests that there's definitely at least one team which was variable in performance over the two days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, whilst you might expect that removing results such as the ORD v D4 score from the set would improve the R-squared factor for our fit, this is not the case - there's very little change in the R-squared for single-bout changes for the Tomodachi. We believe that this reflects the difference in tournament-experience of the teams involved, versus the higher ranked teams at EuroClash (who are more used to managing their rosters and effort across a long event).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resulting strengths of the WFTDA tier of Tomodachi, then, are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tokyo Roller Girls &lt;strong&gt;100&lt;/strong&gt;
Devil Dog Derby Dames &lt;strong&gt;100&lt;/strong&gt;
Okinawa Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;82&lt;/strong&gt;
Hawai'i Pacific Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;60&lt;/strong&gt;
Fairbanks Rollergirls &lt;strong&gt;60&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where we would give the "unofficial championship", by a whisker, to Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your next chances to see some of these teams: Devil Dog Derby Dames will be competing in Hawai'i's Big Island Brawl against the rest of Hawai'i, and teams from the continental USA (June), where you will also find Pacific Roller Derby. Okinawa Roller Derby are off to Europe to play in a tournament hosted by Rollergirls of the Apocalypse, in Kaiserslauten, Germany. Fairbanks are concentrating on their Alaskan neighbours, with the UWR State Tournament coming up in May. And Tokyo Roller Girls are looking for people to play them, so do ask!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Unsanctioned Tier&lt;/h4&gt;
With two of the three competing teams in the unsanctioned tier essentially exhibition teams (Pan-Asian Spring Rollers representing the Chinese and Thai derby leagues, and Team Women's Roller Derby Japan an open team for skaters who wanted to compete), and the third a Tokyo Roller Girls' home team (Yokosuka Sushi Rollers), there were no expectations on the three bouts.
&lt;p&gt;The results were:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;YSR (Yokosuka Sushi Rollers)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;307&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PASR (Pan-Asian Spring Rollers)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;51&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;YSR (Yokosuka Sushi Rollers)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;307&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PASR (Pan-Asian Spring Rollers)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;51&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;YSR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;152&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WRDJ (Women's Roller Derby Japan)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;167&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WRDJ&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;218&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PASR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;157&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
With just three teams and three bouts, there's not really much point in running statistical tests on the performance, as there's not enough data to produce a reasonable result. (The R-squared statistic is fairly poor for the set, due to the visibly wide variation in the teams' performance.)
&lt;p&gt;In fact, within statistical error, Yokosuka Sushi Rollers and Women's Roller Derby Japan are inseparable in performance, with the Spring Rollers' lack of time to train together evidence in their lower placing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establishing a winner really isn't the point of the unsanctioned tier, however - it's to give the teams a chance to get good experience against people they'd never reasonably be able to play. And, in particular, for the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers, this will be a great learning experience for them to take back to their home leagues in Hong Kong, Shanghai, Beijing and Bangkok.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Men's Tier.&lt;/h4&gt;
Glenmore Reservoir Dogs and Team Japan Men's Roller Derby (NinJapan Rollers) played each other twice over the tournament, with scores:
&lt;p&gt;GRD 273 : TJMRD 113
GRD 288 : TJMRD 138&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it should be fairly evident that, despite the Canadians winning both bouts, there's a close-to-significant improvement in NinJapan Rollers even in the second bout. (In both Men's Roller Derby World Cups, NinJapan have noticeably improved over the tournament, so this is in keeping with their character.)
These were Japan's first men's games since the last World Cup, in fact, and were more significant for the training opportunity, perhaps, than the resulting scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click here: for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/1"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and here: for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/3"&gt;Quad Wars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over to Argentina now, for the Quad Wars 2017 tournament, which saw teams from Argentina and Chile compete in a "B-tier" tournament (in the sense that Argentina uses "B", which is different to Europe - most of these teams are not actual B-teams).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-17011 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/qw.png" alt="QW" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competing were: hosts Lado Oscuro Roller Derby (LORD); Sailor City Rollers' B team, the Tsunami Bombs; Metropolitan Roller Derby's B team, the Bayonetas; Dirty Fucking Dolls; Brutal Lips; and the Sarcasticats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quad Wars has a Star Wars theme, fitting for a host league whose name is "Dark Side" in Spanish, and the teams were arranged in bracketed light and dark side groups, with a playoff for the championship at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results (from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/91785"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) are:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;LORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DFD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;215&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BRUTAL_LIPS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;51&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NERD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;203&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SARCASTICATS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;122&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BAYONETAS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;177&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NERD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DFD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;58&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;LORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;91&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BRUTAL_LIPS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;124&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BAYONETAS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;114&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TSUNAMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;142&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;LORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;57&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NERD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;209&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SARCASTICATS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TSUNAMI&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;157&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BRUTAL_LIPS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;34&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DFD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;131&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;BAYONETAS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;37&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;NERD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;247&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;DFD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;143&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;TSUNAMI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;78&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;BAYONETAS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;47&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;TSUNAMI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;63&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;NERD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;155&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;DFD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;27&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
The last four bouts (in red) represented a final playoff for the championship, which was won by NERD. We can't highlight surprising results using Flat Track Stats, as they do not have a Latin American ranking... but we can use our own &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to do this instead. In general, the big surprise here is the performance of Sailor City B, the Tsunami Bombs, which we rated as close to the winners, NERD in strength... but performed below expectations.
&lt;p&gt;NERD won the tournament overall, but we can provide the same analysis of the team ratings (and how consistent they were) as before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running the regression over all of the scores gives us a very good R-squared value of 0.8, suggesting that the tournament was well-run, and all the teams managed their schedules and fitness well over the multiple days of competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The estimated strengths of the teams from the regression are (with some confidence):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No Excuses Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;100&lt;/strong&gt;
Dirty Fucking Dolls &lt;strong&gt;41&lt;/strong&gt;
Tsunami Bombs (SCR B) &lt;strong&gt;21&lt;/strong&gt;
Brutal Lips &lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt;
Bayonetas (Metropolitan B) &lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt;
Lado Oscuro Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt;
Sarcasticats &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting feature here is the close grouping of most of the teams: we'd suggest that NERD and DFD could reasonably consider themselves high-B/low-A teams (in Latin American terms), rather than the B/C level of the other closely placed competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in seeing more Latin American Derby, then Metropolitan and Sailor City's A teams are competing at the Violentango 5, WFTDA Recognised Tournament in just a few weeks (13-15th April).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click here for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/1"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and here for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/2"&gt;Tomodachi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>euroclash</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>lado oscuro roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>quad wars</category><category>statistics</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 13:20:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: Newcastle Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/21/euroclash-interviews-newcastle-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Newcastle Roller Girls' first International Tournament, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, less than a week away, we just have time for one final interview topic...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...the hosts of EuroClash themselves, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. NRG's Canny Belters had a very good 2016, playing across in the USA for the first time, as well as topping British Champs Tier 1 (becoming the second ever Champions). Along the way, they also came up with the idea of hosting their first ever International tournament - and people will probably remember their campaign to win funding to support it. This being successful, the last few months have been spent on organising the very tournament which we're writing about...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13711 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/newcastlerg_1.png" alt="newcastlerg_1" width="122" height="250"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missy Pow Pow, Canny Belter's Co-Captain, and one of the driving forces behind EuroClash answered some of our questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Newcastle's Canny Belters had an exceptional year in 2016, topping British Champs Tier 1, after promotion from Tier 2 the previous year. You've now stepped down from British Champs this year, leaving the Hinnies to carry the torch - but was the Championship win your goal from the start, and how did it feel to win it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We always play to win! [laughs] But we didn’t think we’d necessarily will ALL the games. The first win against Glasgow came as a big shock to me, I just wasn’t expecting it. The game was actually a WFTDA strength factor challenge so we had a score in mind that we wanted to achieve, which was nowhere near a win. I remember looking at the score board during the game, unbelieving!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We quickly re-assessed our goals and from that point our aim was to win the whole Championship. It was an amazing experience, watching not only your team mates, but the rest of the league, friends and family come together to support and push us forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You also played over in the USA, at the most popular destination for EuroClash attendees - Beach Brawl in Florida. This was Newcastle's first trip to the USA, and, as is traditional, you beat expectations about the US teams you played. How was the transatlantic experience - the environment, and the potentially different style of play? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were really excited to play US teams for the first time; it felt like a good way to benchmark where we were, as it can be hard to gauge from rankings alone. The tournament was an amazing experience – being in one place that was all about roller derby, being surrounded by different teams, most of which were from the USA and Canada, and of course having the opportunity to bond as a team away from the pressures of work, and derby admin, was wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With regards to style of play I don’t think there is a European style or an American style. Each team is different. We played two American teams, Blue Ridge, and Oklahoma, and they were entirely different. What I liked best though is not knowing a lot about who we were playing, therefore we were able to go in to each game just playing our own game without thinking about the style, strengths or weaknesses of the opposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your brother league, Tyne and Fear, have been hosting the Men's European Cup for several years now - it almost seems surprising that there's not been a women's equivalent in Newcastle until now. What led to the decision to organise EuroClash this year? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've been working hard to climb the rankings so we know how hard it can be for teams to get high level WFTDA sanctioned games. In 2015 we played our first European tournament at SKOD, then last year Beach Brawl; both tournaments not only boosted our rankings but really raised our game - we learned a lot. Having had such a great experience abroad, we decided we wanted to create opportunities like that here in the UK, to play our part in developing the sport. So we're really excited to put on a whole weekend of high level European games, including teams who don't often play in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you select the teams attending EuroClash - they're all pretty close in the European Rankings, but were there other considerations? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It mostly came down to where teams were ranked as all of the games will be WFT-DA sanctioned. We really wanted to play (and watch!) some exciting games and we also thought about which teams had never played each other before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017/8 has really become the "year of European Roller Derby" - with so many tournaments, new and established, located or relocated to Europe. How would you place EuroClash in all of this? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve been planning EuroClash since last year so we like to think we were ahead of the curve there! [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting the opportunity not just to play but also to watch more high level live roller derby at the likes of the first WFTDA Playoffs in Europe this autumn and the 2018 Roller Derby World Cup is fantastic - it makes everyone raise their game and that can only be a good thing for the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which teams are the Canny Belters most looking forward to playing at EuroClash? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve never played Bear City or Paris before so we’re really excited to play both of those teams. We watched Paris play at Beach Brawl last year, and the year before at SKOD and they’re such a strong team that keep going from strength to strength. I’m really looking forward to seeing how we fare against them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that I’ve never seen Bear City play. They are a complete mystery to me, which in itself is super exciting! As for Central City, we played last in 2015, it was a close game with CCR narrowly taking the win. This game is bound to be an-other nail biter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And which teams, or matchups, are you most excited to be able to watch when you're not skating? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bear City v MMR looks like it’ll be an edge of the seat game - they’re even closer now the new WFTDA rankings have just come out. And we’re really looking forward to seeing some of our NRG team mates in action in the Team Ireland v Team Scotland re-match - we didn’t get to see them at Road to TBC last year, but even just following the game on Twitter had our hearts racing so we think that game will be a brilliant way to end the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, after EuroClash, what's next for the Canny Belters in 2017? (And is it too early to predict a 2018 EuroClash?) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve got some home fixtures still to confirm for this season, but the big news is that we’re off to Colorado in June to play at Mayhem. And if EuroClash 2017 is a success then we’d love to make it an annual event; watch this space…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash will be held from the &lt;strong&gt;25th&lt;/strong&gt; to the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/strong&gt;, Newcastle. Ticket available here:&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets"&gt;https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; , and on the door.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>euroclash</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/21/euroclash-interviews-newcastle-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 09:57:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: Team Scotland Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/14/euroclash-interviews-team-scotland-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With less than two weeks to go before &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.euro-clash.com"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;' first International Tournament - we're also now just two interviews away from covering all of the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This interview is a particularly special one for us, though, as we're covering the second National Team attending EuroClash - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Team-Scotland-Roller-Derby-235701999922927/"&gt;Team Scotland Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current Team Scotland has only played publicly in two events: The Road to TBC in Cardiff last year (placing 6th); and against Team Belgium in February. Neither of those events featured the final roster of skaters, however: EuroClash will be the first public appearance of the Final 20 in competition.
At EuroClash, Team Scotland will be competing against Team Ireland, who they lost to (in a very tough game for both teams) in Cardiff. This time around, with more training, and the final 20 selection, TS will be hoping to change the result.
The Team Ireland/ Team Scotland bout at EuroClash is a National Teams Event leading up to the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 2018 in Trafford, Greater Manchester, hosted by Rainy City Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13779 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/scotland.png" alt="scotland" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to properly represent Team Scotland, we talked to Crazylegs - the sole three-times member of the Team Scotland roster, and Malin Landsborough - one of the skaters new to the team this time around - about all things Team Scotland and EuroClash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Scotland has been at both previous World Cups - placing 11th the first time, and around the same place the second (slightly underranked each time). The Scottish spirit has always been strong - but how has the experience of the National Team changed (if it has) between versions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crazylegs: It’s definitely changed a lot from World Cup to World Cup; I'd like to say the uniforms have been getting better, but we went from the unfortunate dresses of 2011, to the giant name misprints in 2014, and our training shirts for 2017 have been causing all sorts of jammer body part entrapment issues with the loose arm holes. Let's hope for a successful 2018 squad uniform - we are wide open for sponsorship if anyone is up for a challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess for Toronto in 2011, everything was an unknown - I kept a proper daily diary during my 2011 World Cup journey and I read it back the other day; mind blowing. We knew absolutely nothing! It was the first time any of us had been part of such a big tournament structure and outside of Europe. For a lot of skaters it was their first time skating outside of Scotland. We were excited by every single thing - every shout out, every freebie, the school buses, every time someone asked us to sign a programme. Our wee Scotch corner of supporters made us cry, it was so cool to see people travel to far to come and cheer. I remember being totally shocked that they came!
It happened again in Dallas, with our amazing support from home, and by 2014 we knew much more about setting expectations with skaters and planning and organising beforehand so it was a bit of a calmer experience, but still, playing National teams is always going to be a bit of an unknown because we don’t tend to see them regularly play outside of WC tournaments, and, coupled with shorter qualifier games, and a last minute changing schedule, it’s definitely a different kind of challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, I think we’re focusing more on heads-down regular team training just now, we started sooner and that will hopefully give us more time to build on skills and tactics as a team and will translate into a more consistent level of play for Manchester. The team is looking really strong with a load of potential and I’m all fired up for my third World Cup!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This iteration of Team Scotland's first public outing was at The Road to TBC, long before the selection happened. Despite the early point in TS' training, the team placed pretty well, although the close bout against Spain was unlucky for your resulting placement. What were the high points for you at the tournament, and what did you learn from it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C: It was great! I think the best thing that any team can do to forge fast bonds and get to know each other really well is to travel together and play in a tournament, so for that reason it was a huge success for our training squad, we have a team of characters and they are all lovely. We got to know each other better, learned how we each react to nerves, pressure and being away from our usual team environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was challenging because as a training squad of 30, the management selected teams by picking from a hat, and we also had skaters playing in multiple positions to test out strengths, so we really had to approach it as a training opportunity, which can be difficult in a public tournament, but I think we managed beautifully and the whole team vibe in the games was really positive and focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few of the team got to learn just how bad I am at navigating Google Maps, yet how amazing I am at summoning random taxis to resolve emergency lost-in-Wales situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malin: Road to TBC was a great opportunity for the team to skate together early on in the TS training, and because of this (still being the top 30) we couldn’t all skate in it. But as one of those whose name unfortunately didn’t come up for it, I still truly enjoyed watching it from the side line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel the high point of this tournament was really that it brought us together as a team! It allowed us the chance to really get to know each other in a competitive setting early on in our training. Plus the performance that Scotland put out was fantastic to see – too many close games for my wee heart to take. It did also help us identify our training focuses in moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One striking thing about this Team Scotland selection is the continuing increase in the proportion of Dundee (and Granite City) skaters in the 20. The 2011 TS was almost entirely Auld Reekie and Glasgow, and now all 4 teams are much more equally represented. How does it feel [Malin] to be part of this trend, and what do you [both] think it says about the development of roller derby in Scotland?
&lt;/strong&gt;
C: I think this is a really important question. It's great to see a broader spread of skaters representing from across the teams in Scotland, it's kind of shaping up to look how it should and I think this is reflected in a few other countries this time around. Having wider representation means a more extensive set of experiences to draw from on the team. I'd love to see that trend continue and see competition in Scotland being pushed year on year across all competitive teams, so that we collectively drive the level of play much higher for the athletes here who aspire to that, and want to find the hardest challenges without always having to travel so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to help us build a Team Scotland that the strongest eligible players in our sport are all really keen to be part of, and we can enable that with smart planning; aligning training and game commitments, creating clear training and rest cycles and by working to understand the sanctioned play demands on the skaters teams taking part in WFTDA Play Offs or British Champs - all of which happens in tandem with the National team training. Having that understanding of the priorities of the leagues and teams representing on Team Scotland can ensure that we get the best out of our athletes. This will ensure the continued growth of our sport in National and local play and this is really important as we move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M: It’s a fantastic feeling to be part of such an increase of Northern skaters making the TS cut: we at Dundee have been putting so much into our training the past couple of years, so to make it to this point just cements to us that it is all worth it. For so many of us to make the training squad was such an incredible achievement, especially looking back to the last selection where we at Dundee only had wee Milky representing us, words couldn’t even describe the feeling finding out such a high percent of us made the top 20! This feeling is only heightened by the response we received when the selection was made public, the support we feel behind us is incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is incredible to see the development in Scottish Roller Derby over the past few years! The support we have received from the larger Scottish leagues has been inspiring and has allowed us to level up (and gain WFTDA apprenticeship). Passing on knowledge and camaraderie throughout Scottish derby has brought all levels of leagues together; it’s exciting to see how all the Scottish teams are moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This interview is partly to promote the EuroClash Tournament in Newcastle. Speaking of that, Team Scotland will be attending to compete with Ireland again, who you last encountered at Road to TBC. How are you preparing for the rematch, and what do you hope to achieve this time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C: Team Ireland is such a good, solid team to play, we never seem to get pitched against them in WC tournaments, so it’s great to play them outside of that. There was a lot of positive feedback from within our team about that game – we felt like we had some really strong moments. It was one of those ‘if only we’d had 20 more minutes’ games! It will be really interesting to play again so soon and I hope we can better our score differential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like Team Scotland is hitting the ground running having just been given news of the final squad, so there really hasn’t been much time to prepare for this one - but we have been training every month for the last few months and we have a lot of trust in each other. A lot of the Team Scotland skaters are playing in 2 or 3 of our own league games in the tournament, so we’ll be nice and warmed up for the Ireland game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M: Yes, when we played at Road to TBC it was a close, hard fought game on both sides. As a league we’re continuing with our training focuses and gelling as a team on track, so we can go into this rematch as a united front. This is another step on our road to Greater Manchester, so if we can use this opportunity to put everything we’ve been training into practice, it’ll be a success to us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love a rematch and can’t wait to meet the Team Ireland squad on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And when you're not on skates, what teams or games are you most looking forward to catching?
&lt;/strong&gt;
C: I'm really looking forward to seeing Paris play and also Tiger Bay - I've not seen either of those teams play for a wee while, and both are usually really good to watch. Auld Reekie are playing Paris in April, so it's always good to get a wee spy on them beforehand. I'll be playing with Auld Reekie against MMR, Berlin and the new Leeds team at EuroClash, and I think each of those games will offer a really good and potentially very different kind of challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M: It’ll be great to see all the talent on show throughout the weekend, but I have to say I’m most excited to be there to support our pals at ARRG through their games!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's next for Team Scotland on the road to Greater Manchester?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C: There will be lots of scrimmage and game opportunities set up before the WC I'm sure - we've just upped our training to twice monthly, and our management are looking about for opportunities to help us train against the toughest teams. After Euro Clash we'll probably know more about team positions and move into a more focused training cycle. I'd love to play some more of the European teams in preparation, because we can get to them fairly easily. We'll also most definitely be working on our uniform game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M: I think for Team Scotland moving forward will be for us to settle into our positions within the team and understand how we all work together, just like any newly formed team. It’s great to see how we’ve improved from the first selection to the final 20 and so I’m excited to see this carry on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also anticipating a busy period of fundraising leading up to Greater Manchester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, given the performance of Scotland in the last two World Cups - and the likely even greater scope of the 2018 Roller Derby World Cup in Greater Manchester - how are you hoping that Scotland will do third time around?
&lt;/strong&gt;
C: Well obviously, we want to win it. Falling somewhere above USA, Australia and Team England would be fab :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M: If we can improve on our position from the previous World Cups that would be fantastic, but this is a huge opportunity to bring back experience and knowledge from higher level roller derby, which can only benefit Scottish Roller Derby as a whole. EXCITED!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash will be held from the &lt;strong&gt;25th&lt;/strong&gt; to the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/strong&gt;, Newcastle. Ticket available here:&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets"&gt;https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; , and on the door.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>euroclash</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/14/euroclash-interviews-team-scotland-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 10:07:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: Auld Reekie Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/10/euroclash-interviews-auld-reekie-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a bonus for this week, we're returning to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for one more interview before the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we're talking to&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk"&gt; Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The second oldest league in Scotland, ARRG have been active on the European stage almost as long as they've been competing - and their trip to the USA last year was their third. Whilst they qualified for WFTDA Division 2 Playoffs in 2016, the team declined the invitation for a host of good reasons - unfortunately, given the changes in competitive divisions in 2017, it will be harder work to make it a second year running.
Last year, Auld Reekie's All-Stars competed against Dublin and Newcastle out of the other EuroClash attendees - with a win against the former, and mixed results (a win and a loss) against the latter.
Team Scotland Roller Derby, who will also be competing at EuroClash, have 6 Auld Reekie skaters on their roster of 20, so they will also be represented in the bout between Ireland and Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13740 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/arrg-logo.png" alt="arrg-logo" width="200" height="89"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie's Sharlotte Patterson (also a Team Scotland Rostered skater) talked to us about the team's past and future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The ARRG All-Stars had a pretty good 2016 - starting off with a couple of wins against two other EuroClash attendees, Dublin and Newcastle.What was the high point of the year for you?&lt;/strong&gt;
Oh my goodness where to start? It was a fantastic year for us. We really played well together as a team. It’s hard to pick just one point in the year, there were so many good times for ARRG and myself. I think that I am just proud to a part of this wonderful team and play with very talented people. Everyone works hard at fostering togetherness and making us all feel like part of a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You then went across the Atlantic to compete in the Big O 2016, a return to the tournament from 2014. Despite facing even tougher opponents than the last time, we think you held up pretty well and reached the playoffs selection point with a high enough ranking to be invited to D2, which you declined. Overall, how was the transatlantic experience - does it ever get "normal" to travel across to the USA? And do you think you'll be keeping up the tradition, now that more WFTDA things are being scheduled on this side of the Atlantic?&lt;/strong&gt;
The Big O was an incredible experience and it was my first time visiting the USA. It was a really good environment and the organisers of the tournament were super welcoming. It was a great chance for the team to bond being together for a long period of time away from home.
I’m not sure you could ever say that it be ‘normal’ to travel such a huge distance to play roller derby - an amazing experience, yes! One that I will always remember as my first far flung trip away and my first tournament. The team were really strong and we came out with some very good results which helped us move up the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to say anything further on tradition about going over but it is really exciting that there are more WFTDA things being scheduled this side of the Atlantic; this will mean more opportunities for European teams as cost is always something that will impact teams on going far away for games. I can’t wait to see how this progresses and watch/play in all the high level derby that is out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coming up this weekend, though, you're still giving yourselves the tough challenges, playing current-hot-stuff league in the UK, Rainy City Roller Derby! How did that come about, and how are you feeling about challenging the WFTDA #26 team?&lt;/strong&gt;
This was a game arranged last year, and we have travelled down to scrimmage Rainy on a few occasions over the last year. They are a lovely team to play against and it has provided us with some valuable extra training.
This weekend is going to be an incredibly challenging game but one we can absolutely rise to the challenge of. We have been training hard and have had extra team training sessions this year, not just for this game but for our upcoming season. I know that the All Stars will go down and will always give their absolute best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At EuroClash, Auld Reekie will be playing Middlesbrough Milk Rollers, Bear City Roller Derby and Leeds Roller Derby. How are you feeling about the three bouts, and are there any specific plans you're making for them?&lt;/strong&gt;
Really excited. The last time we played against Middlesbrough Milk was back in 2015 for British Champs and it all came down to the last jam. I still replay that in my head at times because I was the jammer for Auld Reekie during the last jam and it was nerve-racking. Bear City and Auld Reekie have played each other a few times in the past and remained fairly close in the rankings. This will be our first time playing the new merged Leeds team. All three games are going to bring their own challenges, but we have been training as hard as we always do and really nailing our tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you're not on skates, are there any teams, or matchups, which you're particularly looking forward to seeing?&lt;/strong&gt;
There’s so many amazing teams taking part in Euro Clash that it’s too hard to pick. I’m really excited to watch all the other teams because each game is going to be as exciting as the next! It’s so good to see such high level teams have the chance to play in a European tournament and hopefully this is the start of many many more to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EuroClash also features a rematch between Team Ireland and Team Scotland. Last time, Ireland had had a single training session, and Scotland had a selection from the training team - this time you both have more experience of playing together, and Scotland has selected its final 20. (Congratulations on being a member!) How did it feel to be selected for the team - and how are you feeling about the rematch with Ireland?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, I am so proud to have been selected as one of the final 20 to play for my country. It’s an honour and I can’t wait to get stuck in. To be able to go to the World Cup to play and watch some of the best skaters in the world is going to be an unforgettable experience. I’m excited about the rematch with Ireland, it’s going be a challenging game as well as a great training opportunity for Team Scotland; we now have our final 20 selected and will be settled into our specific roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After EuroClash, what's next for ARRG's All-Stars? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The All Stars have a trip coming up to play Kallio and Paris at the end of April, and we will also be playing Newcastle again on 27 May. Our league has been pretty busy since the start of the year and our C team the ASTROs have a game against Bairn City on the 25 March and our B team the Reserves will be taking part in their first British Champs game on 22 April. It’s a really exciting time to part of ARRG and we have many more games coming up for all three of our teams over the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash is held between the &lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt;th and &lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt;th &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt;, by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at the Walker Activity Dome. Tickets available at the EuroClash website: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets"&gt;https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the door.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>euroclash</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>team scotland</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/10/euroclash-interviews-auld-reekie-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 12:23:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: A Chat with: Paris Rollergirls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/07/euroclash-interviews-a-chat-with-paris-rollergirls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next up in our series of interviews with the attendees at Newcastle Roller Girls' &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is the second mainland European team, a team tipped for greatness by The Derby Apex... &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.parisrollergirls.com/"&gt;Paris Rollergirls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-15753" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/prg2017.jpg?w=600" alt="PRG2017" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the two top leagues and teams in France, vying with Toulouse for the top spot, Paris Rollergirls had an exceptional 2016, winning the Elite tier of the French National (against Toulouse, by only a few points), travelling to the USA for the first time (at Beach Brawl), and making serious gains in their WFTDA Rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They've also had the time to mark their 7th anniversary with, amongst other things, a stylish rebranding with an iconic Tour Eiffel logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to Paris' Kill Belle about their 2016, their plans for EuroClash, and their seriously exciting schedule for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[soundcloud url="https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/311055810" params="auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true" width="100%" height="450" iframe="true" /]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash will be held from the &lt;strong&gt;25th&lt;/strong&gt; to the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt;, at the Walker Activity Dome, Newcastle. Tickets available from the EuroClash &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, at £&lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt; advance, £&lt;strong&gt;30&lt;/strong&gt; on the door. (Day tickets £15 on the door).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>euroclash</category><category>international derby</category><category>paris rollergirls</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/07/euroclash-interviews-a-chat-with-paris-rollergirls/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 09:51:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: Central City Rollergirls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/28/euroclash-interviews-central-city-rollergirls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this week's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; interview, covering the attendees at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;' first international Tournament, this &lt;strong&gt;March 25&lt;/strong&gt;th to &lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt;th, we're back in the UK with one of the first teams in the UK... Birmingham's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://centralcityrollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;Central City Rollergirls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In common with many of the attendees at EuroClash, CCR A attended the Beach Brawl in Florida in 2016, winning two out of three bouts with impressive margins. They also managed to compete against two other EuroClash attendees towards the end of the year - holding Dublin to a near draw, and also playing Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year, as well as EuroClash, Central City are once again joining forces with Dublin to play San Fernando Valley Roller Derby, of California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13730 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/central-city.png" alt="central-city" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CCR's Co-Captains, Bunny Massacre and Woo Ha!, answered a few questions for us about the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In common with quite a few EuroClash attendees, CCR had their first trip to the USA last year, at Beach Brawl. As with most first-time USA trips for European teams, you got a good 40+ place rankings boost from this… but how was the experience for you generally, and did you find it different to what you expected?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bunny: We had a fantastic time. This was something that we had wanted to do for such a long time and making it a reality was incredible. The whole trip increased our bond as a team; everyone worked so hard on and off track. I had tried to curb my expectations about our tournament experience. We had taken part in European tournaments in the past which had given us a great basis to work with and unsurprisingly a lot of the set up was similar! We had anticipated challenging and tough games, and weren’t disappointed! Overall it was a wonderful experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woo: It was an incredible experience - right through from the team decision to take part to the fundraising and combined league efforts and on to the actual tournament. The team was in great shape when we arrived and ready to face the somewhat unknown. We had limited intel on the teams we were facing so we approached each game with a view to playing OUR game and nailing our strategy objectives. We learned a lot (the logistics of a USA trip alone comes with its challenges) but we loved the challenge of games outside of the norm for us and the experience of tournament play was invaluable. It was a 100% positive experience!
&lt;strong&gt;You're also one of the few teams to beat London's B team, Brawl Saints, in 2016. Even London B used to be considered untouchable by other UK teams - how was it to play them (and do you think it's a sign that the rest of UK derby is really catching up to London)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woo: What a great game it was too! We're huge fans of the LRG Brawl Saints girls! The competitive Derby landscape is an exciting place to be; teams are getting tighter, strategy is getting slicker and the UK coaching standard is at an all time high. There's so much more we've got access to now for learning from vs 2 years ago... so yes, the playing field is definitely shifting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bunny: We had been working really hard to the build up to this game, as we knew it would be stiff competition. It was also our first home game in 18 months, so there was a real mixture of excitement and nerves! There was an overwhelming sense of pride and of course happiness when the final whistle blew. They were a great team to play. As Woo says there’s so much more knowledge, strategy and coaching available to us now and in such a diverse variety of ways. This is all having a significant impact on the standard of UK game play and definite sense that a real attempt is being made to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You'll be playing hosts Newcastle, and Tiger Bay Brawlers at EuroClash. When you played them last, both in 2015, TBB had a strong win, and Newcastle a close defeat… but in the last two years, both teams have changed things up quite a bit. How are you feeling about the two games?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bunny: We have a long history with both these teams, there’s real excitement to play them again. We are well aware that both teams are going bring their A game and be incredibly challenging to play. What’s great is that they are fantastic teams to compete against, we always really enjoy facing these ladies on track and no matter how fierce the game, it will also be great fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woo: There's huge excitement here at CCR for these match ups. We're really chuffed to be part of the action. Both opposition teams represent a massive opportunity for us to bring our best game to track against a bunch of classy, hardworking women. It's going to be tough, we're under no illusion, but having played both teams previously as well as going through some changes ourselves, we're really excited to see how it plays out on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, in the time between your two fixtures, which teams are you most looking forward to watching?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woo: So many awesome match ups! It's always great to watch Paris in action - we love those girls. We're excited to see the international game at the end of the tournament, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bunny: Playing at tournaments for me always brings along the added bonus that we get to watch incredible derby too! All of the fixtures look particularly exciting, but I’m looking forward to seeing Bear City play as I haven’t had an opportunity to watch them live in a while. And, of course, watching Team Ireland, where we may get the chance to support a couple of CCR team mates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets to EuroClash are available at: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets"&gt;https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and are &lt;strong&gt;£25&lt;/strong&gt; in advance. More information is available at the event page, linked at the top of this article.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>euroclash</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/28/euroclash-interviews-central-city-rollergirls/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 13:03:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: Bear City Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/21/euroclash-interviews-bear-city-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Newcastle Roller Girls' first international tournament, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, fast approaches, we're keeping to our schedule to bring you more interviews with the attending teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we're covering one of the two competitors from mainland Europe, Berlin's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://bearcityrollerderby.com/en"&gt;Bear City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bear City have had a long history in European Roller Derby, founded back in 2008 (as Berlin Bombshells) as one of the first two teams in Germany, they also played the first bout in Germany against Stuttgart Valley Rollergirlz back in 2009, and attended the first ever European international tournament, Roll Britannia, the same year. Joining WFTDA as an apprentice league in 2010 (trailblazing in Europe once again, as they would when gaining full WFTDA membership in 2012, first in mainland Europe), they also founded the EROC European organisational conference at that time. It's fair to say that the league has probably done more than most to promote and develop the sport in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More recently, Bear City Roller Derby have divided their time between their regular attendance at the WFTDA Division 2 Playoffs [which the recent changes to the format may break this year] and participation in the German National Tournament, the Bundesliga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13756 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/bcrd-bear-city-roller-derby_0.png" alt="bcrd-bear-city-roller-derby_0" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bear City Captain Peanut Butter Panic and Co-Captain FoXy Führer answered some questions for us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bear City has been one of the few European teams to represent at the WFTDA Division 2 Playoffs consistently for 3 years in a row now. You even managed to improve on your seeding in 2016, taking 5th place from 8th seed. How did it feel to be representing Europe on this stage, and how do you prepare for something like this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a great honor to be able to take the stage, and help show how competitive European derby has become. Granted, there are many other high-level leagues also representing Europe in D1, but to be able to be part of those leagues showing that strong and competitive play is not only in North America, really makes us proud and fuels our fire to continue pushing the level of our play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We prepared for this by really analyzing our previous games in the season and focusing on 2 or 3 things that we needed to improve on. For example, in Midwest BrewHaHa we identified that our offense needed a lot of work, so we made sure to focus on offense during our training and scrimmage times: offense starts, offense on power jams, offense on a scoring pass, etc. Even if we weren't always successful, we kept trying different ways to be more effective and help lighten the load for our jammers. Some ideas stuck, and became integral parts of our toolboxes, some ideas still need to be refined before we can use them, and some just didn't work at all. The important thing for us was to keep trying and refining our plays. We also ramped up our trainings, with some additional training times and increased intensity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In fact, Bear City spent more time in the USA than in Europe in 2016, with four more bouts at the Midwest BrewHaHa as well. There's obviously significant costs to the increased investment in play with USA teams, what do you feel are the main benefits, other than Ranking?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our league decided many years ago, that we wanted to play on the highest level we possibly can, whether it's nationally or internationally. With that in mind, we set up our league structure to support this goal, and even though at times players were not able to afford the costs, it was really important for us to find ways to finance the trips without leaving them behind. For that, and this is one of the biggest benefits, we've created a really close and motivated league, who always supports each other. Besides the A – Team, our B - Team, C – Team, Officals, and all members work together behind the scenes to reach this goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also the additional team bonding that comes from this kind of trip. We typically fly out a few days before the trip to help adjust to the time change and jet lag, and in the time we have fun activities to help us get to know the city better, and to keep us moving before game time. We've done bus tours, boat tours, escape rooms, each of which impart a piece of the city onto us and really allow us use the time to come together as more than only a group of individuals that play the same sport. We also see the cities that may not be the typical choices when planning a trip to the US, some of which we probably would have never visited otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whilst your attendance of at the Bundesliga is with an exhibition team (not your A team), you still managed to top the rankings in the German Nationals. Why did you choose to enter a different roster to the "standard" A team, and how do you feel about the increased number of National tournaments in Europe?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the Bundesliga and the „Ranking“ season at the same time, can make it difficult to coordinate our season plan. As we schedule our season plan, we need to always have in mind that the majority of the Bundesliga games will be after September, due to the sanctioned season running from about March - August. Naturally, we always want to bring our strongest game to the Bundesliga, and we felt that these games are a great opportunity for our league to give back to Germany and the leagues here. Due to the increased intensity our A Team sees during the season, we decided to mix our A and B teams for the Bundesliga to give those players a chance to excel where they may not have been able to during our regular season games. In the Bundesliga games, we also take the time to try new tactics, player rotations, formations, and really step out of our comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly, the increase of National Tournaments in Europe is very exciting and opens new opportunities for new team matchups to happen. Additional national tournaments in Europe mean that more teams will be able to play each other closer to home, we will see new matchups, and really get a feel for how strong various teams actually are. Presently, teams, us included, decide to go to the USA for a tournament or tour in order to play teams closer to their ranking; however, with the increase in tournaments in Europe, that play comes closer, and perhaps we will even see more US teams traveling to Europe for tournament play. Thank you to all the teams who have worked hard to organize and host these tournaments which give us the opportunity to play. We even have WFTDA D1 Playoffs in Sweden! It is a milestone that all of us have been working toward for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On EuroClash - you'll be playing the hosts Newcastle, Auld Reekie and Middlesbrough in your fixtures. Of these, we don't think you've played Newcastle or Middlesbrough before - Auld Reekie / Berlin bouts have been a more regular fixture, and one which seems to go either way! How are you feeling about (and preparing for) these games?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie has always been one of our favorite opponents! Both of our leagues were founded in 2008 and since then we have a very good and friendly relationship. We are very similar in relation to our structures, visions, and gameplay. They are always good hosts, fair opponents, and a tough team to play against. So everytime we meet on track, it feels like meeting a really good old friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we have never played Middlesbrough before, we've kept an eye on them and have seen their hard work they put in during 2016. They went to the US, played different teams there, and won every single game. Middlesbrough is definitely going to be a tough opponent for us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, never underestimate the hosting league! Hosting leagues seems always exhausted, stressed out, there is a lot of going on – organizing a big tournament like that is not always fun and a big challenge for the whole league. However, it is also a good opportunity to grow together as a league and forces are released from which you thought they were not there. Newcastle has the home field advantage here, and will be on fire!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For us, it is always an exciting challenge to play teams we have never played before. We are using our resources to make sure we are up to date with how the teams are playing and what their rosters look like. Footage is always a great resource to utilize, which allows us to see what strategies teams are using and how we can effectively shut those strategies down. Playing three games in two days is tough, both physically and mentally, even with previous tournament experience. Which means that part of our training also includes effective mental training, so we can continue to push forward and always bring our strongest game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, in the time between your two fixtures, which teams are you most looking forward to watching?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering that all of the teams are ranked closely, I feel that none of the games should be missed! It'll be hard not to watch the games until the last minute, when we need to prepare for our own games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, we are definitely excited to see Paris play, since we will be playing them the next weekend. It will be a nice preview to what we can expect in our game against them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash will be held from the &lt;strong&gt;25th&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt; at Newcastle Roller Girls' regular venue, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Walker+Activity+Dome/@54.9687101,-1.558266,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487e7068944e76d1:0xe1a6394d9f25325!8m2!3d54.968707!4d-1.556072"&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Tickets and other information at the official website: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;http://www.euro-clash.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bear city roller derby</category><category>euroclash</category><category>interviews</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/21/euroclash-interviews-bear-city-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 10:19:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: Leeds Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/15/euroclash-interviews-leeds-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leeds Roller Derby is, technically, the youngest team attending Newcastle Roller Girls' &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;in March, having formed from the merger of Leeds Roller Dolls and Hot Wheel Roller Derby only &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/19/by-their-powers-combined-they-are-leeds-roller-derby/"&gt;scant months ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
Whilst Hot Wheel had a lower ranking than Leeds Roller Dolls, we're pretty sure that the new LeedsRD will gain from the breadth of skaters available to it, and would predict that their performance will be at least as good as Leeds Roller Dolls (currently ranked 22nd in Europe by Flat Track Stats).
There's certainly a wealth of experience in both teams, as LRD spent much of 2016 in the Tier 1 of British Champs (finishing in the middle of the table), and then in the Mayday Mayhem across in the USA; whilst Hot Wheel, who were just breaking into Europe, debuted at SKOD 2016 in Belgium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14923 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/02/lrdtrain.jpg" alt="lrdtrain" width="1600" height="922"&gt; Leeds Roller Derby don't have a logo, so we're showing you their first practice together instead!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LeedsRD Co-Captains Lana del Slay and Nina answered a few questions for us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We should start with the big news: Leeds Roller Derby didn't exist as a league until late last year, when Leeds Roller Dolls and Hot Wheel Roller Derby merged. You've published your first combined roster, and there's a good contribution from both leagues - what would you say each league brings to the new collaboration?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lana del Slay: I think each league brings similar things, that's part of the reason we merged. We have great people who bring a range of experience and knowledge but mainly passion and enthusiasm for the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 was a pretty good year for both of your source leagues: Leeds Roller Dolls and Hot Wheel both did exceptionally well in British Champs, but also the Dolls had their second successful trip to the USA in the Mayday Mayhem, and Hot Wheel their first "international" tournament at SKOD2016 [beating their seeding by 4 places!], following the Dolls (who attended in 2014). What were the high points for you over 2016, and will the new Leeds Roller Derby be picking up where Leeds Roller Dolls left off, in terms of International derby?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lana del Slay: Both those things were high points for sure, but I think we’re all in agreement that the decision to merge is the best thing either team has ever done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nina: And that’s our biggest priority right now - focusing on us, Leeds Roller Derby. Our number one goal for the season is becoming a &lt;em&gt;team&lt;/em&gt;, which may not sound very ambitious considering where both of us came from in 2016 but we feel it's the best thing for us. This isn’t just about 2017, it’s about the season after that, and the season after that. Once we know our teammates then we can focus on international derby. And there is so much talent in the UK and Europe we are happy to concentrate our efforts this side of the pond for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This interview is to help promote EuroClash, which is just one big tournament that LeedsRD is throwing itself into in its first year. How are you preparing for taking on some of the top European teams, and who are you most looking forward to playing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nina: Lots of training and getting to know each other! In terms of the teams, we are excited to play both ARRG and Dublin. Each team brings something different. ARRG we haven't played in quite some time so will be a bit of an unknown whereas both LRD and HWRD played DRD 2015/2016 [&lt;em&gt;ed: Leeds Roller Dolls took a win in late 2015, whilst Hot Wheel lost last October&lt;/em&gt;] so will be interesting to see how we perform against them as Leeds Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With the schedule as it is, LeedsRD will also have the chance to watch quite a few other games - are there any teams, or matchups between teams, which you're particularly looking forward to?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nina: Yes! Definitely Bear City and Paris. Newcastle and MMR are always good teams to watch too because their blockers are so physical and hard hitting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 is already a big year for Leeds Roller Derby, but is there anything else coming up in the future for the league? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lana del Slay: So much is happening in the Leeds Roller Derby camp. We are beavering away putting the final touches to our season outside of the British Champs. We plan to have a few home games over the year where we can hopefully showcase our full league and host games for the A and B team as well as our Junior league. October is going to be a very big month for us. We’re going to be celebrating 10 years of roller derby in Leeds with our rebrand which we’re going to be launching then, and let's not forget the return of the Great Yorkshire Showdown which is also going to be in October.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>euroclash</category><category>hot wheel roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>leeds roller dolls</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/15/euroclash-interviews-leeds-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 10:53:36 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>