<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about fair city rollers)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/fair-city-rollers.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Fair City Rollers: Rising</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/20/fair-city-rollers-rising/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Sunday is the only time you'll see Perth's local roller derby league, Fair City Rollers, on track at home this year, due to the popularity of their excellent local venue, Bell's Sport Centre. As a result, for those following the team, it's an opportunity not to be missed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-26879" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/fcr_map-layered.png?w=1024" alt="FCR_map-layered" width="1024" height="948"&gt; Fair City, and the leagues combining to face them as "Scotland's Rising Stars"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fear Maidens, Fair City's travel team, will be facing a mixed exhibition team drawing newer skaters from Ayrshire Roller Derby, Bairn City Rollers' Central Belters, Dundee Roller Derby, Granite City Roller Derby, Lothian Roller Derby and Mean City Roller Derby. Coming together as "Scotland's Rising Stars", these skaters represent some of the best new talent in Scottish roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fear Maidens have played one previous bout this year, losing away to Dundee's B team, the Bonnie Colliders, back in &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/8969"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Due to way Flat Track Stats' rating changes are applied (always equally, but oppositely, to both teams), this has almost certainly underrated the Perth team at present, due to both Dundee teams' considerable strength gains year on year. Whilst this game against an exhibition team will not compensate in the ratings, we're confident of a strong showing from Perth's only roller derby team at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City's Invader Zoom told us, "We are so excited to be playing at home again and can't wait for the people of Perth to see some of our new recruits in action. Our last home game was a nail biter that had the audience on the edge of their seats all game, and we are sure this game will be just as thrilling with a challenge team of skaters from 6 different Scottish leagues!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as Roller Derby action on track, there will be the usual collection of stalls, including an opportunity to support the charity &lt;a href="http://www.clicsargent.org.uk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CLIC Sargent in Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, raising money to help Young Lives versus Cancer. Fair City Rollers will be participating in CLIC Sargent's Rainbow Assault assault course event in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City Rollers' "&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1869400046436599/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pack to the Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;" is at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/Sty37VvYGx92"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bell's Sports Centre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Perth, on the &lt;strong&gt;24th June&lt;/strong&gt;, 2018. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>fear maidens</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/20/fair-city-rollers-rising/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 13:36:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2018 Seasons beginnings for DRG!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/28/2018-seasons-beginnings-for-drg/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a late start due to the very wonderful &lt;em&gt;Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/em&gt; earlier this year in Manchester (!), Dundee Roller Girls are hosting their Season Opener on &lt;strong&gt;15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of April 2018&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;D.I.S.C. in Dundee&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boasting an action packed day for both DRG's A and B team, doors open at &lt;strong&gt;12:30&lt;/strong&gt; with tickets on the day at &lt;strong&gt;£6.&lt;/strong&gt; You can look forward to &lt;em&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/em&gt;' Fear Maidens facing off against the Bonnie Colliders at 1pm, with &lt;em&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/em&gt;' All Star Reserves taking the track against the Silvery Tayzers at 3pm!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a new season of games, come new captains! So we thought we would have a wee chat with both teams' captains to see how the season is shaping up. First up is ALLY-J and Tiny Tearaway captaining the Bonnie Colliders!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="26529,26530" type="circle" columns="2"]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table style="width:100%;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Questions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;ALLY-J&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;Tiny Tearaway&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;931&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Position&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Jammer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Jammer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Derby Hero&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Hubs &amp;amp; Mayhem&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Lady Trample and Mayhem&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Motto&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Lets do dis"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Nothing is impossible, the word itself says "I'm possible""&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How long have you been skating?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I’ve been quad skating with DRG since March 2016, so 2 years now (time flies!) but used to inline skate from the age of 10!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I have been skating 6 years this coming May (scary) and I have been with DRG for 2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;What does this season hold for the Colliders?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We've had the opportunity of playing in Copenhagen, Newcastle and in our home town, and this season we're going to build as a whole Team! We totally found our feet working with each other, and we are looking at focusing on attendance, positivity and building our knowledge of the game!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Yes its going to be very exciting for the Colliders. We have some fantastic games lined up already and a strong team full of skaters determined to be the best.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;As a B team, what challenges to you face?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Finding our way of working together as a team. Fitting in our newest skaters and helping them gain lots more skills and understanding of the game.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We are all part of a very supportive league so the challenges I see aren’t limited to us as a team. We face the same challenges as the A team; attendance, working together well and pushing ourselves to the best of our abilities.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How does the league, as a whole, carve space for the B team?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;As a league, our A and B team train together, which is an amazing opportunity. We are constantly learning from each other, talking over drills and skills; with us skating alongside folk from Team Scotland, really being able to learn from the best is our greatest asset.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;B team, A team who? We're a league that trains together. Skaters for both teams, crossovers and new skaters. We all do the same drills and are expected to put the same amount of hard work and effort into every one from the newer skaters to those who were on Team Scotland.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;And if you could set goals for yourself and for the team this season?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;My personal goal is to work on my jammer skills and tactical knowledge. I want to work well for the team and push myself this season! For the Colliders: to focus on ourselves as a team. Although we are all building our personal skills, I really want everyone to bring positivity and sportsmanship to the Colliders.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Our B team has played and flourished with smaller numbers the past season. It would be great to see us play with higher numbers. This would give us the chance to have a solid jammer rotation and walls that are to be reckoned with. To be part of that jammer rotation is my goal for this season.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Second up is the captains of the Silvery Tayzers, Seaton and Bosies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="26532,26531" type="circle" columns="2"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table style="width:100%;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Questions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;Seaton&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;Bosies&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;102&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;37&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Position&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Pivot/ Offence&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Blocker&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Derby Hero&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Serelson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Kid Block&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Motto&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Shitemare"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"SITFU"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How long have you been skating?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;6 years, started and stayed with DRG since then.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Skating for six years, initially with GCRD and have been with DRG for almost 2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;What does this season hold for the Tayzers?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I'll probably cry and give dramatic speeches alot. Hoping that as a league we'll be able to continue to perform like we did last season but also move passed that, honing in our skill set. The Tayzers have always performed under a "get the job done, nae fancy shit" mentality and I want to continue that while progressing within the WFTDA rankings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We are continuing to evolve the skills, tactics and endurance that we've developed last season. Which will set us in good stead for the exciting and tough games we have lined up for this year.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;As an A team skater, how do you stay ontop of your game&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I hydrate and then spew it up if I go too fast.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Pepsi Max, avocados and hummus. And cross training.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How has becoming a WFTDA league changed your priorities and training?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I think it gives us clear global equivalents to try to compete against, which we haven't really had before. It's good to be able to feel super involved with the development of the sport as a whole, as well as having access to more teams.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;It allows us to skate against teams of a similar calibre at national and international level, as well as competing in tournaments! This emphasises the need for a strong mental game, the ability to work as a tight unit and to continue to function when the fatigue sets in!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;And if you could set a goal for yourself and your team?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Finish a game without a spew or a cry, working on my mental game is a constant priority as well as my on track skills. As a team, I just want to end every game as a happy wee unit proud of what we have just done.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;My personal goal is the same as it was when I first started skating, which is to get lower! As a team if we can continue to work together, support each other on and off track and leave each game with a sense of achievement, then that's a job well done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26534" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/fbimage-01-1.png" alt="FBImage-01 (1)" width="6035" height="8534"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15th April 2018&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; Dundee DISC&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/908750512641504/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Event Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; 12:30-5pm&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; £6 on the door&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>interviews</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/28/2018-seasons-beginnings-for-drg/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 09:00:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2017: the year of (more) Scottish Derby?</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/08/2017-the-year-of-more-scottish-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we previously flagged, while the number of Scottish Leagues had been growing recently, the conversion of those leagues into bouting leagues had been a little slower... until 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most prominently, Perth's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/FairCityRollers/"&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (who are effectively a new league after their hiatus led to a large changeover of members) and Scotland's second-northernmost league, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://helginrollerderby.wordpress.com/"&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, will be joining forces to take their first bout together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-15876 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/packfromthedead.jpg" alt="PackFromTheDead" width="1702" height="630"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;April 16th&lt;/strong&gt;, in Perth's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Live+Active+Bell's+Sports+Centre/@56.4029941,-3.437384,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48863b152b41b60b:0x2b806df2e1d11749!8m2!3d56.4029912!4d-3.43519"&gt;Bells' Sport Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (famous for its domed roof and exceptionally shiny floor surface), &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/254873508256762/"&gt;the event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, going by the name "Pack from the Dead", will kick off as doors open at &lt;strong&gt;1pm &lt;/strong&gt;for a&lt;strong&gt; 1.30pm &lt;/strong&gt;start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking to us, Fair City said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce FCR’s comeback bout will take place in Perth on Sunday 16th April. After having a break of almost 5 years from competing, we’re back! We’ve created a brand new team of dedicated players, who’ve worked their butts off to get bout ready. FCR will be playing against Elgin’s team ‘Helgin’ at Bells Sports Centre and we want to welcome them to Perth for what will be a fantastic game. We’ve trained hard and played friendly matches against some fantastic teams, all with the aim of getting us bout ready…and now we want to shout out ‘bring it on’! 'Pack From The Dead' was the perfect name; FCR have been resurrected. Everyone is welcome, under 12s are free, please get your tickets now. Looking forward to seeing you all there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helgin Roller Derby are equally excited, with their Mane-iac telling us: "I'm very proud of how far Helgin has come as a club over the last two and a half years. We've come a long way from our very first days as a group of 4 girls attempting to skate in a small hall, to having a team of mins-passed skaters and preparing to play in our first game. Just thinking about playing in this game gives me butterflies, it's such an achievement for the club, and an exciting and momentous day for all the skaters. I can't wait to put on my Helgin uniform, skate on track as a team and show everyone what Helgin's made of!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fellow skater Bruteyvicious agrees, "It's a pretty momentous occasion. It was just a fantasy for us a year ago, but we moved steadily and grew together until we reached this point. We've played in many scrims between us but actually playing as a team together is really going to feel special! This is why I joined Derby, to play alongside my team in a sport I love. We will give 100% and will continue to do so and strive to keep playing and improving. I'm confident we can hold our own in our first bout. I can only imagine the adrenaline I'll feel on the day, I really can't wait."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it's not just Helgin and Fair City who are planning to hold their first bouts this year.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.invernessrollerderby.com/"&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are also planning to bout before 2017 is out, with a date scheduled for 19th August. Whilst we know ICRD will be hosting the bout, almost everything else (including their opponent) is not public at this time - as soon as there is an official announcement to be made, we will be highlighting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the other end of the country, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DoonhameDerbyDolls/"&gt;Doonhame Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, of Dumfries, are also planning their first public bout, although even less details are available than for ICRD. We hope to bring you details in the second half of the year!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>doonhame roller derby</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/08/2017-the-year-of-more-scottish-derby/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 14:01:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Skaters on track for New Town Cherry Popper</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/09/new-skaters-on-track-for-new-town-cherry-popper/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;March 19th&lt;/strong&gt; sees the Livingston area's &lt;strong&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; host a one of roller derby's traditions - a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1048868645164481/"&gt;cherry popper bout&lt;/a&gt;, showcasing new skaters from a mix of leagues. The bout will be held in New Town's current bouting venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/DSZTrnU8cYo"&gt;Blackburn Community Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6395" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/412387_204493976333497_2093997456_o.jpg?w=600" alt="412387_204493976333497_2093997456_o" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skaters from Auld Reekie Roller Girls, Bairn City Rollers, Lothian Derby Dolls, Doonhame Derby Dolls, Ayrshire Roller Derby, Fair City Rollers and Preston Roller Girls will join host New Town's own new skaters on track in two exhibition teams: The Morello Mashers (skating in hot pink) and the Women of Mass Destruction (skating in sapphire).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an ideal opportunity to see the potential of new roller derby skaters as they play their first bout in public. It's particularly exciting to see skaters from some of Scotland's leagues who are not publicly bouting yet, as this is a preview of perhaps what we might expect from Ayrshire, Doonhame and Fair City when they enter public bouts as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a slightly later game than we normally have in Scotland, with doors opening at &lt;strong&gt;4:45pm&lt;/strong&gt;, for a 5:15pm start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are available online from &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2521813"&gt;brownpapertickets&lt;/a&gt; for just &lt;strong&gt;£4&lt;/strong&gt;. Under 14s are free. Tickets will also be available on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>cherry poppers</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/09/new-skaters-on-track-for-new-town-cherry-popper/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 21:19:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-bouting Leagues Roundup of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/30/non-bouting-leagues-roundup-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year has seen another uptick in the number of new leagues in Scotland, with both &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HelginRollerDerby"&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/WeeCRD"&gt;Wee County Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; joining the ranks of &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/InvernessCityRollerDerby/"&gt;Inverness City&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/FairCityRollers/"&gt;Fair City&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Ayrshire-Roller-Derby-Official-618921518215712/"&gt;Ayrshire&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DoonhameDerbyDolls"&gt;Doonhame Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; as leagues making the journey towards their first public bout. As traditional, we're covering all of these leagues together in a Review of the Year, as usually bouts are a big part of what the bouting leagues cover about in their own articles. Since we have so many non-bouting leagues this year, however, we're splitting this article over several pages for readability - click the links at the bottom of each page to move between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every league forms its own relationships with the wider derby community when starting out, but some of our non-bouting leagues have developed particularly close ties.
Inverness City Roller Derby were very happy that Helgin Roller Derby started up nearby in Elgin, and the two have been combining resources:
"Helgin are fantastic and are growing so fast.
We try to go through as often as possible to coach them and help them with anything they may need help with and they often come through to us for a session and with such a big turn out at these sessions it boosts team morale."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5376" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/pudz.jpg" alt="PuDz" width="960" height="540"&gt; Power of Scotland's PudZ, selfie with combined Inverness and Helgin skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helgin are equally happy with the relationship, as they benefit from ICRD's experience and numbers. "All of our skaters rave about Nat from ICRD’s sessions for days afterwards – she really works us hard and we learn a lot! […] We’re looking to link up with ICRD at least once a month in 2016, so that we can all get a bit more contact and pack skills practice – something that can prove difficult if you’ve got a session with low numbers."
Of course, Helgin have also been keeping up their connections with the team to the East of them, and Granite City have been as supportive as they were at Helgin's founding, even donating kit and support for their fresh meat sessions. The Brawlermen also donated Power of Scotland's PudZ for a training session, "Our session with PudZ from Power of Scotland was brilliant – it was our first proper session where we got to practice game tactics and we learned so much!", which also included ICRD, "we had PudZ from POS run a session on walls and pack work which was also tremendously good fun."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, at the south end of the country, Dumfries' Doonhame Derby Dolls made the fortuitious discovery of nearby Carlisle's &lt;a href="http://www.bordercityrollers.com/"&gt;Border City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;, who are newly founded this year. The two leagues have quickly become quite attached, as Doonhame noted: "We only recently discovered that Carlisle had a team on the go through Facebook, one of our girls is from the area and she never even knew haha! This is now the closest team to us! We got in touch and done our own first ever guest coaching with 3 of our girls travelling down to their training night and they couldn't have been more welcoming, they're a great bunch of guys as we expected and they were so pleased to learn and understand where to go from where they'd got to. Georgie and Chloe Holmes helped start is up and have done well starting from scratch. We have kept in touch and they have been along to support us at games in Newcastle and Glasgow, making wee banners and being total fangirls which is amazing (it's usually us fangirling others!). "
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h6&gt;RECRUITMENT AND TRAINING&lt;/h6&gt;
All of the non-bouting leagues have been focussing on the three most important things for any newer league: recruiting skaters, training them to pass mins, and raising money to support all of this.
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, &lt;em&gt;Helgin&lt;/em&gt; held several successful fresh meats this year, recruiting 19 since we &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/23/helgin-roller-derby-scotlands-northernmost-league/"&gt;interviewed them last&lt;/a&gt;, and have also gained some transfers from other leagues "We’ve gained another few regular skaters, including some skaters formerly of Granite City Roller Derby, New Town Roller Girls and Belfast City Rockets, and we’ve now got enough people training on a regular basis to be looking to put a team together". They also have a tremendously organised public training plan, as anyone can see from the regular updates on their Facebook page, "This started back when we were chopping and changing venues a lot, as we were still trying to find permanent training locations, and we needed to keep people informed of where the sessions were. Many people commented that they liked knowing what was coming up, so we just kept it going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We like to be organised, and have a progressive training plan so that we can see the development of our Fresh Meat – sometimes sessions go to plan, sometimes you’ve got an odd number of people there and the ‘paired work’ session plan goes out the window! Slowly but surely we’re working it all out, and we hope to get our next batch of Fresh Meat minimum skills passed much quicker."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They've also been doing quite well at fundraising, having entered multiple grant shortlists, and also "doing rather well with community fundraising, and held another successful pub quiz at the end of August, keeping us afloat for a bit, and we’re looking to put on another at the end of January or beginning of February, to boost funds for 2016."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inverness&lt;/em&gt;, being one of the more established leagues in this article, has been growing a little more slowly, "We've had a few intakes but the struggle to find new members in Inverness is ongoing, we've lowered the age limit to 16 to try grow the team a little, we've got a few new(ish) faces and everyone is coming on leaps and bounds, and we should fingers crossed have them all mins passed just after the new year."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perth's&lt;em&gt; Fair City Rollers&lt;/em&gt; have had an interesting year, given that we reported last year that they were aiming to bout in 2015. Instead, this year has been one of introspection and consolidation. "Over the past year we've redefined ourselves as a team; who we are, what we do and where we're headed.  Our direction has become more bout focused and we've started to work towards becoming an actual bouting team again.
Over the past year we've worked on aligning focus and skills, and recruitment.  We're currently about halfway through our training programme of the new skaters we recruited in September, and are aiming to bout in 2016"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-5372" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/11880588_901492176606579_4883872526247151434_n.jpg?w=300" alt="11880588_901492176606579_4883872526247151434_n" width="300" height="300"&gt; The Wee-County Golden Gauntlet logo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clackmannanshire's &lt;em&gt;Wee Country Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt; have been attempting to retain the momentum from their initial launch (which we interviewed them about &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/29/a-wee-chat-with-wee-county-roller-derby/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), partly by launching their distinctive gauntlet logo,
We really wanted our logo to describe the fight we have for derby, and our community spirit rolled into one. Its our take on the clackmannshire logo of the gauntlet, with 'Look Aboot Ye' as a tag line. It works as a double meaning, having to be aware at all times who and what is around you on track.
There was a real buzz around the team in the beginning, it was great: lots of attention and press coverage. We had a strong initial recruitment and kept a steady flow of interest, with word of mouth travelling fast. It has been a challenge to form a solid basis for the team, but we have a great foundation of members now. Its been a tough year, of trial and error and lots of personal growth. We were overwhelmed by the support and commitment of the members we do have, as they get stuck in and really help to make our team a family.
Looking at how far we've come and comparing it to how far we have to go to allow us to have our debut bout is quite a step, but were confident that we have the determination and the strong mind set to make it happen."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5381" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/11050639_820246781416517_7188774811881300574_n.jpg" alt="11050639_820246781416517_7188774811881300574_n" width="540" height="960"&gt; Coach Graeme Gow keeping a watchful eye on the paceline at Ayrshire Roller Derby (Credit: Sally Wilkes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt;, meanwhile, have enough mins-passed skaters that they're starting to attend scrims and the like. "ARD have had an excellent year. We were joined by coach Graham Gow of Power of Scotland and Mean City fame. Our team may be small at the moment but it is growing all the time! Our mins passed players are regularly participating in open scrims and learning all they can. We would really like to thank all  the local teams that have helped and supported us this last few months." In addition, ARD have been at a whole host of fundraising and publicity-related engagements, including a stall at their local Christmas Fair. They've also had enthusiastic spectating presence at many bouts this year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, to the south, &lt;em&gt;Doonhame&lt;/em&gt; have been growing strong,
"Recruitment was a challenge to start, with maybe 6-10 people showing up at the start of the year, we then took a break from 'Fresh Meat' open nights and 're-evaluated our training / introduction methods. We then went on to having 2 of our most successful openers in Sept and October with a full house (of 30odd) both nights, and around half of that number dedicating and joining the team! Its the keeping them excited and committed that's the harder bit. We try to encourage everyone to the best of their ability and push those wishing to be pushed, but at a pace that's comfortable with them. We have been very lucky to be able to have a lot of amazing players come along and guest coach for us. To be able to have such a high profile skater like Stefanie Mainey come and guest at our bootcamp in May 2015 was amazing! She was brilliant  and really put us through our paces on the track and giving us some great insights! We love learning new stuff and stretching our mindsets."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5368" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/received_10153711888193956.jpeg" alt="received_10153711888193956" width="600" height="339"&gt; Doonhame's 7 cherry popping skaters at Bristol Roller Derby's event. (Credit: Andy Jardine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Ayrshire, Doonhame have a strong core of mins-passed skaters now, but they've been seeking out public cherry-popper bouts as well as scrims. Most notably, they even managed to appear on film in their first ever appearance (at Bristol Roller Derby's Summer Double Header): "There was 7 of us that popped our cherries in Bristol. It wasn't just any normal cherry popper though, we were filmed by the BBC 'See, hear' programme to promote the abilitly to skate with deaf / hoh players. What a rush! It was so nerve racking, exciting and hundreds of miles away from home, but we did it!
After we got the taste, we actively started to look for cherry poppers, charity games, closed scrimms, anything to let us get out there to play. Its really difficult, frustrating, when you have a handful of players passed skills, gagging to play, but not enough players yet for a full team! Which leads to all of these brilliant events opening up their doors to us, where you learn just how special roller derby is. This has meant us travelling to Edinburgh, Dundee and Newcastle for scrimms and bouts to join other teams. The friendships and camaraderie throughout playing with other teams would be the highlight of travelling, and of course gaining the experience and playing along side some awesome derby gals. "
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h6&gt;PLANS FOR NEXT YEAR&lt;/h6&gt;
We asked each of the leagues about their plans for next year, and it looks like most of them have the same aim in mind: getting on track for their first public bout!
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doonhame&lt;/em&gt;: "All in all I think 2016 is going to be amazing for DDD as we are pushing our girls hard to try and bag a full team line up to finally play as a proper DDD full team. Until then though the girls that have passed will be playing in mixed scrim and bouts when they can and it's great we're always thought of to take part. 2016 will just be Onwards and upwards for DDD. Watch this space!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ayrshire&lt;/em&gt;: "We reckon we will be putting a team together at the beginning of next year and we REALLY cant wait to get stuck into playing!
I feel like it will be next year's [update] that has all the exciting stuff in it!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fair City&lt;/em&gt;: "[We] are hoping to pop our collective team cherry at the start of March 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, within the year of the restructure, we'll be back on track and competing against other teams.  Exciting times for the FCR!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wee County&lt;/em&gt;: "For next year we're hitting training and promotion head on, really pushing ourselves to the limits i know we can achieve. New and improved training programmes will be put in place to fully structurise the fresh meat members, also one for the more advanced skaters.
Were looking to get into the community in a big way, and doing our bit for local charities.
Our goal for 2016 is to integrate roller derby into the Wee County in a big way, so as always, look aboot ye."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Helgin&lt;/em&gt;: "Well, fingers crossed, we get all of our current skaters mins passed in early 2016, and then we’re going on the road to join some boot camps and open scrims to get a bit more experience in game play.  This, along with regular training with ICRD will hopefully have us bout-ready by the end of the year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re planning to hold three more Fresh Meat intakes – probably around February, May and September to keep our skater numbers up, and probably a similar number of fundraisers to keep us going financially. We’re also hoping to get our Business Plan finished over the Festive period (since our training venues are closed and we can’t skate :() and will be able to widen the net of the funds we can apply to, so that we can get scrim vests, more hire kit, more people first aid trained, and even cover our hall hire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve also been in discussions with Moray Sports Centre (a new state-of-the-art sports centre planned to be built on the southern boundary of Elgin) and things are looking hopeful that we may well have a new home in the future – one large enough to host bouts!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inverness&lt;/em&gt;: "We are looking forward to 2016 and having a team ready to start playing after all these years, we will be frequenting Dundee's open scrims with everyone learning to nso's for a couple of turns and then scrimming when mins passed, also we will have a regular session every month with Helgin to keep building on pack skills and game play.  Fingers crossed that later in 2016 Icrd will hit the track as a team!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all goes to the plans above, it's quite possible that next year, there will be no non-bouting leagues roundup, as there'd only be one or two leagues left to cover in it! As always, it's an exciting time with the growth of Scottish derby, and 2016 might see the next big wave of leagues entering the bouting world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>review of the year</category><category>wee county roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/30/non-bouting-leagues-roundup-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 12:29:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-bouting Leagues: Round up of 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/01/11/non-bouting-leagues-round-up-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While we've covered the majority of the bouting leagues in Scotland in our Round-ups of 2014, we cannot and should not forget those leagues who did not bout in the last year, either because they are still growing towards that exciting first bout, or for other reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught up with &lt;a href="http://www.invernessrollerderby.com/"&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.faircityrollers.com/"&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ayrshire-Roller-Derby-Official/618921518215712"&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; to get their perspective on the past year. Doonhame Derby Dolls have also been having an exciting year, and their experience in trying to start up a second junior derby league in Scotland &lt;a title="The Future of Derby: Junior Roller Derby, Part Two" href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10/the-future-of-derby-junior-roller-derby-part-two/"&gt;has been covered here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby, having started as a Women's Derby League in late 2013, caused some surprise by announcing their intent to change to a Co-Ed league structure in mid 2014 (becoming Scotland's second Co-ed league, although not the second bouting Co-ed, with Mean City's change to Co-ed more recently). Ayrshire's Nicola Manley had this to say about their year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby has had a good year in 2014. We have restructured the management at ARD and have a very dedicated team. We have recently enjoyed success with some fundraising and as a result will be able to provide some kit so new recruits can come and try out skating. We have been working hard on our training schedule to find one that works for us and provides plenty of variety.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our change to a CoEd league was perhaps a little soon and not without its own problems....namely lack of male interest also, some women were uncomfortable with idea so we need to think carefully about this in the New Year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have a number of skaters ready to take their minimum requirement skills test shortly, so we plan to be putting a team together in the spring. We are extremely grateful to our friends in other local leagues for all of their support and have had guest skaters come and help us out from time to time, which has been greatly appreciated!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the northernmost league in Scotland, Inverness City Roller Derby (ex Nasty Nessies) have also gone Co-ed, as well as continuing to strengthen and develop the league as a whole. Speaking for the league, Bee-Yatch said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2014 was a busy year for ICRD and our greatest news of the year was securing a permanent venue, we are now in Hilton Community Centre on Monday and Wednesday evenings. Having secured this venue means we can now actively recruit again for ICRD and have just started advertising for our next intake which starts in February.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt; At the moment ICRD have a mixed bunch of skaters and are working on getting all of the team MINS passed, some skaters are already MINS passed and are on hand to help the newer skaters and encourage/motivate them to keep going and be awesome!  Last year we brought the age for training down to 16 as we had interest from younger skaters wanting to become involved  in the team. As we don’t currently have a junior league (we’re working on it though!) we decided to lower the age to 16, on a strict no contact basis until skaters become 18.  This has had a positive effect on the team and along with being co-ed we are keen to promote Roller Derby as an inclusive sport open to all regardless of age, gender or ability.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt; ICRD launched our new website this year as well to reflect our new name, logo and colours. The site is easy to navigate and over the coming months will have information from skater profiles to taster sessions for those interested in strapping on a pair of skates and joining up! The website can be found at &lt;a href="http://www.invernessrollerderby.com/" target="_blank"&gt;www.invernessrollerderby.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all of the non-bouting leagues in this round-up, Fair City Rollers will be leaving most quickly - they caused some excitement on being announced as one of the teams at Voodoo-hosted Highland Rampage tournament in February, marking their return to bouting status after some time rebuilding. Lauren Kettles, Fair City's PR rep had this to say about their preparations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;At the beginning of this year, we were mainly focused on getting our existing skaters through the last of their minimum skills, so it may have seemed like we were less visible for a while. However, after a couple of Fresh Meat intakes  and increasing our numbers again, we started to contact other leagues. I've been out and about getting some experience in various NSO positions in Dundee, Glasgow and Forth Valley. I then took on responsibility for interleague liaison and continue to keep the league up to date with information on scrims, bouts and other training opportunities. All other leagues we've had contact with have been really helpful, welcoming us back with invites to open scrims and opportunities to train with guest coaches. It's important for us to be strongly engaged with the wider derby community, particularly as we build our team towards bouting again. It's been really valuable to us all to be able to keep in contact with other leagues over the year, as any derby related learning is beneficial whether it's on or off skates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Looking towards our inaugural bout, we've been working hard, getting our intermediate skaters through their mins and training up September's newbie intake. We've also been scrimming with other local leagues at open opportunities and getting some valuable NSO experience too. Guest coaching has also been beneficial, with trainers from across Scotland putting us through our paces. Highland Rampage will be a great opportunity to get back into bouting and also begin to establish Fair City Rollers as part of the derby community again. Some of the other leagues taking part have already been helpful to us with scrim invites etc, and we look forward to joining them on track for real.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All three leagues also have Plans for 2015, with all three focussing on recruitment and expansion into the new year. Fair City have already held their first Fresh Meat of the year, last Monday, while Inverness will be holding theirs in February. Ayrshire are simply open to new recruits on a permanent basis, and encourage everyone to contact them via their Facebook page. With Fair City gaining a 2014 Communities grant from the Big Lottery Fund, enabling them to double their training sessions per week, and Inverness City skating in a charity bout and also planning bootcamps for March, it will be an exciting year for all three leagues in 2015!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 in review</category><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>interviews</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/01/11/non-bouting-leagues-round-up-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 12:03:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Review 2014: Non-bouting Leagues Roundup</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/09/derby-review-2014-non-bouting-leagues-roundup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While many of our Scottish leagues have held bouts in the past year, that doesn't make the newer, or relaunching, members of the Scottish Roller Derby community any less important. New leagues are an important part of the derby community, spreading skating to places that it hasn't been before. So, let's spend a little time catching up on what the non-bouting leagues have been doing in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013, Scotland continued to gain new leagues at an impressive pace. Leaving aside Voodoo Roller Dollies (who will be covered in a different article), women's derby leagues sprouted up in Dumfries and Galloway, and in Ayrshire. As is traditional, both the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Doonhame-Derby-Dolls/161632670699789"&gt;Doonhame Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ayrshirerollerderby"&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; were founded by women who wanted to skate, but found themselves too far from the existing leagues to join one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/doonhameandfriends1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3255" alt="Doonhameandfriends1" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/doonhameandfriends1.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="408"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Doonhame Derby Dolls, and friends from GRD and Mean City Roller Derby (Sourced from DDD Facebook page.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;The Dolls have been particularly successful, as skater Claire Warner noted "Our first meet saw 50+ in attendance and that number has grown since (with over 70 paid up members now on the books)!"
As with any new league, that success was supported by the wider derby community, as Claire told us "Our first night was led by Jodie from Glasgow Roller Derby (the woman who had inspired [founders] Debz and Grace) and Cat, a Windsor Rollergirl who luckily for us had just moved to the area, and who has been coaching us ever since. We have had other guest skaters joining in and sharing their skills too, Bruisedog from Mean City, and Turbolinz from GRD came for a visit, Tessington World of Adventures from Granite City Roller Girls and Hazzard from LRG have all dropped in to share their skills, knowledge and love of derby with us, the freshest of fresh meat."&lt;/p&gt;
Doonhame have been exceptionally organised in themselves, as well. In the last four months, they've managed to set up their league branding and management structure, gain sponsorshop, and also garner a huge amount of local media attention, including a spot on ITV Borders News. They've even managed to hold two RollerDisco fundraisers, the funds from which they are planning on using to subsidise costs for skaters on low incomes.
From all of that, you would not be wrong in guessing that their plans for 2014 are.. expansive.
"There is sooo much more planned for this year too (we have just been away on a Dolls development planning weekend)!", Said Claire, "Not only do we plan to gain affiliation, sponsorships/funding to improve access opportunities for other local women, we aim to hold our own local bootcamp to help us work towards passing minimum skills, put on a demonstration bout and hopefully be scrimmaging by the end of the year. In addition to all this we are also looking to take part in local charity fundraisers, spreading the Derby Love and helping those in need in our local community. we will also be running roller disco's on a regular basis throughout the year and hopefully we are about to start organising our own junior derby league!!"
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/ayrshire2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3257" alt="Ayrshire Roller Derby's earliest skaters." src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/ayrshire2.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="411"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Ayrshire Roller Derby's earliest skaters. (Sourced from ARD Facebook page)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Dolls were inspired by one Glasgow Roller Derby skater, Ayrshire Roller Derby was inspired by another. As Lorna McIlvanney told us: "We wanted to start up an Ayrshire league but thought it would be difficult and never had the time to do it. Then at Rollerstop, we spotted Sylk from GRD and approached her to see if she might be able to help us set up. She said she would give advice and help with training as and when. [...] We have had massive amounts of help from Sylk, along with various Mean City skaters. We have been invited to scrim with other leagues (once we are mins passed) and have had messages of support and offers of help from many, which has been awesome."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARD have exciting plans for 2014, as well, as Lorna explained, "We are planning on getting to as many bouts as possible and getting involved where we can e.g. as NSO's etc. Our sights are set on passing mins shortly. We have fundraising plans and recruitment drives coming up. Then, scrims for experience and hopefully we'll be ready for our very first bout. We hope to one day base ourselves in the three Ayrshire (North, East, South) and maybe have our home teams structured that way. That's further down the line obviously, but it nice to have goals."
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;⁂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;As well as the brand-new leagues of 2013, leagues founded from 2012 and earlier still continued to develop over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
In Glasgow, the &lt;a href="http://deadlydivasrollerderby.webs.com/"&gt;Deadly Divas&lt;/a&gt; experienced a hiatus for various personal reasons. A spiritual-successor league, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/renfrewshirerockinrollers"&gt;Renfrewshire Rockin' Rollers&lt;/a&gt;, also appeared, with similar stated aims, but is also currently static. RRR Co-founder, Juggs Knock'her said "At the moment due to a lot going on in our personal lives things are on hold. We plan to have a fairly relaxed approach to skating, as well as training to WFTDA rules and Renegade. We are looking to recruit both women and men. Basically derby is about fun and we hope to keep it that way."
With the Deadly Divas also hinting that they might be waking up, it remains to be seen what happens in the space of second-leagues in Glasgow.
&lt;p&gt;Moving northwards, the resurgence of Perth's &lt;a href="http://www.faircityrollers.com/"&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; continued apace in the past year. League chair Pistol Panties was excited about their continued growth, "Initially, we were holding open sessions and just trying to build our numbers up, with the rec sessions, and we have achieved that. We had a big fresh meat intake in August, funded by a local charity geared towards increasing attendance at women's sports, which was a great success and we had a great response from everyone. That really was a stroke of genius, because it allowed us to invite all Scottish leagues along to an open scrimmage, which not only meant we got to see our friends, but it allowed the girls to get a real flavour of what Roller Derby is really about. We now have good numbers of regular attendees, and a team of (very nearly) mins passed skaters."
The league even managed to one-up most of the rest of Scotland, organising a guest coaching session from Steel City Rollergirls' Shrinking Violet in June. "We worked on basic skills, which was really useful even for the more experienced skaters, we all wanted longer with her, so we did a bit of off-skates afterwards too!".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City are now holding regular fresh meat sessions, with the last one being on the 27th of January, and regular training sessions are up to 3 hours a week. "We feel excited about this year," said Pistol, "and to be in a position to be thinking about getting back to competing in the near future. Basically, the only way is up!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/icrdlogo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-3250 " alt="Inverness City Roller Derby's new, striking, logo." src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/icrdlogo.jpg?w=614" width="368" height="362"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Inverness City Roller Derby's new, striking, logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inverness' Nasty Nessies Roller Girls underwent a few changes over 2013, not least a change of name and branding. The newly styled "&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/InvernessCityRollerDerby"&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;" will retain the "Nasty Nessies" name and logo for their travel team. While ICRD has not yet bouted, their skaters continue to make appearances in exhibition and cherry popper bouts hosted by other leagues, and travel to open scrims in the rest of Scotland. They've also been working on an interesting outreach project, as Scarlett O'Horror told us: "We've just completed a collaboration with &lt;a href="http://www.fixers.org.uk/"&gt;Fixers&lt;/a&gt; - a group that helps promote community participation and challenge stereotypes. We made a film with them, featuring our own lovely skaters, which will be premièred in Inverness - very exciting!"
2014 looks like being the year for roller derby in Inverness, however, "We have a lot planned for this year! We will hopefully move into a new training venue this year, and have a few more mixed bouts lined up, including participating in a bout in April, which is really exciting for us. Some very lucky members are also off to Texas to watch the World Cup in December - picking up tips and training ideas, no doubt! And t-shirts. Always t-shirts."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, at the northernmost point of Scotland, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ShetlandRollerDerby"&gt;Shetland Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; has continued to hold both derby and open skate sessions throughout the year. Men and women are welcome, and the Open skates in particular have been popular.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;⁂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;As you can see, it's been an eventful year with the growing leagues of Scotland, and 2014 promises to be even more interesting!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>deadly divas roller derby</category><category>derby review 2014</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>renfrewshire rockin' rollers</category><category>shetland roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/09/derby-review-2014-non-bouting-leagues-roundup/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 15:22:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Interview with Pistol Panties: Fair City Rollers in 2012 and beyond</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/29/an-interview-with-pistol-panties-fair-city-rollers-in-2012-and-beyond/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of the blog's End of Year interview series, we caught up with Fair City Rollers' Pistol Panties to talk about roller derby in Perth, and the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/29/an-interview-with-pistol-panties-fair-city-rollers-in-2012-and-beyond/271296_475653322465325_1961521013_o/" rel="attachment wp-att-2014"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-2014  " alt="Pistol Panties and the rest of FCR vs Furness Firecrackers. (Photo by Ian Mccreadie)" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/271296_475653322465325_1961521013_o.jpg" width="663" height="442"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Pistol Panties and the rest of FCR vs Furness Firecrackers. (Photo by Ian Mccreadie)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Despite complications in the latter half of the year, Fair City managed 4 bouts in the past year, including a strong showing against the Furness Firecrackers in September. What's the high point of the year from a bouting perspective?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we showed over the past year how a team can improve with hard graft. We think that's reflected in our scores, especially against Furness, we all really enjoyed the bout and even though it wasn't a win, we were still very proud of what we achieved. We are very grateful for the help we had from guest coaches from the other Scottish Leagues and most notably from Alma Geddon of ARRG, who has been a constant source of support for us, both from a training perspective and with the league as a whole. We wouldn't have improved as much as we have without the support we have had from Alma, and Scotland's leagues in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's the best moment of the year from Fair City's perspective?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its hard to pick a specific moment... for me it was drawing a small lead in our bout against Wakey Wheeled Cats in June. That Cats are such a great bunch of girls so it was great to host our re-match, and we had a feeling it might be a close bout, because we thought we had improved as a team, and we felt sure they would have too. I think it was during the second half when we pulled ahead by only a few points there was a flash of "We could actually win this", and I think that was enough to push us to work harder and come back fighting. Even though we didn't win the game, it was definitely a high point for the whole team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bell's Sports Centre is a fantastic venue, and you've been kind enough to donate it to Granite City for their home bouts this year. Do you think it helps a league to have a really solid venue for bout hosting, and how difficult was it getting Bell's?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've had a lot of support from Granite City in the past, so that decision wasn't a hard one, but yes it helps to have a really good relationship with your venue, which we have with Bells. They're always accommodating towards us, when sometimes it can be difficult to find that with a fairly new sport, I'm sure most leagues have experience of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You gained a new sponsor in IntoTheNitemare this year as well. What's your relationship with Raven, and how do you feel about the sponsorship and money-raising side of derby? (How is hire a Fear Maiden going?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know there is a split at the moment between those who see sponsorship in Derby is crucial, and those who see it as moving towards the more commercial side of the sport. When the relationship is mutually beneficial, and everyone is in agreement we see it as a positive thing for the league. That's what we have with Raven, and supporting the derby family is our priority. We think that its important to keep things fresh and capture peoples imagination, which is where the Hire a Fear Maiden came into existence.....its going really well, were hoping to have more success with it next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The big shock for all of Scottish Roller Derby was Fair City's announcement that they were going rec-only for a while. While it's still sensitive, would you like to tell us a little about the difficult decision that this involved?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It really wasn't a choice, it is a necessity at the moment. It has been a blow for us to lose so many skaters this year but we feel really positive about what's happening and where we go from here. At the end of the day there were people who weren't getting what they wanted from the league, or there was another league closer to where they actually live. People should always pursue what is best for them at that time, rather than stay with the league that doesn't suit their needs. There have been some really positive developments for us recently, and were hoping that the new year will bring more of the same!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The promise of a future revival is implicit in the announcement on the Fair City facebook page. What do you have planned for 2013? (This isn't the first time a roller derby league has reinvented itself and come back stronger.)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still a Roller Derby League first a foremost, but we are taking time out to focus on recruitment. As a team FCR are full of people who are really pro-active and positive about the future, and who really want the league to succeed, and that's what's most important to us. Right now were concentrating on listening to our members and giving them what they want from the league. The recreational element facilitates this because it allows us to draw in a bigger audience and get people interested in skating, and we can think about forming a team when we have a solid foundation to build that on. So watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>fcr</category><category>fear maidens</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/29/an-interview-with-pistol-panties-fair-city-rollers-in-2012-and-beyond/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 15:15:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fair City Rollers vs Wakey Wheeled Cats</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/06/03/fair-city-rollers-vs-wakey-wheeled-cats/</link><dc:creator>pandacatkaty</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/06/521762_414813661870699_126978470654221_1494040_105998569_n1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/06/521762_414813661870699_126978470654221_1494040_105998569_n1.jpg?w=668" alt="Image"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Saturday (June 9) the Fair City Rollers bout team, the Fear Maidens will take on the Wakey Wheeled Cats at Bells Sports Centre, Perth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will be a rematch, following a bout down south last September. And Maidens captain, Pistol Panties says the team is ready to face their Yorkshire counterparts again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She said: "It's probably the most exciting and anticipated bout we have because that was my first bout coming back to FCR and I was made captain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"So them coming up to play us, we're interested to see how they've improved and they'll be interested to see if we've improved. We are hoping to get a better score this time round, because last time half the team were playing in their first bout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"And it will be really nice to see them because we we had so much fun at the afterparty and they're a great group of girls."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the Fear Maidens have been working hard to prepare for the bout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pistol Panties added: "We’ve been practising a lot and just trying to focus our energy into mentally preparing because there are some people who are fairly new to the team, as well as the more seasoned players.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We’ve taken feedback from the last few bouts and as far as tactics are concerned we’ve been focusing on default strategy and get our jammers more experienced and improve on our last bout."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 2.30pm on Saturday and entry costs £6.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout preview</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>fear maidens</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>wakey wheeled cats</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/06/03/fair-city-rollers-vs-wakey-wheeled-cats/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2012 18:02:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Popping your bout cherry...</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/05/06/popping-your-bout-cherry/</link><dc:creator>pandacatkaty</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/05/155425_3480119255780_1655254998_2752599_1239366284_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/05/155425_3480119255780_1655254998_2752599_1239366284_n.jpg?w=487" alt="Image"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For most skaters, the first time you bout fills you with a mixture of fear and excitement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You have worked for months to take your place on your league's bout team, passing mins and then getting to grips with tactics, scrimming as much as possible and talking to more experienced skaters to get hints, tips and advice. You know, deep down, you are ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, as bout day draws nearer, chances are the nerves will start to set in. Skating in front of a crowd, playing well, heck even what you choose to wear on the day can create doubt and nerves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Reggie Reg, the Fair City Rollers' newest bouting member, the trick was to not let the nerves get the best of her during her first bout recently, when the Fear Maidens took on Granie City Roller Girls' Northern Fights in Scrimmage of the Damned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, Reggie Reg gives an insight to bouting for the first time, and offers advice to any skaters preparing to compete in their virgin bout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;How long had you been skating before the bout?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Six months&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; What was the best advice you got for bouting and who gave it to you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the day of the bout, Jill Antonic told me to just enjoy myself; that it didn't matter if we win or lose; that there is no league table; and that at the end of the day it was all about having fun. This made me feel much less anxious but at the same time motivated me to give it my best!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; What was your "getting ready" ritual on the day?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Porridge and banana for breakfast, some stretches in the morning to loosen me up, fake tan and lots of dramatic zombie makeup; and I walked quickly to Bells to get rid of some nervous energy!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; What did you like most about bouting?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I liked feeling part of the team; I loved having my team shirt with my name on it; I liked using all the skills I had learned during training; I liked feeling that I was making a difference to how the team was playing!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; How did it feel going out and competing in front of people?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the mortification of falling in front of my fans during the skate out, I totally forgot about everyone watching when it came to competing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; What bit did you not like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Falling during the skate out!!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* What advice would you offer first-time bouters?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the skate out, look at where you are going instead of the people watching! Also, everyone gets nervous but too much can be debilitating. You just need to keep calm and remember that everyone in the sport is very supportive, even the opposing team. So just have fun and do your best!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a title="BoutDay.com" href="http://www.boutday.com"&gt;BoutDay.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fair city rollers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/05/06/popping-your-bout-cherry/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 15:46:41 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>