<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about fcr)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/fcr.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:41:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>An Interview with Pistol Panties: Fair City Rollers in 2012 and beyond</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/29/an-interview-with-pistol-panties-fair-city-rollers-in-2012-and-beyond/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of the blog's End of Year interview series, we caught up with Fair City Rollers' Pistol Panties to talk about roller derby in Perth, and the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/29/an-interview-with-pistol-panties-fair-city-rollers-in-2012-and-beyond/271296_475653322465325_1961521013_o/" rel="attachment wp-att-2014"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-2014  " alt="Pistol Panties and the rest of FCR vs Furness Firecrackers. (Photo by Ian Mccreadie)" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/271296_475653322465325_1961521013_o.jpg" width="663" height="442"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Pistol Panties and the rest of FCR vs Furness Firecrackers. (Photo by Ian Mccreadie)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Despite complications in the latter half of the year, Fair City managed 4 bouts in the past year, including a strong showing against the Furness Firecrackers in September. What's the high point of the year from a bouting perspective?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we showed over the past year how a team can improve with hard graft. We think that's reflected in our scores, especially against Furness, we all really enjoyed the bout and even though it wasn't a win, we were still very proud of what we achieved. We are very grateful for the help we had from guest coaches from the other Scottish Leagues and most notably from Alma Geddon of ARRG, who has been a constant source of support for us, both from a training perspective and with the league as a whole. We wouldn't have improved as much as we have without the support we have had from Alma, and Scotland's leagues in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's the best moment of the year from Fair City's perspective?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its hard to pick a specific moment... for me it was drawing a small lead in our bout against Wakey Wheeled Cats in June. That Cats are such a great bunch of girls so it was great to host our re-match, and we had a feeling it might be a close bout, because we thought we had improved as a team, and we felt sure they would have too. I think it was during the second half when we pulled ahead by only a few points there was a flash of "We could actually win this", and I think that was enough to push us to work harder and come back fighting. Even though we didn't win the game, it was definitely a high point for the whole team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bell's Sports Centre is a fantastic venue, and you've been kind enough to donate it to Granite City for their home bouts this year. Do you think it helps a league to have a really solid venue for bout hosting, and how difficult was it getting Bell's?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've had a lot of support from Granite City in the past, so that decision wasn't a hard one, but yes it helps to have a really good relationship with your venue, which we have with Bells. They're always accommodating towards us, when sometimes it can be difficult to find that with a fairly new sport, I'm sure most leagues have experience of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You gained a new sponsor in IntoTheNitemare this year as well. What's your relationship with Raven, and how do you feel about the sponsorship and money-raising side of derby? (How is hire a Fear Maiden going?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know there is a split at the moment between those who see sponsorship in Derby is crucial, and those who see it as moving towards the more commercial side of the sport. When the relationship is mutually beneficial, and everyone is in agreement we see it as a positive thing for the league. That's what we have with Raven, and supporting the derby family is our priority. We think that its important to keep things fresh and capture peoples imagination, which is where the Hire a Fear Maiden came into existence.....its going really well, were hoping to have more success with it next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The big shock for all of Scottish Roller Derby was Fair City's announcement that they were going rec-only for a while. While it's still sensitive, would you like to tell us a little about the difficult decision that this involved?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It really wasn't a choice, it is a necessity at the moment. It has been a blow for us to lose so many skaters this year but we feel really positive about what's happening and where we go from here. At the end of the day there were people who weren't getting what they wanted from the league, or there was another league closer to where they actually live. People should always pursue what is best for them at that time, rather than stay with the league that doesn't suit their needs. There have been some really positive developments for us recently, and were hoping that the new year will bring more of the same!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The promise of a future revival is implicit in the announcement on the Fair City facebook page. What do you have planned for 2013? (This isn't the first time a roller derby league has reinvented itself and come back stronger.)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still a Roller Derby League first a foremost, but we are taking time out to focus on recruitment. As a team FCR are full of people who are really pro-active and positive about the future, and who really want the league to succeed, and that's what's most important to us. Right now were concentrating on listening to our members and giving them what they want from the league. The recreational element facilitates this because it allows us to draw in a bigger audience and get people interested in skating, and we can think about forming a team when we have a solid foundation to build that on. So watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>fcr</category><category>fear maidens</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/29/an-interview-with-pistol-panties-fair-city-rollers-in-2012-and-beyond/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 15:15:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fair City Rollers Vs Furness Firecrackers Bout Report</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/10/08/fair-city-rollers-vs-furness-firecrackers-bout-report/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perths finest,the &lt;a href="http://www.faircityrollers.com/"&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; played host in a James Bond themed bout against Cumbria's &lt;a href="http://www.furnessfirecrackers.co.uk/index.php"&gt;Furness Firecrackers&lt;/a&gt; on Saturday the 29th of September 2012, in the superb setting of the Bells Sports Centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/10/fcrfurness-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/10/fcrfurness-1.jpg" alt="" title="fcrfurness 1" width="614" height="188" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1799"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Stu Mackin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first few jams of the first period were very low scoring,with both teams assessing the oppositions strengths and weaknesses.Lead Jammer status alternated between the two and things were shaping up nicely for an interesting bout when,in jam 4,the scoreboard went down and an official timeout lasted until a barebones scoreboard was re-established.The enforced break of the timeout,seemed to serve Furness well and in the next few,fast-moving jams they built up a lead over Perth,with Hell For Heather and Steffinately Maybe in particular doing some excellent point scoring,Jam 7 ended 51-20 in favour of the Firecrackers.
Jam 8 saw the Maidens start a slow fightback.A powerjam in Perth's favour gave Louisville Destroier a chance to redress the points balance and despite some excellent recycling work from Furness she managed to pull the score back to 53-35.The next two jams saw the Maidens continue to chip away at the points deficit,but the combination of a  powerjam for Furness and two Maidens in the Bin in Jam 11 saw them,stretch out in front again a little,roughly halfway through the first period the scores stood at 66-50.
In the next two jams the Firecrackers extended their lead,taking lead jammer status in both and creeping the score upwards in their favour again,they continued to dominate the next few jams,denying Perth lead jammer status in all but one with excellent pack work.Jam 18 saw the turning point,when Jaggy Sw'aggie took the score to 87-74,in a powerjam for the Maidens and calling it off to start the next jam with Doh! still in the bin.Perth took advantage of this to put another ten points on the board,but not before the Furness jammer,now released,managed to score two.Perth kept up the pressure over the next two jams,taking lead in both and pulling the scores ever closer by four points with half time fast approaching,to make the score 89-88
The last jam of the half was a hard-fought one,both teams wanting to take the lead into the second period,despite some stellar walls from the Firecrackers skaters Tash Bandicoot,Steely'll Kill'Her and Kammakezzie,it was the Maidens Jaggy Sw'aggie that took the points as her opposite number,Doh!,was sent to the bin once more.Ending the first period with a Perth lead,89-98&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first jams of the second period saw Furness determined to narrow the points gap and Perth equally determined to keep things in their favour,by three jams in,the Firecrackers began to claw back some points with the score now 103-115,three more and the eight point difference had gone down to seven.An old school pivot line start saw Furness take lead ,get a powerjam and take the score to 117-124.The next jam,Doh! took lead and racked up a much-needed eighteen points in a powerjam for the visitors,score now 135-124.The next two jams saw Perth,at first hold Furness in check,allowing them to only score a few points.The following play saw Perth bring themselves back in close with a useful seven point powerjam,held back from scoring more by a disciplined Firecrackers pack bring the score to 138-133.Furness stepped up the pressure over the next two jams,denying Perth any points with some superb walls and pack work,keeping jams short,taking the four and out,building their lead to 149-133.
In jam 35 Stephinately Maybe took lead for Furness and with three of the Maidens in the bin,easily took the score up to 184-133.Perth rallied and held the next jam pointless for both teams,the next few after that saw low scoring,with some great pack work from both sides preventing either from taking full advantage,It took another three jams before the scores crept up to 192-146.With five minutes to go on the clock in jam 41,Furness failed to field a jammer,which gave Perth's Pistol Panties the opportunity to put a very impressive and much-needed 34 points on the board,much to the fans delight this brought the Maidens right back into the running,making the score now 199-180.The last two jams of the bout were again,hard-fought affairs,with the sides closely matched,despite a huge effort from Perth,the bout ended in favour of the Furness Firecrackers,final score 200-182.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/10/fcrfurness-2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/10/fcrfurness-2.jpg" alt="" title="fcrfurness 2" width="614" height="261" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1801"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Stu Mackin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MVP's for the Firecrackers were-
Best Blocker-Steely'll Kill'Her
Best Jammer-Steffinately Maybe
Best Dressed-Kit Kruger
MVP-Yorky Thud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and for Fair City Rollers
Best Blocker-Mini Me
Best Jammer-Jaggy Sw'aggie
Best Dressed-Knock Turnal
MVP-Louisville Destroier&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>fcr</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/10/08/fair-city-rollers-vs-furness-firecrackers-bout-report/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 20:37:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fair City Rollers Vs Furness Firecrackers</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/09/21/fair-city-rollers-vs-furness-firecrackers/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/09/spyshoved.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/09/spyshoved.jpg" alt="" title="spyshoved" width="614" height="868" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1739"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of FCR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.faircityrollers.com/"&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; hold their last home bout of the year against the &lt;a href="http://www.furnessfirecrackers.co.uk/"&gt;Furness Firecrackers&lt;/a&gt;,at Bell's Sports Centre,Perth.The spy themed action takes place on Saturday the 29th of September,doors open 2pm,entry £6.
More details on the &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/219159734879857/"&gt;Facebook Events&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fcr</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/09/21/fair-city-rollers-vs-furness-firecrackers/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 22:50:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fair City Rollers Fresh Meat</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/07/11/fair-city-rollers-fresh-meat/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/07/fcrmeat.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/07/fcrmeat.jpg" alt="" title="fcrmeat" width="614" height="869" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1527"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you live in the Perth area and want to get fit,meet new people and be part of an awesome Roller Derby team?
Then you need to contact the Fair City Rollers on &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Fair-City-Rollers/126978470654221"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fcr</category><category>fresh meat</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/07/11/fair-city-rollers-fresh-meat/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 11:22:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bout preview: Fair City Rollers vs Granite City Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/17/bout-preview-fair-city-rollers-vs-granite-city-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>pandacatkaty</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/gcrg1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1111" title="gcrg" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/gcrg1.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="868"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;In what should be a brilliant bout, the Fair City Rollers Fear Maidens will take on the Granite City Roller Girls Northern Fights in Perth this weekend in the Scrimmage of the Damned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second of four home bouts planned for 2012 for the Fear Maidens, who have been working hard to prepare for what is bound to be a hard-hitting and high scoring contest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a small number of skaters available, FCR have recruited three guest skaters from the Fierce Valley Roller Girls - Fun Ghoul, Deep Fried Pixxie and Jo Anarchy - to join the fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scrimmage of the Damned will take place on Sunday (April 22) at Bell's Sports Centre, Perth, doors open at 1.30pm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>fcr</category><category>gcrg</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/17/bout-preview-fair-city-rollers-vs-granite-city-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 18:18:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fair City Rollers Vs Auld Reekie Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/03/20/fair-city-rollers-vs-auld-reekie-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/03/cell.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/03/cell.jpg" alt="" title="cell" width="614" height="868" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-984"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image by Van Damn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perth's &lt;a href="http://www.faircityrollers.com/"&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; host a bout against &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; Cannon Belles on Sunday 25th March.The bout takes place at &lt;a href="http://www.liveactive.co.uk/venues/bells-sport-centre/how-to-get-there"&gt;Bells Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt;,Hay Street,Perth.Doors open at 1:30pm,entry is £6 on the day,or £5 &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/232683"&gt;in advance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>cannon belles</category><category>fcr</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/03/20/fair-city-rollers-vs-auld-reekie-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 12:43:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bout Report: Pivots of the Caribbean: Dundee vs Fair City 26/11/11 </title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/12/01/bout-report-pivots-of-the-caribbean-dundee-vs-fair-city-261111/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is an excellent bout report over on &lt;a href="http://aoanla.blogspot.com/2011/11/bout-report-pivots-of-caribbean-dundee.html"&gt;Ante Ortus A Novus Lumen Ars&lt;/a&gt; for the long awaited rematch between &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girl's&lt;/a&gt; Silvery Tayzers and &lt;a href="http://www.faircityrollers.com/"&gt;Fair City Roller's&lt;/a&gt; Fear Maidens.Comprehensively written as always by Aoanla with photographs by Laura MacDonald.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/12/pivcarib.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/12/pivcarib.jpg" alt="" title="pivcarib" width="614" height="320" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-636"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photograph courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>drg</category><category>fcr</category><category>fear maidens</category><category>pictures</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/12/01/bout-report-pivots-of-the-caribbean-dundee-vs-fair-city-261111/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 12:13:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls Vs Fair City Rollers</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/01/dundee-roller-girls-vs-fair-city-rollers/</link><dc:creator>cillablock</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perth's Fair City Rollers travel to Dundee in November for one of the most exciting rematches this year. Almost a year to the date since these two teams last met,  massive crowd gathered at the Bell's Sports Centre in Perth for one of Tayside's most hotly anticipated games. Both teams brought their 'A Game' that day, but the Dundee Roller Girls (previously Dundee Destroyers) got their first win and came out on top to beat the Fear Maidens with an impressive score of  161 - 80.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both teams have undergone some radical changes from players to team names but one thing is for sure, both teams have grown so much since their first meeting, that this game is set to be the rematch of the year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/10/pivots-small.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-400 aligncenter" title="Pivots Of The Caribean" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/10/pivots-small.jpg" alt="Dundee Roller Girls" width="614" height="898"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>drg</category><category>fcr</category><category>in the news</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/01/dundee-roller-girls-vs-fair-city-rollers/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 14:01:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Wakey Wheeled Cats Vs Fair City Rollers-24/9/11</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/09/12/wakey-wheeled-cats-vs-fair-city-rollers-24911/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.faircityrollers.com/"&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; travel down to Huddersfield to take on The &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/groups/94328521811/"&gt;Wakey Wheeled Cats&lt;/a&gt; on Saturday the 24th of September,£5 entry,under 10's go free,stalls and bar and a spot of wrestling at half time!
&lt;a href="http://kirkleesactive.co.uk/centres#huddersfield-map"&gt;Directions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/09/wakey-fcr.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/09/wakey-fcr.jpg" alt="" title="wakey fcr" width="509" height="720" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-148"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of Fair City Rollers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fcr</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/09/12/wakey-wheeled-cats-vs-fair-city-rollers-24911/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 14:55:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fair City Rollers-Fresh Meat Intake</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/09/06/fair-city-rollers-fresh-meat-intake/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perth's finest, the &lt;a href="http://www.faircityrollers.com/"&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; will be holding a Fresh Meat session at The Bell Sports Centre,in Perth,7pm on Tuesday 27th of September.
If you fancy trying your hand at this Roller Derby thing,then mark that date in your diary and get in contact with FCR via their website/Facebook.
They will be able to answer all queries about what to wear,safety equipment,skates etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/09/sept-11-fm.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/09/sept-11-fm.jpg" alt="" title="sept 11 FM" width="614" height="867" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-138"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of Fair City Rollers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fcr</category><category>fresh meat</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/09/06/fair-city-rollers-fresh-meat-intake/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 10:00:28 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>