<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about fierce valley roller cubs)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/fierce-valley-roller-cubs.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:39 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The MacIntyres Take Over Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/the_macintyres_take_over_roller_derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's often said that the junior part of any sport is the most important part, as it contains its future.
Scottish Junior Roller Derby's first club, Fierce Valley Roller Cubs, is no more, but two of its graduates are now starting to make waves in Scotland, and the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We thought it was a good time to talk to Skye ("Bee"), and Callie ("Cal-amity") MacIntyre; earlier this year, Skye (guest) bench-coached the victorious Lincolnshire Bombinos away against Newcastle Junior Roller Derby, with Callie awarded Best Jammer in the same bout. They both have a lot of past experience, and ideas for the future, of Roller Derby, so what better people to talk to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Picture of the Lincolnshire Bombinos team, including Callie, and Skye (Bench coach)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/Callie_and_Skye.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Lincolnshire Bombinos, with Callie (#999) and Skye (Bench, right). [Photo: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.incidentlight.co.uk/"&gt;incidentlight&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So I guess we'll start with a bit of history: how long has it been since you two started derby?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Callie and I both started in about June 2014, through Fierce Valley [Roller Cubs] and we haven't stopped since! Callie had a wee few months break between Cubs disbanding and Rollerstop opening up, but that hasn't swayed her in any way. Roller derby is one of the main sports that both of us have picked up and kept at as there is so much appeal for us 😁😁&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, let's talk about the appeal for each of you: why did you start playing... And why are you still playing now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;I started to play because it was a different kind of sport: it wasn't like anything that I had played before, and I though it was really interesting. Now I play because I love to meet new people when I play against different teams, and I gain new experiences when I play with different teams because everyone is taught differently.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Roller Derby is appealing because there is such a lovely community, that's the main thing for me. Granted, there's some competition between skaters/teams but that's present in any sport. I have always loved roller skating, ever since I was wee. I'd love to continue with derby and have loads of new experiences like trying for Team Scotland and maybe playing for the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;Nothing has really changed for us as we were still juniors (except the rules, haha) but the changes make Derby. We can adapt to it and grow from learning all these new things that are being introduced. I love that derby is becoming more mainstream and the sport that we love and spend most of our time playing, is becoming bigger and more people are growing to love Roller Derby too 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, for you, Skye, you're now on the Bairn City Rollers, was that a big change for you, moving from Juniors to the BCR training and bouting ?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;It was a scary jump as a junior because I'd seen all these adult Derby games and been thinking "wow... this is intense..." but, when I finally made the jump, the only difference was that everyone else was physically bigger (as in stronger and more skilled). It was still the same game, it was still the same rules, and I still loved it. I'd really urge anyone who's been in Juniors and is about to age out to make the jump, it's so worth it! It may be daunting but go for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;Callie is itching to move up to adult derby 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Callie, before the game we're going to get onto, you had a previous practice &amp;amp; Scrimmage with the [Lincolnshire] Bombinos - how did that happen, and do you have memories / thoughts about it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Initially I went to Team GB [Junior Roller Derby] training in Oldham, where I met some of the Bombinos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's where I got my foot in the door... My mum struck up a friendship with one of the Bombinos coaches (Beverley Gormley) who has been fantastic, sending us links for games we might be interested in. I then went to a mixed game in Sheffield and I met the rest of the Bombinos there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have become really good friends with Eve (Lady Macdeath) and a few of the other Bombinos. At the game the children's parents, who have never met me, were supporting me all through the game and I won best jammer too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;I was feeling really accomplished: I've been playing Roller Derby for a very long time, and to get an award for a very exciting game was so good.  To hear the Bombinos shouting encouraging words was a fantastic feeling, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Skye, looking pensive." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/Skye1.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Skye [Photo: David Prentice]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, let's talk about the game in more detail!
How was it being benched by / benching your sister?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;I thought it was really fun because I know her very well and I respect her, so it was easy listening to her and everyone in the team respected her . She was really supportive towards the whole team and never gave up which made everyone respect her more. She was so enthusiastic which I loved about her.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;It was really fun as I have played against, and alongside, Callie but never benched her in a game situation. I've never had a chance to take a step back and see her get her "game face" on and see her play as an independent skater. She listened to me as well (which she never does!) which was amazing and just seeing her having fun meant a lot 😊&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, this was also your first time benching a public game, Skye... How much practice had you had previously?
(and would you do anything different next time you bench?)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;I've had previous experience coaching Juniors and benching internal scrims but in all honesty, I was still asking questions about effective benching when we got to Newcastle 😂 . As it was a junior game, though, I felt confident benching the game for them.
I've been looking to bench a public Juniors game for ages and amazingly this opportunity popped up, and I'm super grateful to the Bombinos for allowing me to bench.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for doing anything differently; I hadn't trained with [the Bombinos] so I didn't know what their tactics were and how they played, so I'd try and do a bit more research 😊.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the feedback I got from the Bombinos was great! They all enjoyed my benching and how I handled it: they felt that I was very relatable as I am about their age, and was very relaxed and not intimidating. They also said that I was very supportive when shouting "you've got this!" And "keep going!" etc. as they passed the bench. So much so that they commented on the [Bairn City Rollers] page that they liked me so much that they were wanting to steal me and take me to Lincolnshire 😁😁&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;All I wanted to do was help lead them to victory, and they did us proud with an over 100 point lead 😊😊&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And are you tempted to try more non-competitive roles in future (announcing? Refereeing?)
(Callie: how do you feel about trying a non-skating role? Anything tempt you?)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;I would love to bench a game once, maybe refereeing. I've always been interested in benching as it is something I feel like I would be strong at. I always have experience when I'm training as I am usually captain when we are doing scrims.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;I would potentially look at refereeing as I got older. I would happily do the cake stall at derby games again though 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;I would love to bench again and I would be more than happy to help out as an NSO, but coaching, benching, and skating is where it's at for me at this exact moment in time. I'm even thinking about attending the Coaching bootcamp in York later this year [ ], because I know there is a lot of junior skating talent that is ready to be developed and I want to be one of the people that could help 😊😊.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Picture of Callie, Jamming, for Lincolnshire Bombinos" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/Callie1.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Callie, jamming [Photo: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.incidentlight.co.uk/"&gt;incidentlight&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, Callie: what interests you about benching?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;I'd really like to bench because it gives me better leadership experience, I also have some more re games under my belt than the newer kids. I would love to guide them and use the skills and tactics I have learned through my previous games with Fierce Valley Roller Cubs and the more recent games with Lincolnshire and the Sheffield and Newcastle juniors to take other juniors to a win. Although, its not the winning that counts really, its that everyone feels good and enjoys themselves&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That's a very positive attitude to have!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;That's what Derby has taught me: we lost at our Sheffield game, but I came away with a lot more friends I would never have met if I hadn't been there&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Speaking of all the contacts you guys now have, what're your plans for the future in general, as skaters?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;For me, trying for Team Scotland and the World Cup. That's the dream 😁😁&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For 202x?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Yeah 202x. I've made friends with Eve who is about to age up to the adult teams and she may potentially try out as well 😊&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;For me, it's attending more games with the other Juniors, aiming for Team GB: I would love to represent Scottish Junior Derby as part of that.
I want to help my sister coach and develop other kids, as well as me, until I am 16 and can move to an adult team. Then I want to push myself as far as I can with that. Team GB is a huge focus for me for the future.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you feel that it would help to have more Junior Derby in Scotland, or is the Rollerstop team in Glasgow enough to keep new talent coming?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Personally, I think we we need more. There are new teams out there but games are few and far between at the moment. I am travelling to England to get games on my level because I have been skating for years whereas some others are very new to it. Once they are all up and running it will be great but a larger number of teams over the Scotland area will encourage more teams to travel to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully there will be other leagues who see the value in a junior team and maybe start some up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talent we have in Scotland is there, it just needs a helping hand 😀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;Skye is coaching the kids [at Rollerstop] right now but I know she has an idea that I hope she can develop.
It's doing concentrated training for level 3 skaters with a view to getting them ready for going to an adult team. Also for Junior British Champs if it happens and for trying out for Team GB. Right now it's just an idea, but it would let kids like me train on a level that perhaps some newer skaters aren't at yet, and would hopefully give them drive to get there and join in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Skye, jamming, in Bairn City Rollers bout." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/Skye2.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Skye [Photo: Dave Moore]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Skye, do you want to talk a bit about that plan too?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;My mum was talking to a few people who wanted to discuss the idea of a Junior British Champs for the future and the options for that, and it came to mind that whilst the kids are training, why not "up the level" for the kids who want to take that next step. The "tweens" who aren't old enough for adult teams but are ready for the next level of game play which is essentially adult games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;What do they do in the inbetween times? I know, I have been there and it's tough. Adults want to help train, but the idea of maybe full contact scrimmage with people who are legally still children can be offputting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, in Australia, there's a whole multi-level thing for modified contact scrimmage and so on, which might help with that, too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;If that would help then yeah, all for it and looking at it. Anything to bring more people to the sport and keep them with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would love to talk with coaches for adult teams, see if there can be some sort of programme of skills that can be shared, best practise maybe to keep the kids inbetween Junior and Adult leagues active and keen and looking forward to their next steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;Mum and I honestly just talked about it 2 days ago. It made sense because when I was in limbo, before the Bairns took me on, I nearly quit and it would have been a mistake to have done that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was very difficult for junior derby in Scotland in general, about then&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;We thought we were losing it altogether, no one's fault, but we are so glad it didn't disappear totally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;I owe a lot to Coach CB and the rest of the Fierce Valley team, and the Bairns as well 😊&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Callie, what about you - how did you manage in the gap between FVRC closing, and then your current Rollerstop + sort-of-guest-Bombinos-skater position?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;I kept up skating at Rollerstop in general, just to keep me moving. Rollerstop Derby lessons came at the right time, although we even looked at the logistics of going to Newcastle for Derby if need be, but it just wouldn't have worked long term.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I know your mum's been very committed to helping you keep going in Roller Derby...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Haha, she hasn't been at home for the last few weekends because of derby, always driving us to games, supporting us, washing our kit (!) (the most important part) and meeting more Derby parents to get us out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;She sees the benefits in Derby to us, confidence, health, experiences and new friends 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's a really good relationship you three all have 🙂&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Mum has been a huge support in our derby career, she's been our taxi driver to games and a massive help. She continues to support us through our derby lives 😊&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, this has been a great interview, really: but I want to hand over the mic to you guys, if there's anything you want to add that we've not covered?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Skye&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Both Callie and I think that Junior Roller Derby needs to be spoken about and put out there a wee bit more and we are glad that there is more recognition about the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;I'm also super glad about the fact that (some) teams are opening up to 16-17 year olds as it's giving Juniors more of a chance to train.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Callie&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;[I] would love to see more Junior teams in Scotland so there are more teams to play and gain more experience, and that some games between teams across the border and here become more frequent 😊&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>coaching</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>team gb junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/the_macintyres_take_over_roller_derby/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 06:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs needs you!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/04/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-needs-you/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in being involved in the future of roller derby in Scotland? Now’s your chance; Fierce Valley Roller Cubs is looking for guest coaches from the wider world of Scottish roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-1833 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/10/cubs.jpg" alt="cubs" width="291" height="288"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based in Falkirk and training every Sunday, Fierce Valley Roller Cubs is open to all between the ages of 5 and 17, and currently has a range of skaters from beginners to advanced level. Cubs skaters have taken part in several intraleague games, the first of their kind in Scotland, and last year crossed the border to take part in their first external game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4611 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg" alt="10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n" width="530" height="376"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you could spare a couple of hours to share your knowledge and skills with the next generation of derby players and help take Fierce Valley Roller Cubs to the next level, please get in touch for more information: cubs@fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs was the first junior roller derby league in Scotland, and began training in September 2013.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/04/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-needs-you/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 10:47:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cubs Take On New Opposition</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/07/cubs-take-on-new-opposition/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In September, Fierce Valley Roller Cubs celebrated their third birthday, and on Sunday October 9th, they will play their first game against other junior skaters. This mixed junior game will take place as part of a triple header hosted by Barnsley Black Heart Rollers and will feature skaters from Sheffield Steel Junior Rollers and Newcastle Junior Roller Derby League.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9210" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/13880228_1012374508875985_648255813429450617_n.jpg" alt="13880228_1012374508875985_648255813429450617_n" width="784" height="295"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cubs will be sending thirteen level 3 and advanced skaters to take part, some of whom will be playing in public for the first time, while others are veterans of several intraleagues. Needless to say, the level of excitement is high and the bus journey to Barnsley at 6.30am on Sunday promises to be a lively one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last word (as always), goes to the Cubs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s great to finally play against people that aren't in our own team. As good as it is to have bouts amongst our own team this bout against a different team gives a chance to see how well we are progressing. I'm really excited for the road trip and can't wait to get out on track” – Vanilla Crush.
“I am really happy and excited that we are getting to meet another junior team and play against them” – Lu Dog Millionaire.
“It’s not often that I see 6.30am at the weekend, the long journey will be worth it though, are we there yet?” – Purple Punisher.
“I am super chuffed to be captaining our first away game, it will be an eye opener for all involved I am sure” – Stunami.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Facebook event page can be found &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/583974361781762/"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;  Further information about Fierce Valley Roller Cubs is available &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/fiercevalleyrollercubs/?fref=ts"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/07/cubs-take-on-new-opposition/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 10:13:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs taster session</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/18/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-taster-session/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs are recruiting!  Scotland's first junior roller derby league will be holding a fresh meat taster session on Sunday 24th April, from 13:30 - 14:30, in the Mariner Centre, Falkirk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4611" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg" alt="10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n" width="960" height="681"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FVRC welcomes boys and girls aged 5-17, with no previous skating experience necessary.  We can provide kit to borrow for the session, with the exception of a mouthguard and helmet, so there is no commitment.  The taster will cover basic skating skills, most importantly, how to stop and fall safely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To register your interest, or for more information, please contact freshmeat@fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/18/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-taster-session/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 10:26:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs - Review of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/23/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-review-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following on from a year of firsts in 2014, 2015 proved to be another busy year for Fierce Valley Roller Cubs.
With three fresh meat intakes throughout the year, skater numbers have grown to around thirty 5-17 year olds regularly attending training, across three skill levels. We have retained a large number of skaters from our first few intakes, meaning that at the moment, the majority of our members are level three skaters, although a successful taster session at the start of December should help to boost numbers in levels one and two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/cubs2.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5271"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-5271 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/cubs2.jpg?w=300" alt="cubs2" width="420" height="280"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
This year, Fierce Valley Roller Cubs were invited by three different leagues – Bairn City Rollers, Dundee Roller Girls and Fierce Valley Roller Girls – to take part in double headers. The game in Dundee marked the first time the Cubs played away from Grangemouth – the Cubs word is spreading far and wide! Several newer skaters played for the first time in public at one of these games this year, and all loved the experience. From a coaching point of view, it’s always satisfying to see everything we work on in training come together in a game.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/cubs1.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5270"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-5270" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/cubs1.jpg?w=300" alt="cubs1" width="348" height="232"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year also saw some changes to the way we structure our training, due to a change in the JRDA minimum skills, which brought them almost in line with WFTDA’s mins. This meant that our advanced skaters, i.e. those that had passed the “old” level three, had to work towards the new skills. Despite a step up in skill level and difficulty, all of our skaters worked hard and we already have quite a number who have passed the new level three.
For 2016, our goal is to play against another junior team, which has proved difficult so far due to the lack of other juniors. Fierce Valley Roller Cubs is almost unique in being both co-ed and open to kids as young as five, with most others being either female only, aimed at teenagers, or both. We are ever hopeful that the growth in junior roller derby will produce plenty of opponents for us!
The last words go to a Cub, Hayley:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long have you been part of Cubs, and why did you get involved?&lt;/strong&gt;
I've been involved with the Cubs for just over a year now. Like many I first found out about roller derby after watching Whip It, and I quickly became obsessed with the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point the Cubs were still in the process of setting up and I went to see my first game in Edinburgh, which made me want to play even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended missing the Cubs starting as i was busy with school and the idea of playing derby slipped my mind, until my dad suggested I see if a junior team had started yet. I then found out that the Cubs had started up and were the only junior team in Scotland, and that they were holding a freshmeat intake in the next couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was really nervous about joining, despite having bought skates a few years back when I had first found derby and getting a bit of practice in. At the taster session I fell and ended up having to get carried out by my dad and I went to the hospital the next day, thankfully nothing was broken (I did however end up with biggest bruise of my life), and from then on I was absolutely hooked on derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has your involvement in Cubs changed this year?&lt;/strong&gt;
This year I have been helping out at the Sunday sessions for level 1 and 2 skaters as an on skates helper. In doing so my own skating skills have improved, as I've been able to spend more time on skates, but I've also been able to see our fresh meat getting better and more confident at skating and help them develop into great skaters. I've been able to use this volunteer experience to help with my university application and I'm incredibly grateful to all the coaches at the Cubs for this, as skating has given me skills that I can use in other aspects of my life, such as perseverance and commitment, as well as strengthening my confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was your biggest achievement this year?&lt;/strong&gt;
My biggest achievement has been passing level 3 for the second time, after the requirements were changed to be closer to WFTDA's minimum skills, which included the dreaded 27 laps in 5 minutes. When I first started skating I thought there was no way I could ever skate that fast or be able to do things like transitions and backwards skating. This year I've really seen myself improve, going from fresh meat at the end of 2014 to advanced now. I've also played in two games this year, including my first game ever, which were also a big achievement. Although both times my team lost, it was amazing to see everyone working together and trying their absolute hardest, no matter what position they were playing. I'm sure anyone that was in attendance will say our last game of the year was an incredibly tense and well fought game, with a lead change of 2 points in the last jam!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/cubs3.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5272"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-5272 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/cubs3.jpg?w=300" alt="cubs3" width="357" height="238"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hayley jamming in her first game&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And what was the most memorable thing you did as part of Cubs?&lt;/strong&gt;
Taking part in my first ever game has to be the most memorable and terrifying thing I've done with the Cubs. I was so nervous before and couldn't imagine myself jamming and definitely not getting lead jammer and picking up points for the team. Although I was shaking before I felt great afterwards. I was incredibly proud of myself and my team for working so hard. I was also proud of the skaters on the other team for putting up such a good fight and playing so well. The second game I played in this year was also memorable as I could see just how much myself and the other skaters had improved in only a few months, as I found that we were playing together as a team much better, by playing offensively to help our jammers and using techniques such as star passes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would you like to see in 2016 for FVRC?&lt;/strong&gt;
Unfortunately I won't be with the Cubs for all of 2016 as I'll be turning 18, but I would love to see the Cubs playing other junior teams and continuing to grow in numbers and talent. As there are more junior derby teams starting up in the uk I think 2016 will be a great year for the Cubs to hopefully get to show off all the hard work that the skaters and coaches have put in. I hope that even once I've left I'll be able to come back and support the Cubs, and see the young skaters I've trained with continue to get better and better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All photos courtesy of Laura MacDonald.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>interviews</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/23/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-review-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 09:35:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Once Upon a Skate...</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/01/once-upon-a-skate/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join Fierce Valley Roller Girls as they end their year with an exciting double header! Up first will be Fierce Valley Roller Cubs, Scotland's only junior roller derby league, in a Goodies vs. Baddies intraleague. Fierce Valley Roller Girls will then be joined by skaters from Bairn City Rollers, Mean City Roller Derby and Lothian Derby Dolls to face off as Storybrooke vs. Enchanted Forest in a Once Upon A Time themed game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/once.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5172"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-5172 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/once.jpg?w=300" alt="once" width="563" height="212"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the venue is rather 'intimate', we recommend buying your tickets in advance to avoid disappointment. Tickets are priced at £5 in advance/£7 on the door, and kids under 14 go free with a paying adult.  Tickets are available in advance &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2469041"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors will open at 3pm for a 3.30pm start. As always, there will be a selection of handmade crafts, home-baking and team merchandise for sale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/01/once-upon-a-skate/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 09:47:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs New Skater Intake</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/24/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-new-skater-intake-2/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs are recruiting! The next new skater intake will be held on Sunday 2nd August at the Mariner Centre, Falkirk. The Cubs welcome boys and girls between the ages of 5 and 17 to be part of one of the fastest growing sports in the world. No skating experience is necessary, and kit can be borrowed for the the first session. Email freshmeat@fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk to register your interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4611 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg?w=300" alt="10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n" width="390" height="277"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs is the only junior roller derby league in Scotland and one of only a handful in the UK. From the first training session in September 2013, the league has grown to over 30 skaters over four levels, and has recently played a third public game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/24/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-new-skater-intake-2/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 10:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs New Skater Intake</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/04/14/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-new-skater-intake/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs are recruiting! The next new skater intake will be held on Sunday 26th April 2015, at the Mariner Centre, Falkirk. FVRC welcomes girls and boys aged 5-17, with no skating experience necessary, to come along and give it a try. Email freshmeat@fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk for more information and to register your interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4611 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg?w=300" alt="10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n" width="533" height="378"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/04/14/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-new-skater-intake/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 11:37:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs - Round-up of 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/18/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-round-up-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After becoming Scotland’s only junior roller derby league on its launch in September 2013, 2014 has been another year of firsts for Fierce Valley Roller Cubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/cubsrev3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4418 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/cubsrev3.jpg?w=300" alt="cubsrev3" width="482" height="321"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year began with an intake of skaters in January, and the interest in junior derby has remained high enough to hold a further three intakes throughout the year. As of the end of 2014, FVRC currently has around forty skaters from across Central Scotland regularly attending at least one of our three sessions per week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2014 was also a year of learning and adapting, not only for the young skaters but for the coaches too. When we found that a number of Cubs were passing their level one and level two assessments (taken from the JRDA), it became clear that two sessions on a Sunday would not be enough so a third session, for skaters aiming to pass level three, and focussing more on derby skills and gameplay, was added on a Friday evening. We also took the decision to have all skaters at the same level train together regardless of age rather than splitting them into two groups of 5-10 and 11-17 year olds. This has worked very well to this point and has helped kids of all ages to progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first major milestone of 2014 came at the end of May, when Fierce Valley Roller Cubs were invited by ARRG to stage a demonstration at half time in one of their games. Despite some initial nerves, the Cubs were thrilled to have the opportunity to show off their skills in front of a large crowd at Meadowbank, and it was a proud moment for the coaches too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following this, July saw a week-long derby summer school held, which started with a taster session and included sessions from guest coaches from Power of Scotland and FVRG. The summer school was well-attended and popular with the Cubs, and is something we will look to repeat in summer 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The culmination of the summer school, not to mention the months of hard work beforehand, was FVRC hosting the first ever public junior derby game in Scotland. Two teams of advanced Cubs skaters faced off in front of a large crowd in Grangemouth, and it was great to see the level of support from the wider derby community for our event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/cubsrev1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4419 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/cubsrev1.jpg?w=300" alt="cubsrev1" width="443" height="295"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As word of the Cubs spreads, we have been asked to visit schools and other groups to demonstrate what junior roller derby involves. Another demonstration scrimmage at half time in Capital City’s debut bout followed and brought us to the attention of a wider audience still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2014 was rounded off with another game, this time as part of a Harry Potter-themed double-header with Fierce Valley Roller Girls. With more skaters involved, a number of whom who have now passed their level three assessments, the progression in skills, tactics and derby knowledge was apparent in a closely fought game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Away from the track, we set up a Parents’ Committee which has been a great help to us in organising events including a family fun day, Halloween party and Christmas roller disco. In this way, we’ve seen that roller derby is something that whole families can become involved in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, 2014 has been hugely successful for Fierce Valley Roller Cubs – 2015 has a lot to live up to!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last word on 2014 goes to Teeny Bash, who has taken part in every event this year and captained Team Ravenclaw in the second Cubs game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/cubsrev2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-4420 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/cubsrev2.jpg?w=300" alt="cubsrev2" width="300" height="200"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;14 was a busy year for FVRC, what will you remember most about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will remember my first bout because it was the most exciting day ever. I couldn't sleep the night before and all I could think about was how it would feel to do the skate out that I have watched the roller girls do. My mum took me to watch a FVRG bout and I just wanted it to be me out there skating. I said one day I am going to make that team. That's my goal but I have to wait a whole 7 years, boo. :-(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FVRC made their public debut at an ARRG bout back in May, how did that feel?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major butterflies!!! It felt amazing to be out there skating in front of the crowd cheering for the cubs. I felt so proud of being a roller cub that day. I think we showed them what us kids can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And how did it feel to play in the first junior roller derby bout in Scotland?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will never be a first one again and I was there taking part in it. We made roller derby history that day and I was there, yey! I won't ever forget that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you learn this year, and what do you think was your biggest achievement?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be good enough to do a double game with the big girls. My biggest achievement was passing my level 3 skills test which means I can now go out and play another team. I can't wait to play another team, and show how good we are getting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love love love roller derby!!! I tell everyone I know about roller derby and how great it is. I didn't want to do dancing like all the other girls my age did so was stuck, now I have something I love doing. I can skate and keep fit and enjoy myself. I made a lot of new friends at derby and we all get on with each other. I will never stop skating, ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos courtesy of Laura MacDonald.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>interviews</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/18/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-round-up-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 09:22:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>FVRG Double-Header with The Cubs</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/17/fvrg-double-header-with-the-cubs/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 13th December, &lt;a title="FVRG Website" href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk" target="_blank"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; will be hosting a double-header event, featuring Scotland's only junior roller derby team - the Fierce Valley Roller Cubs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 4 teams playing in the event will represent the Hogwarts Houses from Harry Potter: The Cubs will be split between Hufflepuff and Ravenclaw, and the adult skaters will be in either Gryffindor or Slytherin.Both The Cubs and FVRG have competed in their own intra-league games earlier this year, but this is the first time that the two will play in the same event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The double-header will take place in Grangemouth Sports Complex. The hall doors will open at 3pm for a 3:30pm start - plenty of time to browse the stalls and the bake sale before the action starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are priced at £6 (+admin fee) from &lt;a title="Buy Tickets" href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/956261" target="_blank"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt;, and kids under 14s go free with a paying adult. If there are still tickets left on the day, they will be sold for £8 on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join the &lt;a title="Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/732876330125845/" target="_blank"&gt;FVRG Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt; for further details - and keep your eyes peeled for our Ticket Giveaway competition!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/11/10429276_884219831589870_6448227145220386816_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4212" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/11/10429276_884219831589870_6448227145220386816_n.jpg" alt="Poster designed by Mho McDougall from FVRG" width="614" height="515"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Poster designed by Mho McDougall from FVRG&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/17/fvrg-double-header-with-the-cubs/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 21:58:28 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>