<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about fight hawks)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/fight-hawks.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>BCR's Central Belters are back on track in 2018</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/30/bcrs-central-belters-are-back-on-track-in-2018/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt;'&lt;/a&gt; Central Belters are back on track and ready to kick some ass for the first time in 2018. On August 18th, they will be taking on Granite City's Fight Hawks at Grangemouth Sports Complex.
&lt;p&gt;This is the Belters' first game since early 2017 and sees a few changes to their team. Whilst some skaters have moved on or retired, the Belters have also had some new faces join their squad, including a couple of familiar faces that used to play elsewhere in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fight Hawks had a great year in 2017, winning all five of the games they played. Now in 2018 they already have 3 games under their belt, the most recent a close bout against Dundee Roller Derby's Bonnie Colliders last weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the details can be found over on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/1767150326733129/"&gt;event page here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/1767150326733129/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone wp-image-27087 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/beltvhawk.jpg?w=700" alt="Wolves vs Hawks" width="700" height="394"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2018 upcoming bout</category><category>bairn</category><category>bcr</category><category>central belters</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>gcrd</category><category>grangemouth</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>granite city</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/30/bcrs-central-belters-are-back-on-track-in-2018/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 12:29:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City's Hawks off to Fight in Portugal!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/15/granite-citys-hawks-off-to-fight-in-portugal/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As well as the exciting home games in Scotland this weekend, there's also an equally exciting away game, as Aberdeen's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GraniteCityRollerDerby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; send their B team off to Portugal to play in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/596021074083791/"&gt;Quad Cup 2018!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second iteration of the Quad Cup, the 2017 version seeing hosts, Coimbra's Rocket Dolls Roller Derby, play Black Thunders Roller Derby of Madrid, Lyon Roller Derby B team, Gones'n'Roses, and the exhibition team Liberty Rebellion in a 2 day round robin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26858" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/quadcup2018.jpg" alt="QuadCup2018" width="2048" height="1071"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This 2018 iteration of the European tournament pits the Fight Hawks against the returning teams of the hosts, and Black Thunders Roller Derby in a round-robin format in one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These will be the first games for the Fight Hawks this year, after their final bout in 2017, an extremely closely fought &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/98576"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 point win&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; against York Minxters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their opponents, meanwhile, have had one or two bouts already this year: Black Thunders playing Las Palmas to an overwhelming win early in the year; and both teams having faced As Brigantias (A Coruña, hosts of the upcoming WFTDA Playoffs in August). Whilst neither team defeated A Coruña's finest, the Black Thunders did considerably better than Coimbra, with a mere 34 point loss on an overall low-scoring game. As the Madrid team also defeated all comers in the 2017 Quad Cup, they must be the favourites this time around as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flat Track Stats agrees, with their European rating (at the time of publication), giving Black Thunders a 91% chance of victory over the hosts, and a 95% chance of victory over the Fight Hawks, who come in as the underdogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of these, however, the Fight Hawks are also the clear wildcards - with few close connections between their rating games and those of the two Iberian teams, they have the highest uncertainty in their performance; and their "rating momentum" was upward for the entirety of last year. With even FTS's pessimistic prediction giving Granite City B an expected 21:25 score ratio against the hosts (translating to perhaps a 20 to 30 point final score difference), it seems very possible for Aberdeen to provide the upsets this weekend. Given the disruptive behaviour of their namesakes, what would be more appropriate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Quad Cup 2018 will be held in the &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/qnbiz2Jpvh62"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pavilhão Multiusos de Coimbra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Coimbra, Portugal, with the first bouts starting at &lt;strong&gt;11am&lt;/strong&gt; (WEST, BST) on the &lt;strong&gt;17th June&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coimbra</category><category>european derby</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>rocket dolls roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/15/granite-citys-hawks-off-to-fight-in-portugal/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 10:11:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City's Hawks flock to the ARRGmageddon</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/21/granite-citys-hawks-flock-to-the-arrgmageddon/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the run up to Auld Reekie Roller Girls' first B-level tournament, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/535844416618826/"&gt;ARRGmageddon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the team travelling the furthest by far will be Aberdeen's Fight Hawks, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.granitecityrollerderby.co.uk/"&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s B team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hawks have played two of their three competitors this year, with very similar losses against Auld Reekie's ASTROs (in Edinburgh) and Dundee's Bonnie Colliders (at home in Aberdeen). They finished off their year so far with a win against Mean City Roller Derby's women's team (also by a very similar ratio, but in their favour!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We managed to catch new Fight Hawks Captain, Phanny, for a quick chat about their year, and ARRGmageddon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, how would you say the Fight Hawks year has been so far? Is there anything you'll be building on or focussing on as Captain?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's quite a tough question! The Hawks have, we have had a good year - we've definitely come on leaps and bounds from where we started - we're a stronger team, and we work better together. I (just) think we're quite gelled, and we like to have fun, we like to have a nice time;  we're not all about win win win, but when we do, its nice. And then we do enjoy a... sometimes we come off a loss and we're feeling pretty happy as well, because we've done our best as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Given your location, having to travel long distances together to get to bouts must help with the gelling?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah... Bus time is an opportunity to maybe speak to people that you wouldn't normally speak to, and then on the way back, from any tournament or games, it's a Party Bus, so a chance to drink with your teammates on the way up the road (laughs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARRGmageddon will be the first tournament that the Hawks have played in, do you have any plans for how to approach it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've had discussions about who's going on when, what's the best way to work this, not tiring out players before you get to the hour long game. I think, definitely going in for fun for the short games, and then really focus on the hour long game as the "big one".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's next for the Fight Hawks?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christmas Party! [laughs] As a team, we'll have a short break over the Christmas period - we'll be back on it around Janurary, and I believe... we're into games again in February!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARRGmageddon is this weekend - the &lt;strong&gt;26th November&lt;/strong&gt; - starting at &lt;strong&gt;11am&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Meadowbank+Sports+Centre/@55.9559777,-3.1579275,16.15z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x4887b86eb150070f:0x6955a8c9b9a10cc5!8m2!3d55.956619!4d-3.1563086"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Tickets  &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2714193"&gt;£8 online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, £10 (£6 concessions) on the door, free entry for under 14's, with a discounted rate for those just turning up for the final full-length bouts (from 4pm)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrgmageddon</category><category>articles</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>interviews</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/21/granite-citys-hawks-flock-to-the-arrgmageddon/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 08:33:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>June 11th's Packed Scottish Derby Schedule...</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The weekend of the 11th is another extravaganza for high level Scottish Roller Derby, with both Auld Reekie Roller Girls and Glasgow Roller Derby engaged in multiple bouts across the weekend, and Fierce Valley playing away in the continuing British Champs Tier 3 North fixtures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Glasgow and Fierce Valley playing away, the Scottish home games are happening at Auld Reekie's traditional venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Meadowbank+Sports+Centre/@55.956622,-3.1585026,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4887b86eb150070f:0x6955a8c9b9a10cc5!8m2!3d55.956619!4d-3.1563086"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, doors open at &lt;strong&gt;2:20pm Saturday 11th&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-7441" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13235130_10156950736565224_2994993262049877442_o.jpg?w=1024" alt="13235130_10156950736565224_2994993262049877442_o" width="1024" height="385"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heading up &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/350352705088707/"&gt;the double-header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Auld Reekie's All-Stars are taking on Kallio Rolling Rainbow, one of Finland's finest teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After their usual impressive performance at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-big-o-2016-schedule-timezones/"&gt;The Big O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Oregon, Auld Reekie are riding high, ready for another challenge - Kallio are slightly higher ranked than they are (FlatTrackStats &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/79684/rankings"&gt;predicts a win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the Finns, albeit with some uncertainty). This will be a WFTDA Sanctioned bout and contribute to both teams' rankings, so it will be an especially hard-fought contest, as both teams will want to reach Division 1 (or remain in Division 2) of the WFTDA Rankings in order to qualify for Playoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other bout is no less exciting in its own way, marking the debut of ARRG's new 'C'-team, the 'All-Star Rookies'&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/#sup"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as they take on Granite City Roller Girls B, the Fight Hawks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, with a team debut, it's hard to make predictions as to the result of the bout; this will be a contest between Auld Reekie's new skater training and the experience gained by the Fight Hawks over the last year. (Having seen some of ARRG's rookies in "rising stars" bouts in the last few months, however, there's some very impressive performers there...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets on the door will be £8 (just £4 per bout), or £5 online via &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2553305"&gt;BrownPaperTickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Concessions tickets will be just £6 on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Glasgow Roller Derby are apparently the stars of the show down in Oldham, as Rainy City Roller Derby are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://rainycityrollerderby.com/event/euro-weekender/"&gt;hosting a weekend of derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, in which Glasgow feature in 3 out of 4 bouts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a Scotland versus Wales playoff, Glasgow's A team, the Irn Bruisers, will be taking on Tiger Bay Brawlers' A; and their B team, the Maiden Grrders will also be facing off against TBB's B-Bombs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FlatTrackStats predicts an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/7953/7929"&gt;incredibly closely-matched bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; between the A-teams (the result depends on which team you give "home-team advantage" to). The B-teams are almost as close in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/10262/11067"&gt;FTS's predictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, although it looks like their stats very narrowly favour the Welsh team (albeit by only a few percent). With only one exception, match-ups between GRD and TBB have been hard-fought, high-level affairs, so we do anticipate some great derby here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Rainy City Roller Derby are scheduled against simply "Glasgow Roller Derby", which we might guess is the A team... Last time they faced each other, Glasgow came out with a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/59869"&gt;convincing win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;; but Glasgow's significant team changes this year have FTS &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/10262/11067"&gt;predicting a win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the home team this time around. Glasgow will have to pull out something special to keep the win record on their side...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the rankings of Tiger Bay Brawlers A, and Rainy City Roller Derby, these bouts also fill in a chunk of the higher-level UK matchups missing from British Champs this year. With the results from these games, we'll be publishing an "extended" BC Tier 1 ranking, extrapolating where some of the teams not competing in T1 might have ended up, this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[On the Sunday, Kallio Roller Derby are also featuring in this derby weekend, so presumably there's some exciting train travel in Kallio's Sunday morning schedule...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://britishchamps.com"&gt;British Champs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, after an extended period &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/17/british-champs-at-dundee/"&gt;hosted in Scotland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the Tier 3 North fixtures continue in the North of England, with Hallam Hellcats hosting a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/587023974805101/"&gt;double-header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of bouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7445" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13267947_1010255862421996_6895825634478283487_n.jpg" alt="13267947_1010255862421996_6895825634478283487_n" width="530" height="750"&gt; Hallam's bout poster was also available as a limited edition physical print! (Design by Ed Syder) &lt;a href="http://edsyder.tumblr.com/"&gt;http://edsyder.tumblr.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hosts will be taking on Preston Roller Girls, while Scotland will be represented by Fierce Valley Roller Girls taking on Manchester Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FVRG will be hard pressed to defeat currently unbeaten Manchester, but a loss will keep them at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/womens-tables-2016/"&gt;bottom of the table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and in danger of relegation. Meanwhile, Hallam and Preston will be fighting it out to avoid the second-from-bottom spot in the table - there's not much to call between them, but FTS believes that home-team advantage gives the hosts &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/25963/8972"&gt;a slight edge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="sup"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;the Auld Reekie current team naming scheme is a bit confusing - the A team are simply "All-Stars", whilst the B team append "Reserves" and the C team "Rookies". This makes it a bit hard to unambiguously form acronyms for the two, but we're working on this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>auldreekierollergirls</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>fvrg</category><category>gcrd</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>hallam hellcats roller derby</category><category>kallio rolling rainbow</category><category>manchester roller derby</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 11:04:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rising Stars and Bs at Aberdeen!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/05/rising-stars-and-bs-at-aberdeen/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Granite City Roller Derby's Northern Fights have been a little distracted by British Champs in the first half of this year, leaving GCRD B, the Fight Hawks to play their home games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7236" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/4627878756.jpg" alt="4627878756" width="757" height="1069"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.granitecityrollerderby.co.uk/blog/4584694771"&gt;This weekend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; sees the trend for Scottish Double Headers with Rising Stars bouts continue as Aberdeen's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Beach+Leisure+Centre/@57.155602,-2.082094,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48840e4028217933:0x30c6b9176815da5b!8m2!3d57.155602!4d-2.0799"&gt;Beach Leisure Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; hosts the Fight Hawks taking on Dundee's B team, the Bonnie Colliders, introduced by two teams of newer skaters from around the country demonstrating their talent (and getting experience to boot).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With doors opening at &lt;strong&gt;12:30pm, May 7th&lt;/strong&gt;, this is an ideal opportunity to see these skaters, many of whom are from the several new Scottish leagues which are still working towards their first bouts, on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second bout is an unpredictable&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt; match up between Scotland's newer B teams, which should be an unmissable event. Both the Bonnie Colliders and the Fight Hawks have been working hard to develop themselves over the past year, and, while the Fight Hawks are probably the underdogs, the home team advantage could well give them the edge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that isn't enough incentive, the refreshment stall will be raising money for&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.justgiving.com/fundraising/ChristophersCLANChallenge"&gt; Christopher's CLAN Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a 12 month fundraising effort to raise £20k for teenagers and their families affected by cancer in the NE of Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always with GCRD's home games, entry is completely &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;literally, FlatTrackStats can't compare the teams, and has incomplete entries for GCRD B!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>gcrd</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>rising stars</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/05/rising-stars-and-bs-at-aberdeen/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 11:29:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fight Hawks at the Trawler: GCRG's B Team speak.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/31/fight-hawks-at-the-trawler-gcrgs-b-team-speak/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coming soon to Edinburgh, &lt;a href="http://lothianderbydolls.com/"&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; will play Aberdeen's second ever derby team, as &lt;a href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/"&gt;Granite City Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; launch their B-squad, the &lt;em&gt;Fight Hawks&lt;/em&gt;. We caught up with Fight Hawks Bench Manager, Pert Hits, to find out a bit more. (Season Tickets for &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/346223992230568/"&gt;the bout on the 12th&lt;/a&gt;, and LDD's two subsequent games, can be obtained from &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/1820858"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City are only the fourth Scottish league to form a B-team (after ARRG, GRD and DRG). How does it feel to be able to launch a second travel team? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels natural.  With the roster sort of set for the Northern Fights, it had left a fair few of our skaters with no games to play, which was a real real shame given the calibre of skaters we are seeing coming through our fresh meat course (a number of whom completed the 3 month course and passed all mins first time!).  As the number increased over the course of the year, it just felt like the right time for it to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you tell us a little about the makeup of the team, and the selection process? Are these all new skaters to GCRG fans?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a look at the sheer number of mins passed skaters we had that were not dedicated to the British Championships and who were game ready.  Various things were looked at, perhaps the more important factors were attendance to training and scrim practice.  The team selection will be quite fluid as time goes on with different players perhaps being selected for each game.  Of the 14 skaters submitted for our first game, only 4 of them will be familiar faces to GCRG fans.  The rest may have been spotted in various "cherry poppers" across Scotland to those with a keen eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GCRG B are named 'The Fight Hawks'. Obviously, this continues the 'Fight' theme with GCRG A 'Northern Fights', but which Night Hawks (the painting, perhaps?) were you inspired by, and what do you hope it says about you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are actually named after a local term for seagulls, which we have in Aberdeen in abundance.  A quick youtube search and you can see why we went with this name; they're brash, brave and persistent.  And we will steal your chips when you're not looking.  But we do pay for Doritos, so please feel free to invite us for game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your first bout is away against Lothian Derby Dolls, down in Edinburgh. How are you preparing for the bout? What result are you hoping for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With British Champs winding down for the Northern Fights, we are in a good position to have our training sessions tailored directly towards the Hawks' needs. As bench and line-up, myself and Krusty have been watching like... hawks... as the girls train and giving feedback to our training committee, who have been very good at taking it into account and getting the right drills we need. We have also been doing "Hawks vs the rest" at scrim practices just to ensure the team meld and we get a good hive mind.
We are heading down to Edinbrugh looking to score more points. Perhaps the more important win, however, is knowing we gave 100% and played well as a team. Even defeats on the score board feel like wins if you know you did your best and worked well as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What're the Hawks' plans for the future? With GCRG A committed to British Champs, will you guys be taking on more eclectic teams?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not entirely certain what the future holds for us. I would certainly be expecting a good jaunt around Scotland in 2016, playing various teams, and with the right amount of fundraising taking our team a little further afield would a dream!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>b-teams</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/31/fight-hawks-at-the-trawler-gcrgs-b-team-speak/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 14:42:49 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>