<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about flat track stats)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/flat-track-stats.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>In the News: Rating WFTDA.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/11/in-the-news-rating-wftda/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although we've written a lot on SRD [&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/09/27/ranking-of-roller-derby-internationally/"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/08/ranking-the-world-and-other-fts-visualisations/"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/03/srd-rank-november-update/"&gt;3 &lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/17/meanwhile-in-europe-the-daga-denter-tournament-2016/"&gt; 4&lt;/a&gt; etc] and privately [&lt;a href="https://aoanla.wordpress.com/2015/05/31/british-championships-premier-tier-some-statistics/"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://aoanla.wordpress.com/2016/09/27/ranking-mechanisms-from-sport-and-roller-derby/"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://aoanla.wordpress.com/2018/02/09/the-2018-roller-derby-world-cup-rating-and-pairing-a-postmortem/"&gt; 3&lt;/a&gt;etc] on rating and ranking Roller Derby over the years, the question of how to do this fairly in WFTDA has been another topic of discussion recently. &lt;br&gt;Like Tennis, and many other sports, the WFTDA "rankings" (which are really a rating) are not slaved to the ordering of any particular tournament, including WFTDA Championships - meaning that it is possible for the current WFTDA Champions to not also be #1 in the Rankings released at the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Statistically, this is, of course, not a problem, but the position is still counter-intuitive to some members of the community. Some blame the specific construction of the WFTDA rating system itself, whilst others simply believe that Tournaments should supersede mathematical methods for determining rating. &lt;br&gt;As a result, every year when the WFTDA Championship winner does not automatically become the WFTDA #1 rated team, the question of "how good are WFTDA Ratings?" is raised again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of this, we decided to actually test this, rather than just complaining about an aspect of the rating we didn't like. &lt;br&gt;Using Flat Track Stats' records of all Roller Derby bouts, we selected the entire history of all WFTDA Sanctioned bouts in the history of the sport, all the way back to 2005. Using these, we calculated what the ratings and rankings would look like now, if we used various methods for rating teams.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elo_rating_system"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"Elo" ratings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, named for Arpad Elo, who developed them initially to rate performance of Chess players, are a particularly easy kind of rating to implement. As a base comparison to our other ratings, we wrote a very quick Elo rating for WFTDA Sanctioned bouts, based entirely on Win/Loss records: the rating does not care how much a team won or lost by, just that they &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We'll compare this to three other ratings:&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/"&gt;FTS (WFTDA)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: the Flat Track Stats rating, as optimised for WFTDA Sanctioned bouts. FTS is also an Elo rating, although its updates take into account the degree of success, not just that a team won; it also has a couple of other factors to account for things like home team advantage. &lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;SRDRank (v2)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;:&lt;/a&gt; this blog's in-house rating scheme. We've &lt;strong&gt;written&lt;/strong&gt; a lot about this before, but it's essentially an entirely different kind of rating scheme to Elo; rather than updating pairs of teams on each game, SRDRank is a &lt;em&gt;Massey-style&lt;/em&gt; scheme, which tries to produce consistent ratings to explain all of the games in its "purview" at once. This version of SRDRank was optimised for monthly predictions, against the world, not just the smaller subset of WFTDA Sanctioned games.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/category/rankings/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: the official WFTDA rating and ranking, which is used to rank teams for selection into the official WFTDA tournaments. WFTDA ratings are specifically designed to be "easy for people to understand" without specialist knowledge, as well as, presumably, aiming to reflect the history of performance of their member leagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Predictive accuracy&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:heading --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key conflict between expectations of Rating systems and the reality, is often one between "prediction" and "postdiction".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"&lt;em&gt;Prediction&lt;/em&gt;" is, of course, using a rating to guess what a future result would be, by comparing the ratings of the competitors previously.&lt;br&gt;"&lt;em&gt;Postdiction&lt;/em&gt;", conversely, is using a rating to judge "how well" two teams have performed, over their recent history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst it may seem that the two are closely related, in fact, it isn't inherently true that a rating which has high accuracy at one is also highly accurate at the other. In general, prediction is harder than postdiction - it's always hard to guess what's going to happen beforehand - but for teams whose strength has varied a lot over their season, it also can be hard for a postdictive approach to represent their "overall performance" in a satisfying way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In neither case, of course, does "high accuracy" mean "always places the winner of a particular tournament at #1". All rating systems are statistical, and try to produce the best overall measure of performance, for all teams, and all possible contests. The difference between the top teams is just as relevant as those between the middle and lowest rated teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equally important to the accuracy of a rating - at either task - is the frequency at which it is updated. Elo ratings, including the FTS ratings, are designed to update every time a game happens, so their accuracy can be measured either side of a given result. Some other ratings are published less frequently - WFTDA's ratings are monthly to bimonthly, depending on the time of year, and SRDRank is &lt;em&gt;designed&lt;/em&gt; to produce predictions no faster than daily. Frequent ratings aren't necessarily the "best" ratings, especially for postdiction - a "long-term overview" can sometimes produce a better overall view of historical performance than a rapidly updated one focused on bout-by-bout changes; but for prediction, especially in the middle of tournaments, it's usually best to have all the most recent information available for your next bet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To illustrate this, we've plotted the performance of four different ratings, at both postdiction and prediction, when we take updates at yearly, quarterly, monthly, fortnightly, and "bout-by-bout" intervals. For some rating schemes, not all intervals were available: FTS doesn't easily provide "historical rating" collections for anything more frequent than quarterly results. (We have a single data point for the FTS "bout-by-bout" period, for prediction, thanks to Ioan Wigmore.); WFTDA ratings are not updated faster than monthly at best; SRDRank doesn't produce "bout-by-bout" updates for this kind of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all cases, the postdiction accuracies (as percentage "correct") are shown by triangles, and the prediction accuracies by circles; the same colour is used for a given rating scheme. More "rapid" updates are to the left of the graph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27847} --&gt;

&lt;figure class="wp-block-image"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/screen-shot-2018-12-10-at-22-28-40.png" alt="" class="wp-image-27847"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Success rates for prediction (calling games ahead of time) and postdiction (representing performance after the fact) for 4 rating systems, with different time bases.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that should be clear is that postdiction is, in general, easier than prediction: &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; rating has a higher postdiction accuracy than prediction accuracy, for every update period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Elo rating has some of the highest postdiction accuracies, partly because it responds "fully" to every win or loss: a win counts 100%, even if it was a narrow victory, so each result pulls the rating around strongly, making it reflect history. This tendency to be "recency-biased" also explains why its postdiction gets "better" on shorter updates: a "weekly" postdiction only has to represent the last week of play accurately, and that's what Elo is best at. When we need the Elo rating to represent an entire year of performance, its bias towards the most recent month harms it overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That same effect, also means that the Elo rating is also the worst at prediction: because it counts all wins equally, a single narrow upset can throw off any trend it was measuring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SRDRank and FTS are closely matched for the update periods where they can be compared, with SRDRank having a slight advantage in prediction, and a noticeable one in postdiction; by comparison, the WFTDA rating is worse than all other ratings at postdiction, except on the yearly scale, and only better than the Elo rating at prediction. SRDRank is particularly good at "yearly review" postdiction: representing the entire year's performance overall; this is because of design decisions which mean that it considers an 18 month period of games in order to make its rating evaluation. The same "long term" view means that its postdictions are worse at reflecting "short term" history than the recency-focused Elo, although it still out-performs every other metric at this task.&lt;br&gt;The WFTDA rating, meanwhile, is hampered by having a maximum amount it can respond to any "strength change", meaning that it struggles to keep up with the more performant ratings on postdiction; and its simple rating calculation is not sophisticated enough to predict well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For prediction, the "sports prediction" literature generally considers accuracies above about &lt;strong&gt;70%&lt;/strong&gt; to be excellent. On that measure, only two ratings are excellent for Roller Derby prediction: SRDRank (fortnightly or weekly updates), and FTS ("bout by bout", although it is likely that it would also be excellent on the same timescales SRDRank is). It is likely that better than 75% or so win/loss prediction accuracy is impossible for Roller Derby: there are always closely-matched games which "could go either way", which even an accurate algorithm will guess wrongly about half the time by definition.&lt;br&gt;We should also say that, by this measure, the WFTDA rating isn't that bad at all, only just missing out on that 70% benchmark, although it's not in the same class as the other two schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For postdiction, there are less expectations on excellence, as the difficulty is partly dependant on how "variable" the sport is. The ~85% accuracy attained by Elo (quarterly or shorter) and SRDRank (yearly) is exceptional, however. The WFTDA rating actually does fairly well at "yearly" postdiction - summarising the years' performance in a single measure - but it is worse than every other metric when applied on a more frequent basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Predictive Accuracy (with close misses)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:heading --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned above, simply judging a rating on its ability to call wins and losses causes problems when evaluating close games. A good rating will predict that a close bout will be close; but inevitably, random chance will cause it to be wrong about which one of the contestants will actually win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several ways in which we can correct for this issue: we can move to measuring the success at predicting actual score-lines (not just winners and losers), but this is hard to compare for our metrics (mainly as the Elo rating isn't designed to predict score-lines); or, we can give credit to the rating for results it gets wrong&lt;em&gt; if the game was close, and the rating predicted it to be close.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[As an aside: SRDRank was actually optimised against the first metric: getting score-lines as close as possible, for the entire world's history of games.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example of how this changes our evaluation of ratings, we've graphed the accuracies of the Elo and SRDRank ratings again, for both pre- and post-diction. This time, we've included a second set of points for each: the success measured, including games which the rating called the winner wrong, but correctly predicted the result to be close either way (within 10% on the scoreline).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27850} --&gt;

&lt;figure class="wp-block-image"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/screen-shot-2018-12-11-at-13-14-51.png?w=700" alt="" class="wp-image-27850"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Success rates for prediction and postdiction for 2 rating systems, including successes on calling close games as close (regardless of who won).&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, including "close games" results in a significant boost to our evaluation of all the metrics, although it does not "reverse the order" of any of our ratings in terms of relative performance. (Notably, SRDRank's yearly postdiction now narrowly beats all comers when you include close games, even defeating Elo's best postdiction with close games.)&lt;br&gt;Although we did not include them on the graph (in order to make the graph still somewhat readable), we'd expect similar gains for the FTS and WFTDA ratings; an average of around 2% additional "successes" for each test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Best Rating for a Job&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:heading --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the metrics above, we can attempt to select the "best" ratings to use for a particular task. We've selected four representative tasks, and mapped them to the mode (pre- and post-diction) and "timescales" on which they operate, to select recommendations, and warnings, on the approaches you should consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Season Review&lt;/strong&gt; is the task of summarising, as best you can, the overall performance of the field over the past season. This is a postdiction task, on a long timescale (six months to a year). This is also a very closely contested task, and there's not much to call between all 4 ratings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medium-term Prediction&lt;/strong&gt; is the task of predicting results several weeks to months in advance, to plan tournaments and games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Play-by-Play Prediction&lt;/strong&gt; is the task of predicting results on the minute, judging your next game at a tournament, for example. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medium-term Review&lt;/strong&gt; is the task of summarising, the overall performance of the field, on the scale of months. This is the "coaching" metric, when judging how well your team is evolving. For this, second place is very tight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:table {"className":"is-style-stripes"} --&gt;

&lt;table class="wp-block-table is-style-stripes"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Task&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2nd Best&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Worst&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Season Review &lt;br&gt;(Yearly postdiction)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;SRDRank&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;WFTDA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;FTS &amp;amp; Elo&lt;br&gt;(&lt;em&gt;joint&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medium-term Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;SRDRank&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;FTS&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Elo&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Play-by-Play Prediction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;FTS&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;SRDRank &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;(weekly)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Elo&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medium-term Review &lt;br&gt;(Quarterly postdiction)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Elo&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;SRDRank &amp;amp; FTS&lt;br&gt;(&lt;em&gt;joint&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;WFTDA&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:table --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:heading --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Yearly Performance Ratings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:heading --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can also (bearing in mind the relative expectations of accuracy, as discussed in the rest of this article), generate the full "rankings" for all of the WFTDA member leagues for 2018. (The WFTDA Ranking here is the one from 30 Nov 2018, the most recently available ranking and rating from WFTDA).&lt;br&gt;We present here the top 20, with ratings, from each scheme - notice that, despite the differences, there are far more similarities than disagreements.&lt;br&gt;(Ratings are &lt;em&gt;truncated&lt;/em&gt; for space: the error introduced by truncation rather than rounding is much smaller than the expected error on the ratings themselves, so this is not an issue.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Top 20s (Tabular)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:heading --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:table {"className":"is-style-stripes"} --&gt;

&lt;table class="wp-block-table is-style-stripes"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rank&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WFTDA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SRDRank&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;br&gt;2.&lt;br&gt;3.&lt;br&gt;4.&lt;br&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Victoria (1255)&lt;br&gt;Rose (1241)&lt;br&gt;Gotham (1174)&lt;br&gt;Denver (1162)&lt;br&gt;Arch Rival (1110)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Victoria (3.36)&lt;br&gt;Rose (3.35)&lt;br&gt;Gotham (3.15)&lt;br&gt;Denver (3.07)&lt;br&gt;Arch Rival (3.03)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rose (2637)&lt;br&gt;Victoria (2592)&lt;br&gt;Gotham (2516)&lt;br&gt;Arch Rival (2281)&lt;br&gt;Angel City (2267)&lt;br&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rose (1005)&lt;br&gt;Victoria (1003)&lt;br&gt;Gotham (984)&lt;br&gt;Denver (977)&lt;br&gt;Arch Rival (962)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.&lt;br&gt;7.&lt;br&gt;8.&lt;br&gt;9.&lt;br&gt;10.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Angel City (904)&lt;br&gt;Montreal (871)&lt;br&gt;Texas (857)&lt;br&gt;Jacksonville (841)&lt;br&gt;Crime City (827)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Angel City (2.71)&lt;br&gt;Texas (2.57)&lt;br&gt;Montreal (2.49)&lt;br&gt;Crime City (2.48)&lt;br&gt;Jacksonville (2.41)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Denver (2262)&lt;br&gt;Texas (2182)&lt;br&gt;Montreal (2167)&lt;br&gt;Jacksonville (2102)&lt;br&gt;Minnesota (2100)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Angel City (946)&lt;br&gt;Texas (924)&lt;br&gt;Montreal (901)&lt;br&gt;Crime City (899)&lt;br&gt;London (890)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11.&lt;br&gt;12.&lt;br&gt;13.&lt;br&gt;14.&lt;br&gt;15.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Atlanta (778)&lt;br&gt;London (767)&lt;br&gt;2×4 (713)&lt;br&gt;Helsinki (704)&lt;br&gt;Santa Cruz (693)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;London (2.34)&lt;br&gt;2×4 (2.33)&lt;br&gt;Rainy City (2.27)&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Canberra&lt;/em&gt; (2.25)&lt;br&gt;Atlanta (2.24)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;London (2087)&lt;br&gt;Crime City (2084)&lt;br&gt;Atlanta (2070)&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oly&lt;/em&gt; (2055)&lt;br&gt;Dallas (1974)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rainy City (887)&lt;br&gt;Jacksonville (885)&lt;br&gt;Minnesota (880)&lt;br&gt;Atlanta (880)&lt;br&gt;2×4 (875)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16.&lt;br&gt;17.&lt;br&gt;18.&lt;br&gt;19.&lt;br&gt;20.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Minnesota (691)&lt;br&gt;Rainy City (686)&lt;br&gt;Rat City (686)&lt;br&gt;Arizona (655)&lt;br&gt;Stockholm (648)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Helsinki (2.15)&lt;br&gt;Rat City (2.13)&lt;br&gt;Minnesota (1.99)&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bay Area&lt;/em&gt; (1.96)&lt;br&gt;Santa Cruz (1.94)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bay Area&lt;/em&gt; (1951)&lt;br&gt;Rainy City (1941)&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philly&lt;/em&gt; (1938)&lt;br&gt;Arizona (1928)&lt;br&gt;Santa Cruz (1925)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rat City (874)&lt;br&gt;Santa Cruz (870)&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bay Area&lt;/em&gt; (866)&lt;br&gt;Helsinki (863)&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Canberra&lt;/em&gt; (849)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:table --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;All WFTDA Leagues (graph, image)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:heading --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we've previously discussed, however, strict rankings are a bad way to represent the performance of teams. It's much better, even with 1-dimensional ratings, to report those ratings, providing a better measure of the "distance" between teams, than to imply that all teams are equally "1 better" than the team immediately "below" them in ranking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, we've generated a graph of all the teams rated by at least one of our ratings in their yearly review. We order the teams in "WFTDA ranking" order, with teams not in the official WFTDA ranking placed at the end. &lt;br&gt;In order to provide a good comparison, we've rescaled all the ratings to represent logarithmic relative strength, compared to the "top" team in the rating*. (That is: for every "1" difference in rating, the better team is expected to score about 2.7× as much in a game; for every "2" difference, 2.7&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;× (7.4×), for every "3" difference, 2.7&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;× (20×) and so on.)&lt;br&gt;This image is unavoidably large in order to be legible; click the preview to get the full-size version.&lt;br&gt;Note that the full range of the entire rated cohort for all ratings is about &lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;, corresponding to the top 3 teams being expected to score around &lt;strong&gt;3000×&lt;/strong&gt; more points than the bottom 3 (or, effectively, a complete shutout).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27849} --&gt;

&lt;figure class="wp-block-image"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/rating-performance-sheet3-crp.gif" target="”_blank”" rel="”noopener" noreferrer&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/rating-performance-sheet3-crp.gif?w=700" alt="" class="wp-image-27849"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;All WFTDA Member Leagues, displayed in WFTDA 30 Nov 2018 order (with extras not in that rating appended after), with all their ratings. (Ratings scaled to the same type for direct comparison.)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's worth noting that, in general, there's still a reasonable agreement on the overall "shape" of the rating; the ratings all broadly agree on the strength difference between the top and bottom ends of the list, and whilst there are disagreements in order, there's also a lot of agreement about the overall place of most teams.&lt;br&gt;It's also possible to see how the "difference in skill between ranks" changes: the steeper the slope of the curve, the more change there is in relative skill as you change ranking. For WFTDA Member leagues, there seems to be a relatively flat middle section, where adjacent teams are actually very close in strength; at the top end, there's a much steeper rating change with rank, until the curve flattens again around the top 3 or 4. (All the ratings pretty much agree that Victoria and Rose are near-tied in the top 2, they just disagree about which is a tiny sliver ahead.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:heading --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We've given an overview and test of the official WFTDA rating scheme, versus 3 contenders for a range of use cases.&lt;br&gt;Contrary to some complaints, the WFTDA rating scheme turns out to be a pretty good rating, for post-diction, on the longer timescales. &lt;br&gt;More sophisticated schemes do better than it at almost all tests, but its performance, given its simplicity and the trade-offs it makes to try to prevent high-skill teams playing low-skilled teams for blowouts all the time, is acceptable.&lt;br&gt;Also, this test run underlines just how hard it is to make gains in predicting (or postdicting) game results: the gap between the worst and best performing metrics in this test is never more than 10%, and the gap between the "good" ratings tends to be around the 1% level. &lt;br&gt;We do note that, for prediction, Flat Track Stats attains class-leading performance, especially on short time scales. (It is just as good when rating European teams, MRDA teams, or any other region where it has an actively calculated rating.) We'd encourage regions which do not have their own rating scheme to contact Flat Track Stats to host such a thing for them. (The other benefit to this is that you have a place to store all your results: Flat Track Stats is also a public repository of all the game data which is uploaded to it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:separator --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator"&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:separator --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*WFTDA estimated strength differences are calculated using the predicted strength ratios in the WFTDA algorithm, &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the predicted "points gained". Other calculators use the points-gained formula, as they're interested in seeing how the rating &lt;em&gt;changes with results&lt;/em&gt;: we're interested in how strong WFTDA's rating &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; thinks teams are, which is different. (The fact that these &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; different for WFTDA is why sufficiently strong teams can't play weak teams without losing overall rating: points gains doesn't keep pace with strength difference. None of the other rating schemes in this article have this behaviour.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>flat track stats</category><category>international derby</category><category>reviews</category><category>srd rank</category><category>statistics</category><category>wftda championships</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/11/in-the-news-rating-wftda/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 16:03:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash 2018: Two Weeks To Go (Schedule + Updated Predictions)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/05/09/euroclash-2018-two-weeks-to-go-schedule-updated-predictions/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/26/euroclash-2018-newcastle-roller-girls-tournament-expands-beyond-the-euro/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;written once already&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about the return of the, now International, Roller Derby tournament to Newcastle Upon Tyne...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26639" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/euroclash2018.png" alt="EuroClash2018" width="1920" height="1440"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...but, with the publication of the official Schedule, and a lot of activity from many of the competing teams, we thought it was worth a quick update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, to the schedule: the official schedule in UK time is below, but we've also prepared a fancy multi-time-zone version &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/EuroClash2018/"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for anyone expecting a livestream and wanting to follow their favourite team from abroad.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Saturday 19 May&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;9am&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="profileLink" href="https://www.facebook.com/TigerBayBrawler/?fref=mentions"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/a&gt; vs &lt;a class="profileLink" href="https://www.facebook.com/SteelCityRollerDerby/?fref=mentions"&gt;Steel City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11am&lt;/strong&gt; Newcastle Roller Girls vs &lt;a class="profileLink" href="https://www.facebook.com/birminghamblitzdames/?fref=mentions"&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="profileLink" href="https://www.facebook.com/dublinrollerderby/?fref=mentions"&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; vs &lt;a class="profileLink" href="https://www.facebook.com/DockCityRollers/?fref=mentions"&gt;Dock City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;3pm&lt;/strong&gt; Birmingham Blitz Dames vs Steel City Roller Derby
&lt;strong&gt;5pm&lt;/strong&gt; Newcastle Roller Girls vs Tiger Bay Brawlers
&lt;h3&gt;Sunday 20 May&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;9am&lt;/strong&gt; Newcastle Roller Girls vs Steel City Roller Derby
&lt;strong&gt;11am&lt;/strong&gt; Dublin Roller Derby vs &lt;a class="profileLink" href="https://www.facebook.com/middlesbroughRD/?fref=mentions"&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt; Dock City Roller Derby vs &lt;a class="profileLink" href="https://www.facebook.com/auldreekierollergirls/?fref=mentions"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;3pm&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="profileLink" href="https://www.facebook.com/CentralCityRollerDerby/?fref=mentions"&gt;Central City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; vs Steel City Roller Derby
&lt;strong&gt;5pm&lt;/strong&gt; Middlesbrough Roller Derby vs Auld Reekie Roller Girls
&lt;strong&gt;7pm&lt;/strong&gt; Dock City Roller Derby vs Birmingham Blitz Dames
&lt;p&gt;Also, since our first update, several of the teams competing have played at significant tournaments: Birmingham Blitz Dames playing exceptional derby at the K-Town Shakedown in Kalamazoo, Michigan, winning 2 out of 3 games, and only losing the last, against Royal City (Guelph) by 9 points (against a predicted loss of around 150!). We predicted that Birmingham might well be underranked in our last update, and this proves us very right...
Similarly, a great performance by Dublin at Southern Discomfort 2018 in South Carolina, beating expectations in every single bout by huge margins - only losing one bout (against Ann Arbor) by 3 points (against a predicted loss of around 90), and winning every single other - has pushed their expected rating up significantly, although as they already top the expected teams at EuroClash, this doesn't really change our prediction for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, for Dock City Rollers and Newcastle Roller Girls over in Tri-City's Put Up Your Toques in Ontario, it was also a very good weekend. Dock City beat expectations against Winnipeg, and Newcastle both won, and beat expectations, against each of their opponents, giving both of them a substantial boost - but not enough for Dock City to gain on Dublin at the top of the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steel City played a single game since our last update, against the Chicago Outfit, where they also out-performed expectations, by a good 50 points or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By comparison, Middlesbrough and Central City have had a relatively quiet time of it, with no further bouts since our last writeup. Central City will play one game, this weekend, as they take on London Rockin' Rollers up in Glasgow for British Champs Tier 1, where their current rating expects a 3:1 score ratio in victory! Nevertheless, games dropping out of consideration, and teams moving around them, have caused ranking changes in WFTDA for both teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Auld Reekie's position is not affected by their own games played since our last update - their closed bouts away against Kallio and Bear City are not marked as Sanctioned on FTS, and so don't count towards their WFTDA ratings there. Whilst they lost a bit of rating compared to last time, their predicted performance seems to have now stabilised, so a rating including these games should be more accurate.
Similarly, Tiger Bay Brawlers' bout against Rainy City B can't count towards WFTDA ratings, as only A teams can contribute ratings. The Cardiff team significantly improved on expectations - narrowly defeating a team which "should have" easily defeated them with a 100 pt margin - so it's unfortunate that this bout is not included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, we have our own rating system - SRDRank - which draws from the full set of FTS bout records, ignoring WFTDA Sanctioning, to produce a rating which takes into account every single game played by a team, including B teams. We've not had time to update the full rating page for this, but just for EuroClash, we've run a special iteration of the rating just for the tournament, and added a column for it here.
(&lt;span style="background:darkseagreen;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Green&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; rows are teams which have gone up in the expected "finishing order" for EuroClash, according to FTS, and &lt;span style="background:indianred;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; rows are those which have dropped. We mark ranking changes in FTS and WFTDA with + and - signs in the Ranking row.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="3" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt; "WFTDA" Ratings 09 May 2018 (WFTDA Rating 30 April)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rank&lt;/strong&gt; (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Rating (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;SRDRank (09 May)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;34 ++&lt;/strong&gt; (38 ++)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7775/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;800.4 (443.76)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.50&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;48 ++&lt;/b&gt; (66 -)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/29732/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dock City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;757.3 (311.87)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.16&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;62 +&lt;/strong&gt; (71 -)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7948/rankings/wftda"&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;729.4 (307.57)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.26&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background:darkseagreen;"&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;65 +&lt;/strong&gt; (50 +++)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7736/rankings/wftda"&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;724.5 (373.88)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.06&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;67 ++&lt;/strong&gt; (64 -)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7949/rankings/wftda"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;717.7 (315.71)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.80&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background:indianred;"&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;68 + &lt;/strong&gt;(81 ++)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7763/rankings/wftda"&gt;Central City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;713.3 (278.36)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.99&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background:indianred;"&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;82 +&lt;/strong&gt; (92 -)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/3417/rankings/wftda"&gt;Steel City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;692.5 (259)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.53&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;93&lt;/strong&gt; (90 -)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7953/rankings/wftda"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;676.0 (262.62)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;94&lt;/strong&gt; (82 +)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/5912/rankings/wftda"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;674.9 (277.65)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.97&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
Interestingly, despite WFTDA, FTS and SRDRank all disagreeing about the relative ordering of the teams, all of the rankings place Dublin clearly at the top. We also all generally agree about the "range of skill" at EuroClash 2018, despite disagreeing about which team is at the bottom: WFTDA expects Dublin to be able to beat Steel City (their lowest rated team) by about a 3:1 ratio - and SRD Rank puts the same contest at about 13:5, whilst FTS thinks that the lowest strength team is Auld Reekie, but also expects Dublin to be able to beat them by about 3:1.
&lt;p&gt;We won't get either of those games at EuroClash 2018, though, as almost all of the scheduled bouts are against teams which are closely matched in one or other of the ratings.
All of our rating schemes expect &lt;em&gt;Dublin's&lt;/em&gt; games to be closely fought - Middlesbrough and Dock City are in 2nd to 4th place in all of the rating schemes we have here, and both have a chance at unseating the expected tournament top dogs from Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie have some difficult games - if you believe FTS, all of their games will be very difficult - but SRDRank has a lot more faith in them. Expect the Edinburgh based team to beat expectations against very tough opponents in Dock City and Birmingham, if we're right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ascendant Birmingham will be counting on the WFTDA rating being accurate when they take on Dock City - both other ratings place them slightly below, not above, the Swedish team - but everyone agrees that they should have an easier time against the Americans from Steel City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steel City will be wanting to bring upsets to both their games - again, going by their ratings from a little more than a year ago, they should win both of their bouts, against Birmingham and Central City... and their current rating has been steadily climbing in recent months. EuroClash could be the place where an American team does to Europe what European teams traditionally do in the Americas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day Tickets (and Weekend Tickets) for EuroClash are available here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/ticketshttps://www.euro-clash.com/tickets"&gt;https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash 2018 will be held at the &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/KwjQQaZfuNF2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;19th&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;20th&lt;/strong&gt; May 2018, by Newcastle Roller Girls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>euroclash</category><category>flat track stats</category><category>international derby</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/05/09/euroclash-2018-two-weeks-to-go-schedule-updated-predictions/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 19:24:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Ranking Systems - an extension to Papa Whisky</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/14/derby-ranking-systems-an-extension-to-papa-whisky/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, Papa Whisky published an &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@papawhiskey/how-do-rankings-work-1d0a1c5bc5d3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;article on how the WFTDA Ranking system works&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a good introduction to the system, but perhaps missed a few technical points, which we feel are important. In addition, we think it might be useful to introduce other rating systems used in Roller Derby for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article aims to address these two issues, and should be read in concert with the above linked article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, there is some maths. In this maths, we use: &lt;strong&gt;Pu&lt;/strong&gt; to mean "the points scored by your team", &lt;strong&gt;Po&lt;/strong&gt; to mean "the points scored by the opponent", as well as some other values later on.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Other Ranking systems - &lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
While Papa Whisky implies that Flat Track Stats does ranking and rating in a similar way to WFTDA's own official ratings and rankings, in fact the FTS algorithm is somewhat different.
&lt;p&gt;FTS ratings are a variant of &lt;em&gt;Elo ratings&lt;/em&gt; - named for Arpad Elo, who developed them for Chess in the late 1950s. Rather like WFTDA Ratings, FTS Ratings are an indication of how well you should do, but with a different basis - Elo Ratings are logarithmic, like Richter factors for earthquakes, or decibels for sound, so every 400 (or so) difference in Elo Rating is a ten-&lt;em&gt;fold&lt;/em&gt; (or so) factor in expected score &lt;em&gt;ratio&lt;/em&gt;. [FTS probably doesn't use the number 400 exactly.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FTS ratings also update based upon how well you do, versus your expected performance. FTS measures performance in terms of what they call "difference over sum" (DoS) - this is the ratio of the point spread (your points minus their points) to the total points (your points plus their points) in the game:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;(Pu-Po) / (Pu+Po)&lt;/p&gt;
 Essentially, every game you play adds points to your rating, based upon how well you beat the expectation from your relative ratings. (The actual calculation used by FTS is not published, but classical Elo ratings give you a bonus based on the sum of your opponent's rating and a factor proportional to the fraction of the score you got.)
&lt;p&gt;At any given time, a team's FTS Rating is the sum of all of the bonus points they have gotten over the team's entire history. [In fact, most teams will have more than one FTS Rating - FTS maintains multiple ratings; for WFTDA, MRDA, Europe, North America etc - which differ mostly in which games count towards a teams' total points.]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Other Ranking systems - MRDA&lt;/h3&gt;
The MRDA also does not use WFTDA ratings or rankings for their quarterly ratings. In fact, non-members have no knowledge of how the MRDA Rankings are calculated.
&lt;p&gt;This also means we can't say much more about it here, which is extremely problematic.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Other Ranking systems - &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRankv2.html"&gt;SRDRank (v1,2)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
Our own rating system, SRDRank, is the most different in principles to the rating systems here.
&lt;p&gt;Every other rating system works on pairwise comparison - a given game affects only the ratings of the two teams which play, and the rating of Team A will be the sum of all the effects from the games in its history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRDRank is based on global optimisation: every game doesn't just tell us something about the two teams which played, but also something about every other team which has played them recently, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRDRank v1 and v2 perform this calculation in slightly different ways, but in both cases they care about the points ratio:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;Pu/Po&lt;/p&gt;
in any given game. (Technically, we use log(Pu/Po), but that doesn't affect understanding.)
&lt;p&gt;SRDRank v1 models each game as a "spring" between the two teams (which has a natural length proportional to the result of the game) - we run a simulation of the system with all the springs in place, and see where it ends up putting all the teams. The relative positions of the teams as the result of the springs tensioning against each other give their "ratings", and "Rankings".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRDRank v2 uses least-squares linear regression to do the same thing. This is a technique to find the values for a set of unknowns (in this case, the team strengths) which "best fit" the observations (in this case, the ratio of scores in the games played) by minimising the distance between the results in reality, and the results predicted by the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both SRDRank v1 and v2 adjust the importance of games so that older games are less significant than newer ones (by making the springs "weaker", or by allowing more distance with less penalty) - the amount we do so has been optimised itself by analysis of the history of the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRDRank v2 also attempts to detect teams which have changed suddenly in strength (because, say, their roster completely changed at the start of the season), by performing statistical tests on the predictions it makes. Teams which do change suddenly are "split" into a new and an old team, at the point of the change - which means both that the new roster can be given a different rating to the old one; and also that the history of the team doesn't contaminate our predictions for teams which play them in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRDRank v1 and v2 are included in our github repo for prediction code, &lt;a href="https://github.com/aoanla/ranking-chain-inference"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Pros and Cons of Rating Systems - WFTDA&lt;/h3&gt;
In his article, Papa Whisky notes that one of the weaknesses of the WFTDA rating system is that it is currently slightly opaque - the magic "median" value isn't what you'd expect it to be from the published results, because the WFTDA median is calculated from a longer list which is not published.
&lt;p&gt;However, that isn't the real problem with WFTDA ratings - although it is related. To explain their issues, we'll need to do a little bit of simple mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you know from the article, WFTDA ratings award you points for any sanctioned games based on the result of the calculation:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;300 * Pu * So / (Pu+Po)&lt;/p&gt;
where So is the Strength Factor of the opponent. Given that a Strength Factor is just the WFTDA Ranking Points divided by the median Ranking Points, we can write this as
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;300 * Pu * Ro / ( Pu+Po) * Rm&lt;/p&gt;
where Ro is the opponent's ranking points, and Rm is the median of them.
&lt;p&gt;In order to "keep the same rating", a team needs to score equal to its current WFTDA Ranking Points. So, we can write the condition for retaining Rating as:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;300 * Pu * Ro / ( Pu+Po) * Rm = Ru&lt;/p&gt;
This relationship is the source of all of the issues with the WFTDA Rating system.
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, let's rearrange this to give the fraction of points the team needs to score to maintain rating, in terms of everything else:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;Pu/(Pu+Po) = (Ru/Ro) * (Rm/300)&lt;/p&gt;
So, the first thing we notice is that the "fraction of points" you need is proportional to the &lt;em&gt;ratio&lt;/em&gt; of the two teams' WFTDA Ranking Points. This is the source of those "weird results" which Papa Whisky notes for bouts between teams of very different strengths.  In particular, it can mean that there's simply not enough available points for a team to retain its ranking, even if it got 100% of the points.
&lt;p&gt;To see that that's true, let's imagine that our team gets 100% of the points, so Pu/(Pu+Po) is 1. That implies that
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;(Ru/Ro) = (300/Rm)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;Ru = (300/Rm)*Ro&lt;/p&gt;
300/Rm is a bit more than 2 (we'll come back to this later), so our team needs a 100% blowout to break-even against a team with about&lt;em&gt; twice&lt;/em&gt; its Rating. In the example Papa Whisky uses, Gotham had a SF (and thus rating) more than twice that of Windy: there was no possible way for Gotham to benefit from that game, as they would need to score &lt;em&gt;more than 100%&lt;/em&gt; of the points!
&lt;p&gt;The other problem is that teams need to continually beat expectations in order to retain ranking. To see that this is the case, let's assume that the two teams have identical WFTDA Ranking Points, Rx. In that case, the formula gives:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;Pu/(Pu+Po) = (Rx/Rx) * (Rm/300) = Rm/300&lt;/p&gt;
where the final step is straightforward.
If a team plays a team with exactly the same strength as it, we would expect the points to be divided equally, so Pu/(Pu+Po) should be 0.5 ... which implies
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;0.5 = Rm/300  ⇒ Rm = 150&lt;/p&gt;
Of course, Rm does not equal 150 - it's set to the median WFTDA Ranking Points, which is currently around 141.
&lt;p&gt;The result of this is that teams need to &lt;em&gt;beat&lt;/em&gt; their own expectation by about 7% in every game, &lt;em&gt;just to stay where they are&lt;/em&gt;. In a case where two well matched teams perform as expected... not only does the losing team lose ranking, but so does the &lt;em&gt;winning&lt;/em&gt; team. (This does balance out a little, in that it affects all teams, so there's a general "deflation" in scores one month to the next... but it is still counterintuitive.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pro of the WFTDA rating system is that it's very easy to understand, and you can calculate expected scores and so on with just a piece of paper and some mental arithmetic (as long as you know the median Ranking Points). However, with computers ubiquitous nowadays, it is not clear how much of an advantage this is - &lt;a href="https://derbyontoast.com/head-to-head"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DerbyOnToast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (and our own SRDRank visualiser) can both automate ratings calculations for you, so you don't need to be able to do them yourself.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Pros and Cons of Rating Systems - FTS&lt;/h3&gt;
The FTS Rating system has all the problems that Elo systems have in general.
&lt;p&gt;In particular, Elo ratings consider that all results are relevant, even years after they happened. Rating changes only happen as a result of new games being played - so if you don't play any games for a year or two, you'll just keep the same FTS rating regardless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has the counter-intuitive result that it's sometimes better to just not play games, rather than lose rating. (If Gotham had decided not to play any games at Champs or later, they'd still be top of the leaderboard... more strikingly, the Oly Rollers retained a significant FTS rating for several years, despite not entering any scores at all.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related to this, FTS ratings take time to adjust to sudden changes - if a team suddenly becomes much weaker or strong (due to, say, a complete change of roster), it takes quite a lot of games for FTS to catch up, as there's only so much change FTS can accommodate in a single bout. Additionally, while this adjustment is taking place, all of the opponents have unfair rating changes - FTS changes are symmetric, so for team A to gain rating, team B must lose rating, even if the cause is entirely due to a change in team A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FTS's advantage is that, like WFTDA Ratings, FTS ratings are quick and easy to calculate. So quick, in fact, that FTS recalculates all of its ratings at least once an hour, to guarantee that predictions are as up to date as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FTS also does not suffer from either of the problems of WFTDA Rankings - there is no combination of teams for which either team "can't win".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Pros and Cons of Rating Systems - SRDRank&lt;/h3&gt;
SRDRank, being a different class of rating system to the other two, has entirely different issues.
&lt;p&gt;SRDRank's main issue is its relative complexity. Whilst least-squares regression, and statistical tests, are no more advanced than first year undergraduate level, this is still a significant increase in complexity over the other two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRDRank's other issue stems from the global nature of its calculation. As with FTS, an undetected sudden change in team strength can cause unwanted effects in the ratings of other teams. As SRDRank is a globally optimised rating, this effect can make (small) changes in rating even for teams which never play the team in question. We attempt to minimise this effect via the statistical test and splitting step, but there will always been a short period where there's not enough evidence to detect a sudden change, and where ratings will be somewhat affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, SRDRank is limited by the depth and quality of information available to it. Because it uses FTS's own records as a data source, it can only use information that FTS consider relevant. Because of this, there a several uncontrolled sources of error which reduce SRDRank's accuracy - we don't always know if there's a "home" team, as FTS doesn't track the host of a bout, and assumes that one team must be a "home" team regardless - and for tournaments, FTS is poor at assigning hosts for tournament type events which run over many fixtures; we don't know the length of a bout (which affects the reliability of a rating); we don't know rosters for most games (because most bouts don't upload statsbooks), so we can't model expectations based on players who are missing or present - and so on.
We also, of course, as with all rating systems, can't rate teams for whom there is no information at all. If your team doesn't upload stats or scores to FTS, then FTS and SRDRank can't rate you. Historically, this has affected Mexico and Latin America as whole more than most other reasons, which is extremely problematic, as it also decreases visibility of the fantastic amount of derby happening in those areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In comparison, SRDRank can rank and rate the entire world's roller derby teams, not just subsets of them. It also allows detection of cliques within the community - groups of teams which play each other more than others, and thus are better rated relative to other members of the group than the outside world - and selection of ratings based on geographical location.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
Knowing a bit about possibilities for rating systems is important in judging how to use them (and which ones are good at which things).
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in gaming your WFTDA rating, it's best to avoid playing teams with less than 70% of your rating (to avoid matchings where you simply can't score enough to improve your rating, regardless of what you do); and preferably play teams closer in rank to you, but who you think you can beat by more than 10% of the score...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>flat track stats</category><category>mrda</category><category>srd rank</category><category>statistics</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/14/derby-ranking-systems-an-extension-to-papa-whisky/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 12:21:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>nonUS/Canada Derby Roundup: Nov 19,20 Edition</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/15/nonuscanada-derby-roundup-nov-1920-edition/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coming to the end of the year, and the bouts keep on coming in Europe (and Latin America)! As always, bout information is drawn from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, so if we're missing you, please get your information into FTS! (We can help with this, if you have issues.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also use &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (our own ranking scheme) to provide some result predictions (especially in places where FTS refuses to).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Scotland&lt;/h3&gt;
Starting in Scotland, there's only one home bout we know about:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Up in Aberdeen, the city's "Open" league, Granite City Brawlers, are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/662329417258500/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; their first home bout, against newly formed Crash Test Brummies B team, the Beta-Test Brummies. We've a preview for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/12/granite-city-brawlers-debut-home-game/"&gt;this here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87968/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (As the Beta Brummies are debut, this is impossible to predict.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Also, however, Scottish skater-owned-and-operated Skate and Derby store, 5th Blocker Skates, are having their 5th Birthday Bash in Glasgow, with &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1037218366354767/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a full day&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;of various derby activities!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;UK &amp;amp; NI&lt;/h3&gt;
Over in the rest of the UK and Northern Ireland....
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Belfast City Rockets are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/761145590695158/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Auld Reekie Roller Girls C, the ASTROs, in the latter's first international. We interviewed them about &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/12/an-interview-with-astros-captain-princess-die/"&gt;this here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85620/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (FTS calls this as a precisely 50:50 chance for each team to win!)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Way down south in London, London Rockin Rollers are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/298700180502058/"&gt;hosting a double header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, with LRR B taking on the Norfolk Brawds [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85398/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;], and LRR A facing Limerick [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85397/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]. (FTS favours LRR A and the Brawds respectively, as does SRD Rank)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Birmingham's Central City Rollergirls are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/695104153971201/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; their own A and B bout, with both teams taking on their opposite numbers in Paris Rollergirls.[&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/86455/overview"&gt;FTS A&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/86456/overview"&gt;FTS B&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (FTS and SRD Rank favour Paris A and Central City B, with the B bout expected close.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Moving slowly north, Southend's Seaside Sirens are facing Rebellion Roller Derby in a closed bout (so no event page). [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87920/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (FTS and SRD Rank disagree here on the likely winner)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;And, in a second closed bout, Eastbourne Roller Derby (Women) are taking on Surrey Roller Girls B [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87978/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (FTS thinks this is really close)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;And, in Nottingham, there's a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/375907632740295/"&gt;mighty triple header&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;with Nottingham A facing Hallam Hellcats [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87761/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;], Nottingham B taking on Hull's Angels B [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87759/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;], and men's league the Super Smash Brollers facing Southern Discomfort B (Mild Discomfort) [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87760/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (FTS expects two close bouts for the women, with the edge for the hosts (SRD thinks they'll be slightly less close, but agrees on likely winners). FTS won't call the men's bout, SRD rank favours Mild Discomfort)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Europe&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In France, the multi-tiered French Championships continue to power on, with bouts on both the 19th and 20th between Lorient, Anjou, Brest, Thonon, Lyon, Mâcon, Pontarlier, Clemont-Ferrand,La Roche sur Yon, Le Mans and Caen (across two different "zones" hosted by Lyon and Brest) .[&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/299942973723482/"&gt;event page&lt;/a&gt; (zone 4, Lyon) &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/624491007720706/"&gt;event page&lt;/a&gt; (zone 8, Brest)&lt;/strong&gt;] [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/86044/overview"&gt;FTS tournament link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Also in France, however, Roller Derby Toulouse are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/264562440605239/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; their own triple header, with Toulouse A taking on exhibition team the Unnamed Bitches [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87002/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;], Toulouse Men's Quad Guards facing similarly exhibition Unnamed Basterds [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87003/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;], and Toulouse B facing Namur Roller Girls [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87001/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (FTS and SRD Rank won't call the Unnamed bouts, as they're Exhibition. The B v Namur bout looks close, with FTS calling it for Namur.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The German Bundesliga also continues, as Roller Derby Dresden &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/371999369812452/"&gt;host&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; BearCity [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/75647/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] on Saturday,  and (apparently - no event page, but on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://derbyposition.com/en/bout/344/nachholspiel/"&gt;Derby Position&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) Bear City host Stuttgart on the Sunday (FTS won't call these, due to ranking system restrictions - SRD Rank thinks that Bear City are likely winners.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In Norway, there's an almost unheard of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/668877636620789/"&gt;quadruple header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, hosts Oslo facing Manchester's Rainy City B [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87433/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] and Dublin B [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87434/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] , Dublin and Rainy facing each other [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87435/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;], and, to round things off, Oslo B taking on Rainy C! [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85238/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (FTS thinks that Rainy B have the advantage in the triple, with Rainy C also looking likely to take their own bout. SRD Rank thinks that Oslo A will be stronger at home; but agrees on the B/C bout.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In Sweden, Gothenburg Roller Derby are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/357503061262445/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; fellow Gothenburgers Dock City Rollers B (against their own B team)[&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87912/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] and Copenhagen Roller Derby (against their A team)[&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87996/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (Gothenburg A are likely to win, but Dock City B look like taking the win here (SRD Rank considers the B bout to be on a knife-edge).)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;And, finally, in the Netherlands, Breda's Suck City Rock'n Roller Dolls are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1587863974612388/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Enschede's Roller Derby Twente.[&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/86907/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (FTS calls this for the visitors, and SRD Rank agrees.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
 
&lt;h3&gt;Latin America&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;And, in Argentina, Buenos Aires Roller Derby are hosting a triple header on Sunday, with BARD A playing Wonderclan (also of Buenos Aires) [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87981/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] in a double header with BARD B against 2x4 Roller Derby's Las Pibas [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87982/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] and BARD C facing Cosmicclan (Wonderclan B) [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87998/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (FTS won't predict these bouts. SRD Rank can't call the third bout, due to lack of connectivity; but predicts BARD A and 2x4 B (Las Pibas) to win their respective bouts.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Late Additions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Also in Sweden, Örebro Roller Derby are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/669971856484591/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the first set of bouts in the Seriespel (Division 1) - with the hosts playing Uppsala, Stockholm B and Umeå over the weekend in four bouts. [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/88014"&gt;FTS tournament page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (SRD Rank favours Stockholm B here - although Umeå also look strong.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>european derby</category><category>flat track stats</category><category>latin american derby</category><category>srd rank</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/15/nonuscanada-derby-roundup-nov-1920-edition/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 11:55:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>November 5,6th non-USA Derby Roundup</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/03/november-56th-non-usa-derby-roundup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's another weekend, and while there's apparently something happening in the USA, there's still tons of roller derby going on elsewhere. As always, for most events here, we're using the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;FlatTrackStats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; database, so if you want to be featured, please add yourselves. We also use our own &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/03/srd-rank-november-update/"&gt;November release of SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, our own ranking scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Thanks this time, especially, to (deep breath):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Demolitia Derby Queens, Heart of Appalachia, Cornfed Derby Dames, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Dark River Derby Coalition, Cen-Tex Rollergirls, Big Easy Rollergirls, LeHigh Valley Rollergirls, Neo Roller Derby, Cape Fear Roller Girls, Hammer City Roller Girls, Sintral Florida Derby Demons, Grand Raggidy Roller Girls, Piedmont Riot, Hellions of Troy, Black Hills Wildfire Roller Derby, West Coast Derby Knockouts and Peterborough Area Roller Derby, who have all responded to requests for missing bout data in Flat Track Stats as well. Please let us know if we can help you to get missing bout data into FTS, and we will do our best.]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scotland&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting out in Scotland, there's two things going on:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In Edinburgh, Auld Reekie Roller Girls B are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1594409394188095/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the rising Granite City Roller Derby. We've previously written on this &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/18/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-and-away/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85859/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In Dundee, the annual home teams tournament is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/771230369646444/"&gt;running&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. We've written about this &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/27/dundee-home-teams-returns/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. (There's no FTS link as FTS does not track these home teams.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;UK&lt;/h3&gt;
In the wider UK, there's also plenty of Roller Derby going on:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In Croydon, there's a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1029286510487415/"&gt;double header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, as Croydon A take on Dublin Roller Derby B, [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/86878/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] and Croydon B take on Dublin C! [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/86879/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (FTS expects the hosts to win the A game, but Dublin C to win against Croydon B. SRD Rank thinks that Dublin might get a clean sweep.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Rainy City Roller Derby continue their busy year, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/721358984684500/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; a double header, featuring Wirral Roller Derby A v Rainy B, and Wirral B v Rainy C! [FTS links &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85237/overview"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87753/overview"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (SRD Rank gives Rainy B the win on the first bout, and Wirral B the win on the second.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;On Sunday, Deathrow Hull are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1180970668590150/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Sunderland Roller Derby for the latter's 2nd ever public bout! [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/86836/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (with just one bout to go on, FTS thinks that Sunderland might be the likely winners - SRD Rank opines oppositely.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;And, finally, Severn Roller Torrent are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/596227740550690/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Nottingham Roller Girls.[&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/86837/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (FTS expects a closeish game, with the hosts winning, SRD Rank agrees.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Europe&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;As we've written about &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/25/glasgow-cross-the-irish-sea-dublin-v-irn-bruisers/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, while Dublin B and C are off in Croydon, Dublin Roller Derby A is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/299480537069476/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Glasgow Roller Derby in Ireland! [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85892"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (The hosts are likely to win this, from FTS and SRD Rank.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Up in Sweden, Norrköping Roller Derby are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/211973202554203/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; a double header, with Norrköping B taking on Uppsala [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85454/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] on only their second game and the A team playing  the mighty Kallio B [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85455/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (FTS and SRD Rank both consider Kallio B to be terrifying, and likely to take a win against the hosts; with only one bout to go on, the B game is harder to predict, and SRD Rank cannot rank the B team as they're not connected to the main group.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Nantes Derby Girls are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/162850257501786/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; their own triple header tournament, hosting Gent Go-Gos and Dirty River Roller Girls (of Turku, Finland). [FTS links: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85940/overview"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85941/overview"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85942/overview"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (FTS considers the hosts to be the most likely winners here, and SRD Rank agrees)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Also in France, the 2016-17 French Championships continue, with Lille Roller Girls hosting a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/836427439832842/"&gt;2 day tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; also featuring Miaous' Roller Derby Panthers, Creil's Knock'n'Roll Cannibals, Calaisis' Black Tagada, Pigalle's Les Gueuses de Pigalle and Switchblade RollerGrrrls (of Lille) [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/86044/overview"&gt;FTS tournament page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (The Switchblades are overwhelmingly the favourites here, with Miaous's Panthers following slightly behind.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Over in Tenerife, Tenerife Roller Derby are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1602777286684228/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; their own triple header, hosting Paris Roller Girls B and Royal Windsor B! [FTS links &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85851/overview"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85852/overview"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85389/overview"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] ! (FTS considers Tenerife and Paris B to be near identical in strength, taking into account home team advantage. It believes that Royal Windsor is much lower strength. SRD Rank agrees, but thinks that Paris is likely to win overall.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In Stuttgart, the Bundesliga 2016 continues as they &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/75646/overview"&gt;host&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; St. Pauli (of Hamburg). [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/75646/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (FTS predicts a close game, with a slight edge to the visitors. SRD Rank agrees.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;also in Germany, the Baloney Ponies of Kaiserslautern are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/338163249848498/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the Sisters of Mayhem [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85748/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]  (FTS cannot rank these teams, and thus cannot predict this. This is unsurprising, as they're essentially exhibition teams.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;and in Vienna, Vienna B are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/946772168800686/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Gothenburg Roller Derby Badass Beavers [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/86447/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] (FTS rates the hosts as the likely winners here, as does SRD Rank.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Late Additions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Also in Ireland, Cork City Firebirds are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/470442813165568/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the East Coast Cyclones (of Wicklow). Thanks to the work of the FTS Admins this is now on FTS (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/87861"&gt;FTS Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), where they call it as a very close win for the visitors.. SRD Rank can't call this, as there aren't enough recent connected bouts on record for Cork.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>european derby</category><category>flat track stats</category><category>statistics</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/03/november-56th-non-usa-derby-roundup/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 13:52:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>nonUS Derby - 29October Update</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/27/nonus-derby-29october-update/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a pretty good crop last weekend, we've decided to do this round up again - and due to some pretty exciting things happening in the Southern Hemisphere, we've making this a Euro+Australia update!
As always, this information is from bouts submitted to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If you don't feature here and want to, please consider helping Flat Track Stats to track all of flat track roller derby by submitting your leagues' games!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting close to home though:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Scotland&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;As we've previously &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/19/are-you-ready-for-a-skating-spooktacular/"&gt;written about&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Mean City Roller Derby are hosting a Halloween double header, Hallowmean, with Mean City (Women) facing off against Auld Reekie Roller Girls All-Star Rookies (ASTROS) (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85946/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), and Mean City (coed) facing Bairn City Rollers (coed) (not tracked by FTS). [FTS and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/08/ranking-the-world-and-other-fts-visualisations/2"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; agree that the ASTROS have the advantage here, although we think they have more of an edge than FTS do.]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;UK&lt;/h3&gt;
Over in the UK, there's one big tournament we're aware of:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Central City Roller Derby's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1712812048986605/"&gt;Jamdemic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;sees the hosts' B team face off against Oxford Roller Derby, Brussels Derby Pixies, Leeds Roller Dolls B, Tiger Bay Brawlers B and London Roller Girls C!  Astonishingly, this is a full round-robin tournament, plus additional final placement bouts! (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/86848"&gt;FTS tournament page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) [We would expect Brussels and London C to top the list, with Tiger Bay B and Oxford fighting for 3rd place. FTS disagrees slightly, believing that Tiger Bay can take the silver.]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Also in the south, Royal Windsor Rollergirls are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1268603769836803/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Hot Wheel (both fresh from bouts last weekend) (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85943/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) [FTS and SRD Rank concur that Hot Wheel are the likely victors - FTS has the benefit of the last weekend's bouts and thinks things are closer than we do.]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;And Rebellion Roller Derby have a double header &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1783951281861467/"&gt;planned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  as Rebellion A take on Brighton Rockers (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85860/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), and Rebellion B take on Southern Coed Roller Derby's Apex Predators (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85861/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) [We and FTS think that Brighton have the likely win; neither of us can call the other bout as there's not any records on file for Rebellion B.]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Europe&lt;/h3&gt;
Mainland Europe, Ireland and Scandinavia have a massive load of roller derby this weekend!
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In France, the  2016-17 season of the  &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/309931276032950/"&gt;French Championship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in kicks off, with Rouen/Montreuil, Lutece/Orléans on Saturday, and more bouts on the Sunday featuring additionally the Psyko'Quads of Sainte-Geneviève-des-Bois and Paris Roller Girls C,(&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/86044"&gt;FTS tournament page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; a second &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1124220774281840/"&gt;hosted section of the Championship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Oisan, with hosts Sc'Alpes Hell versus the Rabbit Skulls of Avignon and Roller Derby Saint-Etienne. (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/86044/overview"&gt;FTS tournament page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) [In the first tournament: FTS and we agree that Lutece is the strongest team, but we differ on the rest of the ordering (notably, we rate Rouen second, and FTS prefers Orléans).  In the second, FTS and we agree that the hosts have the advantage over Rabbit Skulls. Saint-Etienne have played so infrequently that SRD Rank can't rank them - FTS makes a guess that they're the weakest competitor.]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, Germany is just finishing off its own championship, as the Bundesliga 2016 comes to a close with Frankfurt's Bembel Town &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1779619422260006/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Cologne (Köln). (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/74692/overview"&gt;FTS tournament page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) [FTS and we agree that Köln is likely to win, with us predicting a closer game than FTS.]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In northern Finland, on Sunday, we see the start of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/211068652632021/"&gt;Pohjola Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 2016/17 (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/85241/overview"&gt;FTS tournament page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;). We will have more about this tournament series&lt;b&gt; in a future article&lt;/b&gt;. [FTS and SRD Rank agree that Riverdale is very likely to defeat Seinäjoki, but can't predict Jyväskylä B v Shitty Village, as it's the former's debut bout.]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In Denmark, Aalborg Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/215827912164790/"&gt;host&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Copenhagen Roller Derby B in a halloween-themed bout (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85225/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) [SRD Rank can't predict this, as Copenhagen B haven't got enough recent connected bouts. FTS is willing to take a stab at Aalborg being the winners.]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Over in Namur, Belgium, the home league is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/160947164357066/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; a double-header on Saturday, as Namur B take on Charleroi's Blackland &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85916/overview"&gt;(FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and Namur A faces Paris Roller Girls B (Les Quedalles) (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85917/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) ... and then are playing a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1321421697898273/"&gt;friendly intraleague&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the Sunday as part of the Beautes Soniques music festival! [FTS and SRD Rank concur that Paris B has the likely win over Namur, and that Namur B the win over Blackland... but we differ significantly on how close they will be (recent performance by Blackland has been much lower than expected, and SRD Rank responds faster to recent results than FTS).]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In Ireland, Dublin Roller Derby (fresh from playing 2 bouts away last weekend!) &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1208441099174940/"&gt;host&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; a three-way triple head, as the hosts' B team plays Limerick Roller Derby, and Roller Derby Porto flying over from Portugal! (FTS links: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85684"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85686/overview"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85685/overview"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) [FTS thinks that Porto will be the overall winner, and Limerick the overall loser... but SRD rank disagrees and ranks Dublin B top of the list.]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Moving back north, in Sweden: Uppsala Roller Derby B &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/304926583233283/"&gt;host&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Växjö (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85925/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) [This is Växjö's debut bout, so no predictions are possible!]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;and in neighbouring Norway, Oslo Roller Derby hosts a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1848913605338025/"&gt;triple header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, with Oslo A playing Stockholm's Royal Swedish Army A (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85997/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), and Oslo B playing both Royal Swedish Army B (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85999/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and Karlstad's Sun City! (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85998/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) [FTS and SRD Rank agree that Oslo A have the advantage, and Karlstad the disadvantage. We disagree over the middle bout - FTS believes that Royal Army B will take it, whilst SRD Rank favours the home team B.]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pacific&lt;/h3&gt;
Moving over to the Southern Hemisphere, then, both Australia and New Zealand also have big tournament events.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In Australia, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/321023354931893/"&gt;2016 Bendigo Rebellion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is kicking off on Saturday (in Bendigo, hosted by Dragon City Derby Dolls), and coming to a close on Monday. Essentially the entirety of Australia is involved, from Victorian Roller Derby League B, through Melbourne, the Adeladies, Glenorchy's Convict City, Sydney's South Side and more... and across three different skill divisions! (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/85836/overview"&gt;FTS tournament page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) [Our predictions for the three skill divisions are: Victorian's Queen Bees to top "The First Order", Canberra's VCB's to top "The Jedi Masters", and Otway or Wagga to top "The Clones". FTS would differ, due to some results in October (which aren't included in our ranking), placing Queen Bees to win "The First Order", Diamond Valley in "The Jedi Masters", and East Vic to take "The Clones". (Our least certain result is for Wagga - they have only one bout in our rating period...) ]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Somehow avoiding this, Varsity Derby League B are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1148742081880558/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Adelaide's Light City in their native Canberra. (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85248/overview"&gt;FTS link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) just to ensure that every piece of Australia is playing derby this weekend. [FTS and SRD Rank agree that this is a close bout - but we disagree on the winner, with FTS favouring the hosts.]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Meanwhile, across in New Zealand, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/595951320589286/"&gt;New Zealand Top 10 Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (New Zealand's national championships) is coming to a close as Wellington's Richter City &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/595951320589286/"&gt;host&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; opponents Pirate City of Auckland, and a bout between Dunedin and Christchurch's Dead End. (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/74807/overview"&gt;FTS tournament page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) [FTS and we call the hosts as winners of the first bout, but we believe it will be very close, while FTS considers it a done deal. For the second bout, we disagree, with FTS favouring Dunedin, and us Dead End.]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Finally, and not on FTS as it's an intraleague, we'd like to give a shout out to Okinawa's Devil Dog Derby Dames, who are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/329712107377601/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; a Halloween-themed game, with music from the Okinawan-Hispanic Ballet Folklorico Mexicano de Okinawa at half time!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Latin America&lt;/h3&gt;
Also not on Flat Track Stats until a volunteer discovered it [Please, Latin American leagues, add stuff to Flat Track Stats - you're mostly invisible to the world unless you let us know about you!], there's yet another big tournament this weekend, in Chile!
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The third "Latin American Roller Derby Tournament" (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/311051265925230/?action_history=null"&gt;Tercer Torneo Latinoamericano de Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/strong&gt;features 3 days of competition between 9 teams for the "Latin Cup". (There's also an opportunity to see  Latin American National teams - Perú, Chile, Argentina and Colombia - play in the last day in a round-robin; and a Men's derby demonstration bout.) The hosts, Metropolitan Roller Derby, of Santiago, compete against ToxicLima (of Lima, Peru), Tacones Banditos (of Vińa del Mar, Chile), Complot Derby Club (of Santiago), Liga Buenos Aires Roller Derby (of Buenos Aires, Argentina), No Excuses Roller Derby (of Buenos Aires), Ladies of Hell Town (of São Paulo, Brazil), Bogotá Bone Breakers (of Bogotá, Colombia) and Sailor City Rollers (of Buenos Aires). (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/86909"&gt;FTS tournament page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) [It's basically impossible to call this tournament with SRD rank, as the Latin American leagues aren't connected to the main group we rank. FTS also has only sporadic records from them, so it has issues too.]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Late Mentions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Late mentions to Dorset Knobs Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1087138264689243/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Bristol Roller Derby [added to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/86988"&gt;FTS here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;And to (not on FTD as its a charity intraleague), Grin 'N' Barum Roller Girls' &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1716130268642656/"&gt;Bout Against Cancer&lt;/a&gt; on Sunday.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>flat track stats</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>statistics</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/27/nonus-derby-29october-update/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 12:46:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs 3: The SRD Predictions</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/09/15/wftda-division-1-playoffs-3-the-srd-predictions/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned in our last &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/09/14/roller-derby-analytics-comparing-performance-with-fts-on-the-wftda-d1-playoffs/"&gt;analytics&lt;/a&gt; article, the work we've been doing on Roller Derby analytics is now sufficiently advanced that our predictions about last week's Division 1 Playoffs were just as good as those of Flat Track Stats. We think that this is probably good enough to start making a few public predictions - and where better than in &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; weekend's coming &lt;a href="http://static.wftda.com/tournaments/2015/brackets/d1-playoffs-jacksonville-bracket.pdf"&gt;Division 1 Playoffs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, this playoffs is yet another history-making event, with &lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; attending as the first ever Scottish league to reach Division 1, and only the second UK league after London Rollergirls! (Last week was similarly historic for Sweden, with Crime City Rollers and Stockholm Roller Derby both attending for the first time.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WFTDA prediction for this playoffs is:
1. London Rollergirls (#4)
2. Denver Roller Derby (#5)
3. Jacksonville RollerGirls (#9)
4. Atlanta Rollergirls (#13)
5. Tampa Roller Derby (#18)
6. Detroit Derby Girls (#21)
7. Glasgow Roller Derby (#26)
8. Steel City Roller Derby (#29)
9. Pikes Peak Derby Dames (#36)
10. Charlottesville Derby Dames (#38)
corresponding to the seeding for the tournament itself (numbers in brackets are the WFTDA rank).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both we and &lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt; disagree with this prediction somewhat, and in generally the same areas. We tend to consider Steel City somewhat underranked, and Pikes Peak somewhat overranked, but differ as to precisely how much.
Using score ratios, our prediction for the final standing is:
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;1. London Rollergirls&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;2. Denver Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;3. Jacksonville Roller Girls&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;4. Atlanta Rollergirls&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;5. Tampa Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;6. Detroit Derby Girls&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;7. Steel City Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;8. Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;9. Charlottesville Derby Dames&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;10. Pikes Peak Derby Dames&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and using score difference simply swaps the position of Glasgow and Charlottesville. In fact, by both metrics, the Glasgow / Charlottesville bout is predicted to be the closest bout of the &lt;em&gt;entire tournament&lt;/em&gt;, with potentially less than 20 points between the two!
&lt;strong&gt;This bout is on at 5pm Friday, UK time.&lt;/strong&gt; You can watch it live on &lt;a href="http://www.wftda.tv"&gt;WFTDA.tv&lt;/a&gt;, or attend the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/106285746391762/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby viewing party&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flat Track Stats predicts (with its idea of the WFTDA rank in brackets):
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;1. London (#2)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;2. Denver (#7)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;3. Jacksonville (#8)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;5. Atlanta (#16)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;5. Tampa (#18)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;6. Detroit (#20)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;7. Steel City (#23)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;8. Pikes Peak (#41)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;9. Charlottesville (#43)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;10. Glasgow (#50)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;although it also agrees that the Glasgow/Charlottesville bout will be extremely close (giving Glasgow a 37% chance of winning)!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>analytics</category><category>articles</category><category>flat track stats</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>wftda</category><category>wftda division 1 playoffs</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/09/15/wftda-division-1-playoffs-3-the-srd-predictions/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 18:46:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Roller Derby Analytics: Comparing performance with FTS on the WFTDA D1 Playoffs</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/09/14/roller-derby-analytics-comparing-performance-with-fts-on-the-wftda-d1-playoffs/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In previous analytics posts, we've discussed the potential for least-squares ("&lt;a href="http://www.masseyratings.com/theory/massey97.pdf"&gt;Massey&lt;/a&gt;") methods as a mechanism for predicting Roller Derby team scores, and used a primitive version to analyse the &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/"&gt;performance of the Women's and Men's World Cups&lt;/a&gt;. At the time, we mentioned that a significant issue for least-squares fits is that, by default, they treat all data equally - there's no sense in which an older result is "superseded" by newer results automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subsequently, we also posted some results on &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/07/visualising-the-internationalisation-of-roller-derby-part-1-of-2/"&gt;determining the connectivity of Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;, showing that nowadays there is &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/07/visualising-the-internationalisation-of-roller-derby-part-2-of-2-2011-to-present/"&gt;one dominant group&lt;/a&gt; of Derby teams, internationally, who have all played at least one other member of the group in the last year. This work also allows us to measure how rapidly this group grows over time (starting from a given date, how long does it take for the majority of teams to have played sufficient games that all of them are connected in this way). Given the time-dependance issues of Least-squares methods, we use this data to sample only enough bouts to capture the largest group (this turns out to require between 7 and 9 months worth of bouts at any point in time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optimisation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two potential improvements to our least-squares algorithm over the "vanilla" default version. Firstly, we can attempt to compensate for home advantage by adjusting the scores for the home team by a small amount relative to reality (removing their theoretical advantage). Secondly, we can attempt to provide some "time awareness" by weighting old results relative to newer ones, so the influence of any given bout reduces over time. The difficulty is determining the precise values for these two corrections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the Flat Track Stats datasets, we ran searches across the potential values for the two corrections (using 7 months of bout data to produce predictions, and then testing them against the subsequent month, for each value). There's quite a flat region of good performance for both, but we determined that a home advantage correction of around 0.1 to 0.15, and an exponentially-decaying weight with time-base on the order of 3 months gave the best results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to test our model, what better subject than the&lt;a href="https://www.wftda.com/tournaments/2015"&gt; WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs&lt;/a&gt;, which are increasingly international with each year. We generated predictions for both score-ratios and score-differences for each of the bouts in the WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs 2 (held 11-13 Sept 2015), using both unoptimised and weighted-optimised versions of our Least-Squares model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When calculating the expected score ratios, we can compare directly against the performance of &lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt; (which publishes expected score ratios for all bouts). The FTS predictions were taken from the site on the 11th and 12th of September, so FTS predictions for the second day of the Playoffs included data from the first day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Our model was run on the dataset ending on the 8th September for all predictions, using bouts from 1 Jan 2015 through to that date (approximately 9 months).)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can plot the resulting predictions, along with the actual score ratios (using a logarithmic scale) here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/fts-v-calc.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4890" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/fts-v-calc.png" alt="Plot of FTS, Least-squares (optimised) and Real score results for WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs 2." width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Plot of FTS, Least-squares (optimised) and Real log score ratios for WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, our model does at least as well as Flat Track Stats does at predicting score ratios - we both fail at the Crime City v Rose bout by some margin, but also have many close matches to our predictions in other situations. This is perhaps easier to see by plotting the difference between the real score ratio and the predictions, for FTS and our model:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/delta-fts-v-calc.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4891" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/delta-fts-v-calc.png" alt="Plot of absolute prediction errors for FTS, Least-squares (optimised) for log score ratios, WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs 2." width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Plot of absolute prediction errors for FTS, Least-squares (optimised) for log score ratios, WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can measure our overall performance by computing the Mean and RMS error - the Mean error gives a measure of our systematic bias (if as many of our guesses are high as low then they cancel out), while the RMS error gives a value for generally how bad our guesses were in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Division 1 Playoffs 2, both our Mean and RMS errors are smaller than those of FTS (-0.135 v -0.330 for Mean error - showing that we both slightly underestimate on average; 0.476 v 0.607 for RMS error). In both cases, the dominant contributor to the error is the Crime City bout, although we still outperform FTS even if that particular bout is removed. (In fact, even without optimisation, standard Least-Squares outperforms FTS on these metrics.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, if we try to predict on the basis of Score difference, rather than Score Ratios, we do considerably better in precisely the extreme cases that cause ratio methods problems. (Here, we can't compare against FTS, as they do not publish score difference predictions.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/calc-diff.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4892" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/calc-diff.png" alt="Plot of Least-squared (optimised) prediction and Real score difference results, WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs 2" width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Plot of Least-squared (optimised) prediction and Real score difference results, WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, although the Score difference prediction does better than we expected, it does fail to predict the winner as often as the Score ratio prediction: Score-diff calls 4 bouts wrongly, while ratios call 3 (and FTS 5), although there is considerable overlap across the bouts each find problematic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have established an optimised Least-Squares predictor for Roller Derby bouts, and tested it on WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs 2 bouts. We appear to be at least as successful as the more technologically sophisticated Flat Track Stats algorithm at predicting score ratios (potentially because ELO ranking metrics find sparse competitor graphs more difficult to handle), although neither algorithm has what we would regard as a superlative degree of predictive ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our next article, we will publish some predictions for WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs 3, featuring London Rollergirls and Glasgow Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(In future, we hope to explore some other sport ranking algorithms, notably the &lt;a href="http://www.constantinou.info/downloads/papers/pi-ratings.pdf"&gt;pi-rating&lt;/a&gt; used as the basis of Constantinou's &lt;a href="http://www.pi-football.com/"&gt;pi-football&lt;/a&gt; prediction system. Like soccer, Roller Derby has highly volatile bout performance, so we hope that pi-rating will be able to improve on both of the systems in this article.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This analysis was performed using the September 8 dump of the Flat Track Stats bouts and teams databases. This data is released under a &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/"&gt;Creative Commons 4.0 Non-Commercial&lt;/a&gt; license. In the spirit of this license, which permits all uses which are not-for-profit, this article and the data in it are also released under a &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;Creative Commons 4.0 Non-Commercial Share-Alike&lt;/a&gt; license - this means that you may use this article in any way which is not-for-profit, as long as you license your derived work in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>analytics</category><category>articles</category><category>flat track stats</category><category>fts</category><category>wftda</category><category>wftda division 1 playoffs</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/09/14/roller-derby-analytics-comparing-performance-with-fts-on-the-wftda-d1-playoffs/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 14:49:57 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>