<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about flattrackstats)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/flattrackstats.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Visualising the Internationalisation of Roller Derby Part 2 of 2 (2011 to present).</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/07/visualising-the-internationalisation-of-roller-derby-part-2-of-2-2011-to-present/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the first article in this series (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/07/visualising-the-internationalisation-of-roller-derby-part-1-of-2/"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) we introduced the use of FlatTrackStats bout records to visualise the connections between derby teams over time. As with that article, this article is licensed &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;Creative Commons: Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (you may reuse and share this article freely, as long as you attribute it to the author, do not profit from it, and license any derived work with the same license). This article was generated, as the previous one was, with data kindly provided by FlatTrackStats, licensed &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/"&gt;CC:BY-NC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, we covered the period in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wftda.com"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mensrollerderbyassociation.org/"&gt;MRDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.juniorrollerderby.org/home.php"&gt;Junior&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;derby from the origins of organised derby in 2005 through to the emergence of junior derby, the men's game and the first truly international period of derby in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we will cover the period from 2011 to the start of 2015. As with the previous article, our colour coding scheme is: &lt;span style="color:#ff0000;"&gt;Red is USA&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;Blue is Canada&lt;/span&gt;,  &lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;Green: Europe&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="color:#33cccc;"&gt;Cyan: Australia&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="color:#800080;"&gt;Purple: New Zealand&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="color:#ffff00;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#ffcc00;"&gt;Yellow the Asia-Pacific&lt;/span&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;, and White: Latin America. Groups which are densely connected from playing lots of games together will group physically closer in the plots, while less connected groups are thrown out to the edges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The success of London Rollergirls playing across in the USA in 2010 inspired other European teams to try the same thing a year later (bolstered by the first ever World Cup also being in that year). The largest connected group in &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt; looked like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-111.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-large wp-image-4687 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-111.png?w=660" alt="W Group 1 2011" width="660" height="644"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to the 2010 plot, the additional &lt;strong&gt;European&lt;/strong&gt; teams (&lt;em&gt;Central City&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Lincolnshire Bomber&lt;/em&gt;s et al) connecting with the USA pull the densely connected centre of the plot out somewhat, making it less insular. Conversely, &lt;em&gt;London Rollergirl&lt;/em&gt;s are pulled in the other direction - from this point on, their green dot is the one nestled in the core of the central, well-connected part of the plot, disconnected somewhat from the rest of Europe. We also see that &lt;strong&gt;Australasian&lt;/strong&gt; derby has joined the International community proper, with Victorian Roller Derby League placing them in contact with the Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;strong&gt;Latin America&lt;/strong&gt; is showing the first signs of widespread derby growth, with a healthy crop of new leagues all playing each other:
&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-31.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-4688 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-31.png?w=300" alt="W Group 3 2011" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Men's derby, by contrast, is not yet fully international in &lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;, with the biggest connected group resolutely USA and Canada:
&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-112.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-large wp-image-4689 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-112.png?w=660" alt="M Group 1 2011" width="660" height="627"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Although both Europe and Latin America are starting to show their own growth:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-32.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-thumbnail wp-image-4690 " src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-32.png?w=150" alt="M Group 3 2011" width="150" height="150"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-6.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-thumbnail wp-image-4691 " src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-6.png?w=150" alt="M Group 6 2011" width="150" height="150"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
it was a year later, in &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, that the Men's Derby community joined up across the Atlantic:
&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-113.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-large wp-image-4692 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-113.png?w=660" alt="M Group 1 2012" width="660" height="598"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
and not until &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt; that Latin America joined the biggest group:
&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-114.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-large wp-image-4693 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-114.png?w=660" alt="M Group 1 2013" width="660" height="634"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
just in time for Men's Derby to properly take off in Australia (now the largest group separate from the main one):
&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-23.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-4694 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-23.png?w=300" alt="M Group 2 2013" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Women's derby was exploding in Europe, and European teams were increasingly travelling across to the USA to play tougher teams, creating a second pole of derby in the community:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-115.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-large wp-image-4695 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-115.png?w=660" alt="W Group 1 2013" width="660" height="663"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(notice also the first appearance of Yellow in any of our graphs, as &lt;em&gt;Tokyo Roller Girls&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Kokeshi Roller Dolls&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Devil Dog Derby Dames&lt;/em&gt; all make their appearance in the derby scene already integrated into the International scene).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, fast forwarding to the present day, what does roller derby look like at the start of &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Women's Derby&lt;/strong&gt; is increasingly truly international, with the dense central cluster of "connected Division 1" type teams being slowly infiltrated by European and Australasian (and a few Latin American) teams drawn in from the edges, although Asia-Pacific derby is still limited to the three Japanese leagues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-116.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-large wp-image-4697 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-116.png?w=660" alt="W Group 1 2014" width="660" height="662"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bucking the trend, however, &lt;strong&gt;Latin American&lt;/strong&gt; derby maintains a strong community of its own, disconnected (for the most part) from the rest of the community:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-24.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4698" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-24.png?w=300" alt="W Group 2 2014" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-4.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4699" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-4.png?w=300" alt="W Group 4 2014" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
as does the geographically separated Alaskan derby community:
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-33.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4700" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-33.png?w=300" alt="W Group 3 2014" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Mens' Derby&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt; looks a lot like Women's Derby did in 2010 or 2011, with a large group of USA/Europe, connected by only a few European mediators:
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-117.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-large wp-image-4701 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-117.png?w=660" alt="M Group 1 2014" width="660" height="633"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(although Men's derby is a lot more balanced in the sizes of the USA and Europe groups than Women's Derby was in 2010), and a strongly developing and independant Australasian Men's Derby group:
&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-25.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-4702 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-25.png?w=300" alt="M Group 2 2014" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Junior Derby&lt;/strong&gt;, meanwhile, is still resolutely an American pursuit for the most part:
&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-118.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-large wp-image-4703 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-118.png?w=660" alt="J Group 1 2014" width="660" height="595"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
(the few European Junior Derby leagues tend not to have travel teams, or, in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; case, have no teams with the same age limits to play), although, as with Men's Derby, there's a small Australasian group in evidence as well:
&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-34.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-thumbnail wp-image-4704 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-34.png?w=150" alt="J Group 3 2014" width="150" height="150"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The astute reader will, at this point, be asking why we've not talked about &lt;strong&gt;Coed Derby&lt;/strong&gt; yet. The problem with Coed Derby, based on the FTS records, is that most (WFTDA/MRDA) Coed teams have been Exhibition teams, set up without the formal League structure. As such, they are excluded from the terms in which our plots are constructed: there's literally no bouts on record for formal Coed Travel Teams until 2013!
Interestingly, what Coed Derby there is seems to be following a very different track from the USA-led structures in the rest of the community. The single biggest grouping of Coed Teams in &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt; was entirely Europe (in fact, UK) based:
&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-119.png"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter wp-image-4705 size-medium" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-119.png?w=300" alt="C Group 1 2014" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, what for the future?&lt;/strong&gt;
Well, on the trends we've seen so far, I expect &lt;strong&gt;Men's&lt;/strong&gt; Derby to follow a rather even development, with Australasia joining the International group within the next year, forming a rather well balanced community split three ways in weighting.
&lt;strong&gt;Women's&lt;/strong&gt; Derby remains rather unbalanced towards the USA, just because of the delay in derby seeding outside that continent. The evidence suggests that the power imbalance is slowly easing (Glasgow Roller Derby making it into the &lt;a href="http://wftda.com/rankings"&gt;top 30 WFTDA teams&lt;/a&gt; recently, with Stockholm and Helsinki just outside, is a sign of this), but it will probably take several more years before the core derby cluster is noticeably less red than it is now. (We expect it to take about as long for London Rollergirls A to reconnect with the rest of European derby.) The newest region, Asia-Pacific, is something we will cover in a few planned articles to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Junior&lt;/strong&gt; Derby's status outside of the USA is worrying - the evidence from the last year, as several very talented US players have graduated from Junior to Women's derby leagues, suggests that a strong Junior Derby community is very important in the maintenance of a strong Adult community as well. We hope that more will be done in this area across Europe in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for &lt;strong&gt;Coed&lt;/strong&gt; Derby - it's impossibly early to predict. It's possible that the growth of formal teams could be driven entirely from Europe, but as there is no history of this in the sport to date, it is very hard to predict what form its influence could take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tools used to generate these plots are available at the author's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/aoanla/ranking-chain-inference"&gt;github repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, along with other statistical tools under development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>analysis</category><category>articles</category><category>flattrackstats</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>statistics</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/07/visualising-the-internationalisation-of-roller-derby-part-2-of-2-2011-to-present/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 16:58:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Visualising the Internationalisation of Roller Derby (part 1 of 2)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/07/visualising-the-internationalisation-of-roller-derby-part-1-of-2/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, we've been including some more analytics content on the blog, with included content here and some links from articles to more detailed discussions on the author's personal wordpress. In order to improve our analytics, it's important to have a big set of real world measurements to compare to - you can use these to train your model, and then also to test the new model's predictive power (obviously you use different subsets of your data for training and testing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;FlatTrackStats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; has a very large and complete set of bout records for flat track roller derby, dating back to the very first bouts in 2003. Even more luckily, the FlatTrackStats guys are committed to openness of data, so their records are licensed Creative Commons: Non-Commercial (this means that anyone can use their data for free, as long as they credit FTS, and don't try to profit from whatever they're doing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the interests of paying this forward (and because the author also personally believes that it's in the best interests of roller derby to not restrict information unless absolutely necessary), this article and all images therein is licensed &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;Creative Commons: Non-Commercial-ShareAlike&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (you can reuse this article, and the images therein for anything, as long as you credit me as the source, don't profit from your actions, and share your resulting things under exactly the same license).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have the FlatTrackStats team and bout databases, up to the last week, we need to process the data in order to make it useful for our model. Part of this processing involves dividing up all of the teams (for any given period of dates) into subsets, such that everyone in a subset has played at least one person in that subset. And if you're doing that kind of processing anyway, you end up writing some tools to visualise the resulting subsets just to check on them... and it turns out that this kind of visualisation is historically interesting in itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article presents the result of some visualisations of the partitions of Flat Track Roller Derby for each year, starting from 2005 (which is really when the first teams solidified from the experimentation in 2003-4). As this data is taken from the FTS bout database, it only includes bouts which teams submitted to FTS (or which were in the DNN derbymatic database, which was also rolled into FTS when DNN closed). We also exclude Exhibition and Home teams from our plots, which mostly has effects for Men's and Coed derby post 2010. Teams are represented by circles, with lines connecting them representing a bout between those teams in the time period covered. The plotting algorithm treats connections like elastic bands, so groups of teams who all played each other are drawn into dense central regions of the plot by the forces between them, while less connected groups are pushed out to the edges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, Women's Flat Track Roller Derby was in its infancy. In fact, there are only 9 travel teams known to FlatTrackStats for the period 1 Jan 2005 to 1 Jan 2006, and of course all of them are in the USA. If we partition them into the groups which played each other, we find that there's one "big" group, with 5 members, and 2 small groups with a pair of teams a piece. (It turns out that most of the "isolated" groups we find in any year are 2 or 3 member groups, with teams who are just starting out and only really played one game that year.) The members of the big group are quite familiar today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-1.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-4654 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-1.png?w=300" alt="Graph of dominant group of Women's Derby Teams, 2005" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(that's Gotham just sliding off the left edge of the graph).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no Men's, Junior or Coed teams at this early stage of Flat Track Derby, of course.
But Women's Derby is growing rapidly. Moving on to 1 Jan &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt; to 1 Jan 2007, many new teams have started up, mostly in the USA, but with one in Canada. And almost all of them (except one pair of teams) have played at least one other team in the biggest group:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-11.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4655" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-11-e1433665617798.png?w=300" alt="Women's FT 2006 Biggest Group" width="300" height="287"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
(here we start to see our colour scheme - &lt;span style="color:#ff0000;"&gt;Red is USA&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;Blue is Canada&lt;/span&gt;, and later on &lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;Green will be Europe&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="color:#33cccc;"&gt;Cyan: Australia&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="color:#993366;"&gt;Purple: New Zealand&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="color:#ffcc00;"&gt;Yellow the Asia-Pacific&lt;/span&gt;, and White: South America - drawn from FTS' internal categorisations). This group is really the founding set of the competitive Division 1, and most of them are still there today.
&lt;p&gt;But, in &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, something new happens. There's the continuing explosion of USA derby (the biggest group by far):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-12.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4656" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-12-e1433665562310.png?w=660" alt="Women's Largest Group, 2007" width="660" height="635"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
But the second biggest group, albeit only three teams, is the beginning of European derby: London Rockin' Rollers, Birmingham Blitz Dames and Stuttgart Valley Rollergirls taking their first steps onto the track:
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-2.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4657" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-2.png?w=300" alt="Women's Second Largest Group, 2007" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
(2007 is also the start of Men's Flat Track Roller Derby, with Harm City playing The Dirty Dozen for the first ever official bout.)
&lt;p&gt;By the end of 2008, the European Derby seed is beginning to grow, but they're still entirely separate from the big connected group in the USA. As well as a smattering of teams in the USA and Canada who only played one bout in 2008, there's also the beginning of Cyan on our graphs, with Adelaide Roller Derby playing Victorian Roller Derby League for the first Australian derby on the Flat Track. These are both trends that continue into the end of &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, with three entirely disconnected centres of Derby developing:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;The big USA/Canada (where you can see the tightly linked central bunch of "Division 1" teams continuing to dominate derby):
&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-13.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4658" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-13-e1433665656698.png?w=660" alt="W Group 1 - 2009" width="660" height="652"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The growing Europe (Names from FTS database, so Glasgow appear under their modern name of Glasgow Roller &lt;em&gt;Derby&lt;/em&gt;):
&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-21.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-large wp-image-4659 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-21-e1433665701389.png?w=660" alt="Group 2" width="660" height="570"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nascent Australia (so early that we have 6 teams, each of which played only one bout):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-10.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-4660 size-thumbnail aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-10.png?w=150" alt="Group 10" width="150" height="150"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-131.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone wp-image-4661 size-thumbnail aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-131.png?w=150" alt="Group 13" width="150" height="150"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-17.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-thumbnail wp-image-4662 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-17.png?w=150" alt="Group 17" width="150" height="150"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
Men's Derby has finally begun to reach a respectable size at this point, but still entirely USA based:
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-14.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4665" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-14-e1433665767740.png?w=300" alt="M Group 1 2009" width="300" height="251"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
In &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, however, two things happen of importance to the future of Roller Derby.
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, Europe finally contacts the USA, with London Rollergirls playing their first bouts across the Atlantic. Given the isolation of USA derby from the emerging European and Australasian areas, the ability of London surprises a lot of their opponents (setting a trend for both reactions to London, and reactions to non-US teams in general when visiting the USA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-110.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-large wp-image-4679 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-110.png?w=660" alt="W Group 1 2010" width="660" height="627"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
(the Green dot in the middle of the Red central dots is London, while the rest of Europe is relegated to the edge, due to lack of connections to the dense nexus of Important USA Teams). &lt;em&gt;Edit: interestingly, London A is already isolated from Europe by this point - they only played US teams in 2010. It is Rainy City who connect Europe with the USA, having played Oly Rollers B.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the very first Junior derby starts up (this is &lt;em&gt;Cleveland Firestarters&lt;/em&gt; (who were later replaced by Cleveland Junior Roller Derby) v &lt;em&gt;Indianapolis Junior Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-16.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4670" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-16.png?w=300" alt="J Group 1 2010" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Meanwhile, Australasian Derby is still developing apart from the rest of the world. Pirate City Rollers represent the first New Zealand travel team to play others, shown in purple:
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-22.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4667" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-22-e1433665837223.png?w=300" alt="W Group 2 2010" width="300" height="244"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
and a second wave of European derby is beginning, with Gent, Stockholm, Helsinki and others forming a new group of emerging teams, many of which will accelerate into importance both politically and competitively in the next few years:
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-3.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4668" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-3-e1433665858342.png?w=300" alt="W Group 3 2010" width="300" height="251"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We'll look at the trends in International Derby since the end of 2010 in our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/07/visualising-the-internationalisation-of-roller-derby-part-2-of-2-2011-to-present/"&gt;second post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in this series, where we'll also publish some links to the code used for these plots.&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>analysis</category><category>articles</category><category>flattrackstats</category><category>international</category><category>statistics</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/07/visualising-the-internationalisation-of-roller-derby-part-1-of-2/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 09:22:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>