<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about fresh meat)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/fresh-meat.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:41:32 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Scotland's newest Coed league, Inverclyde Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/06/scotlands-newest-coed-league-inverclyde-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class="_1t_p clearfix"&gt;
&lt;div class="_41ud"&gt;
&lt;div class="clearfix _o46 _3erg _29_7 direction_ltr text_align_ltr"&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;Over on the West Coast of Scotland, there's still new Roller Derby leagues coming into existence. Inverclyde Roller Derby is one such, an "open"/coed league which appeared earlier this year, growing to around 23 full time skaters, and 5 NSOs. In support of their next recruitment, on the &lt;strong&gt;12th November&lt;/strong&gt;, Greenock's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Lady+Octavia+Sports+Centre,+Bridgend+Rd,+Greenock+PA15+2JN/@55.9382189,-4.7350389,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4889ae1c210c4dff:0x82ef2152eb5cb4cb!8m2!3d55.9382386!4d-4.732828"&gt;Lady Octavia Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;3pm&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/676805075818015/"&gt;event page here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;], they've sent us this in-depth interview to give you their background. (This event is in collaboration with United Sk8s, and will also include a Roller Disco after the end of the fresh-meat recruitment).
Questions and answers here were submitted by the league themselves - the blog has merely provided editorial input.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-11023" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/inverclyde.jpg?w=1536" alt="inverclyde" width="768" height="1024"&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="clearfix _o46 _3erg _29_7 direction_ltr text_align_ltr"&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="_3oh-"&gt;When did you start? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;&lt;span class="_3oh-"&gt;Our league began on the day of our first skate, the 11th of March 2016.
We had no idea if roller derby would take off in this area, so we decided to dive in at the deep end by setting up our first skate only four weeks after deciding to start a league. It took, from the very first, "Hey! Let's start a Roller Derby League!" to "Welcome, to the 1st weekly Inverclyde Roller Derby Hunger Games!", 34 days in total; and boy what a fun-filled 34 days they were!
With just our three founders, we sourced a hall that was willing to let us skate on their precious flooring, wrote a 33 page, fully comprehensive league constitution, set up a not-for-profit league bank account and roped in a few kind and able friends to hand out flyers that we made ourselves on our mobile phones. And, after all of that, on our very first skate... just 5 people turned up.
Did that put us off? Hell nah. We're 6 months down the line with 18 regular skaters and 5 non-skating officials, loving life and tearing it up. Figuratively speaking - or our hall would kill us. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="_3oh-"&gt;Why did you decide to start a league? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;&lt;span class="_3oh-"&gt;We decided to bring roller derby to Inverclyde as we found no existing leagues close enough for us to be able to afford the commute. Having mentioned it to friends, general responses ranged from: "I have no idea what roller derby is,", "Oooo, that sounds fun," to "Aww, I wish there was a roller derby league in Inverclyde!".
Inverclyde, considered an impoverished area, has very little in the way of things like this, and it became apparent that people of Inverclyde not only wanted something new and fun, but desperately needed it. Every single one of our current skaters have praised our league as bringing something exciting and worthwhile to them personally, and to the community as a whole. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="_3oh-"&gt;What you want to achieve? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;&lt;span class="_3oh-"&gt;As a roller derby league, we aim to encourage healthy life styles, spread our love of the sport and develop our mad skills as a league in order to be up there with the best of them. On top of that, we feel like it's important to stand up and represent our local area; as a local community group we want to bring something fun and exciting, and long overdue, to the area that helps promote healthy lives, affordable fitness and a sense of community spirit and pride. We try our best to get involved with other small community groups when they need volunteers, if there are local events on we're always there to represent and we pride ourselves in being an all-inclusive safe space within Inverclyde. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="_3oh-"&gt;Who are your derby heroes? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;&lt;span class="_3oh-"&gt;Scald Eagle of the Rose City Rollers [well timed - Ed] and Trisha Smackanawa of London RollerGirls were the very first high pace, "Oh my goodness" skaters that blew our minds from the very first roller derby bout we ever watched, ever. They lit the roller derby fire in us.
Sutton and Meow You-Ow of the Royal Windsor Roller Girls come in a close second. The very lovely Meow You-Ow was the first person to teach one of our founders how to skate; Sutton skated in the very first ever roller derby bout that the early Inverclyde Roller Derby squad went to see as a league, and she rocked our world!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;&lt;span class="_3oh-"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's great about being part of a team?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;&lt;span class="_3oh-"&gt;The awesome  new friends we have made and the wonderful new people we've met - the support we all have for each other, the camaraderie we all feel on and off track; it is all amazing. Being part of a team has brought many of us out of our shells, given us all something to look forward to each week and, all in all, has been an amazing experience so far. May it long continue, with many more friends to be made.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="_3oh-"&gt;What you want to achieve going forward? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;&lt;span class="_3oh-"&gt;World domination. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="_3058 _ui9 _hh7 _s1- _52mr"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>inverclyde roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/06/scotlands-newest-coed-league-inverclyde-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 10:54:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Girls - Wanna Join?</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/22/fierce-valley-roller-girls-wanna-join/</link><dc:creator>alibonanza</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="" title="11908592_1042693805742471_2412030954146539060_o" src="http://i1.wp.com/www.fvrg.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/11908592_1042693805742471_2412030954146539060_o.jpg?resize=530%2C355" alt="11908592_1042693805742471_2412030954146539060_o" width="222" height="149"&gt;&lt;img class="" title="11888546_1042693869075798_8615470236872184543_o" src="http://i1.wp.com/www.fvrg.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/11888546_1042693869075798_8615470236872184543_o.jpg?resize=262%2C176" alt="11888546_1042693869075798_8615470236872184543_o" width="221" height="149"&gt;&lt;img class="" title="FVRG Taster Sessions" src="http://i1.wp.com/www.fvrg.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/11875044_1042689072409611_6975712594037629319_o.jpg?resize=262%2C175" alt="FVRG Taster Sessions" width="222" height="148"&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;7th August&lt;/strong&gt;, FVRG will be hosting a roller derby taster in &lt;strong&gt;Grangemouth Sports Complex&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;from 11.30 - 13.30.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Fierce Valley Roller Girls is a not-for-profit women's roller derby league within the Forth Valley area. Whilst our competitive team is women-only, we welcome all genders to be referee or non-skating members. Our training sessions and our home games are held in Grangemouth Sports Complex.
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in joining Fierce Valley Roller Girls and are aged 18 or over, please complete our Registration Form &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/join-fvrg/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Signing up as a competitive skater or as a referee?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
If you would like to register as either a skater or a referee, the taster session will give you the opportunity to learn the basics of skating (and stopping!) safely. You will be buddied up with an experienced skater who will share their wisdom - and their equipment - with you. Please bring your own mouth guard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the taster session, we will welcome you into a dedicated roller derby training programme for beginners, tailor-made and led by FVRG coaches. On completion of the beginners training, you will also attend the intermediate training, where your roller derby 'minimum skills' will be assessed. Beginner-training is held on Sunday mornings; intermediate-training is held on Wednesday nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competitive skaters will then move into the advanced training programme and have the opportunity to try out for our travel team. Advanced-training is held on Friday nights; team-training is held on Tuesday nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon completion of their intermediate training, referees will branch off into the referee training programme. It's common for referees to gain their basic training in our intermediate sessions, and then move onto officiating drills in the advanced and team sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Signing up as a non-skating member?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Not everyone in at FVRG skates, believe it or not. If you want to be part of the roller derby community but don't wish to compete of officiate, then you can join us a Non Skating Member. We're always looking for 'Non Skating Officials' (NSOs); artwork designers; photographers; bloggers - the list goes on. All we ask is that you attend at least one of our 'scrims' (internal games) per month to keep you integrated with the league and to learn the rules of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We hope to see you there !&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>#wearefierce</category><category>annoucements</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>fvrg</category><category>join roller derby</category><category>taster session</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/22/fierce-valley-roller-girls-wanna-join/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 08:57:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs taster session</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/18/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-taster-session/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs are recruiting!  Scotland's first junior roller derby league will be holding a fresh meat taster session on Sunday 24th April, from 13:30 - 14:30, in the Mariner Centre, Falkirk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4611" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg" alt="10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n" width="960" height="681"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FVRC welcomes boys and girls aged 5-17, with no previous skating experience necessary.  We can provide kit to borrow for the session, with the exception of a mouthguard and helmet, so there is no commitment.  The taster will cover basic skating skills, most importantly, how to stop and fall safely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To register your interest, or for more information, please contact freshmeat@fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/18/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-taster-session/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 10:26:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Girls taster session</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/13/fierce-valley-roller-girls-taster-session/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Thursday 21st of April, Fierce Valley Roller Girls will be hosting a taster session in Grangemouth Sports Complex, from 9pm - 10.30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7044" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/new-skater-banner.jpg" alt="New Skater banner" width="851" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The taster is designed to let new skaters try roller derby – with no commitment – to see if this is the sport for them. FVRG welcomes anyone aged 18 and over, no previous skating experience necessary.&lt;span id="more-3116"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the session, participants will be buddied up with an experienced skater to learn the basics of skating (and stopping!) safely. Buddies will also loan their equipment for the taster. At the end of the session, the coaches will provide an overview of FVRG and what they do, and will answer any questions that anyone may have about roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New skaters will then be welcomed into a dedicated training program for beginners led by FVRG coaches. Once they progress through their training, regular assessments will be held to give the opportunity to climb the ranks into Intermediate, then Advanced training sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in joining Fierce Valley Roller Girls and are aged 18 or over, please complete the &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/get-involved/join-fvrg/" target="_blank"&gt;Registration Form&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your place in this taster session.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>fvrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/13/fierce-valley-roller-girls-taster-session/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 08:14:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Start Derby in the New Year</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/03/start-derby-in-the-new-year/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a New Year, and one resolution that you might have made is to Try Roller Derby. Certainly, many leagues across the country traditionally run a fresh meat recruitment in January or early February just to take advantage of any newly enthused skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, there's a good distribution of Fresh Meat sessions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, and a bit urgent for those who want to be involved - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/750196985110434/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are holding their Fresh Meat session on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 10th January&lt;/strong&gt; - just a week away! You'll need your own skates and pads to take part, and of course GRD recommend &lt;a href="http://www.5thblockerskates.co.uk/"&gt;5th Blocker Skates&lt;/a&gt; to get you the right kit. The initial signup session will be held at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Glasgow-Club-Drumoyne/190810237616343"&gt;Glasgow Club Drumoyne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;and entry is free for the first session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up in time, Edinburgh's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1652424528374019/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are holding their Fresh Meat session a week later on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 17th January&lt;/strong&gt;. You only need to a mouthguard to attend their session, for hygiene reasons; ARRG will supply kit for the initial tryout session. The initial sesson, and all subsequent training is at the&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Jack-Kane-Sports-Centre/152896351412178"&gt; Jack Kane Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and entry to the initial session is just £5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elgin's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/168691136822816/"&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are holding a "learn to skate" session, co-hosted with Aberdeen's Granite City Roller Derby, on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 30th January&lt;/strong&gt;. As with ARRG, you'll need to bring a mouthguard, but other kit will be provided. The session will be held at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Elgin-Community-Centre/286953997983978"&gt;Elgin Community Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and entry is free. This is a &lt;em&gt;co-ed&lt;/em&gt; session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Livingston's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/636910396412245/"&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; have an extensive array of taster and meetup sessions across January and February. There's a chance to &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/551015165051330/"&gt;Meet The Skaters&lt;/a&gt; in a pub setting on &lt;strong&gt;Friday January 22nd&lt;/strong&gt;, in the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Wetherspoons/105356126214627"&gt;Wetherspoons&lt;/a&gt; in the Almondvale Centre . The actual taster session for would-be-skaters is on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday February 6th&lt;/strong&gt;, in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Blackburn-Community-Centre/298761240230260"&gt;Blackburn Community Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. NTRG request that attendees message them before the event to allow arrangements to be made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the North, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1732447053650457/"&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are holding a fresh meat/beginners session on &lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 3rd February&lt;/strong&gt;. Again, you'll need to bring a mouthguard, but some kit will be available (although you're advised to contact ICRD ahead of time with your shoe size). The initial session will be at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Hilton-Community-Centre-918990224784740/"&gt;Hilton Community Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;; we have no information in entry fees, but the session is &lt;em&gt;co-ed,&lt;/em&gt; as with Helgin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for guys who want to play Derby in the Aberdeen area, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1708084226107265/"&gt;Granite City Brawlermen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are holding their intake on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 6th February&lt;/strong&gt;. You'll probably want to bring a mouthguard, but if you contact GCB ahead of time, they can arrange a loan of the rest of the kit. The session will be held at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Aberdeen-Lads-Club-209093469130951/"&gt;Aberdeen Lads Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, there is no information on entry fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also know that several other leagues are planning intakes in the next few months; we'll keep you informed as and when those are announced!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>new town roller girls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/03/start-derby-in-the-new-year/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 10:26:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs New Skater Intake</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/24/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-new-skater-intake-2/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs are recruiting! The next new skater intake will be held on Sunday 2nd August at the Mariner Centre, Falkirk. The Cubs welcome boys and girls between the ages of 5 and 17 to be part of one of the fastest growing sports in the world. No skating experience is necessary, and kit can be borrowed for the the first session. Email freshmeat@fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk to register your interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4611 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg?w=300" alt="10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n" width="390" height="277"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs is the only junior roller derby league in Scotland and one of only a handful in the UK. From the first training session in September 2013, the league has grown to over 30 skaters over four levels, and has recently played a third public game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/24/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-new-skater-intake-2/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 10:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital City's First 2015 new skater intake</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/03/capital-citys-first-2015-new-skater-intake/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Capital City are on the look out for new members and are holding their first 2015 taster session for new skaters this month. The taster session is open to all men over the age of 18 looking to try out roller derby no experience or kit is needed as they will help to provide this for the taster session. There are two dates available for people to sign up for, which can be done via &lt;a href="http://www.capitalcityrollerderby.co.uk/"&gt;their website.&lt;/a&gt; The taster sessions will be held on Tuesday the 14th and Sunday the 19th of July at their current training venue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested head over to &lt;a href="http://www.capitalcityrollerderby.co.uk/"&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt; to find out more or sign up via their &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1kKJfK-CbIL5lB5uI09XrWCgk2IY3beMATIew9cwxHWY/viewform?fbzx=3453879700298045451"&gt;online form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/ccrdfm-july2015.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4766" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/ccrdfm-july2015.jpg?w=212" alt="Capital City new skater intake 14th and 19th of July 2015" width="420" height="594"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Capital City new skater intake 14th and 19th of July 2015&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>capital citys new skater intake</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mighty unicorns</category><category>taster session</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/03/capital-citys-first-2015-new-skater-intake/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 08:51:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs New Skater Intake</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/04/14/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-new-skater-intake/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs are recruiting! The next new skater intake will be held on Sunday 26th April 2015, at the Mariner Centre, Falkirk. FVRC welcomes girls and boys aged 5-17, with no skating experience necessary, to come along and give it a try. Email freshmeat@fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk for more information and to register your interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4611 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg?w=300" alt="10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n" width="533" height="378"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/04/14/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-new-skater-intake/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 11:37:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Girls - New Skater Intake</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/04/07/fierce-valley-roller-girls-new-skater-intake/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Sunday 19th April, Fierce Valley Roller Girls will be hosting a Fresh Meat taster session at Grangemouth Sports Complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The taster session is designed to let you try roller derby – with no commitment – to see if this is the sport for you. FVRG welcomes along men and women aged 18 and over, no previous skating experience necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/1520624_960949090583610_3770460212018297971_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4602 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/1520624_960949090583610_3770460212018297971_n.jpg?w=212" alt="1520624_960949090583610_3770460212018297971_n" width="377" height="534"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the day, you will be buddied up with an experienced skater to learn the basics of skating (and stopping!) safely. Your buddy will also loan you their equipment for the taster, so no need to buy anything just yet, except a mouthguard. At the end of the session, coaches will give you an overview of FVRG, and will answer any questions that you have about roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re hooked after this taster session, you will be welcomed into a dedicated training programme for beginners. Once you progress through your training, regular assessments will be held to give you the opportunity to climb the ranks into Intermediate, then Advanced training sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in joining Fierce Valley Roller Girls, complete the registration form here http://www.fvrg.co.uk/get-involved/join-fvrg/ to reserve a place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>fvrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/04/07/fierce-valley-roller-girls-new-skater-intake/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 08:39:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital City are on the look out for new blood</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/17/capital-citys-third-fresh-meat/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's time once again at Capital City for another fresh meat intake and they are looking for male skaters that are 18 years old or above, that are looking to try out derby. This is their third fresh meat intake and as previously they will be running two fresh meat taster sessions on consecutive weeks at their training venue in Edinburgh. One on Sunday the 28th of September the other on Sunday the 5th of October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These session's will last for an hour and there is no need for you to have your own equipment as they can provide you with some for the taster session. They will have coaches and advanced skaters on hand to help you out and give you as much advice as you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/ccrd-fm-third.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-3778" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/ccrd-fm-third.jpg?w=614" alt="ccrd-fm-third" width="614" height="227"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you are interested or know anyone who would be interested then send them over to the Facebook event pages below to find out more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday 28th of September
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/536566933142375/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/536566933142375/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday 5th October
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/149548818547374/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/149548818547374/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8VM6Z-FXUQk&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital citys new skater intake</category><category>ccrd</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>third fresh meat</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/17/capital-citys-third-fresh-meat/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 13:23:42 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>