<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about future derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/future-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:34:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Future of Derby: China</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/13/the-future-of-derby-china/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Roller derby (and especially WFTDA-rules flat track derby) has been spreading across the world in recent years, as we’ve documented on this blog, via both &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/07/visualising-the-internationalisation-of-roller-derby-part-2-of-2-2011-to-present/"&gt;analytics&lt;/a&gt;, and our &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/tag/Future-Derby/"&gt;Future Derby&lt;/a&gt; series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One area that we have yet to cover is the substantially unrepresented region of Asia. While Japan has several active roller derby leagues, and their own &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/rdjapan"&gt;umbrella organisation&lt;/a&gt;, this is thanks substantially to the presence of American Forces Overseas, who form the nucleus of those leagues, importing Roller Derby directly from the USA. As active service people tend to stay in their placement for some time, leagues like &lt;a href="http://www.kokeshirollerdolls.com/"&gt;Kokeshi Roller Dolls&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.devildogderbydames.com/"&gt;Devil Dog Derby Dames&lt;/a&gt; have a somewhat reliable core of skaters who can develop and pass on skills, despite the only slowly increasing fraction of native Japanese skaters involved. In Japan, the existence of the local RollerGame spin-off of Roller Derby also helps awareness, especially for &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TokyoRollerGirls/info?tab=page_info"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other regions of Asia, the presence of Roller Derby is much sparser - there's no evidence of roller derby in India, or the south-Asian countries, and the Republic of Korea Roller Derby league seems to have vanished from the internet. In the most populous nation on Earth, however, Chinese Roller Derby is slowly starting to build up.
We talked to the three extant Roller Derby leagues in China - Shanghai Roller Derby's &lt;a href="http://shanghairollerderby.tumblr.com/"&gt;Shang-High Rollers&lt;/a&gt; (Founders &lt;em&gt;Afronaut&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Koko Kabama&lt;/em&gt;), the first league in China from 2012; &lt;a href="http://www.beijingrollerderby.com/"&gt;Beijing Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; (Founders &lt;em&gt;Hootin' Annie&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Jay&lt;/em&gt;, Coach and long-standing member &lt;em&gt;Courtney, &lt;/em&gt;who left BRD very recently, and PR head &lt;em&gt;Izzy Pop&lt;/em&gt;) and &lt;a href="http://www.hongkongrollerderby.com/"&gt;Hong Kong Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; (League founder and President &lt;em&gt;Alison "Six" Gentry&lt;/em&gt;); both founded in 2013.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/brdlogo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4793 size-thumbnail" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/brdlogo.jpg?w=150" alt="BRDLogo" width="150" height="108"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Beijing Roller Derby Logo (by Riley Clay and Nara Yu)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/srdlogo.png"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4794 size-full" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/srdlogo.png" alt="Shang-High Rollers Logo (by Ian Mintz)" width="128" height="128"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Shang-High Rollers Logo (by Ian Mintz)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/hkrdlogo.png"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4795 size-thumbnail" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/hkrdlogo.png?w=150" alt="Hong Kong Roller Derby Logo (by )" width="150" height="81"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Hong Kong Roller Derby Logo (by Pei-Jeane Chen)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
At present, all three leagues are mostly composed of American and European expats (Beijing even have a Scottish derby connection, via ex-Granite City skater Belledefluff).
Such a high expat ration causes problems with turnover, as expats are also often highly mobile.
BRD's &lt;em&gt;Hootin' Annie&lt;/em&gt; told us that the "challenge is retention. We are mainly made up of expats and just about the time a skater is trained enough to be able to bout, it’s time for them to move. We have become a sort of farm team. We train ‘em up and send them all over the world to join other leagues."
&lt;p&gt;Shanghai’s &lt;em&gt;Afronaut&lt;/em&gt; agrees: "Shanghai life is crazy! You don't come here to do normal life things usually, you come here to work  a lot or you come here to party a lot. Most foreigners here don't stay long in the city (average 1 year) so we teach them to skate and then they're gone. The upside to that is we have ex-SHR in quite a few teams around the world. BAD girls (USA), Guadalajara (Mexico), as well as all over Europe. It's amazing!"
And &lt;em&gt;Six&lt;/em&gt; expressed the same problem from Hong Kong, "It's been a struggle to say the least, as life in HK is busy, and a lot of people are coming and going. Most of the girls we get are expats, so they might stay for a year or two, and then head back home, but we do have a stable group of girls who've been showing up since the beginning".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4792 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/brdbout.jpg?w=614" alt="BRDBout" width="614" height="345"&gt; Beijing Roller Derby demonstration bout! (Credit: NetEase)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While all recognise the importance of recruiting a more stable base of Chinese skaters into their leagues, it's hard to promote the sport in a culture where roller derby isn't really known, as &lt;em&gt;Izzy Pop&lt;/em&gt; notes. You can literally translate 'roller derby' as '轮滑德比[lúnhuá débĭ]', but that doesn't really mean much in Chinese, and "轮滑阻拦赛[lúnhuá zŭlánsài], which is more descriptive of the sport, meaning literally 'roller skating blocking competition'. The problem is that people don't know what roller derby is, so if you say either term, they still don't really know what you're talking about."
HKRD's &lt;em&gt;Six&lt;/em&gt; agrees "when recruiting, we usually say [that derby] is along the lines of rugby on wheels", a description that is familiar from European roller derby recruiting 5 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without even a shared writing system (any European can at least read the words "Roller Derby", even if they don't speak English), it is that much harder to train and advertise the sport to Chinese nationals. Even the social networks are different to those in the West and need special attention: Beijing Roller Derby are "us[ing social networks] Douban, Weixin [Latin-script branded &lt;em&gt;WeChat&lt;/em&gt;] and Weibo to help us spread the word. We also have begun work on translating our league documents into Chinese. Next up will be translating our website and other roller derby resources." This includes translating the widespread derby-specific language ("arm whip", "booty block") into natural Chinese equivalents, and even working on a translation project for the WFTDA rules themselves!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese approach to outside internet resources also causes issues - this article itself suffered some delays due to blocking of Gmail and Facebook during the communication process with the teams - which also makes viewing derby streams difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as the language barrier, there are also cultural issues, as Shanghai’s &lt;em&gt;koko kabama&lt;/em&gt; noted "The expectations of women, made by their peers and themselves are vastly different- to be single beyond your mid 20s means you are on the shelf, the traditional way means women are desperate for security and a steady, life. They certainly don't strap on skates and play a full contact sport."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby has made progress in other places where the culture is not aligned with it - see the progress of the &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/11/19/the-future-of-derby-the-middle-east/"&gt;Middle-Eastern&lt;/a&gt; leagues - but it does make the process of recruitment also a process of cultural outreach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also not to say that Roller sports in general are unknown in China, but they tend towards less aggressive expression. Shanghai Rollers’ have been "skat[ing] at the local skate places like skate parks and open areas. That way we meet the Chinese national skaters and we have quite a few friends who are on national teams like slalom and figure skating. Those artistic individual skating sports are the only ones that are big here."
While some of the great American and European skaters currently come from established speed skating backgrounds, it's potentially the case that the artistic skating background of Chinese skating could bring entirely new expression to a native roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the existence of a Roller Sports community in China, kit is hard to acquire in brick-and-mortar shops. Shanghai Rollers advise newbie skaters to look on Taobao, the Chinese eBay equivalent, and Hong Kong Roller Derby told us that the need to buy online "can discourage a lot of interested skaters as they want to try skates/gear on before buying it." This is perhaps a problem which has existed in most regions where Roller Derby is not established; most of the European skate stores were founded by Skaters who also had this problem, and wanted to solve it directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these difficulties, all three leagues are growing and promoting, with Beijing and Hong Kong particularly active on Facebook at the moment. It will be difficult, perhaps, for derby to grow fast enough in China for a National Team (of Chinese nationals) to exist by the time of the next Roller Derby World Cups [2016 for Men, 2017? for Women], but that doesn’t mean that Chinese Roller Derby isn’t making moves to enter the international stage.
At the time of writing, Beijing is listed as a tentative attendee at the first ever Asia-Pacific Derby Tournament, the Japan Open Roller Derby Tournament in 2016. However, the recurring issues with expat skater retention have caused them to have to pull out of the competition at this time. A selection of Beijing Roller Derby's skaters will still be attending in a spectating capacity, and we can hope that their attendance helps to raise the consciousness of roller derby in Asia as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>beijing</category><category>beijing roller derby</category><category>china</category><category>future derby</category><category>hong kong</category><category>hong kong roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>shang-hai rollers</category><category>shanghai</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/13/the-future-of-derby-china/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 13:26:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Future of Derby: Junior Roller Derby, Part Two</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/10/the-future-of-derby-junior-roller-derby-part-two/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the second of our interviews on the current and future state of junior roller derby in the UK, we spoke to Debz "Dread Alert" McDowall of the Doonhame Derby Dolls, currently in the process of setting up a junior league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was behind your decision to set up a junior league?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Youth &amp;amp; Community worker I could see the massive benefit that derby could bring to the life of young women, in terms of self esteem, empowerment, health and wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the actually the original reason I got involved in helping establish the Doonhame Derby Dolls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is your league aimed at? Gender, age group etc?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;League is still in its embryonic stages - we have been delivering in one of our local high schools (Maxwelltown High School) since August 2014 as part of their curriculum, targetted at the Senior Girls PE sessions which are 16-17yrs old. We aim to kick start our generic (out of school) juniors in the new year and we will be working with mainly young women / girls aged 11-17 (split into Under 13s, and then 13-17yrs). We will keep our minds open to co-ed but our focus will be on young women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What obstacles have you faced in setting up your league?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our biggest obstacle has been getting insurance, it is super expensive given that they see Derby as an extreme sport and add to that the fact we are working with under 18s, and it makes it an expensive insurance quote, even if you can actually get someone to consider insuring it. Given that we are all volunteers and need insurance as individuals it makes it costly for us as coaches / youth workers to cover this personally, as although we are working hand in hand with the Doonhame Derby Dolls the juniors side of things is being run separately so doesnt fall under their insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you received much support from your local community and the derby community?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have received tonnes of support from our local community (especially from the derby community ie local derby mums who are loving getting the chance to share some physical activity and an obsession with their daughters), we have sooo many people desperate to send their kids along once we get launched, we have had amazing support from the local Community Sport Hub Development Officer, and Active Schools Co-ordinators, and indeed from Maxwelltown High School who were eager and willing to pilot our project, and other schools are lining up locally for us to roll it out across their Senior Girls aswell now that they have seen the success of it for working with young women who dont normally participate in physical activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you do any research into interest in junior derby?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I researched the physical and mental health and the generic wellbeing outcomes for derby, and applied that to a youth work setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also researched what other leagues were out there, and the way that other junior derby clubs run with regards to health and safety etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We posted out via our social media, and consulted with young women we knew to gauge interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you affiliated to any groups/organisations, either derby related or otherwise?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are affiliated with our league (Doonhame Derby Dolls) who are in the process of being affiliated with UKRDA. And the local Sports Hub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is your overall aim for your league?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To increase the health and wellbeing, self esteem / confidence, empowerment and sense of community/belonging for local young women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide a supportive and safe space for these young women as they develop into adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where would you like to be in a year, and in 5 years?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In One Year: We would like to be running a weekly out of school session for 10-13year olds, another weekly session for 13-18 year olds, and running at least one session per week as part of one of our local schools' curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be well established, well attended, have well informed adult volunteers who are skilled and confident in their youth work as well as their derby, and be having a great time with our juniors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 5 years time: all of the above plus I would like our juniors to be a strong team who are regularly bouting, travelling the country and having a blast! :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you see as being important in the future of junior Derby in the UK?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To have a regulated body (something via UKRDA maybe?) which ensures all junior teams / leagues have robust policies and guidelines in place to ensure the safety of the juniors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A strong network of junior leagues across the country, and some way of ensuring Insurance is easy and accessible and doesnt create the barrier that it currently is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you think it's important to have a junior Derby infrastructure in the UK, i.e. For setting up tournaments etc.?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See my previous answer, yes I do!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>future derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/10/the-future-of-derby-junior-roller-derby-part-two/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 09:43:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Future of Derby: Junior Roller Derby, Part One</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/09/the-future-of-derby-junior-roller-derby-part-one/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing on the theme of the future of roller derby, we turn our attention to the rapidly expanding world of junior derby. As the junior expo game at the World Cup showed, there is a wealth of talent coming through, ready to make the transition to the adult leagues. Closer to home, more leagues throughout the UK are setting up their own juniors sessions. Tiger Bay Cubs have been skating since January 2012 and hosted the landmark first public junior derby bout in the UK. We spoke to coach Pretty Grimm about the trials of setting up and developing a junior league, and their future vision for the Cubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was behind your decision to set up a junior league?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our junior league was founded by two skaters in the adults league that had a real passion and drive for making roller derby available to juniors. One skater is a high school teacher and really believes in what roller derby can do for young adults' confidence and development. We felt as a group of individuals that roller derby helps you grow on and off the track, not only do you get to learn an awesome sport and all the physical skills within that but it also gives the opportunity for young people to develop really essential life skills such as communication, working as a team and being comfortable discussing ideas and giving feedback to peers and authority figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is your league aimed at? Gender, age group etc?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our league is aimed at any young adult between the age of 11-17. We want to be as inclusive as possible and are happy to teach people to skate safely and pass their skating minimum skills whether they progress to blocking minimum skills and eventually playing roller derby. If they decide that roller derby is not for them and they just want to skate we encourage them to still come to skate to work on their skills and have fun skating and maybe try out reffing or NSOing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What obstacles did you face in setting up your league?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of things to consider when setting up a junior league. Firstly we needed to make sure that we were following government guidelines and our coaches all have the required safety checks to work with children and young adults. We are very fortunate that we have support from our local government which includes us in a programme for young adults to try out different sports. This programme helped us ensure that we adhered to all the guidelines set out for us and gave us a regular training spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensuring that the Tiger Bay Cubs was an affordable, approachable and available league was also a struggle at first. We wanted to make sure that people could join no matter what their circumstances. We therefore offer kit hire for free and the skating sessions for free however fundraising and helping the league financially is often difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recruiting new members and having people be aware of us is and has always been a struggle. Coaches who have full time jobs as well as adult league training on top of being a junior league coach can struggle to make time in the day to get out to schools to promote the junior league. However we have goals set in place for a recruitment drive in early 2015 which will hopefully battle some of these issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you received much support from your local community and the derby community?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our junior derby community although very small is very supportive. Parents of the junior league members have always been very supportive. Some of the parents of our members have actually started playing roller derby themselves as a result. Other parents travel over an hour to get their kids to practice and we have a committee which is partly made up of parents too.
The roller derby community is always supportive of other roller derby leagues (big or small quite literally) without the support of adult roller derby players we wouldn't have such a strong league now. We have been going almost 3 years now which is incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you do any research into interest in junior derby?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something we are currently trying to work on with our local government support officer. We want to get out and see how many local schools know about us and if we can offer taster sessions during school hours to get us to increase interest and skater numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a wider scale we have a great relationship with our UKRDA reps especially Judge Redd who is the Junior Derby Director on the board of directors for the UKRDA. We work to get our juniors bouting and playing other leagues around the UK. We are currently discussing more bouting opportunities around the country so stay tuned for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you affiliated to any groups/organisations, either derby related or otherwise?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above we have a great amount of support from our local government. They are a pivotal part in the running on the junior league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What have biggest challenges been in becoming a bouting team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numbers, money and finding teams to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skater numbers can always be an issue especially when you have young adults reaching adulthood and have other commitments such as school work, part time jobs and socialising outside of school. We are very fortunate to have some very dedicated skaters in our league both old and new who have stuck with us and have helped us reach a point where we are able to start bouting publically again.
We also recently had a group of players who turned 18 which meant that they were unable to skate for the junior league any longer which left a big gap in our team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we are a community supported league we struggle with being able to fund a lot of things that we need in order to run as a league and thing such as hall hire for a bout is just too far out of our reach at the moment. We are however working very hard with our government support officer to increase numbers, training time, awareness of the sport and hopefully that will mean that our numbers will grow and we will be able to organise another home game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also try to apply for a lot of community grants to help support the league however these are in high demand from sports clubs all over South Wales. We have previously had grant funding and put that into kit to enable skaters to come to try out the sport without the financial burden of buying equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently in discussions with the UKRDA and other junior leagues about more regular junior games and hopefully working towards a junior weekend tournament which would be super exciting. So watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much difficulty have you faced in finding opponents?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding a full team of 14 to play at the moment is extremely difficult however we do not have a full team of 14 ourselves! Bouting with a full roster of a junior league is just not feasible at the moment. However as we mentioned above we are looking into how we can play other leagues with reduced numbers, logistics of travel etc and how we can bring help advance the current state of junior roller derby at this time.
Hopefully early 2015 will bring some exciting new things for junior roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is your overall aim for your league?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to be inclusive to all those who want to skate. We are happy to develop all female, all male and co-ed teams to have a strong bouting junior roller derby league. Our juniors currently train as a co-ed team and we hope with more members we can build a strong team for all three types of bouting derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to be able to play across the UK and Europe and maybe even one day play internationally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where would you like to be in a year, and in 5 years?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a league in a year's time we would like to have more bouting experience under our belt and of course work towards getting a full roster of skaters to bouting level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 5 year's time we would like to be bouting regularly and have a few tournaments under our belt maybe even one in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; What do you see as being important in the future of junior derby in the UK?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support and nourishment of junior teams. Junior roller derby helps pave the future for our adult leagues in years to come. We need support from our adult leagues, the community, parents and our local authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also important to give young adults the opportunity to learn and grow at an early age. It's very exciting to think what that could mean for not only junior derby in itself but also adult derby when junior skaters turn 18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching our junior skaters over the past three years has been awesome. Not just for their ability to skate but also to see what type of people they are becoming. Roller derby doesn't just become exercise for these skaters, similarly to the adults league it becomes part of who you are. Many of our skaters who have been with us for the three years have become amazing individuals and we need more of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you think it's important to have a junior Derby infrastructure in the UK, i.e. for setting up tournaments etc.?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion yes. Everyone involved in roller derby can agree that it is a sport that takes up a lot of time and when you are a volunteer to your adult league, junior league, your job and your family as well as trying to raise funds, awareness and find time to skate it can be very difficult to work towards the bigger picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having an infrastructure and support on a wider scale would help advance junior derby further than where we are at, at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also from a skater's perspective it is that driving force of something to work towards. If we were able to have tournaments or even more regular games it would help grow the sport and keep the current skaters we have.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>future derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/09/the-future-of-derby-junior-roller-derby-part-one/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 09:29:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Future of Derby: Central and Eastern Europe</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/21/the-future-of-derby-central-and-eastern-europe/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Roller Derby is rather well established in Western and Northern Europe, it is still spreading to the East, from the Czech Republic across to Russia. Our next Future Derby article covers the expanding Eastern edge of European derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We asked Prague Roller Derby's L))) and Semtex Sizzle, and a whole bunch of skaters from Russia's first league, St Peterburg's White Night Furies, about the experience of pushing derby out into the East of Europe. (We believe this may be the first non-Russian interview that the White Night Furies have given, so we are happy to reproduce their answers in full!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/PragueCityRD"&gt;Prague Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With derby just established in the Czech Republic with your league, do you think you'll be competing with a National Team or at that level by the next World Cup in, say 2016?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;We don't give up hope, it would be amazing to compete on international level. We hope than in few years more leagues will pop up in other czech cities or even in Prague itself and it will make possible to gather best players not only from PCRD, but from whole country. It could possibly help if other central or eastern European countries would establish new teams (like quite recently in &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/WarsawHellcatsRollerGirls/timeline?ref=page_internal"&gt;Poland&lt;/a&gt;, yay!) so we won't be anymore on the 'edge' of Europe.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What difficulties have you had with growth and promotion in the Czech Republic?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;To answer your first one, well, we still are the first and the only Czech team. We sure hope other teams will appear in Czech, as L))) says.
About the PR activities - we can't do more at the moment since we started, every single newspaper and many lifestyle magazines already covered our existence together with some expat media so we are quite satisfied with our promo.[On language issues with the WFTDA Rules] Not really, we are not perfect, of course, as non native speakers, but most of the players can at least understand English (as most of Czech young people do). Actually... while bouting other European teams we take advantage of our language as nobody can understand us!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Russia - St Peterburg's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/rollerderbyRussia"&gt;White Night Furies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think you've been working on the league + team since June last year (and there might now be a league starting in Moscow this year?) ? How did it all start, and what have the challenges been over the past year and a bit? (Are there any cultural issues with recruitment in Russia, or language issues with derby being mostly English-language?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fight Sparrow&lt;/em&gt;: First of all, we don’t have a sports hall to train in. But I think we will solve this problem. There’s also a problem with understanding foreign players, but we can solve this problem too – some of our players speak English and help us to communicate with them. Some of our players started to attend English courses and I'm going to do it too, hope it will happen very soon. The fact that it is an English-language game must stimulate us to develop ourselves. There are some difficulties with the rules, sometimes we can’t understand them, but with the help of our foreign derby-friends and our trainers' communication we will achieve our goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Generous Jane (GJ)&lt;/em&gt;: Roller derby in Russia started from only one girl who brought this game from Belgium. When she came back to Russia and found out that there is no roller derby here, she decided to change this and tell Russian people about the game. And some people (girls and boys) gathered together on the Palace square in the very center of St. Petersburg on the 22nd of May in 2013. They looked puzzled at this girl on quads who tried to heed the eccentric derby rules. They gathered together many times on the Palace Square and, as time has passed, these meetings became roller derby training (practices). The girl’s name was Katerina Rossolovich. She was the ideological inspirer, absolute leader, coach and the first captain of the first Russian roller derby team.
During our first trainings we spent much time on leveling up the basic roller skating skills, practicing the derby position and crossovers. Then one artist drew the roller derby track on the Palace square for us and it was the time to start playing, though we’ve played like kittens!
Approximately in the beginning of the autumn 2013 we confirmed the name of our team – “White Night Furies” and the logo. When the weather became cold we found a sports hall and started to train there.
In December 2013 two Australian coaches – The Flying Nun Chucker and Ruby Ribcrusher - visited us. Besides ten hours of training we got the invaluable experience, the help and world recommendations on all the private and team questions, muscles, knowledge and incredible emotions from the communication with those excellent coaches. Chuck and Ruby's arrival made a powerful incentive to the development of roller derby in Russia and gave motivation to all of us.
After the two spring Fresh Meat Days (1,2 of March 2014), the team became almost twice as big.
Many of our derby-girls from the team started visiting derby practices while travelling to Europe in the cities they've been staying at. Derby-girls and boys from different countries such as France, Norway, Sweden, the USA came to St. Petersburg to train with us and to coach us. We take part in local events, thus earning the money for the team and promoting our sport which nobody knows about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FireCracker&lt;/em&gt;: After Katerina quit Hulk Hellelujah became our captain, coach and chief. She and two girls are in our coach committee now. Now we even have a sponsor. It's a skateboard shop in Saint Petersburg. And from our trip to Finland we got a mentor-team. It’s a team from Helsinki – Kallio Rolling Rainbow. This summer they said that 99,9% of our derby questions already have answers. So now we can write them anytime and they will definitely help us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Generous Jane (JG)&lt;/em&gt;:
Difficulties.
The first difficulty is that we can't buy quads and derby gear in Russia so we had to order everything from Europe and USA without trying on. And recently the miracle happened and the last girl in our team bought quads, now we can say with a great confidence that we don’t play roller derby on inlines.
Secondly, we don't have a sports hall with the suitable floor, changing rooms and the track. It's very difficult to find such sports hall and at present we haven’t managed to find one.
Further, we are the only team in Russia – wow – that's cool, but we have nobody to play with! And this is a big minus for our karma, motivation and development.
Also, there is no roller derby federation and special medical insurance here. We're trying to solve this problem now.
We have to translate the rules and literature into Russian – this is a long and big process. Those who don’t know the language have to learn them by heart. However, learning them and reacting to them during the game play are not the same things.
This kind of sport isn't developed in our culture. While telling your friends (if only they are not from Australia) you face to such reaction: “I've never heard about it! What is it? Is it played with a ball?”.
And you have to explain as simply as possible that there is a pack, a bout, a jammer. You have to use drawings, pantomime and gestures while demonstration of the elements of the game. But not everybody has studied in a drama school, and that's why this performance, probably, is not so much attractive as it is frightened for the potential players especially when it is a question about contact, injuries, aggression. And this information vacuum makes a distance between us and those who probably were born to play roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You seem to have travelled to a &lt;em&gt;lot &lt;/em&gt;of leagues around Europe to get practices in (from Lisbon through Vienna to Finland?). Could you have grown without the big derby community in Europe? What's been the biggest help to you from the community?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fight Sparrow&lt;/em&gt;: I think that we have grown a lot during the last (2014) year. Now we are an organized and cohesive team.
The special fact is that we have visited two Finnish teams and played three scrimmages with them. Some amazing foreign coaches and players have already visited us and it helped us a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hulk Hellelujah&lt;/em&gt;: Definitely not, we couldn't have grown without support from European derby community. Undoubtedly we couldn't even have started roller derby here without this community, because the idea of creating roller derby team here, in Russia, came from Europe, after watching some roller derby stuff.
The biggest help was from a lot of people who supported us on Facebook, who wrote and came here to train us, to train with us, who hosted us in Kouvola and Helsinki for during our first scrimmages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jochans&lt;/em&gt;: This summer I was in Lisbon and trained with the local team. It was very scary at first because I didn't know what to do, how to skate even. And it at was the first time when I'd got quads on my feet.
Then I joined the fresh meat group and I realized that it doesn't matter in roller derby who you are and where you come from. Things that matter are your desire to skate and a hunger for learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How is recruitment going?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fight Sparrow&lt;/em&gt;: We don't recruit new players now. We hone our own skills. We need an extra time and place in a sports hall, and we can’t do it now, because we haven’t brought ourselves yet to the sufficient derby-standard – namely we haven’t played official bouts with teams from roller derby community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As this is for our World Cup series, can you say if a Team Russia might be a possibility some day? Maybe by the next Cup in 2016/17?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fight Sparrow&lt;/em&gt;: I believe in that! We must and we will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there any changes in derby culture you see either being needed or coming out of the spread of derby into wider locations (not just USA + Western Europe) as time goes on?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hulk Hellelujah&lt;/em&gt;: Can't tell now about any changes because the Roller Derby that we've started here is a big change in itself :) Everything is new and very exciting, so we need to be not an "isolated" part of the European community to talk about changes. The biggest change will be destroying countries' borders, but that's not a roller derby task :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>future derby</category><category>future of derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>prague roller derby</category><category>white night furies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/21/the-future-of-derby-central-and-eastern-europe/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 17:07:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Future of Derby: The Middle East</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/19/the-future-of-derby-the-middle-east/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next up in our series on the Future of Derby is another geographical region where the growth and development of the sport is pushing new boundaries: North Africa and the Middle East. Egypt's &lt;a href="http://www.cairollers.com/"&gt;CaiRollers&lt;/a&gt; swept to some fame a few years ago when they were first founded, getting attention in some major newspapers, but since then other leagues have begun emerging, in the UAE and in Lebanon...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Middle-East has, perhaps, particular challenges for Roller Derby, as it (and Asia) have less Western ideas of women and sports in popular culture. As Derby develops into a truly International sport, encountering and adapting to non-Western cultural ideals will be a key test of the sport and its leadership (as will the ability to decentralise the core of the sport itself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to all three Middle-Eastern leagues we are aware of, to find out how they see the sport developing in their region. &lt;a href="http://www.dubairollerderby.com/"&gt;Dubai Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s The Killer Purple answered questions for them, while the CaiRollers had their Nofearteti respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Roller-Derby-Beirut/763063127094159"&gt;Roller Derby Beirut&lt;/a&gt; is currently just a work in progress, and their founder provided us with the following statement: &lt;em&gt;Women of the Middle East face challenges that cannot compare in any way to the reality we know where I live, in the cold Northern Copenhagen. I've been following the amazing ladies of the CaiRollers, and the way Roller Derby enables them to claim their space in the public sphere. This is not about religion, Orientalism or naïve good-doing; it's about sharing our amazing sport and community with women around the world. It makes me happy and proud to feel the derby community reach out and help in any way they are able to; that's why Derby is so unique. I hope the ladies of Beirut will find this together whilst turning left. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[You can help Roller Derby Beirut with donations at the World Cup or otherwise via this event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/599390206837488/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/599390206837488/&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dubai:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Although Roller Derby in Dubai (and the U.A.E. in general) is young, have you considered a national team submission for the next &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;World Cup&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely. We would definitely consider submitting a National Team, and have already discussed it. The issue, however, is that few of our skaters, if any, are from Dubai/the U.A.E. This is not because we have any kind of restrictive or exclusionary policies but because of the U.A.E.’s demographics. Roughly 80% of the population is expatriate. Local women also tend to be from more protective family backgrounds. Athletic local women are certainly the exception to the rule although this is slowly changing. As it stands, the World Cup’s eligibility rules need to be modified to be able to include places like the U.A.E., Singapore, Hong Kong, Qatar, Egypt, etc. and our particular social make-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Middle-East has perhaps unique problems for the growth of derby, but some issues are common to leagues across the World. What have been your issues to date with growing and spreading derby across the U.A.E?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Possibly the primary factor that limits the growth of derby in Dubai &amp;amp; the U.A.E. is the transient nature of the population. Most people come here early on in their careers, at a time when their lives are changing rapidly, stay for a few years to benefit from the tax-free laws, and then return to their native countries to establish more permanent homes. While they’re here, they take advantage of Dubai’s proximity and ease of access to many tourist destinations, and travel frequently. This constant turnover of people, and serial absence of skaters makes it difficult to plot and monitor progress of an individual skater, and of the league. Expatriates also tend to take long breaks from work in the summer to escape the scorching, draining temperatures. This discontinuity certainly slows our progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another factor that has severely hampered our growth is the lack of infrastructure to support us. At the peak of the quad skate fashion, the U.A.E. was little more than a desert, and as such, has no old roller rinks, no old skates, no former wheely-disco-divas. What we do have is an indoor ski slope, which has that excessive appeal that Dubai prides itself on. The roller derby “story” of grassroots, female empowerment, alternative living, community driven success is not one that might appeal to decision-makers here – people that have the money, resources, and permits to build. This is Eden for big business-big government. Unless a direct monetary advantage can be leveraged, the project is dead in the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Culture probably does play a significant factor as the athletic development of girls and women is considered secondary to their moral well-being. Athletic facilities that women use are primarily built for men. We know that many derby leagues began in parking lots, etc. but try skating in 99% humidity, and 50°C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, finding a decent sports hall, with skateable flooring, has given our league a much-needed boost. With a consistent practice location and times, we’ve gained a good reputation, garnered a lot of media attention, and gotten a lot of new skaters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any hopes for development in the Derby community which would make the sport more successful in the Middle East, and Dubai in particular?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) To be perfectly honest, the only way in which we hope derby develops is in being able to include us to play in the World Cup. It could be a concern that as the sport grows, people jump on the bandwagon and beat the horses. Right now, We like that there isn’t a fat-cat commission setting rules for me to make them money. We like that derby isn’t about money. We like that we've got an international sk8rhood. We like that we’re fierce and I like that we have to fight for our right to party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Egypt (Cairollers):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The CaiRollers have been growing for about 2 years now. What challenges (and support/unexpectedly easy things) have you encountered on the way? (Are any unique to Egypt?)&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenges today remain similar to what they were when we first started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) the gear is not available in Egypt and it's not easy to get it shipped here without paying hefty fines and/or guaranteeing that something will get lost along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) Practice locations - it's difficult to find a suitable surface for us to play on, and when we do it's either too expensive. We don't have any sponsors yet and we pay for all practice venues out of dues which we try to keep to a reasonable amount so that players from all walks of life can play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) Drumming up awareness of what derby us and support and interest from women to play. In addition to which many of our founding players were expats, so in our second year we lost about 80% of the team and had to kind of start from scratch. However, we have managed to build a more local base and now the team is majority Egyptians or women who are living in Egypt for the long term, so turnover won't be as high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unexpectedly easy and awesome thing which has helped with all of the above challenges is the international support that we have received. So many teams from all over the world have supported us by talking us up, donating a ton of gear and even making financial donations to our paypal account. the amount of derby love that has come our way from ALL over the world has been overwhelming and incredible. At the end of our 1st birthday &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/video.php?v=10101801428504640&amp;amp;set=vb.320558514691079&amp;amp;type=3&amp;amp;theater"&gt;slideshow&lt;/a&gt; we had such a long list of leagues to thank and send out love to and that was an amazing thing.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Has the English-language focus of derby, especially with rules + best practice, caused any problems?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Yes, it has caused some issues in terms of teaching our own players the rules, but also in terms of drumming up interest in the game. There is no direct translation for the word Jammer in Arabic. How do we explain roller derby without being able to explain what a jammer is? [In almost all other languages, Jammer remains untranslated, or becomes something like "star" in the destination language - Ed] But we've made do. Recently we've been talking about translating our fresh meat package into Arabic. We've got parts of it translated now, but we want all the details to be available in Arabic so we can sort of be a resource for derby in Arabic.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;If there is a World Cup in 2016/17, would you consider forming a Team Egypt? (Eligibility for national teams tends to be decided by nationality, not domicile.) Have you thought about this already?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would definitely consider it but there's a lot that would go into that consideration. We don't have any sponsorship, though we've been trying to drum up some big name sponsors for a year now. We would need some serious sponsorship in order to be able to go, as many of the women on our team cannot afford to contribute much, if anything towards travel abroad. We would also like to have a couple of bootcamps and play a couple of international bouts if possible prior so that the World Cup is not our first time encountering that level of play. But as a pipe dream, it's definitely something we've talked about from time to time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;As derby grows outside the "Western" cultures of North America and Western Europe, do you see any changes either being required to grow in those new areas, or being fed back into the community from those new cultures?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
I don't think there need to be any real, fundamental changes to the game of derby in order for it to grow, but there has to be perhaps a widening in the scope of what is meant by derby culture. We've been able to adapt the 'badass' tough chick image of derby to our situation here in Egypt. We've got Egyptian women from various social classes and religious backgrounds playing together, some are veiled, some are not. When the veiled women first showed an interest in derby some of them asked if it would be possible to play with their hijab. We of course told them that there is no requirement that they wear racy clothing or have tattoos or any of these other things that they might have picked up from some of the popular media around derby (The movie Whip It is shown on a regional satellite network quite often, and I think this is where a lot of people might be getting their ideas about derby...) In any case, we've adopted a very 'come as you are' attitude here, and I think we've done a good job of reconciling the different viewpoints of our players about what derby culture is and what it should be. So I guess, that's just a long way of saying that I don't think there need to be any drastic changes to derby in order for it to grow in new areas. I think each league will sort of naturally figure out what works best for them.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>cairollers</category><category>dubai roller derby</category><category>future derby</category><category>future of derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>middle east</category><category>roller derby beirut</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/19/the-future-of-derby-the-middle-east/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 09:59:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Future of Derby: Latin America</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/17/the-future-of-derby-latin-america/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;World Cup&lt;/a&gt; approaches, our thoughts turn to how rapidly Roller Derby has spread across the world, and how far it might spread in the future. This is the start of a short series of articles looking at various aspects of roller derby, not merely the geographical, at the edge of roller derby's development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We start with a look at Roller Derby in Latin America, one of the most rapidly developing locations for Men's, Women's and Co-ed derby at the present time. While Derby had just arrived at Brasil and Argentina in 2011 in time for two inexperienced teams to fly up to Canada, in 2014 there is Roller Derby across the entire continent, and in all possible forms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We interviewed CoffinBaby of Peru's &lt;a href="https://es-la.facebook.com/ToxiclimaRD"&gt;Toxic Lima Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://es-es.facebook.com/SeleccionArgentinaRD"&gt;Team Argentina&lt;/a&gt;'s Nina Brava to learn more about how Latin American derby might develop in the &lt;em&gt;next&lt;/em&gt; few years...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toxic Lima &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peru is one of the few Latin American countries to not have submitted a team to the World Cup this year. Did you consider the possibility of competing? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, we considered the possibility but given that we are the only league in the country actually competing, and that we are a very small league with an already short roster, we preferred to wait, to grow and gain more experience. We have only had 2 Interleague games...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Given another 3 years of growth, though, Peruvian derby should develop a lot more...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes; we will consider going to the next World Cup. We plan to travel more to tournaments in South America to gain experience and to get affiliated to WFTDA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the biggest issues for Roller Derby in Latin America at the moment?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe the factors are mainly economic. The investment is very high for us because it is in dollars and we have to add the very high import taxes of our countries. Also, our governments do not invest in sport education, so we live in big cities with hardly any sport spaces. If there is a space, owners give priority to Soccer because it is so popular in Latin America.
We are (also) still waiting for WFTDA to release their official Spanish translation (we have [unofficial] translations made by Latin refs).
We are lucky that Peru is a very touristy country, so we constantly get [derby playing] visitors from all around the world (7 per year approximately) and they are always eager to show us all they can. We have our homes open to anyone wanting to visit Peru.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Given the growth of Derby across Latin America despite these issues, do you think Latin Derby will cause changes in the worldwide Derby culture?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it will. I am hoping there will soon be a South American ranking at Flat Track Stats so we can find a way to compete against each other to get up. We hope for more Latin American tournaments. We are also excited to watch our neighbour countries compete at the World Cup. We are sure they will surprise everybody! Latin america has worked so hard to overcome all our problems, especially trying to find ways to get gear: the heart and effort will be seen on the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Argentina&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, Derby was only just starting in Argentina (and Latin America in general) at the time of the first World Cup. Since then, it seems to have spread like wildfire. Why do you think it has spread so fast and effectively? Is derby particularly suited to Latin American cultures?&lt;/strong&gt;
I think the determination of our people to go further with the resources we have and despite any obstacle is the key to the success of this DIY sport in the region.
It is a very expensive sport for everybody here, but I know people that go to bed thinking, "how can I make my kneepads better with anything I have at home", lots of skaters learning about importation laws, doing the most amazing tricks on R3s. The lack of resources can do wonders for your creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WFTDA announced that they are working on a Spanish translation of the current rules. How much has the English-only nature of the rules hindered derby in Argentina? Do you have unofficial translations or other ways to work around issues?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was part of the group that translated the rules back in 2010; I also translated &lt;a href="http://www.skatemade.org/"&gt;MADE&lt;/a&gt; rules when I was about to play for &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Team-Bionic/240873955984619?sk=info&amp;amp;tab=page_info"&gt;Team Bionic&lt;/a&gt; and last year I translated the &lt;a href="http://www.teamusa.org/USA-Roller-Sports/Roller-Derby/"&gt;USARS&lt;/a&gt; set just for fun. Part of the people working on the WFTDA translation are the same people that made a very good  translation in 2012 and the process is taking forever, even though they have the job done.
We teach the &lt;em&gt;GAME&lt;/em&gt; based on unofficial translations and we ask questions in official forums or to recognized officials from any organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now that there is derby across Latin America, is there much "international" play between the different countries? Is there a distinct "Latin Derby" culture that differs from "USA Derby", or is derby the same everywhere?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of international play in Latin America; I just got back from the first ever derby tournament in Chile with participants from Perú, Argentina and all the regions in Chile.
Argentinean and Chilean teams get together at least twice a year to play.
Last year we had the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RLS9OZZ9yy0"&gt;Latinoamericano de Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; in Columbia with teams from Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Colombia and Mexico.
And after that, we had the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/brasileiraorollerderby"&gt;Brasileirao de Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; with skaters and refs from the whole continent
I'm very excited to see all my friends from Latin America at World Cup in a couple of weeks because: yes! Derby culture it's the same everywhere!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="im"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The next big step for Latin America would be to get a team to the WFTDA D2 or D1 playoffs... Is that a thing that Argentina leagues have as a goal in their minds?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next big step will be to create our own regional Coed Organization. Some leagues have the plan of getting to those [WFTDA] tournaments but due to the structure of WFTDA it is impossible for incredibly talented teams to compete [as they are often Co-ed, or can't travel to all the playoffs]. I've been to WFTDA champs and I watch as much as I can and let me tell you, a lot of teams from Latin America can beat many of the D1 teams. We are just too far away and too poor for the model but we are taking our National teams now to World Cup to show the world what we have been working on the past 3 years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>future derby</category><category>future of derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>team argentina</category><category>toxic lima roller derby</category><category>world derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/17/the-future-of-derby-latin-america/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 17:01:33 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>