<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about fvrc)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/fvrc.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:21 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs needs you!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/04/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-needs-you/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in being involved in the future of roller derby in Scotland? Now’s your chance; Fierce Valley Roller Cubs is looking for guest coaches from the wider world of Scottish roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-1833 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/10/cubs.jpg" alt="cubs" width="291" height="288"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based in Falkirk and training every Sunday, Fierce Valley Roller Cubs is open to all between the ages of 5 and 17, and currently has a range of skaters from beginners to advanced level. Cubs skaters have taken part in several intraleague games, the first of their kind in Scotland, and last year crossed the border to take part in their first external game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4611 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg" alt="10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n" width="530" height="376"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you could spare a couple of hours to share your knowledge and skills with the next generation of derby players and help take Fierce Valley Roller Cubs to the next level, please get in touch for more information: cubs@fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs was the first junior roller derby league in Scotland, and began training in September 2013.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/04/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-needs-you/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 10:47:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cubs Take On New Opposition</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/07/cubs-take-on-new-opposition/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In September, Fierce Valley Roller Cubs celebrated their third birthday, and on Sunday October 9th, they will play their first game against other junior skaters. This mixed junior game will take place as part of a triple header hosted by Barnsley Black Heart Rollers and will feature skaters from Sheffield Steel Junior Rollers and Newcastle Junior Roller Derby League.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9210" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/13880228_1012374508875985_648255813429450617_n.jpg" alt="13880228_1012374508875985_648255813429450617_n" width="784" height="295"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cubs will be sending thirteen level 3 and advanced skaters to take part, some of whom will be playing in public for the first time, while others are veterans of several intraleagues. Needless to say, the level of excitement is high and the bus journey to Barnsley at 6.30am on Sunday promises to be a lively one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last word (as always), goes to the Cubs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s great to finally play against people that aren't in our own team. As good as it is to have bouts amongst our own team this bout against a different team gives a chance to see how well we are progressing. I'm really excited for the road trip and can't wait to get out on track” – Vanilla Crush.
“I am really happy and excited that we are getting to meet another junior team and play against them” – Lu Dog Millionaire.
“It’s not often that I see 6.30am at the weekend, the long journey will be worth it though, are we there yet?” – Purple Punisher.
“I am super chuffed to be captaining our first away game, it will be an eye opener for all involved I am sure” – Stunami.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Facebook event page can be found &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/583974361781762/"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;  Further information about Fierce Valley Roller Cubs is available &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/fiercevalleyrollercubs/?fref=ts"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/07/cubs-take-on-new-opposition/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 10:13:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs taster session</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/18/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-taster-session/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs are recruiting!  Scotland's first junior roller derby league will be holding a fresh meat taster session on Sunday 24th April, from 13:30 - 14:30, in the Mariner Centre, Falkirk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4611" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg" alt="10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n" width="960" height="681"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FVRC welcomes boys and girls aged 5-17, with no previous skating experience necessary.  We can provide kit to borrow for the session, with the exception of a mouthguard and helmet, so there is no commitment.  The taster will cover basic skating skills, most importantly, how to stop and fall safely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To register your interest, or for more information, please contact freshmeat@fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/18/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-taster-session/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 10:26:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs - Review of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/23/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-review-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following on from a year of firsts in 2014, 2015 proved to be another busy year for Fierce Valley Roller Cubs.
With three fresh meat intakes throughout the year, skater numbers have grown to around thirty 5-17 year olds regularly attending training, across three skill levels. We have retained a large number of skaters from our first few intakes, meaning that at the moment, the majority of our members are level three skaters, although a successful taster session at the start of December should help to boost numbers in levels one and two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/cubs2.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5271"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-5271 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/cubs2.jpg?w=300" alt="cubs2" width="420" height="280"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
This year, Fierce Valley Roller Cubs were invited by three different leagues – Bairn City Rollers, Dundee Roller Girls and Fierce Valley Roller Girls – to take part in double headers. The game in Dundee marked the first time the Cubs played away from Grangemouth – the Cubs word is spreading far and wide! Several newer skaters played for the first time in public at one of these games this year, and all loved the experience. From a coaching point of view, it’s always satisfying to see everything we work on in training come together in a game.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/cubs1.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5270"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-5270" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/cubs1.jpg?w=300" alt="cubs1" width="348" height="232"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year also saw some changes to the way we structure our training, due to a change in the JRDA minimum skills, which brought them almost in line with WFTDA’s mins. This meant that our advanced skaters, i.e. those that had passed the “old” level three, had to work towards the new skills. Despite a step up in skill level and difficulty, all of our skaters worked hard and we already have quite a number who have passed the new level three.
For 2016, our goal is to play against another junior team, which has proved difficult so far due to the lack of other juniors. Fierce Valley Roller Cubs is almost unique in being both co-ed and open to kids as young as five, with most others being either female only, aimed at teenagers, or both. We are ever hopeful that the growth in junior roller derby will produce plenty of opponents for us!
The last words go to a Cub, Hayley:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long have you been part of Cubs, and why did you get involved?&lt;/strong&gt;
I've been involved with the Cubs for just over a year now. Like many I first found out about roller derby after watching Whip It, and I quickly became obsessed with the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point the Cubs were still in the process of setting up and I went to see my first game in Edinburgh, which made me want to play even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended missing the Cubs starting as i was busy with school and the idea of playing derby slipped my mind, until my dad suggested I see if a junior team had started yet. I then found out that the Cubs had started up and were the only junior team in Scotland, and that they were holding a freshmeat intake in the next couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was really nervous about joining, despite having bought skates a few years back when I had first found derby and getting a bit of practice in. At the taster session I fell and ended up having to get carried out by my dad and I went to the hospital the next day, thankfully nothing was broken (I did however end up with biggest bruise of my life), and from then on I was absolutely hooked on derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has your involvement in Cubs changed this year?&lt;/strong&gt;
This year I have been helping out at the Sunday sessions for level 1 and 2 skaters as an on skates helper. In doing so my own skating skills have improved, as I've been able to spend more time on skates, but I've also been able to see our fresh meat getting better and more confident at skating and help them develop into great skaters. I've been able to use this volunteer experience to help with my university application and I'm incredibly grateful to all the coaches at the Cubs for this, as skating has given me skills that I can use in other aspects of my life, such as perseverance and commitment, as well as strengthening my confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was your biggest achievement this year?&lt;/strong&gt;
My biggest achievement has been passing level 3 for the second time, after the requirements were changed to be closer to WFTDA's minimum skills, which included the dreaded 27 laps in 5 minutes. When I first started skating I thought there was no way I could ever skate that fast or be able to do things like transitions and backwards skating. This year I've really seen myself improve, going from fresh meat at the end of 2014 to advanced now. I've also played in two games this year, including my first game ever, which were also a big achievement. Although both times my team lost, it was amazing to see everyone working together and trying their absolute hardest, no matter what position they were playing. I'm sure anyone that was in attendance will say our last game of the year was an incredibly tense and well fought game, with a lead change of 2 points in the last jam!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/cubs3.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5272"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-5272 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/cubs3.jpg?w=300" alt="cubs3" width="357" height="238"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hayley jamming in her first game&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And what was the most memorable thing you did as part of Cubs?&lt;/strong&gt;
Taking part in my first ever game has to be the most memorable and terrifying thing I've done with the Cubs. I was so nervous before and couldn't imagine myself jamming and definitely not getting lead jammer and picking up points for the team. Although I was shaking before I felt great afterwards. I was incredibly proud of myself and my team for working so hard. I was also proud of the skaters on the other team for putting up such a good fight and playing so well. The second game I played in this year was also memorable as I could see just how much myself and the other skaters had improved in only a few months, as I found that we were playing together as a team much better, by playing offensively to help our jammers and using techniques such as star passes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would you like to see in 2016 for FVRC?&lt;/strong&gt;
Unfortunately I won't be with the Cubs for all of 2016 as I'll be turning 18, but I would love to see the Cubs playing other junior teams and continuing to grow in numbers and talent. As there are more junior derby teams starting up in the uk I think 2016 will be a great year for the Cubs to hopefully get to show off all the hard work that the skaters and coaches have put in. I hope that even once I've left I'll be able to come back and support the Cubs, and see the young skaters I've trained with continue to get better and better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All photos courtesy of Laura MacDonald.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>interviews</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/23/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-review-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 09:35:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs New Skater Intake</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/24/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-new-skater-intake-2/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs are recruiting! The next new skater intake will be held on Sunday 2nd August at the Mariner Centre, Falkirk. The Cubs welcome boys and girls between the ages of 5 and 17 to be part of one of the fastest growing sports in the world. No skating experience is necessary, and kit can be borrowed for the the first session. Email freshmeat@fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk to register your interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4611 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg?w=300" alt="10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n" width="390" height="277"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs is the only junior roller derby league in Scotland and one of only a handful in the UK. From the first training session in September 2013, the league has grown to over 30 skaters over four levels, and has recently played a third public game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/24/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-new-skater-intake-2/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 10:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs : One Year On</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/31/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-one-year-on/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, 1st September 2013, a little bit of Scottish roller derby history was made, when the first Fierce Valley Roller Cubs, and first junior derby, training session took place. A year has passed, and many more firsts have been achieved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/cubstaster.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3650" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/cubstaster.jpg?w=300" alt="cubstaster" width="300" height="199"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the official start date was September 2013, the history of the Cubs actually stretches back much further, to around November 2011. A number of obstacles, not least funding, had to be overcome before getting our first intake of kids on skates, but when it finally happened, we were overwhelmed by the level of interest and support that we attracted. Our first two taster sessions were very well attended and a large number of those first Cubs are still with us today. It was as steep a learning curve for the coaches as for the Cubs themselves, working towards JRDA skills and assessments and figuring out how to adapt training plans to suit juniors. As word spread and interest grew, and many of our first batch of recruits passed their level one assessments, we were able to hold another taste session before Christmas and start a new intake in January.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the Cubs kept progressing, passing their level two assessments, it became clear that the four training sessions every Sunday wouldn’t be enough for our growing numbers and increasing skill levels, so a third session, on Friday evenings, was introduced for level three skaters. This session focuses on learning derby as opposed to skating skills, and has proven very popular. More recently, we've stopped splitting level one and two into juniors and seniors so all of our skaters, regardless of age, train together from the beginning.&lt;br&gt; As well as increasing numbers of kids taking part - we had further intakes at Easter and in the summer, we also have a dedicated parents' committee who organise fundraising and social events for the Cubs, the first of which was a successful Easter family fun day. It's great to know that we have a reliable group of supportive parents who are willing to help out in lots of different ways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the highlights of the first year was being asked to take part in a demonstration scrimmage at half time at an ARRG bout in May. It was a fantastic experience for those who took part to skate at Meadowbank in front of a crowd, and also to meet the skaters afterwards. We're grateful to everyone involved for letting the Cubs be part of the day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The biggest event in the past year has been, without a doubt, their first public game, which was also the first ever public junior roller derby game played in Scotland. We held a four day summer school in the run up to the game, to finalise those skills and tactics, with guest coaches from FVRG and PoS. We had a great turnout for the day itself and the kids thoroughly enjoyed themselves, showing what they can do. It was fantastic to see the support from the wider derby community and a proud moment for the coaches to see everything coming together on track.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/cubsbout.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3651" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/cubsbout.jpg?w=300" alt="cubsbout" width="300" height="126"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking back, it's hard to believe that a year has passed since the first Cubs session, but at the same time, it's difficult to remember a time that the Cubs didn't exist! The past year hasn't been without its challenges but the overwhelming success of the Cubs makes it worthwhile. As coaches, we have learned so much, and we are very lucky to have such a fantastic group of kids to work with. We currently have over forty skaters over three different levels , and each one of them impresses us with their hard work, determination and enthusiasm every time they put on their skaters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what's next for Fierce Valley Roller Cubs? We're planning another intake before the end of the year, and - exclusive - their second game. We can't wait to see where the next year will take us!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Photos courtesy of Claire Brunton of Zenspirations Photography.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/31/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-one-year-on/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 18:09:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs make Derby History!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/15/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-make-derby-history/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of first last weekend, from Gotham coming to the UK, through Dundee's debut of their B-team... but perhaps the most important event for the future of Scottish Derby occurred at Grangemouth Sports Centre on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After considerable hard work, from both the coaches and organisers, the skaters themselves (and encouragement from parents), Scotland's only Junior Roller Derby league, &lt;a href="http://www.fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs&lt;/a&gt;, held their first ever public bout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/10491187_665792883505850_5377019356439535080_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3540" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/10491187_665792883505850_5377019356439535080_n.jpg?w=660" alt="The Cubs, and Friends (Photo: Laura MacDonald)" width="660" height="440"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Cubs, and Friends (Photo: Laura MacDonald)&lt;p&gt;After a hard-fought game, with Team White taking and holding an early lead through to the end, despite continual resistance from Team Black, the bout ended &lt;strong&gt;White 219:168 Black&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We asked the Captains of both teams (Bon Jodie for Team White, and Purple Punisher for Team Black) to give us their own words about the bout experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bon Jodie&lt;/strong&gt;: I'm 'Bon Jodie' and I had the honour of captaining one team in Fierce Valley Roller Cubs' first public intraleague bout. To captain was an exhilarating experience and to bout for the first time was phenomenal. I was more nervous about bouting for the first time than captaining my team, but I did feel a responsibility from the start to make sure that everyone's spirits were high and they weren't too nervous and were enjoying themselves. Even though in the upcoming days I was extremely conflicted about my feelings towards my bout the second the first whistle blew the nerves were replaced by what I can only describe as determination and adrenaline rush combined. I was very proud of my team, and the other team as we all did so well, afterwards I won MVP during the awards and I was completely overjoyed, overall it was an amazing day I hope to experience again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purple Punisher&lt;/strong&gt;: The bout was meant to be fun and it was just that! Being involved and being captain for the first junior roller derby bout in Scotland was extremely nerve wracking because there was nothing to live up to, we were setting the example. We learnt so much from the bout and the crowd really helped settle the nerves. We made history and being captain was amazing!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bout awards were:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Jammer&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Arch Enemy&lt;/em&gt; (Team White), &lt;em&gt;Haylstone&lt;/em&gt; (Team Black)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Blocker&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Teeny Bash&lt;/em&gt; (Team White), &lt;em&gt;Crimson Crusader&lt;/em&gt; (Team Black)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MVP&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Bon Jodie&lt;/em&gt; (Team White), &lt;em&gt;Stunaimi&lt;/em&gt; (Team Black)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>interviews</category><category>intraleague</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/15/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-make-derby-history/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 19:44:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs Summer School</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/06/17/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-summer-school/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs have enjoyed a very busy and successful time since their launch in September, and are marking this by holding their first ever Summer School.  Running from the 7th to 11th July in the Mariner Centre, Falkirk, each day will focus on a different level, for both new and current skaters, with the option to attend one or more session.  Skaters can look forward to learning lots of new skills, some special guest coaches, and a trip to Blair Drummond Safari Park to finish off the week.  More exciting than that, Saturday the 12th will see the Cubs' first ever public game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/06/summer-school.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/06/summer-school.jpg?w=614" alt="summer school" width="614" height="868" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-3499"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email cubs@fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk to book or for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/06/17/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-summer-school/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 08:36:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs are recruiting!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/06/17/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-are-recruiting/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs are excited to announce their fourth intake of new skaters!  Open to girls and boys aged between 5 and 17, the taster session will take place on Sunday 29th June in the Mariner Centre, Falkirk.  Email freshmeat@fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk for more details.
&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/06/fresh-meat-june-2014-page-001.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/06/fresh-meat-june-2014-page-001.jpg?w=614" alt="fresh meat June 2014-page-001" width="614" height="868" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-3493"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/06/17/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-are-recruiting/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 08:25:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Review 2014: Fierce Valley Roller Cubs</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/20/derby-review-2014-fierce-valley-roller-cubs/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Latest in a series of year review interviews, we catch up with Crash Overload, Vice Chair and Head Coach of the Fierce Valley Roller Cubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/trial3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/trial3.jpg" alt="Photography by Zenspirations Photography" width="614" height="409" class="size-full wp-image-2932"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photography by Zenspirations Photography&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's been a busy year for the Fierce Valley Roller Cubs,from raising awareness and funds with events to running your first trial sessions. What have been the highs, and lows, of the past year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These last six months have definitely been a rollercoaster.  The highs include seeing the interest in roller derby from local children and watching them progress from their fresh meat taster session in September to taking on their Level 1 training and for many of them passing this assessment and progressing on to the next level of training.  The cubs are so enthusiastic and its fantastic to see them coming along to bouts to support their local roller derby teams as well as fully taking on the challenges that roller derby brings. 
We have since taken in another new batch of skaters in January and we are all enjoying watching our league expand and grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, we haven't seen many lows this year and the cubs committee and coaches all work hard to communicate and take the league forward with the interests of the skaters in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The idea to run a Junior League goes back a little further than the past year, first considered in 2011, it's fair to say it's taken longer than you might have liked to get to where you are now. What does it mean to to have The Cubs up and running for those who have been part of that long process?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's true that it's taken a long time to get the Cubs off the ground, the idea was first born in 2011 as a committee of FVRG, but due to a number of factors - mainly money - we couldn't get past the idea stage for a while.   When things really started to happen, around summer 2013, everything happened really quickly and it's not an exaggeration to say that we haven't stopped since then.  For those that have been involved from the start, it's still hard to believe how far we've come in a short period of time.  Looking at our current groups of skaters and seeing the interest in the Cubs continue to grow, it's more than we ever hoped for.  Delighted is probably the word to use, not to mention proud!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fierce Valley Roller Cubs are currently the only Junior league in Scotland, and one of a handful in the UK, have you had any help and advice from the other Junior Leagues in the country?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have taken advice from the JRDA website on training and assessments and are part of a page on Facebook for junior derby coaches to chat and swap advice and ideas.  Our coaches all have differing levels of experience of coaching adults and children and with the combined experience we have, we are moving steadily forward.  We have been making contact with other junior leagues in the hope that when our league are ready - we will have teams to play against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are some differences between the Junior Roller Derby ruleset and it's WFTDA parent, which must influence training and teaching methods. What challenges did you face in adapting an adult Fresh Meat session to work with younger skaters?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, in building the teaching plans, we looked at the skillset required and started creating plans designed for children of varying ages - our league starts at age 5 - and abilities.  The skillset required is almost the same as the WFTDA skillset so the basics are the same, its just the methods of teaching that differ.  We spend time talking through things with the cubs, explaining in language they will understand and try to make each drill fun but at the same time encourage practise and repetition in order to get better at the skill in order to move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We play games and run team building events to allow the cubs to talk and get to know each other, as there is not much time for that during a training session.  We also encourage the cubs to attend roller derby bouts run by local adult leagues to allow their understanding of the game and the rules to develop.  We have run a demo scrim for the Level 1 skaters using local adult skaters and refs to show penalties, walls, blocking and jamming skills which all helps to develop the cubs enthusiasm and confidence in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first sessions were held at the beginning of September 2013 and proved very successful, were you surprised at how readily the Cubs soaked up information and skills?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think all of the coaches have been amazed at how quickly the cubs pick up skills and how determined they are - when they fall they just bounce back up and get on with it!  They ask great questions and the rapport between the cubs themselves and between the cubs and the coaches is building and we can see the start of a strong league developing.  The cubs are already talking about being jammers and pivots, getting excited at the prospect of one day starting to bout as a team and its very encouraging for us to see and hear this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We're all familiar with the Roller Derby saved my soul story and how the sport has positively affected many of it's participants. How do you think Derby will impact on these young skaters?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have already seen the impact on some of the cubs, going from being shy and quiet to more confident young individuals.  They are increasing their strength and stamina and are overall positive in their outlook and in their perception of the sport.  They are all developing strong friendships with each other and have found role models in some of the adult skaters and coaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the cubs come along to a bout, we encourage them to come and speak to the skaters and you can see the excitement and awe in their faces.  Some of our older cubs come along to the junior sessions and take the role of mentors for the younger cubs and we encourage them to develop their coaching and mentoring skills which in turn helps with their confidence and increases their commitment to the league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And its not just the children who are impacted by roller derby, many of the adults who have not been involved in the sport before are now attending bouts, not to mention the parents who have signed up for taster sessions themselves as they are keen to try it.  We also have family groups who are now buying skates and spending time as a family skating outdoors or at roller discos so its fantastic to see how the sport can have an effect on an entire family!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lastly,can you tell us what your plans are for The Cubs in the coming year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well right now we are about to move in to another round of assessments and judging by recent training sessions, many of the cubs are looking good to get through this challenge.  JRDA have three skill levels for juniors and by the summer we are hoping to have skaters who will have passed all three levels and can move into advanced training and start working seriously on drills and look towards creating a bouting team.  We have another fresh meat session planned for a new intake of skaters at Easter too.
We are increasing the number of training sessions to accommodate the number of skaters at the different levels and because we also have an age split - 5 to 10 and 11 to 17 - this means double the amount of sessions required at each level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also looking to run another fundraising event in the very near future and hope to host a junior roller derby summer school for skaters of all levels.  So all in all, its been a busy but awesome year so far and all I can say is - onwards and upwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luv n shoves
Crash Overload&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fvrc</category><category>fvrg</category><category>interviews</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/20/derby-review-2014-fierce-valley-roller-cubs/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 22:09:36 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>