<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about fvrg)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/fvrg.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 11:56:24 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Girls - Wanna Join?</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/22/fierce-valley-roller-girls-wanna-join/</link><dc:creator>alibonanza</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="" title="11908592_1042693805742471_2412030954146539060_o" src="http://i1.wp.com/www.fvrg.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/11908592_1042693805742471_2412030954146539060_o.jpg?resize=530%2C355" alt="11908592_1042693805742471_2412030954146539060_o" width="222" height="149"&gt;&lt;img class="" title="11888546_1042693869075798_8615470236872184543_o" src="http://i1.wp.com/www.fvrg.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/11888546_1042693869075798_8615470236872184543_o.jpg?resize=262%2C176" alt="11888546_1042693869075798_8615470236872184543_o" width="221" height="149"&gt;&lt;img class="" title="FVRG Taster Sessions" src="http://i1.wp.com/www.fvrg.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/11875044_1042689072409611_6975712594037629319_o.jpg?resize=262%2C175" alt="FVRG Taster Sessions" width="222" height="148"&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;7th August&lt;/strong&gt;, FVRG will be hosting a roller derby taster in &lt;strong&gt;Grangemouth Sports Complex&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;from 11.30 - 13.30.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Fierce Valley Roller Girls is a not-for-profit women's roller derby league within the Forth Valley area. Whilst our competitive team is women-only, we welcome all genders to be referee or non-skating members. Our training sessions and our home games are held in Grangemouth Sports Complex.
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in joining Fierce Valley Roller Girls and are aged 18 or over, please complete our Registration Form &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/join-fvrg/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Signing up as a competitive skater or as a referee?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
If you would like to register as either a skater or a referee, the taster session will give you the opportunity to learn the basics of skating (and stopping!) safely. You will be buddied up with an experienced skater who will share their wisdom - and their equipment - with you. Please bring your own mouth guard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the taster session, we will welcome you into a dedicated roller derby training programme for beginners, tailor-made and led by FVRG coaches. On completion of the beginners training, you will also attend the intermediate training, where your roller derby 'minimum skills' will be assessed. Beginner-training is held on Sunday mornings; intermediate-training is held on Wednesday nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competitive skaters will then move into the advanced training programme and have the opportunity to try out for our travel team. Advanced-training is held on Friday nights; team-training is held on Tuesday nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon completion of their intermediate training, referees will branch off into the referee training programme. It's common for referees to gain their basic training in our intermediate sessions, and then move onto officiating drills in the advanced and team sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Signing up as a non-skating member?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Not everyone in at FVRG skates, believe it or not. If you want to be part of the roller derby community but don't wish to compete of officiate, then you can join us a Non Skating Member. We're always looking for 'Non Skating Officials' (NSOs); artwork designers; photographers; bloggers - the list goes on. All we ask is that you attend at least one of our 'scrims' (internal games) per month to keep you integrated with the league and to learn the rules of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We hope to see you there !&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>#wearefierce</category><category>annoucements</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>fvrg</category><category>join roller derby</category><category>taster session</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/22/fierce-valley-roller-girls-wanna-join/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 08:57:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>June 11th's Packed Scottish Derby Schedule...</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The weekend of the 11th is another extravaganza for high level Scottish Roller Derby, with both Auld Reekie Roller Girls and Glasgow Roller Derby engaged in multiple bouts across the weekend, and Fierce Valley playing away in the continuing British Champs Tier 3 North fixtures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Glasgow and Fierce Valley playing away, the Scottish home games are happening at Auld Reekie's traditional venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Meadowbank+Sports+Centre/@55.956622,-3.1585026,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4887b86eb150070f:0x6955a8c9b9a10cc5!8m2!3d55.956619!4d-3.1563086"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, doors open at &lt;strong&gt;2:20pm Saturday 11th&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-7441" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13235130_10156950736565224_2994993262049877442_o.jpg?w=1024" alt="13235130_10156950736565224_2994993262049877442_o" width="1024" height="385"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heading up &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/350352705088707/"&gt;the double-header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Auld Reekie's All-Stars are taking on Kallio Rolling Rainbow, one of Finland's finest teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After their usual impressive performance at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-big-o-2016-schedule-timezones/"&gt;The Big O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Oregon, Auld Reekie are riding high, ready for another challenge - Kallio are slightly higher ranked than they are (FlatTrackStats &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/79684/rankings"&gt;predicts a win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the Finns, albeit with some uncertainty). This will be a WFTDA Sanctioned bout and contribute to both teams' rankings, so it will be an especially hard-fought contest, as both teams will want to reach Division 1 (or remain in Division 2) of the WFTDA Rankings in order to qualify for Playoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other bout is no less exciting in its own way, marking the debut of ARRG's new 'C'-team, the 'All-Star Rookies'&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/#sup"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as they take on Granite City Roller Girls B, the Fight Hawks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, with a team debut, it's hard to make predictions as to the result of the bout; this will be a contest between Auld Reekie's new skater training and the experience gained by the Fight Hawks over the last year. (Having seen some of ARRG's rookies in "rising stars" bouts in the last few months, however, there's some very impressive performers there...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets on the door will be £8 (just £4 per bout), or £5 online via &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2553305"&gt;BrownPaperTickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Concessions tickets will be just £6 on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Glasgow Roller Derby are apparently the stars of the show down in Oldham, as Rainy City Roller Derby are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://rainycityrollerderby.com/event/euro-weekender/"&gt;hosting a weekend of derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, in which Glasgow feature in 3 out of 4 bouts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a Scotland versus Wales playoff, Glasgow's A team, the Irn Bruisers, will be taking on Tiger Bay Brawlers' A; and their B team, the Maiden Grrders will also be facing off against TBB's B-Bombs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FlatTrackStats predicts an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/7953/7929"&gt;incredibly closely-matched bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; between the A-teams (the result depends on which team you give "home-team advantage" to). The B-teams are almost as close in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/10262/11067"&gt;FTS's predictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, although it looks like their stats very narrowly favour the Welsh team (albeit by only a few percent). With only one exception, match-ups between GRD and TBB have been hard-fought, high-level affairs, so we do anticipate some great derby here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Rainy City Roller Derby are scheduled against simply "Glasgow Roller Derby", which we might guess is the A team... Last time they faced each other, Glasgow came out with a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/59869"&gt;convincing win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;; but Glasgow's significant team changes this year have FTS &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/10262/11067"&gt;predicting a win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the home team this time around. Glasgow will have to pull out something special to keep the win record on their side...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the rankings of Tiger Bay Brawlers A, and Rainy City Roller Derby, these bouts also fill in a chunk of the higher-level UK matchups missing from British Champs this year. With the results from these games, we'll be publishing an "extended" BC Tier 1 ranking, extrapolating where some of the teams not competing in T1 might have ended up, this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[On the Sunday, Kallio Roller Derby are also featuring in this derby weekend, so presumably there's some exciting train travel in Kallio's Sunday morning schedule...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://britishchamps.com"&gt;British Champs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, after an extended period &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/17/british-champs-at-dundee/"&gt;hosted in Scotland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the Tier 3 North fixtures continue in the North of England, with Hallam Hellcats hosting a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/587023974805101/"&gt;double-header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of bouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7445" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13267947_1010255862421996_6895825634478283487_n.jpg" alt="13267947_1010255862421996_6895825634478283487_n" width="530" height="750"&gt; Hallam's bout poster was also available as a limited edition physical print! (Design by Ed Syder) &lt;a href="http://edsyder.tumblr.com/"&gt;http://edsyder.tumblr.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hosts will be taking on Preston Roller Girls, while Scotland will be represented by Fierce Valley Roller Girls taking on Manchester Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FVRG will be hard pressed to defeat currently unbeaten Manchester, but a loss will keep them at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/womens-tables-2016/"&gt;bottom of the table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and in danger of relegation. Meanwhile, Hallam and Preston will be fighting it out to avoid the second-from-bottom spot in the table - there's not much to call between them, but FTS believes that home-team advantage gives the hosts &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/25963/8972"&gt;a slight edge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="sup"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;the Auld Reekie current team naming scheme is a bit confusing - the A team are simply "All-Stars", whilst the B team append "Reserves" and the C team "Rookies". This makes it a bit hard to unambiguously form acronyms for the two, but we're working on this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>auldreekierollergirls</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>fvrg</category><category>gcrd</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>hallam hellcats roller derby</category><category>kallio rolling rainbow</category><category>manchester roller derby</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 11:04:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Girls taster session</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/13/fierce-valley-roller-girls-taster-session/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Thursday 21st of April, Fierce Valley Roller Girls will be hosting a taster session in Grangemouth Sports Complex, from 9pm - 10.30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7044" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/new-skater-banner.jpg" alt="New Skater banner" width="851" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The taster is designed to let new skaters try roller derby – with no commitment – to see if this is the sport for them. FVRG welcomes anyone aged 18 and over, no previous skating experience necessary.&lt;span id="more-3116"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the session, participants will be buddied up with an experienced skater to learn the basics of skating (and stopping!) safely. Buddies will also loan their equipment for the taster. At the end of the session, the coaches will provide an overview of FVRG and what they do, and will answer any questions that anyone may have about roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New skaters will then be welcomed into a dedicated training program for beginners led by FVRG coaches. Once they progress through their training, regular assessments will be held to give the opportunity to climb the ranks into Intermediate, then Advanced training sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in joining Fierce Valley Roller Girls and are aged 18 or over, please complete the &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/get-involved/join-fvrg/" target="_blank"&gt;Registration Form&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your place in this taster session.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>fvrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/13/fierce-valley-roller-girls-taster-session/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 08:14:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>International Roller Derby in the Forth Valley!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/23/international-roller-derby-in-the-forth-valley/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 9th of April, Fierce Valley Roller Girls will host their first home game of the year, and against international opposition in the shape of Zurich City Rollergirlz. The game will be the second in a double header, and marks just the second time that FVRG have faced an international league, after taking on Oslo Roller Derby back in October 2013.
Formed in 2009, Zurich City Rollergirlz was Switzerland’s first roller derby league and became a full WFTDA member league towards the end of 2015. Currently ranked at 95 in Europe by Flat Track Stats while FVRG sits at 127, this promises to be a close and hard fought game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6722" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/header.jpg" alt="header" width="960" height="352"&gt;
The double header will begin with a Rising Stars game featuring newer skaters from leagues across Scotland, many of whom will be making the public skating debut. The leagues represented include Ayrshire Roller Derby, Auld Reekie Roller Girls, Bairn City Rollers, Doonhame Derby Dolls, Dundee Roller Girls, Glasgow Roller Derby, Granite City Roller Girls, Inverness City Roller Derby, Lothian Derby Dolls and New Town Roller Girls.
The event takes place at Grangemouth Sports Centre with doors at 14:30 and the first whistle for the Rising Stars at 15:00. FVRG then take on Zurich from 17:15. Tickets are £5 (+ booking fee) in advance &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2514682"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, or £7 on the door.  Join the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/253213188342972/"&gt;Facebook event&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/23/international-roller-derby-in-the-forth-valley/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 09:51:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs T3 North: Gameday 1</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/02/british-champs-t3-north-gameday-1/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;Of the six leagues that make up Tier 3 Regional North of this year’s British Roller Derby Championships – Dundee Roller Girls, Fierce Valley Roller Girls, Hallam Hellcats Roller Derby, Hull’s Angels Roller Dames, Manchester Roller Derby and Preston Roller Girls – only one competed at the same level last year: Dundee Roller Girls, who finished third in the table, with a record of three wins to two losses.  H.A.R.D. and Manchester Roller Derby both took part in Tier 2 National North, where Manchester beat H.A.R.D. in their encounter.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;Each of the other leagues moved up from Tier 4, Fierce Valley Roller Girls and Preston Roller Girls from T4 Local North as winners and runners up, and Hallam Hellcats from T4 Local Central North, as runners up.  The three teams faced off in the T4 North play-offs in November, where Hallam Hellcats beat Fierce Valley and Preston overcame Wolverhampton Honour Rollers to make the play-off final.  Hallam Hellcats took the victory on the day, and both leagues were promoted by making the final.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6023" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/fvrg1.jpg" alt="fvrg1" width="960" height="640"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;For Fierce Valley Roller Girls, T3 North contains some very familiar foes: both Dundee Roller Girls and Preston Roller Girls have faced FVRG on three occasions.  Dundee currently hold the edge with two victories to one, while FVRG have won each of their games against Preston.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6024" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/fvrg2.jpg" alt="fvrg2" width="960" height="640"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;Gameday 1 took place on Saturday 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; of February, in Preston.  The first game of the day saw FVRG take on H.A.R.D. before Dundee faced the host team.  From the first whistle, the game was very competitive, with neither team giving much ground.  H.A.R.D. took an early lead with some controlled offensive play before FVRG began to gain a foothold in the game.  Despite H.A.R.D.’s rock solid walls and good offensive play from both teams, FVRG’s jammers were finding a way through, and the first half ended with FVRG in the lead.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;H.A.R.D. started the second half very strongly, living up to their name with strong offensive play and big hits, to narrow the points gap.  Both teams fought hard and were fairly evenly matched through the second half, with the result that the score was tied at 171-171 heading into the final few jams.  Just when we thought the tension couldn’t get any higher, FVRG took the lead by one point and the jam ended with just 3 seconds on the clock.  With a time-out called by H.A.R.D., one final jam was played and a final lead change occurred, H.A.R.D. eventually winning the game by 182-178.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6022" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/drg2.jpg" alt="drg2" width="960" height="598"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span id="ecxyui_3_16_0_1_1456924961619_4040"&gt;Dundee's Silvery Tayzers travelled to Preston for their first Champs game of the season, having never met the home team before. Both teams set up in a very similar fashion using strong defensive walls and some useful offense for their jammers to take. Dundee started the game well with Preston giving away a powerjam in the first jam, allowing Dundee to move into a quick lead. Dundee were able to build on this with some good defence and recycling from their blockers allowing the jammers to score valuable points and extend the lead into halftime with the score 53 - 158 in Dundee's favour. The second half followed in the same fashion with both teams playing some great offense and Preston picking up some more points, but Dundee were able to see out the game with a 111-262 victory. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6021" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/drg1.jpg" alt="drg1" width="960" height="640"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;The next date in the T3 calendar is 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; March, when Dundee will travel to Manchester to take on the hosts, and Preston will face H.A.R.D.  The all-Scottish clash is next up at the FVRG-hosted double header on 23&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; April, which will also feature Manchester against Hallam Hellcats.  Dundee welcome H.A.R.D. at home on 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; May, when FVRG will also face Hallam Hellcats.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="ecxyiv8781638097MsoNormal"&gt;Photos courtesy of Johannes von Voges&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bout reports</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/02/british-champs-t3-north-gameday-1/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 16:40:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Girls - Review of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/24/fierce-valley-roller-girls-review-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2015 was another busy year for Fierce Valley Roller Girls, highlighted by topping their tier in the first ever British Champs, and rounded off with a fifth birthday celebration.  We spoke to Chair and Parma Violent WhoopAsh for her take on the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5284" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/st-team.jpg" alt="st team" width="600" height="599"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;November 2015 marked the end of your first year as Chair of Fierce Valley Roller Girls.  Tell us a little about your experience in this position this year.&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year has been a whirlwind of activity for FVRG with many highs and thankfully just a couple of lows.  Overall I’m ridiculously proud of what we have achieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Griz (one of FVRG’s founders) had been Chair since FVRG’s inception and she left some pretty big shoes to fill.  Luckily I had sat on the Board with Griz (as her Vice Chair) for the year before so had learned direct from the master :-) and was familiar with how the league operates.  Having attended UKROC in 2014 I was also full of ideas of what we should be focusing on going forward to grow and strengthen the league.&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Board were incredibly busy throughout the year, and whilst we didn’t achieve everything we set out to, we did achieve a lot, and this is a testament to the effort and support of the other Board members.  We have a clear plan of activity for next year too so we’re taking a well earned break over the Christmas period and will be back raring to go in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt; &lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;FVRG took part in the first British Champs this year, what did this mean for the league?  What made it different from previous years, and how did the team prepare?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being part of Champs has led to real friendships being formed between ourselves and the other leagues involved.  We already had links with the local leagues, but now have friendships and support links with both Preston and Spa Town due to meeting them, and partying with them, numerous times over the year.  This is one of the key things I’ve personally taken away.&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a league perspective, being part of Champs has allowed us to show the calibre of our Refs and Officials and our ability to host a good game.  We were also able to give lots of support to the less experienced leagues within the tier, providing Head NSO’s etc.&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to prep for the team we pretty much continued as is.  Our Coaches tailor our training in the run up to games based on our opponents and what we areas we need to develop.  We run a charter of 20 and select our teams from that charter.  Most of our charter have skated together for a long time so are all fairly bonded.  One thing we did try to work on was our endurance for the final.  Clearly we still have a bit of work to do there, as anyone that seen the Wolverhampton game will testify  ;-)&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5286" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/pvssign.jpg" alt="pvssign" width="960" height="540"&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Away from the track, how has the league developed this year?  &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started our year by getting the whole league together to workshop and agree FVRG’s vision, mission statement and values.  We had a great turn out and it was inspiring hear everyone’s views on what we are and what we want to become, and encouraging that generally speaking we all aspired to the same things.  For anyone interested, you can check out what we came up with on our website (&lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/about/our-values/" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.fvrg.co.uk/about/our-values/&lt;/a&gt;).  &lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the close of the previous year we had identified two key areas of focus.  For the first time ever we had closed the year making a loss financially so we agreed that one of our key focuses for the year should be fundraising.  We also identified that our recruitment and retention of skaters needed attention; with more leagues than ever in the central belt we agreed it was important that we promote what is unique about FVRG and also make more effort to integrate new skaters into the league fully, and at an earlier stage.  Throughout the year we put on many successful fundraising events ranging from smaller scale events like car boot, clothes swaps &amp;amp; public scrims, to our hugely successful pub quiz, Halloween party and 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Birthday Ball.  We also introduced some halftime activities to our games ‘chuck a duck’ anyone? J  To support our skater recruitment and retention objective we rebranded our Fresh Meat promotion, relaunched our new skater buddy system (Fierce Friends), and also implemented Welfare Reps.  I’m pleased to say both of these initiatives were hugely successful and we’ve closed the year in profit and with healthy numbers in our Fresh Meat and Intermediate sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other less exciting, but equally important, development was the formalisation of various policies and the introduction of a league contribution measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What do you think was FVRG's biggest achievement in 2015?  &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t pick just one thing here, I think our achievements are all intertwined.  Overall I am most impressed with how the league have rallied at the tougher times and continued to act in a positive and professional manner throughout the year.  We celebrate our successes but are always looking at where we can improve and what we can do differently next time to make things even better.   &lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt; &lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;And what challenges did the league face?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many other leagues across the UK, one of our key challenges is balancing the work load across the league.  Everyone has lives outside of Derby, but if someone doesn’t do it, it doesn’t get done.  We struggled a bit to get people to take on elected positions this year which led to the Board managing more areas of the league than we would have liked.  However, the work that we’ve done on bringing in new skaters and getting them engaged at an earlier stage is really starting to pay off.  At our recent AGM we had nominees for every position and no awkward ‘someone needs to do this guys’ moments.  We’ve also found that league engagement is up.  Maintaining this, and improving it further is one of our key objectives for this year.&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5285" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/fvrg1.jpg" alt="fvrg1" width="960" height="640"&gt;&lt;/u&gt; &lt;em&gt;Photo courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What have been your personal highlights?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really struggled with what to pick here, there have been lots of personal highlights.  From a league perspective I think I’ll need to go for  facilitating the production of our vision, mission statement, and values.  From skating I’d have to say the Manchester game.  We skated short but played as a really solid team and I remember doing some stuff on track that was effective and I was pretty happy with.&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt; &lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Finally, can you give us any idea of what to expect from FVRG in 2016, and beyond?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely.  The Parma Violents are taking part in Champs 2016 and are looking forward to stepping up to Tier 3, further developing our skating ability and team cohesion, playing more challenging teams, and forming links with other leagues.  We’re hosting a charity Sur5al game in February, in supporting Stirling’s Woman’s Aid, and play Zurich Roller Girls in April.  The calendar is filling up for the rest of the year too with so many teams wanting to play us.  From a league perspective, FVRG have excellent Coaches and Officials, and 2016 will see us formalising training plans to support members developing into these roles.  We’ll also continue to work on our skater recruitment and retention, put on fun events for the league and our fans, and support our local community.&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/24/fierce-valley-roller-girls-review-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 10:22:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Girls: Five Years On</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/10/fierce-valley-roller-girls-five-years-on/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In November 2010, three friends decided to try to set up a local roller derby league, and Fierce Valley Roller Girls was born.  I spoke to the league founders, V for Vienetta, Grizabelta and Kirk Jammett, for their thoughts on the last five years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What prompted you to establish Fierce Valley Roller Girls, and how did you get started?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V:&lt;/strong&gt; I had been following ARRG for a while and was interested in derby then after finaly seeing a bout I took Griz and Kirk through to see ARRG's next one. I quickly realised I wanted to be involved in some way with roller derby in Scoland and started to look into learning to ref.
At this time Scotland only had leagues in Aberdeen, Dundee, Perth, Glasgow and Edinburgh and we joked about starting one in Falkirk, the joke continued on for a couple of weeks where it then started to become more serious and then before we knew it we were looking into equipment, finding out about rules, skating, training and trying to find a hall to put this all together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G:&lt;/strong&gt; Our own laziness! V had convinced Kirk and myself to go along to an ARRG bout, and we were instantly hooked. We spent the entire journey home discussing how we could go about getting involved, but living in Falkirk, our nearest leagues were Edinburgh and Glasgow. I already spent a lot of time out the house with my other hobbies (outwith derby I'm a band geek and hospital radio DJ!) so wasn't keen to add more travelling to my week, and eventually 'if only there was something closer' turned into 'we could make this happen if we try'. It was really the boys' vision – but as a predominately female sport at the time, they thought it a bit inappropriate to approach sports halls on their own to try and bring this amazing women's sport to Forth Valley – which is where my involvement really came in! As the radio station is a small charity, I was fortunate to have the knowledge behind me of how to run not-for-profit organisations (or at least know the principles of how to run one!). We managed to convince Bo'ness Recreation Centre to let us skate around for a bit, and after a meeting in a pub to gather some interest – Fierce Valley Roller Girls was born!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K:&lt;/strong&gt; Marco has been pestering us to go to a - then bout - with him, so we finally took up the chance to go see ARRG play. Then followed a rather excited train journey home about what names we could have, and if we could really create our own league in the falkirk area.
A few weeks went by and I got in contact with Marco again and said that if he was serious about starting it to count me in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What difficulties did the league face in the early days?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; V:&lt;/strong&gt; I would say our main difficulty much like any other derby league at that time was getting a hall to practice in. We went round visiting all of the local sports centres/halls speaking to the managers to no avail, we even looked into other halls in the hope of someone letting us. For a while there was a real fear that we would never be able to get somewhere but thankfully Bo'ness Sports Centre said yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G:&lt;/strong&gt; Getting a hall! So many halls had inappropriate floors, and those that didn't were reluctant to let us skate. Bo'ness used to host roller hockey, so we took a chance with asking them, and thankfully they said yes – but even then only for a trial period. Back then we couldn't afford a full hall either- we had 2/3 of a hall, with a net wheel trap!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K:&lt;/strong&gt; The basics - getting a hall that was happy to let us skate in without damaging the floor. So we gathered as much information about the sport, and the different requirements needed to play the sport and tried every hall we could think of to let us just skate on their floor before we even considered the basics of roller derby and getting others interested. Weeks and weeks of every free moment contacting, and researching halls in the area to either be ignored or told ‘no’. 2 men turning up and saying we’re looking to start an all female sport in the area was confronted with many confused expressions. However we decided to give Bo’Ness Sports centre a stop by one day just to see - even though we’d been advised they’d banned skating in their halls. We gave the centre manager the run down on what we needed, and what our plans were going forward, he was kind enough to give us a tour of the halls available, and then offered us a 6 or 12 week probation to make sure there were no issues. And we never got kicked out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What roles did you play, and how have these changed over time?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; V:&lt;/strong&gt; For the first three years I was quite involved in the running of the league as the vice chair, I was also on a few different committee's including our Sports and Training. As time went on and as I got involved in Men's Derby I took less to do with the running of the league but am still involved in different committees within FVRG and find myself helping to train our new refs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G:&lt;/strong&gt; I think I've done everything and everything haha! Managerial-wise – I held the position of Chairperson for FVRG's first 4 years, which was amazingly rewarding and frustrating all at the same time! I took a step down last year to arrange my wedding, but also because I think you do get to a point where you just start to run out of ideas – you need that different perspective for a while. I'm now one of FVRG's UKRDA reps, which I'm still very much adjusting to – the whole 'big fish small pond' to 'small fish big pond' thing! Front-of-house so to speak, I started off as a skater (it's really odd seeing old pictures of my in my Parma Violents top!) but used to get far too nervous and basically just get jelly legs and spend all my time on the ground... Tried my hand at line-up manager a couple of times, and did a few games as bench coach, but then I settled as a full time NSO. NSOing was just something I started doing so I didn't have to sit on my own while Kirk and V were reffing, so I'm always slightly baffled as to where it's taken me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K:&lt;/strong&gt; Being the people with the crazy notion of starting this we got voted in as Chairperson, Vice Chair, and board member at our first AGM in Weatherspoons in Falkirk that memorable November evening.
With relatively low numbers we took on a lot of other tasks, such as sourcing designers to come up with our branding, then obtaining our first range of merchandise. Where possible we focused on keeping these to local businesses to help the area as well.
While the structure of the league has remained - if not grown - things are generally run in a similar manner, but with more and more experience coming into the league and taking on the different board, and spokesperson positions which are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the league grown over the past five years?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; V:&lt;/strong&gt; FVRG has grown in so many different ways and that is all thanks to its members. We started as a handful of people in half a hall skating once a week to a league filed with skaters, refs, dedicated NSOs and off skate members. We run 4 sessions a week covering all skating levels within the league. Our bouting team is sought after to be played against and has risen sharply up the rankings in the last couple of years and our officials travel all over reffing derby at different levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G:&lt;/strong&gt; We've certainly got a lot more structure – we're run more like a business now than just a group of friends muddling along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K:&lt;/strong&gt; Oh whoa! How has it grown! From 5 people skating in a badminton court in Bo’Ness to 4 regular training sessions spanning all levels of skating, to continually growing our knowledge and numbers in not only skaters but officials. And while we see friends moving on to bigger things, personally and in derby, our little league keeps pulling in the numbers and growing all of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your personal highlights and proudest moments?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; V:&lt;/strong&gt; It has been great to see the league build up from its formation and its members develop in their roles and watching the team grow from their first bout to now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G: It's always hard to single out a particular moment – I'm always proud of what our members achieve, on and off track. What does warm my heart though is when I see the friendships that have been formed through FVRG – people who are now the best of friends, who may never have met if they hadn't taken a chance on coming along to a Fresh Meat session one time. Or the transformation of those who are so quiet when they join, to becoming a confident and assertive individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K:&lt;/strong&gt; Personal highlights? Working with the vast number of amazing officials in Scotland, and somehow moving from just standing up in my skates to being picked to represent Scotland’s officials at the first Men's World Cup in Birmingham. While it’s been a lot of work to get to this stage, it certainly wouldn’t have been possible without everyone who has given me feedback and having the faith in me.
Proudest moments, would be seeing what seemed like a crazy idea one afternoon has become something not only we can be proud of, but everyone in the league who keeps pushing the league forward.
That and seeing referees who I’ve helped train go on to do amazing once let loose on the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You were all involved in the first ever Men's Roller Derby World Cup, as officials and as a skater - how was this experience for you?&lt;/strong&gt;
V: It was such an honour and privilege to play and represent Power of Scotland at the first Men's Roller derby World Cup. Between the training on the run up to and the actual world cup, it is an experience I could never forget as there are so many fond memories. The camaraderie between all the teams/skaters was amazing with everyone helping each other out, I got to meet and skate with/against some amazing people from all over the world and the atmosphere between us all in the team area just bfore the closing ceremony was unforgettable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G:&lt;/strong&gt; Amazing! To get to work with some of the best officials in the world, while seeing some of the best men's skaters in the world – I think I spent the entire time starstruck! I was very much the newbie in my crew (when we introduced ourselves it was lots of 'I'm xxx, Head Ref/HNSO of xxx', it came round to me and I was like 'I'm Griz, and I like to NSO'!!) but I learned so much from them and they looked after me amazingly well, especially during what ended up being a quite challenging time personally for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K:&lt;/strong&gt; So many different emotions happened that weekend. From feeling like the least experienced person in my crew - A lot of high level referees were on my crew. To being given amazing feedback on my refereeing, to then some stressful stuff happening closer to home, to then being picked to work on the last 3 games for my crew. Embarrassment, and a lot of laughter at the support I was getting from back home.
I still look back at that weekend and love all of it.
One of the hardest parts was being part of the crowed during the PoS and America game and staying completely impartial. Also, I missed every single Scottish point - every time I left the track they scored! My crew was up next so I couldn’t hang around and watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What advice would you give to a new league starting out?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; V:&lt;/strong&gt; I think the best advice would be not to rush and take your time. Build up your league and tune those skating skills so you are all ready to play together as a team, it can be tempting to start playing before you are all ready. Also make friends and build bridges with other leagues, you never know how much help they will be able to give you and how much you may need them in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G:&lt;/strong&gt; Be prepared for a lot of hard work! There are a number of reasons why people want to start a new league, but there will always end up being policies that need to be written, meetings to be had – and no matter what you do, you'll never please everyone all of the time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K:&lt;/strong&gt; Take as much advice as you can. It’s hard, it’s stressful, it takes all of your time and hard work, but seeing so many happy faces make it worth it.
You’re going to make mistakes a long the way, and recognising and learning from them will help move the league forward.
Most importantly, have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How would you like to see FVRG develop in the future?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; V:&lt;/strong&gt; I would like to see FVRG keep pushing forward and building their team and experience whilst developing all their upcoming skaters, hopefully long term get a 2nd team and who knows, even join WFTDA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G:&lt;/strong&gt; Well our goal for now is to work towards becoming a WFTDA league – but that has been our goal from the outset and it will take as long as it needs to take. We've spent a lot of work in the past year determining our vision, mission statement and values, and everything we do ties into these, so we're becoming much more aware of how the little things we do tie into the bigger picture. I'm always really proud of our community involvement too, so I'm hoping this will continue! And of course, I just want everyone to enjoy being part of FVRG, no matter what role they play :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K:&lt;/strong&gt; While there are the obvious ones of continuing to climb the rankings in Europe and UKRDA, and also joining WFTDA, just being where the league needs to be at that point in time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/10/fierce-valley-roller-girls-five-years-on/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 09:35:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Once Upon a Skate...</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/01/once-upon-a-skate/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join Fierce Valley Roller Girls as they end their year with an exciting double header! Up first will be Fierce Valley Roller Cubs, Scotland's only junior roller derby league, in a Goodies vs. Baddies intraleague. Fierce Valley Roller Girls will then be joined by skaters from Bairn City Rollers, Mean City Roller Derby and Lothian Derby Dolls to face off as Storybrooke vs. Enchanted Forest in a Once Upon A Time themed game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/once.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5172"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-5172 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/once.jpg?w=300" alt="once" width="563" height="212"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the venue is rather 'intimate', we recommend buying your tickets in advance to avoid disappointment. Tickets are priced at £5 in advance/£7 on the door, and kids under 14 go free with a paying adult.  Tickets are available in advance &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2469041"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors will open at 3pm for a 3.30pm start. As always, there will be a selection of handmade crafts, home-baking and team merchandise for sale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/01/once-upon-a-skate/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 09:47:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Girls vs Sheffield Steel Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/01/fierce-valley-roller-girls-vs-sheffield-steel-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Sunday 12th July, Fierce Valley Roller Girls will host their second home game of the year when the Parma Violents take on Sheffield Steel Roller Girls at Grangemouth Sports Complex. This will be the second half of a Scottish roller derby double header for Sheffield, after they face Dundee Rollers Girls in a British Championships T3 North game the previous day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/sheffied.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4745 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/sheffied.jpg?w=214" alt="Sheffied" width="304" height="420"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Parma Violents have won both of their games this year, away to Birmingham Blitz Dames’ Bomb Squad and at home to The Darksiders in a Champs challenge game. If Flat Track Stats’ European rankings are anything to go by, this is bound to be a close game: SSRG are currently ranked at 75, with FVRG just one place behind at 76.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 11:00 for the first whistle at 11:30. Tickets are available in advance &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/1802022"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for the discounted price of £5 (+ booking fee), or £7 on the door. Join the Facebook event &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1623363374568588/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/01/fierce-valley-roller-girls-vs-sheffield-steel-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 10:29:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Girls intraleague</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/04/24/fierce-valley-roller-girls-intraleague/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sunday May 3rd will see two teams of skaters from Fierce Valley Roller Girls, plus some special guests from ARRG, BCR, DRG and GRD, face each other as Heroes and Villains in a Disney-themed game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/intra-may.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4625 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/intra-may.jpg?w=212" alt="INTRA MAY" width="326" height="461"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the venue is rather 'intimate', it is recommended to buy your tickets in advance to avoid disappointment. Tickets are priced at £5 in advance/£7 on the door, and kids under 14 go free with a paying adult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors will open at 2pm. As always, there will be a selection of handmade crafts, home-baking and team merchandise for sale. Join the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1604485703131602/"&gt;Facebook event&lt;/a&gt; or buy tickets &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/1470725"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/04/24/fierce-valley-roller-girls-intraleague/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 10:57:22 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>