<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about gcrg)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/gcrg.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Granite City Roller Derby- A Roundup of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/21/granite-city-roller-derby-a-roundup-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-wp-1447877216475.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img title="wp-1447877216475" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-wp-1447877216475.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2015 was a crazily busy and exciting year for Granite City roller Girls. We took part in British Championships for the first time, gained an accredited NSO, some of our members left to pursue new adventures, we expanded our league and at the end of 2015, we changed our name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Northern Fights took part in British Championships which was so exciting for the entire league! We were placed in Tier 3, Regional North; along with our good pals Dundee Roller Girls as well as Sheffield Steel Rollergirls, Furness Firecrackers, Liverpool Roller Birds and Halifax Bruising Banditas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first game in February saw us playing against Dundee Roller Girls. A fierce first game of the season and Champs! Dundee took the win with 366 to 58.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There wasn't long to wait until our next game in March where we were paired up against Sheffield Steel Rollergirls. The game was close and moments were tense, too tense. My poor wee heart! Final scores were GCRG 144 and SSRG 186.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June it was our turn to play Liverpool Roller Birds who scored 284 to our 111 with our next game just around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;July saw GCRG take on Furness Firecrackers who won our game with 325 to 112.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-fb_img_1447877829715.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1447877829715.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-fb_img_1447877829715.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo credit: the lovely  Ian McCreadie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August the Northern Fights played their last game of 2015 British Championships against Halifax Bruising Banditas. We won our final game of the year with a score of 226 to 72.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spoke to Berocca Bama, the Northern Fights co-captain for 2015, about taking part in British Championships.
&lt;em&gt;
"The Northern Fights had the privilege of taking part in the 2015 British Championships. It was an exciting year and although we started off with many skaters who were new to the team, every single one stepped up to the challenge and we went from strength to strength, surprising ourselves and others along the way. The dedication and drive of each sportswoman on the team makes me very proud to have played alongside them this season and fills me with excited anticipation for all that 2016 holds. Go Fights! "&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we had a record breaking, based on no fact at all other than it seemed a huge amount, number of skaters coming up from fresh meat together. One intake generated 12 new league skaters. 12! That’s almost an entire team. This increase in mins passed skaters is a combination of all of the hardwork put in by our fresh meat training squad (namely Shan, Krusty, Berocca Bama and Nikki) and the hardwork and determination that our ‘noobs’ bring with them to training each and every week. As a mentor I get to witness this first hand…and yes…I have cried many a proud tear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-wp-1447876987607.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img title="wp-1447876987607" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-wp-1447876987607.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo above: 11 of our 12 strong mins passed skaters from the start of the year, followed by 6 more later in the year &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This increase in mins passed skaters necessitated the need to introduce a second team. So, in 2015, Granite City Roller Girls welcomed their B Team. The Fight Hawks. Kakaw!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hawks played their first game in September against Lothian Derby Dolls. It was a tense game and I think we all learned never to start celebrating a win until the score says ‘Official’. A win was taken and fun was had all round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October the Hawks played Mean City. A loss was taken this time around but so much was learned and again, great times were had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spoke to Fight Hawks' co-captain Whips 'n' Lashes about our newest team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt; "2015 was an exciting year for GCRD with the creation of our B team – The Fight Hawks. Fierce and determined we rose to the challenge, with our first game together being a nail biting win. For a lot of our ladies this was their first ever public outing and the professionalism, attitude and energy they showed made our league and support very proud! 2016 is already looking like a good year and we hope to continue our development not only as a team but as a league and we are looking forward to the next lot of skaters coming up. Kakaw!"&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-fb_img_1447877532971.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1447877532971.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-fb_img_1447877532971.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo credit: the glorious Dave McAleavy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some say ‘you learn more in defeat that victory’, I can’t speak for everyone but I feel this is true. We may not have had an amazing win streak this year but after every game we have learned about ourselves and our team. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;December will see the annual GCRG Christmas ceildhi where we will celebrate our achievements of the year. Through the medium of dance and good times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision was made this year to rebrand. I, for one, am ridiculously excited about our new colour scheme. As a league and as skaters we are growing and we voted to change our name from Granite City Roller Girls to Granite City Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-bz4tbsp92ovcwuqx4vpjtodas6auvqgnsen4sztbxcw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="bZ4TBsp92oVCWUqx4VpjTODas6auVQgnsEN4SZtbxcw.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-bz4tbsp92ovcwuqx4vpjtodas6auvqgnsen4sztbxcw.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture above: our super amazingly fantastic new logos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge thank you goes out to everyone who has helped us to have an amazing 2015; referees and NSOs,  we couldn’t do any of this without you, announcers and photographers, our wonderful training team, everyone who has helped make bout days happen, our fans for never failing to keep our spirits high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here’s to 2016 and GRANITE CITY ROLLER DERBY!!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>gcrd</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/21/granite-city-roller-derby-a-roundup-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 10:49:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City Roller Girls - A Roundup of 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/30/granite-city-roller-girls-a-roundup-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I transferred to Granite City Rollergirls in February 2014 and have been lucky enough to spend a fun filled (almost) year with the league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a busy year for GCRG! We have had a few changes to the league, some friends left for pastures new, some returned and we got some amazingly talented new teammates and referees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been many promotion opportunities for us including the Discover Aberdeen dolphins and live demonstrations in the Bon Accord Centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/gcrg.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4487" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/gcrg.png" alt="Granite City Roller Girls  official logo" width="335" height="151"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Granite City Roller Girls official logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our final game of 2014 against Bedforshire's Rebellion Roller Derby was a fantastic game to watch. The team really pulled together and used every skill that they had been working on and ended our bouting year on a high with a win of 184 to 155.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the whole league will agree that one of our highlights of 2014 was cheering our wee hearts out for Jill Stephen (Fight Cub), Jill Simpson (Rock n Riot), and Carolyn Mackenzie (Clinically Wasted) when they represented GCRG in Team Scotland at the Blood and Thunder Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended 2014 with an annual Skateroonie where fights, refs and newbies got together to play games, eat food and more importantly, play tug of war (the girls took victory ). This was followed a few days later with a league night out to end 2014 appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My own highlight for 2014 was playing my debut game as a Northern Fight against Hull. There was a great atmosphere and I was super proud to represent the Fights for the first time. Any occasion where we get together whether to skate or just have a nice time is always a highlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10571952_10154540553565160_2015222088721681186_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4479" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10571952_10154540553565160_2015222088721681186_o.jpg" alt="Photo credit: Caroline Allison" width="614" height="461"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photo credit: Caroline Allison&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a mentor for our fresh meat I have the luxury of seeing our newbies turn from timid wee lambs into confident team mates. The structure of fresh meat training has changed so you can really see the progress from one week to the next. I'm so excited to see what the future holds for our newbs! They will be taking part in their first team scrimmage in January and I for one will be beaming with pride...and just a wee warning that I shall probably cry proud little tears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year promises to be an exciting whirlwind for GCRG as we will be taking part in British Championships Heartland series! Some of our eagle eyed readers may have seem the recent announcement of GCRG's B team. There is so much to come and I'm excited!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I spoke to GCRG's captain for 2015, Mental, about what the roller derby community can expect from GCRG next year;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"From the start of 2015 we have entered the British Championships, these are very exciting times for GCRG. For me personally I've got big boots to fill but I believe if you put in 100% you get 100%. I can see a more focussed, determined and stronger team for 2015"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10460596_10203580393204655_5761820161661248642_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4480 size-full" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10460596_10203580393204655_5761820161661248642_o.jpg" alt="Photo credit : Andy Morris" width="614" height="410"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photo credit: Andy Morris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/30/granite-city-roller-girls-a-roundup-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Scotland</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/16/world-cup-interview-team-scotland/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Team-Scotland-Roller-Derby/235701999922927"&gt;Scotland&lt;/a&gt; competed in the 2011 &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; and secured 11&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; place, after a difficult placement group with the USA and New Zealand.  Jill Stephen represented Scotland last time (skating as Fight Cub) and is back for more. She was kind enough to let me interview her.
&lt;p&gt;This weekend Scotland will be competing in &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/724704624268299/?fref=ts"&gt;The Road to Dallas&lt;/a&gt; alongside Team Ireland, Wales and West Indies, having already played two warm-up bouts (against the &lt;a title="Team Scotland v Euro Stars – This Saturday!" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/03/team-scotland-v-euro-stars-this-saturday/"&gt;Euro-Stars&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="Are they HOT or WOT? Team Scotland’s latest challengers speak." href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/12/are-they-hot-or-wot-team-scotlands-latest-challengers-speak/"&gt;Hot or WOT&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/team-scotland.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4001" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/team-scotland.png?w=300" alt="Team Scotland logo" width="300" height="246"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Team Scotland logo by Admiral Attackbar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the topic of team selection - Can you tell me a bit about how your team selection process worked?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a long and thorough process. There were round one tryouts, round two tryouts and a final top 20 training team picked as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tryouts were open to anyone and were a great way to practice with people from leagues all over the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It never felt tense or pressured and everyone was very relaxed. The scrims were great fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it difficult having people from different leagues get together for training?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having skaters from various leagues undoubtedly makes it tricky to all meet up and practice but we’ve managed to get a good few practices in so far with more planned before the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The training sessions have been tough but excellent. It’s such a privilege to be skating such talented women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have very packed derby calendars as it is so free weekends are like gold dust!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have you been personally preparing for the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a complete diet overhaul since selection which has made a huge difference to my fitness and agility. I’ve also been working on upper body strength at the gym.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mental preparation has also been a big part of my training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flying to the USA from anywhere is expensive as a team, how have you been fundraising and achieving sponsorship?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have some wonderful sponsors including S1 helmets and Atom wheels. There have been a few fundraisers including bouts, a bootcamp and some fabulous merch! We’ve also received extremely generous donations over at &lt;a href="http://gogetfunding.com/project/get-team-scotland-to-dallas"&gt;http://gogetfunding.com/project/get-team-scotland-to-dallas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We still have a few events up our sleeves before we head out as well. Keep your eyes peeled!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What teams are you most looking forward to playing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would LOVE to have the opportunity to play any of the top 3 finishers from the last world cup (USA, Canada, England).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You always learn so much from a really tough game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you most looking forward to about the World Cup this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching the new teams that have entered this year will be awesome. Also, playing and hanging out with all my Team Scotland team mates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You skated in the World Cup in 2011; has this had an impact on your training for December?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like Roller Derby is still changing in such a way that all you can ever do is work as hard, focus and train. Nobody will really know what to expect until we get there and it will be a million miles away from the derby we were playing 3 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Team Scotland roster&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;0 Louise Kerr&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;09 Jill Simpson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;11 Parry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;111 Mackenzie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1111 Jenny Gow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;182 Jill Stephen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;22 Grace Maclean&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;28 Lauren Bianchi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;210 Rogue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3 Cider&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;39 Davis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4 Megan Hyndman&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;69 Laura Liston&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;85 Skinner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;87 Caitlen O'Carroll&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;931 Rebecca Ryan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;F104 Marshall Lawless&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bench coach - Coach Noble&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Line up Manager - Murphy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Manager - Jill Antonic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/16/world-cup-interview-team-scotland/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 09:19:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>GCRG Rock Night</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/23/gcrg-rock-night/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Friday 17th October Granite City Roller Girls are hosting the next long awaited Rock Night!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A night of Rock music featuring some homegrown talent, a booze raffle and other awesome prizes up for grabs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/gcrg-rock-night.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/gcrg-rock-night.jpg" alt="GCRG rock night" width="614" height="868" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3859"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lineup includes;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking Sideways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A local band from Aberdeen heavily influenced by Biffy Clyro
&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/talkingsideways" rel="nofollow"&gt;www.facebook.com/talkingsideways&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miss Lucid
&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;Miss Lucid offer their own style of 'in your face' rock, driven with the punk/grunge undertones of bands such as The Clash and Nirvana, blending large sonic sound scapes and crafted melodies reminiscent of Placebo and Manic Street Preachers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MissLucid" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/MissLucid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
Guttergodz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;An eclectic mix of influences in the band such as Thin Lizzy, The Wildhearts, Elvis Presley, Backyard Babies, The Clash and so on. In 2010 they made it into the shortlist of bands rated 'particularly awesome' by Kerrang radio and at the start of 2013 they were crowned 'Best Rock Band' at the Fudge awards in Aberdeen and made it to the final of Cafe Drummond's battle of the bands to win £2000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/guttergodz" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/guttergodz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 8pm with £8.00 entry. An absolute bargain!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus booze raffle!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...did I already mention booze raffle? I'm just pretty excited about somebody winning a hamper of booze and rocking out to some great music&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So come on down to Downstairs at 82 Holburn Street and start your weekend off on a high!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fundraiser event</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/23/gcrg-rock-night/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 21:04:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City Roller Girls &amp; Granite City Brawlermen Recruitment Day</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/22/granite-city-roller-girls-and-granite-city-brawlermen-recruitment-day/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/gcrg-recruits-6-september-2014.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-3611" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/gcrg-recruits-6-september-2014.jpg?w=212" alt="GCRG recruits 6 September 2014" width="212" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/gcb-recruitment-6-september-2014.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3612" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/gcb-recruitment-6-september-2014.jpg?w=212" alt="GCB recruitment 6 September 2014" width="212" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City Roller Girls and Granite City Brawlermen are recruiting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday 6th September is an exciting day for Roller Derby Recruitment in Aberdeen with not one but two intakes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, Granite City Roller Girls are holding their intake day at Aberdeen Lads Club (Dill Road) from 11:00-13:00. Then from 13.30 to 15.30 the Brawlermen will be welcoming new recruits as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both GCRG and GCB have experienced coaches who can teach people of all levels so no skating experience is necessary and we can provide equipment - please drop us a message on Facebook to let us know what shoe size you take so we can make sure we have skates for you on the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GCRG are also on the lookout for referees so any ladies or gents who would like to get involved with this aspect of the sport should pop along too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby is a brilliant way to get fit and meet new people! All we ask is that you’re over 18 years old, wear non restrictive clothing and bring plenty of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put on some skates, be your own hero!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information please email newrecruits@granitecityrollergirls.org.uk or granitecitybrawlermen@gmail.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also find our Facebook events at
&lt;a title="GCRG Fresh Meat" href="http://www.facebook.com/events/711800382227020/"&gt;www.facebook.com/events/711800382227020/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/311415489033203/?fref=ts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fresh meat</category><category>gcb</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/22/granite-city-roller-girls-and-granite-city-brawlermen-recruitment-day/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 22:32:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee and Granite City - A Retrospective.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/03/23/dundee-and-granite-city-a-retrospective/</link><dc:creator>clinicallywasted</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the 29&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of March 2014 Granite City Roller Girls will face off against Dundee Roller Girls’ Silvery Tayzers. This will be the third time the teams have played each other in the space of 4 years – a period of time that has seen a change in the look, the feel and the integrity of our sport and as such, a change in The Fights and The Tayzers. Clinically Wasted and Milky offer an interesting retrospective into how their leagues have developed in this time, and their aspirations for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City and Dundee were the first younger leagues to spring up in Scotland after the teams on the central belt had become more established. As a result, the leagues formed a symbiotic relationship, assisting each other wherever they could.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;-Roller derby in Dundee has always been close with GCRG. They made the journey week after week to help us with every aspect of derby - from putting us through our minimum skills to helping us structure our league. It's fair to say that we wouldn't be the team we are without the help they gave us in the start, and their continuing support.&lt;/em&gt; (Milky)&lt;em&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;-The relationship between Aberdeen and Dundee goes back along time, before I had even put on a pair of skates myself. The maturing of both leagues has ran side by side, and for a while it almost felt like we had a conjoined league of Dundeen where we would attend each others training and in fact GCRG’s first ever closed door bout featured a few of the Dundee girls.&lt;/em&gt; -(Clinically Wasted)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/935888_10153084748090392_1488004219_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3344" alt="Courtesy of Zenspirations Photography" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/935888_10153084748090392_1488004219_n.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Courtesy of Zenspirations Photography&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Riding off the back of Highland Fling, Dundee hosted their first ever home game in November 2010. Their opponents - GCRG's Northern Fights.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;-A select few of us remember bouting GCRG  - our first home bout as Dundee Destroyers. We didn't have any tactics really, we were just ecstatic to be sharing the track with our big sister league. We didn't take ourselves or the bout too seriously. As newbies we were all still caught up in the novelty of bouting - I think the majority of our time was spent considering uniforms, chants and face paint. Needless to say, GCRG had the edge on the day and took home the win. &lt;/em&gt;(M)&lt;em&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;-We were flying high with all the good intentions and in our fishnets, high socks and pants we were ready to kick butt. Dundee so kindly got somebody to film the occasion so it can eternally be watched. The video always makes me smile, because I remember how much fun we had that game, playing against our sisters. &lt;/em&gt;(CW)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/gcrgvsrk1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3346 " alt="Courtesy of Andrew Leatherbarrow." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/gcrgvsrk1.jpg" width="614" height="407"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Courtesy of Andrew Leatherbarrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you haven't seen it already, here is a link to the video by Dylan Drummond: &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IPylGsXKJAE" target="_blank"&gt;Northern Fights vs Rippin Kittens 2010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time marched on. Outside of these two league's UKRDA were fighting for recognised sport status, London RollerGirls had joined WFTDA, people were taking knee down starts…remember them? Our sport evolved. And then these sister leagues played again, this time in Aberdeen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;-By our return bout the following year, we were now Dundee Roller Girls. Skating under a new name and colour and with new ambitions and values. The team was much more focused - we'd spent months studying our tactics, rules and honing our skills. The atmosphere for us was a little more tense this time as we were aiming for a win. The bout was hard fought from both sides, but again GCRG just pipped us in the final minutes. It was the best we'd skated as a team and the closest we'd come to victory. We finished proud of ourselves and incredibly proud of our friends in GCRG who had grown so much and who continued to teach and support us.&lt;/em&gt; (M)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- The game was hard, well fought, close and most of all fun. The level of derby and strategy had changed, but that buzz of seeing your friends play well made it all worth while. (CW)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/nfvsst.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3348" alt="Courtesy of Granite City Roller Girls" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/nfvsst.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Courtesy of Granite City Roller Girls&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fast forward to now, in 2014. DRG and GCRG have both had an incredible few seasons. Both teams are serious about progressing our sport and promoting the athleticism and empowerment they've worked so hard to achieve. Each team has changed vastly since they first lined up against each other in 2010; Dundee are in fact a completely different league with only 4 rostered skaters playing from the original line up, and Granite City only having 3 original Fights playing. Despite all the changes the two teams have experienced, they've continued to meet on track throughout the years, together and as opponents, still supporting our derby sisters and always proud of each teams acheivements.
&lt;/strong&gt;
-&lt;em&gt;We've remained each other's biggest fans. For me, I still frantically follow Twitter feeds for away scores as if it were for my own league. Regardless of the outcome of our upcoming bout, there's not a team in the world I'd rather share a track with, and not a team in the world I'd rather drag my battered body to share a pint with afterwards! &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;(&lt;/em&gt;M)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;em&gt;We always love catching up with the Dundee girls, and when we hear of their upcoming games it's as if we are skating with them! Tentatively waiting for scores on twitter and facebook! &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;People have come and gone and attitudes have changed but I know for certain one thing; at the final whistle, we will all hug, we will go grab a beer and we will all party like it’s 2010! (&lt;/em&gt;CW)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Girls play Dundee Roller Girls Saturday 29th of March 2014 at the Beach Leisure Centre in Aberdeen. Doors at 2.00pm for 3.00pm. Free Entry.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/blamming-season.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3347" alt="Courtesy of Granite City Roller Girls." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/blamming-season.jpg" width="614" height="868"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Courtesy of Granite City Roller Girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>aberdeen</category><category>articles</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>pictures</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>video</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/03/23/dundee-and-granite-city-a-retrospective/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 19:50:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Talking Derby To Us: Podcasts come to Scotland</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/05/talking-derby-to-us-podcasts-come-to-scotland/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of ways that Roller Derby has been discussed and promoted online and off, from League Websites, through blogs like us, and bigger entities like &lt;a href="http://derbynewsnetwork.com"&gt;Derby News Network&lt;/a&gt;, the derby magazines (the UK's own &lt;a href="http://www.leadjammermag.com/"&gt;Lead Jammer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.insidelinemagazine.co.uk/"&gt;Inside Line&lt;/a&gt; amongst them), and YouTube/Vimeo/etc videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podcasts, on the other hand, are a somewhat rarer breed, much to the sadness of everyone who wants to listen to people talk about Derby on their daily commute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/talkderbytome.png"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-3241" alt="No, really, Talk to Them. They're Listening." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/talkderbytome.png?w=614" width="614" height="81"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The folk up in Aberdeen are well aware of this, however, and have their most talkative member, sMACklemore, (otherwise known with his announcing hat on for Granite City Roller Girls) on the case. He'll be hosting the new derby fortnightly podcast "&lt;strong&gt;Talk Derby To Me&lt;/strong&gt;" starting this very month, with an array of guests from around derby, thanks to the magic of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Episode 1 is due for release around the &lt;strong&gt;11th of February&lt;/strong&gt;, and will feature:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GCRG Vice Captain (and Team Scotland Training Team member) Rock'n Riot,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GCRG Ref (and Scottish Roller Derby Blog contributor) Buffy Boiler,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also GCRG Ref (and holder of longest name in derby) Tessington World of Adventures,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;along with a "mystery guest" from a location "within the UK".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact with the team is currently via their Facebook page here: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/talkderby"&gt;www.facebook.com/talkderby&lt;/a&gt; where they'd welcome anecdotes about your derby Fresh Meat days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: The podcast discussed in this article is now available at &lt;a href="http://www.mixcloud.com/talkderbytome/talk-derby-to-me-episode-1/"&gt;http://www.mixcloud.com/talkderbytome/talk-derby-to-me-episode-1/&lt;/a&gt; and at &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/talkderbytome/"&gt;https://soundcloud.com/talkderbytome/&lt;/a&gt;, the latter of which also allows mp3 downloads.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>aberdeen</category><category>articles</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>podcasts</category><category>roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/05/talking-derby-to-us-podcasts-come-to-scotland/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 13:40:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>GCRG Rock Night 2.0 Fundraiser</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/03/gcrg-rock-night-2-0-fundraiser/</link><dc:creator>zenrhe</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Well it's that time again folks! GCGR are putting on another awesome Rock night!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
I'd advise you to duck tape your socks down because they are likely to get rocked off!!!...
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="RockNightFeb2014" alt="RockNightFeb2014" src="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/nextgen-image/671/600x0x100/aff44b4a9b1bbf4f9a5f128e88579378"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning from the previous rock night we welcome back &lt;strong&gt;Laid Back&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a list as long as both of your arms put together Laid Back are a covers band not to be missed!.. ( Rage against the machine, Guns n Roses, Wheezer, Queens of the Stone Age, Kings of Leon, The Killers, The Cult, Foo fighters, Queen, ACDC....I could go on!!!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to unforeseen commitments the Ruckus have had to pull out of Rock night...but not to worry, we have....&lt;em&gt;drum roll&lt;/em&gt; Voodoo Vibe!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:14px;line-height:1.5em;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voodoo Vibe&lt;/strong&gt; are a four piece cover band that play anything from The Rolling stones to The White stripes. If you liked to know more you can give them a like here or check out their web page.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/l.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.voodoovibe.co.uk%2F&amp;amp;h=eAQHV5osh&amp;amp;enc=AZOez09A737UCTcAWQ1FMzJY5tb82ei5dRIQavMUM1yx1v_2XHt0DRl2fAkTd_swn6w&amp;amp;s=1" target="_blank" rel="nofollow nofollow"&gt;www.voodoovibe.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Voodoo-Vibe/439242632806419" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/pages/Voodoo-Vibe/439242632806419&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors 6.30pm, first band on @ 7.00pm. £6.00 entry. Awesome cake and booze raffle on the night.! See you there!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date/Time&lt;/strong&gt;
Date(s) - 01/02/2014
&lt;i&gt;6:30 pm - 11:00 pm&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a title="Downstairs" href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/locations/downstairs/"&gt;Downstairs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/calendar/event?action=TEMPLATE&amp;amp;text=Rock+Night+2.0+Fundraiser&amp;amp;dates=20140201T183000Z/20140201T230000Z&amp;amp;details=Well+it%27s+that+time+again+folks%21+GCGR+are+putting+on+another+awesome+Rock+night%21I%27d+advise+you+to+duck+tape+your+socks+down+because+they+are+likely+to+get+rocked+off%21%21%21...Returning+from+the+previous+rock+night+we+welcome+back+%3Cstrong%3ELaid+Back%3C%2Fstrong%3E.With+a+list+as+long+as+both+of+your+arms+put+together+Laid+Back+are+a+covers+band+not+to+be+missed%21..+%28+Rage+against+the+machine%2C+Guns+n+Roses%2C+Wheezer%2C+Queens+of+the+Stone+Age%2C+Kings+of+Leon%2C+The+Killers%2C+The+Cult%2C+Foo+fighters%2C+Queen%2C+ACDC....I+could+go+on%21%21%21%29Due+to+unforeseen+commitments+the+Ruckus+have+had+to+pull+out+of+Rock+night...but+not+to+worry%2C+we+have....%2Adrum+roll%2AVOODOO+VIBE%21%21Voodoo+Vibe+are+a+four+piece+cover+band+that+play+anything+from+The+Rolling+stones+to+The+White+stripes.+If+you+liked+to+know+more+you+can+give+them+a+like+here+or+check+out+their+web+page.%3Ca+href%3D%22http%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fl.php%3Fu%3Dhttp%253A%252F%252Fwww.voodoovibe.co.uk%252F%26amp%3Bh%3DeAQHV5osh%26amp%3Benc%3DAZOez09A737UCTcAWQ1FMzJY5tb82ei5dRIQavMUM1yx1v_2XHt0DRl2fAkTd_swn6w%26amp%3Bs%3D1%22%3Ewww.voodoovibe.co.uk%3C%2Fa%3E%3Ca+href%3D%22https%3A%2F...&amp;amp;location=Downstairs&amp;amp;trp=false&amp;amp;sprop=http%3A%2F%2Fgranitecityrollergirls.org.uk%2Fevents%2Frock-night-2-0-fundraiser%2F&amp;amp;sprop=name:Granite+City+Roller+Girls" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img title="Rock Night 2.0 Fundraiser" alt="gc button2 Rock Night 2.0 Fundraiser" src="http://www.google.com/calendar/images/ext/gc_button2.gif" border="0"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>aberdeen</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/03/gcrg-rock-night-2-0-fundraiser/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 11:01:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fresh Meat - Intake day for GCRG - February 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/12/26/3060/</link><dc:creator>zenrhe</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Granite City Roller Girls are recruiting!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We are holding our next Intake Day at the &lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen Lads Club (Dill Road) from 14:00 - 16:00 on Saturday 1st February 2014.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Roller derby is the fastest growing sport in the UK and we are looking for new skaters and referees. No previous skating experience is necessary! We have skates and protective equipment all waiting for you to try on before the Derby Bug bites you and you rush off to buy yourself some new gear :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="ngg-singlepic ngg-center aligncenter" alt="gcrg_freshmeatfeb2014" src="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/wp-content/gallery/events/gcrg_freshmeatfeb2014.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;Joining GCRG is a brilliant way to get fit and meet new people!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Yes this is a women's sport but GCRG are on the look out for referees, so any guys who would like to get involved in the sport should pop along too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;All we ask is that you are over 18 years old, wear non-restrictive clothing, and bring plenty of water. This session is &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt;. Check out our &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/550103361732369/" target="_blank"&gt;facebook event.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
See you on the track!!
&lt;p&gt;GCRG xx&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Course starts Wednesday the 5th 7pm – 9pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Training" href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/training/" target="_blank"&gt;Check out how our training is done&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;div style="float:right;margin:0 0 15px 15px;"&gt;
&lt;div class="em-location-map-container" style="position:relative;background:#CDCDCD;width:400px;height:300px;"&gt;
&lt;div class="em-location-map" id="em-location-map-d24f9" style="width:100%;height:100%;"&gt;Loading Map....&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="em-location-map-info" id="em-location-map-info-d24f9" style="display:none;visibility:hidden;"&gt;
&lt;div class="em-map-balloon" style="font-size:12px;"&gt;
&lt;div class="em-map-balloon-content"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen Lads Club&lt;/strong&gt;
Dill Road - Aberdeen
&lt;a href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/locations/aberdeen-lads-club/"&gt;Details&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="em-location-map-coords" id="em-location-map-coords-d24f9" style="display:none;visibility:hidden;"&gt;&lt;span class="lat"&gt;57.17197669999999&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="lng"&gt;-2.1183613000000605&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date/Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date(s) - 01/02/2014
&lt;i&gt;2:00 pm - 4:00 pm&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Aberdeen Lads Club" href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/locations/aberdeen-lads-club/"&gt;Aberdeen Lads Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/calendar/event?action=TEMPLATE&amp;amp;text=Fresh+Meat+-+February+2014&amp;amp;dates=20140201T140000Z/20140201T160000Z&amp;amp;details=%3Cstrong%3ERoll+Up+Roll+Up%21%3C%2Fstrong%3EGCRG%27s+present+their+Fresh+Meat+afternoon.+This+is+the+chance+for+you+to+come+and+see+what+its+all+about+and+sign+up+for+the+next+training+course.Course+starts+Wednesday+the+5th+7pm+-+9pm%3Ca+title%3D%22Training%22+href%3D%22http%3A%2F%2Fgranitecityrollergirls.org.uk%2Ftraining%2F%22%3ECheck+out+how+our+training+is+done%3C%2Fa%3E&amp;amp;location=Aberdeen+Lads+Club&amp;amp;trp=false&amp;amp;sprop=http%3A%2F%2Fgranitecityrollergirls.org.uk%2Fevents%2Ffresh-meat-february-2014%2F&amp;amp;sprop=name:Granite+City+Roller+Girls" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img title="Fresh Meat   February 2014" alt="gc button2 Fresh Meat   February 2014" src="http://www.google.com/calendar/images/ext/gc_button2.gif" border="0"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>aberdeen</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/12/26/3060/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 11:04:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Merry Xmas from GCRG!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/12/19/merry-xmas-from-gcrg/</link><dc:creator>zenrhe</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/image.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>aberdeen</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>image</category><category>pictures</category><category>xmas</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/12/19/merry-xmas-from-gcrg/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 18:00:21 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>