<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about glasgow roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/glasgow-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 07:28:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Chaos returns to Glasgow after 6 years.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/chaos2019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arguably one of the high points of roller derby in Glasgow was way back in August 2012, when Glasgow Roller Derby hosted their first
tournament event, &lt;em&gt;Chaos on the Clyde&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/884747741612081/"&gt;FB&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/17770"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120829101350/https://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/bouts-events/bouts-eventschaos2012/"&gt;WEB&lt;/a&gt; ). (This was also around the time that the National Museum of Roller Derby was getting going, and
so, as well as the international competition, the NMRD stall also helped to develop derby in different senses.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, thanks to the venue used being closed not long after, and other suitable venues being inaccessible, it's been 6 years now until Glasgow Roller Derby have been able to bring back the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Image of flyer for Chaos on the Clyde 2." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/07/Chaos2019flyer.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, back it is, with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/854543498244493/https://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/events-calendar/2019/8/17/chaos-on-the-clyde-2"&gt;Chaos on the Clyde 2&lt;/a&gt; hosted in GRD's regular venue of the ARC in late August this year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read on for more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/chaos2019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>chaos on the clyde</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/chaos2019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 07:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>West Track Story: The Teams</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/05/west-track-story-the-teams/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Nantes Derby Girls' 5th edition of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/629986423840264/"&gt;West Track Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; coming up this weekend, we thought we'd make you a little guide to the teams competing in this WFTDA Recognised Tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the tournament is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/events/wftda-recognized-tournaments/"&gt;WFTDA Recognised&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, each bout will be Sanctioned, contributing to the teams' ranking for the important "Playoffs" rankings which decide which Division you make, if any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the tournament is WFTDA Recognised, WFTDA.TV is re-streaming the video - if you'd like to check the schedule in your timezone, we have a viewing guide here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/westtrackstory2017.html"&gt;https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/westtrackstory2017.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-17455 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/wts5.jpg" alt="WTS5" width="526" height="276"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Nantes Derby Girls&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17407" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/nantes.jpg" alt="nantes" width="200" height="200"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hosts Nantes are one of the stronger teams in Europe - ranked 24th by Flat Track Stats. Founded in September 2010, Nantes became a member of the the FFRS (the French Roller Sports Governing Body) in 2012, and a WFTDA Apprentice in 2013, with full WFTDA membership the usual year later.
Nantes have been running West Track Story since 2013, when it had just 4 teams attending; it soon grew to a 5 team event, with WFTDA "Official" status coming in 2016 for West Track Story IV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as West Track Story, which they have won 4 out of 5 times, Nantes also competes in the French National Championships, in the highest ("Elite") tier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nantes are currently ranked &lt;strong&gt;#144&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/rankings-february-28-2017/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;#155&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Mar-ranking.html"&gt;SRDRank&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and&lt;strong&gt; #24 &lt;/strong&gt;in&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/europe"&gt;Europe(FTS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4717" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/glasgow_roller_derby_3_color_logo.png?w=185" alt="Glasgow_Roller_Derby_3_Color_Logo" width="185" height="300"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first Roller Derby league in Scotland, GRD recently celebrated their 10th birthday, and we interviewed one of their founding members at the time. [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/04/10-years-of-roller-derby-in-glasgow-mistress-malicious-on-grds-10th/"&gt;READ MORE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]. Glasgow have been full WFTDA members since 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2015, Glasgow's B team attended West Track Story III, where they defeated Kallio B, but lost out to the Berlin B team and hosts Nantes narrowly, and to Amsterdam by a knife-edge (just 7 points).
Glasgow Roller Derby are the only team attending with a history of competing in both Europe and Internationally.
This year, it's Glasgow Roller Derby A attending, and they will be hoping to show that they're past their problems in the past year and back on track to start regaining WFTDA rank. In the past year, GRD have played none of the teams at West Track Story - although they played Gent way back in 2012, and won. Both teams have changed significantly since then, however!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow are currently ranked &lt;strong&gt;#195&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/rankings-february-28-2017/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;#307&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Mar-ranking.html"&gt;SRDRank&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and&lt;strong&gt; #51 &lt;/strong&gt;in&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/europe"&gt;Europe(FTS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;GO-GO Gent Roller Derby&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17411" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/gent.png" alt="Gent" width="200" height="200"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first Roller Derby league in Belgium, when they founded in late 2008 as "Gent Go-Go Roller Girls", the league rebranded to its current name in 2016. We miss the cats in their old logo. GO-GO Gent have been WFTDA members since 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gent host their own WFTDA Recognised European Tournament - A Skate Odyssey - since 2013, but this is the first time they've turned up at Nantes' event. As well as competing at SKOD each year, Gent play widely across Europe - in the past year, they played Dirty River, Nantes and Antwerp, all of whom managed to pull out wins. This time, Gent will be looking to show they can win, as they rebuild their ranking from 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gent are currently ranked &lt;strong&gt;#150&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/rankings-february-28-2017/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;#207&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Mar-ranking.html"&gt;SRDRank&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and&lt;strong&gt; #33 &lt;/strong&gt;in&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/europe"&gt;Europe(FTS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Dirty River Roller Derby&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17414" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/dirtyriver.jpg" alt="Dirtyriver" width="193" height="250"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hailing from Turku, Finland, and founded in 2010, Dirty River Roller Derby are named (fairly obviously) for the locally famous state of the river Aura which passes through the city, although they changed their name from "Grrrls" to "Derby" in 2014. The league have been full WFTDA members since 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as being strong competitors in the Finnish National Tournament (the Suomi Cup) since its founding (placing no lower than 4th in any year, and 2nd in 2015), Dirty River also compete across Europe, and played both Nantes and Gent in 2016 - losing to the former by only a pair of points, 215-213. Dirty River have been regular attendees at the (Gent-hosted) Skate Odyssey tournaments, but this is their first West Track Story.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="clearfix _ikh _3-8j"&gt;Dirty River are currently ranked &lt;strong&gt;#145&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/rankings-february-28-2017/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;#206&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Mar-ranking.html"&gt;SRDRank&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and&lt;strong&gt; #39 &lt;/strong&gt;in&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/europe"&gt;Europe(FTS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Antwerp Roller Derby / One Love Roller Dolls&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17417" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/antwerp.jpg" alt="antwerp" width="200" height="114"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antwerp Roller Derby, known better as One Love Roller Dolls, were founded in 2010, and joined WFTDA four years later in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular competitors (with Gent) at the Benelux region tournament, Skates of Glory (which One Love founded and host), One Love also compete across Europe. In the last year, they have played only Gent out of the competitors at West Track Story, beating them by just 6 points! One Love are currently on an upward trajectory in their rankings, and will be looking to continue that in this WFTDA Recognised tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antwerp are currently ranked &lt;strong&gt;#152&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/rankings-february-28-2017/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;#151&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/17-Mar-ranking.html"&gt;SRDRank&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and&lt;strong&gt; #22 &lt;/strong&gt;in&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/europe"&gt;Europe(FTS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dirty river roller derby</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>go-go gent roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>nantes derby girls</category><category>one love roller dolls</category><category>tournament</category><category>west track story</category><category>wftda recognised tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/05/west-track-story-the-teams/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 16:19:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>10 Years of Roller derby in Glasgow: Mistress Malicious on GRD's 10th.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/04/10-years-of-roller-derby-in-glasgow-mistress-malicious-on-grds-10th/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst 2001 is the official year in which the "Roller Derby revival" began, it took until around 2006 and 2007 until Roller Derby entered the UK. One of the first places that Roller Derby took seed was, of course, Glasgow - and &lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; are celebrating their 10th birthday this year with a massive &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1875166969385996/"&gt;triple-header event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; featuring newbie, coed and experienced bouts, starting from &lt;strong&gt;10:30&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt;.
The event, as always, is at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662012,-4.2516905,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8661982!4d-4.2494965"&gt;Glasgow ARC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at Glasgow Caledonian University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To celebrate this decade of Roller Derby in Glasgow, who better to interview than one of then-Glasgow-Roller-Girls founding member, Mistress Malicious?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style="border:1px;"&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WolAHlKpOUo&amp;amp;w=560&amp;amp;h=315]Glasgow's first ever international bout - back in 2008 - against "Team Canada", featuring Mistress Malicious.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;It seems especially significant to be talking to you as the sole remaining founder of Glasgow Roller Girls in Roller Derby, back in 2007. When you and Teri Toxic decided to start a roller derby league in Glasgow, what did you have in mind?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly I am no longer a member of GRD. I had planned on staying on as a retired skater but life has finally just got in the way. However, I do still keep some of my derby work on as the insurance honcho at UKRDA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look back at the start of Glasgow Roller Girls with a lot of fond memories. The overriding feeling was that that we were at the start of something that was going to be huge. We were sure that we had found something that we knew was amazing, but was still a secret. We just tried to spread the word about it because we were so sure that everyone would have to fall in love with it once they had experienced it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that nobody had any skating or sports organisation knowledge certainly wasn’t going to stop us in our mission!
&lt;strong&gt;As the first league in Scotland (and only the 5th in the UK), Glasgow Roller Girls/Derby were there for most of the important and exciting formative moments in the sport in Europe - you played Canada as one of your first bouts, competed in the first European tournament ever, co-founded UKRDA, all before 2011! What have been the high points for you, personally, over the last decade?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I think of high points its usually events from the early days, I guess that’s because we were so naive and still finding our way so any little success felt like a major achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember our first practices, and reading emails from coaches from London containing skating advice and drills to practice, and everyone was trying to figure out what on earth they were meaning. At that time there was virtually nothing that could be found online, or any nearby teams to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;London Roller Girls coming up to Glasgow when we were around 6 months old to give us a free weekend bootcamp with Bette Noir imparting all her derby knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone travelling to watch London Rockin Rollers and Birmingham Blitz Dames in the first UK interleague game, which included an arm wrestling penalty competition for actual points. Our first game against BBD also included a backwards skating competition with the winner's team earning 10 points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Playing our first game against London Roller Girls. We arrived with one set of helmet covers as we didn't even know we could have more, I don't think we had ever practiced more than one jam in a row!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UKRDA getting roller derby recognised as a sport after having to fight the whole way to get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, to get soppy for a moment, a high point is just what we have achieved with our sport. I consider myself an enthusiastic derby busybody but here have been many many others over the past 10 years and we have all volunteered our time through our passion and love for our sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Roller Girls skaters, including you, formed about half of the first ever Scottish National Team, back in 2011. How did it feel for you, and your fellow skaters from GRG, to represent Scotland on the world stage?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think everyone would have to agree that it was an amazing experience. An opportunity to say that you have represented your country is not to be forgotten. The whole team kneeling singing ‘O flower of Scotland’ would still bring a tear to a glass eye. And who can forget Sarah Oates’ one point against Team USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And now, ten years after that initial decision to start a Roller Derby team… what do you see in the Future of Glasgow Roller Derby, and for yourself as a member?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not a member anymore but the future of Glasgow Roller Derby, as it always has been, is in the hands of its membership and whatever direction they decide to take it. That will depend on whatever its current derby busybodies are going to volunteer their time to get done. I’m sure that [Marshall] Lawless is still determined to finally get that GRD warehouse and, I don’t think it's any secret, but I would love for there to be a GRD Juniors one day...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Glasgow Roller Derby 10th Birthday event is bookable here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/events-calendar/2017/1/26/grd-10-year-anniversary"&gt;http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/events-calendar/2017/1/26/grd-10-year-anniversary&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;at just &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; for the event, or &lt;strong&gt;£7&lt;/strong&gt; for the event and roller disco afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The afterparty will be held at the EuroHostel Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>glasgow roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/04/10-years-of-roller-derby-in-glasgow-mistress-malicious-on-grds-10th/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 20:55:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow's Magnificent 7s ride out!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/13/glasgows-magnificent-7s-ride-out/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned in our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/21/upcoming-bouts-special-jan-2017-edition/"&gt;January round-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the only announced bouts in Scotland in January are in the last two weeks of the month. In fact, by far the larger event is the closer, as the &lt;strong&gt;21st&lt;/strong&gt; sees Glasgow Roller Derby bringing &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1209413072459985/"&gt;Derby Se7ens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to Scotland for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Sur5al, which Glasgow have also hosted previously, Se7ens is a condensed Derby format, inspired by Rugby Sevens which is a very successful variant of the Union game - the first Sevens tournament was held by Essex Men's Roller Derby, and is now an annual event. The benefit, of course, is that you can get more teams to compete in less time, and hence possibly have a higher density of fun. It's also an ideal way for skaters to ease themselves back onto track, before the competitive season really gets going...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experimenting with the Derby Se7ens format to add even more 7s, the Magnificent 7s event sees 7 teams of 7 skaters each play 7 minutes of derby against each other (for a total of 21 bouts, and 147 minutes) to determine the victor*.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To celebrate this inaugural issue of what might become an annual event, GRD have also worked with well-known Scottish Derby photographer, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://boutday.com/"&gt;Dave McAleavy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;to produce this themed poster:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13843 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/7s-2.jpg" alt="7s-2" width="400" height="560"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is often the case with these intense formats, the event has drawn in a wide representation of skaters, with the following teams submitted:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How The West Was Won&lt;/strong&gt; [in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;Black&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] - Team Scotland Roller Derby's entry, an epic mixture of ARRG and GRD skaters from the National Team's Training Squad.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soy Division&lt;/strong&gt; [in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#ffffff;background-color:#999999;"&gt;White&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] - Skaters from the Soy Division vegan exhibition team, including GRD and New Town.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hateful 7&lt;/strong&gt; [in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;Green&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] - a mix of Fierce Valley, Bairn City, and Auld Reekie skaters, discounted from Tarantino's efforts.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/strong&gt; [in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#ff6600;"&gt;Orange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] - Granite City Brawlers' representation, the northernmost team all the way from Aberdeen.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Seven Deadly Spins&lt;/strong&gt; [in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;Blue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] - a mix of mysterious skaters operating under pseudonyms. We're not sure which one is Wrath, but we don't really want to find out!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean City&lt;/strong&gt; [in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;Red&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] - Mean City Roller Derby's finest skate out to serve justice.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GMRD&lt;/strong&gt; [in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800080;"&gt;Purple&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] - Glasgow Men's Roller Derby... or  in this context, Gringos from Mexican Ranch, Dudes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;11am&lt;/strong&gt; with the first game set to begin at 11.30am, and are hosted, as always, at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662153,-4.2519289,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8662153!4d-4.2497349"&gt;ARC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at Glasgow Caledonian University.
Tickets are &lt;strong&gt;£8&lt;/strong&gt; in advance (from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/event-tickets/the-magnificent-7s-1"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and &lt;strong&gt;£10&lt;/strong&gt; on the door, which is still less than 50p a bout...
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*The conventional Derby Sevens, as run by Essex Mens, has 21 minute games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>derby sevens</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/13/glasgows-magnificent-7s-ride-out/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 09:55:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow cross the Irish Sea: Dublin v Irn Bruisers</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/25/glasgow-cross-the-irish-sea-dublin-v-irn-bruisers/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dublin Roller Derby have been a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; busy league this year - earlier on, as we &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/01/europe-goes-to-beach-brawl/"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, they joined Auld Reekie and Newcastle at Gold Coast's Beach Brawl in Florida. Last weekend, they went across to play Middlesbrough Milk Rollers and Hot Wheel Roller Derby [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/21/european-roller-derby-22-october-update/"&gt;as we reported in our roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]. This weekend (as we will be reporting), they're hosting a triple-header for their B-team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And on &lt;strong&gt;November&lt;/strong&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;5th&lt;/strong&gt;, they're &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/299480537069476/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; again, as Glasgow Roller Derby travel across to Ireland to take them on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-10493" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14724154_1255954684466870_1555950462_o.jpg" alt="14724154_1255954684466870_1555950462_o" width="1284" height="2048"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow have had a difficult year, and Dublin Roller Derby are flush with increased confidence after their performance in the US: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85892/rankings"&gt;predicts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; a 90% win probability for the home team. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/08/ranking-the-world-and-other-fts-visualisations/2"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (using the 1 October rankings*) agrees, and also concurs with FTS's approximate prediction that Dublin should score about 70 to 75% of the total points. That said, Glasgow's Irn Bruisers have been working hard to rebuild, and they may still surprise us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;12pm&lt;/strong&gt; for 1pm start. Hosted at Dublin Roller Derby's usual venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Shoreline+Leisure+Greystones/@53.136466,-6.067257,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4867af24e2419651:0x45f0195e8da6d900!8m2!3d53.136466!4d-6.065063"&gt;Shoreline Leisure Greystones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Dublin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets: &lt;strong&gt;€7&lt;/strong&gt; (under 16's free, accompanied) on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Our next ranking calculation will use the 1 November data, but it obviously can't exist yet. We'll update our prediction here before the bout!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/25/glasgow-cross-the-irish-sea-dublin-v-irn-bruisers/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 18:07:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Science v Magic: Twice in one month!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/09/science-v-magic-twice-in-one-month/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've previously mentioned that Glasgow Roller Derby are hosting an exhibition double header on the 20th of the this month, featuring a Science v Fantasy themed B-feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if you like the idea of pitting SF against F, then you don't even have to wait that long, as Glasgow's only Coed league, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby/"&gt;Mean City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, are holding their own &lt;em&gt;coed&lt;/em&gt; extravaganza this weekend (&lt;strong&gt;13th August, 2pm&lt;/strong&gt;) as the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1807206382885256/"&gt;Wizards take on Gallifrey's finest Timelords.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;This is an opportunity to see both established MCRD skaters, as well as their newest up-and-coming skaters in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-8598" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/08/13653353_836734026463019_2149065422421141685_o.jpg?w=2048" alt="13653353_836734026463019_2149065422421141685_o" width="1024" height="724"&gt; Just one of four (4!) posters that Mean City produced for the event!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event will be at Mean City's usual venue, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662153,-4.2519236,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8662153!4d-4.2497349"&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Glasgow, with afterparty at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Rufus+T+Firefly/@55.8635334,-4.2600056,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48884420befd257d:0xff9a66f3090f61a0!8m2!3d55.8635594!4d-4.257813"&gt;Rufus T Firefly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. (Links above link to maps.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advance warning also: the following week (&lt;strong&gt;2oth August&lt;/strong&gt;) features a bit of a clash. As well as the aforementioned &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/550878811750965/"&gt;Soy Division v Vagine Regime/Science v Fantasy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; double header in &lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;, there will also be a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/972951379480637/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls / Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; joint double header in &lt;strong&gt;Grangemouth&lt;/strong&gt;! As the second bout in the schedule features the long anticipated rematch of Bairn City's Skelpies against Tyne and Fear B (the Inglorious B**stards), it seems that both events have unmissable second fixtures...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's &lt;em&gt;possible&lt;/em&gt;, based on the preliminary timings, to just about see the first bout in Glasgow, and then rush across Scotland by car to get to Grangemouth in time for both bouts, but we're not sure we'd risk it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The approximate timings are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First bout (&lt;strong&gt;Science v Fantasy&lt;/strong&gt;) at Glasgow, skateouts start &lt;strong&gt;13:05&lt;/strong&gt; (implies end around &lt;strong&gt;14:30&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second bout (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/SoyDivisionDerby/?fref=ts"&gt;Soy Division&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;/&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GayRobots/?fref=ts"&gt;Vagine Regime&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt; ends &lt;strong&gt;17:10?&lt;/strong&gt; (which implies a &lt;strong&gt;15:45&lt;/strong&gt; start, or earlier depending on slack?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First bout at Grangemouth (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://fvrg.co.uk"&gt;FVRG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; intraleague) starts &lt;strong&gt;15:30&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second bout (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers/?fref=ts"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;' Skelpies v &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/tyneandfear/?fref=ts"&gt;Tyne and Fear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; B) starts &lt;strong&gt;17:20&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes around 40 minutes to get from the centre of Glasgow to the centre of Grangemouth, so it should, hypothetically, be possible to see all of the mixed bout at Glasgow, jump in a car, and arrive &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; 20 minutes before the first game starts in Grangemouth. Assuming that derby runs to time, which is, of course, not something we can ever rely on, and that our guesses about the timings are correct... ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>annoucements</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>soy division</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>vagine regime uk</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/09/science-v-magic-twice-in-one-month/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 11:15:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Meanwhile, in Scotland...</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/10/meanwhile-in-scotland/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regular readers will have noticed that we've had something of a diversion from our regular content recently, as the second Men's Roller Derby World Cup, in Calgary, approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, exciting derby hasn't stopped in Scotland, or Europe, so we should catch up on what's coming more locally...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-8166 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/12654276_631717886965980_4588037546842024195_n.jpg" alt="12654276_631717886965980_4588037546842024195_n" width="784" height="295"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who'd like a Roller Derby extravaganza a little closer than Calgary, or Las Vegas, this week sees the very first &lt;a href="http://www.euroderbycon.com/"&gt;Euro Derby Con&lt;/a&gt;, styling itself the "1st Annual European Roller Derby Convention". Organised by Track Advantage, the con will feature plenty of on-track action (including both sanctioned games and more eclectic challenge bouts), as well as off-track seminars and plenty of vendors in the shopping area. Euro Derby Con is in Barcelona, Spain from the &lt;strong&gt;14th&lt;/strong&gt; to the &lt;strong&gt;17th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;July&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope to have feedback and reports from this exciting event from attendees after it completes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-8164 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/school-of-arrg-knocks5.jpg" alt="School-of-ARRG-Knocks5" width="608" height="430"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even more locally, &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; are holding their 5th "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/promotion/the-school-of-arrg-knocks-roller-derby-bootcamp-is-back/"&gt;School of ARRG Knocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" bootcamp on the &lt;strong&gt;16th&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;17th&lt;/strong&gt;, now featuring both co-ed multitiered training (with slots for pre-mins, intermediate and advanced skaters), and a "Sur5al style" tournament on the Sunday afternoon. It seems that tickets are still available, at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://soak5.bpt.me/"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (be sure to pick the tier of ticket you want, there's quite a few options!).
ARRG also have their traditional Fringe events coming up soon, this time featuring a double header against Dundee Roller Girls and Glasgow Roller Derby. Check it out on &lt;strong&gt;August 6th&lt;/strong&gt;, at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/promotion/battle-of-scotland-festival-fringe-double-header/"&gt;event page here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.wix.com/thedrg"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;, they're also in the teaching zone, with their second "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1696079833978398/"&gt;Open Learning Scrims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" of the month, on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 15th&lt;/strong&gt; at their usual venue of the Dundee International Sports Centre. And if you have the taste for bootcamps later on, look out for DRG's first ever Post-Mins bootcamp, "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1769982133234846/"&gt;Skate Tay Victory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" in September!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; also have a busy &lt;strong&gt;August&lt;/strong&gt; planned, following up their challenge against Auld Reekie above with a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/events-calendar/2016/8/20/mixed-teams-double-header-vr-vs-soy-division-plus-science-vs-fantasy"&gt;double header exhibition extravaganza&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;20th&lt;/strong&gt;, which will see Soy Division (the UK's Vegan derby exhibition team) take on Vagine Regime UK (the UK's L(G)BT derby exhibition team), followed by a "Science v Fantasy" themed bout. Glasgow Roller Derby has quite a few skaters in both Soy Division and Vagine Regime UK, so this will be a pretty interesting bout to see...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...but Glasgow's next official bout will be the week after, as their B and C teams (the Maiden Grrders and Canny Gingers) travel all the way up to Aberdeen on the &lt;strong&gt;27th&lt;/strong&gt; to take on &lt;a href="http://www.granitecityrollerderby.co.uk/"&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s Northern Fights and Fight Hawks in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1717081471898842/"&gt;another double header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the midst of all this excitement, we should also note that &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; are also not resting; with Preston Roller Girls hosting the last round of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/454153454770970/"&gt;British Championships Tier 3 North&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, FVRG will be taking on the hosts (and Dundee taking on Hallam Hellcats) to decide the final places on the &lt;strong&gt;17th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;July&lt;/strong&gt;. These are especially important games for both Scottish teams, in opposite directions: Fierce Valley need to win against Preston to move up from the bottom of the table, while a Dundee win against Hallam will give them a good shot at taking the &lt;em&gt;top&lt;/em&gt; of the table from incumbents Manchester!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FVRG will be hosting themselves a month later, as &lt;strong&gt;18th August&lt;/strong&gt; sees the return of their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1385457658148117/"&gt;Charity Co-Ed Scrims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all the derby we are aware of in July and August... but there's exciting things afoot in September as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>scotland</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/10/meanwhile-in-scotland/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 21:09:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>June 11th's Packed Scottish Derby Schedule...</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The weekend of the 11th is another extravaganza for high level Scottish Roller Derby, with both Auld Reekie Roller Girls and Glasgow Roller Derby engaged in multiple bouts across the weekend, and Fierce Valley playing away in the continuing British Champs Tier 3 North fixtures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Glasgow and Fierce Valley playing away, the Scottish home games are happening at Auld Reekie's traditional venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Meadowbank+Sports+Centre/@55.956622,-3.1585026,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4887b86eb150070f:0x6955a8c9b9a10cc5!8m2!3d55.956619!4d-3.1563086"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, doors open at &lt;strong&gt;2:20pm Saturday 11th&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-7441" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13235130_10156950736565224_2994993262049877442_o.jpg?w=1024" alt="13235130_10156950736565224_2994993262049877442_o" width="1024" height="385"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heading up &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/350352705088707/"&gt;the double-header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Auld Reekie's All-Stars are taking on Kallio Rolling Rainbow, one of Finland's finest teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After their usual impressive performance at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-big-o-2016-schedule-timezones/"&gt;The Big O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Oregon, Auld Reekie are riding high, ready for another challenge - Kallio are slightly higher ranked than they are (FlatTrackStats &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/79684/rankings"&gt;predicts a win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the Finns, albeit with some uncertainty). This will be a WFTDA Sanctioned bout and contribute to both teams' rankings, so it will be an especially hard-fought contest, as both teams will want to reach Division 1 (or remain in Division 2) of the WFTDA Rankings in order to qualify for Playoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other bout is no less exciting in its own way, marking the debut of ARRG's new 'C'-team, the 'All-Star Rookies'&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/#sup"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as they take on Granite City Roller Girls B, the Fight Hawks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, with a team debut, it's hard to make predictions as to the result of the bout; this will be a contest between Auld Reekie's new skater training and the experience gained by the Fight Hawks over the last year. (Having seen some of ARRG's rookies in "rising stars" bouts in the last few months, however, there's some very impressive performers there...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets on the door will be £8 (just £4 per bout), or £5 online via &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2553305"&gt;BrownPaperTickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Concessions tickets will be just £6 on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Glasgow Roller Derby are apparently the stars of the show down in Oldham, as Rainy City Roller Derby are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://rainycityrollerderby.com/event/euro-weekender/"&gt;hosting a weekend of derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, in which Glasgow feature in 3 out of 4 bouts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a Scotland versus Wales playoff, Glasgow's A team, the Irn Bruisers, will be taking on Tiger Bay Brawlers' A; and their B team, the Maiden Grrders will also be facing off against TBB's B-Bombs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FlatTrackStats predicts an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/7953/7929"&gt;incredibly closely-matched bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; between the A-teams (the result depends on which team you give "home-team advantage" to). The B-teams are almost as close in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/10262/11067"&gt;FTS's predictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, although it looks like their stats very narrowly favour the Welsh team (albeit by only a few percent). With only one exception, match-ups between GRD and TBB have been hard-fought, high-level affairs, so we do anticipate some great derby here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Rainy City Roller Derby are scheduled against simply "Glasgow Roller Derby", which we might guess is the A team... Last time they faced each other, Glasgow came out with a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/59869"&gt;convincing win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;; but Glasgow's significant team changes this year have FTS &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/10262/11067"&gt;predicting a win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the home team this time around. Glasgow will have to pull out something special to keep the win record on their side...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the rankings of Tiger Bay Brawlers A, and Rainy City Roller Derby, these bouts also fill in a chunk of the higher-level UK matchups missing from British Champs this year. With the results from these games, we'll be publishing an "extended" BC Tier 1 ranking, extrapolating where some of the teams not competing in T1 might have ended up, this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[On the Sunday, Kallio Roller Derby are also featuring in this derby weekend, so presumably there's some exciting train travel in Kallio's Sunday morning schedule...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://britishchamps.com"&gt;British Champs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, after an extended period &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/17/british-champs-at-dundee/"&gt;hosted in Scotland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the Tier 3 North fixtures continue in the North of England, with Hallam Hellcats hosting a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/587023974805101/"&gt;double-header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of bouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7445" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13267947_1010255862421996_6895825634478283487_n.jpg" alt="13267947_1010255862421996_6895825634478283487_n" width="530" height="750"&gt; Hallam's bout poster was also available as a limited edition physical print! (Design by Ed Syder) &lt;a href="http://edsyder.tumblr.com/"&gt;http://edsyder.tumblr.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hosts will be taking on Preston Roller Girls, while Scotland will be represented by Fierce Valley Roller Girls taking on Manchester Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FVRG will be hard pressed to defeat currently unbeaten Manchester, but a loss will keep them at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/womens-tables-2016/"&gt;bottom of the table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and in danger of relegation. Meanwhile, Hallam and Preston will be fighting it out to avoid the second-from-bottom spot in the table - there's not much to call between them, but FTS believes that home-team advantage gives the hosts &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/25963/8972"&gt;a slight edge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="sup"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;the Auld Reekie current team naming scheme is a bit confusing - the A team are simply "All-Stars", whilst the B team append "Reserves" and the C team "Rookies". This makes it a bit hard to unambiguously form acronyms for the two, but we're working on this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>auldreekierollergirls</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>fvrg</category><category>gcrd</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>hallam hellcats roller derby</category><category>kallio rolling rainbow</category><category>manchester roller derby</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 11:04:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow to pack May with events!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/28/glasgow-to-pack-may-with-events/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s Irn Bruisers taking a short break after completing their fixtures for British Champs, that doesn't mean that the league are slowing down in other areas. In fact, this May looks like being busier than the previous months in terms of events!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/28/glasgow-to-pack-may-with-events/queeri/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-7190"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7190" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/queeri.jpg" alt="queeri" width="500" height="353"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, &lt;strong&gt;May 7th&lt;/strong&gt; sees the return of GRD's popular Queerosity night from earlier in the year, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/events-calendar/2016/5/7/queeriosity-2-90s-grunge-queer-night-with-grd"&gt;this time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with a 90s Grunge feel. The night will run from &lt;strong&gt;7:30pm&lt;/strong&gt; to midnight, at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Garnethill+Multicultural+Centre/@55.8662629,-4.2637716,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x48884426c0484e89:0x5c326c655662014c"&gt;Garnethill Multicultural Centre,&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and tickets are available for just &lt;strong&gt;£2&lt;/strong&gt; online (£3 on the door)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, on &lt;strong&gt;May 21&lt;/strong&gt;, GRD B, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/events-calendar/2016/5/21/double-header-maiden-grrders-vs-amiens-roller-derby-irn-bruisers-vs-middlesbrough-milk-rollers"&gt;Maiden Grrders, will be taking on Blackpool Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Blackpool have had quite a Scottish theme for their year already, having sent a team to the Fierce Valley hosted sur5al and, of course, been both hosted and competed against by Aberdeen's Granite City Roller Derby in Tier 4 of British Champs.
This bout sees the Blackpool Roller Coasters play their toughest opponents yet; the Maiden Grrders are higher ranked than any of the teams in Tier 4 North!
The bout will be held in Glasgow's traditional venue, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662153,-4.2519289,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7"&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at Glasgow Caledonian University, starting at &lt;strong&gt;midday&lt;/strong&gt;. Tickets will be the usual &lt;strong&gt;£6&lt;/strong&gt; online, or a little more on the door.
&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/28/glasgow-to-pack-may-with-events/bootcamp/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-7191"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7191" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/bootcamp.jpg" alt="bootcamp" width="500" height="355"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the jewel of the May schedule comes the day after, as London Brawling's Stefanie Mainey will be holding &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/events-calendar/2016/5/22/grd-presents-bootcamp-with-stefanie-mainey"&gt;a Co-ed Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, hosted by GRD on &lt;strong&gt;May 22nd&lt;/strong&gt;.
To take advantage of her considerable experience as both a coach and skater in one of the top 4 roller derby teams in the World, this will be an Intermediate Skills bootcamp.
Tickets for offskates observers are also available, at a reduced rate (&lt;strong&gt;£25&lt;/strong&gt; versus &lt;strong&gt;£50&lt;/strong&gt; for onskates).
Hosted at the ARC, the bootcamp will fill the afternoon from &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt; to 5.45.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>blackpool roller derby</category><category>bootcamps</category><category>events</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>london rollergirls</category><category>roller derby bootcamps</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/28/glasgow-to-pack-may-with-events/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 09:52:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls head stateside to play world’s best roller derby teams</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/19/auld-reekie-roller-girls-head-stateside-to-play-worlds-best-roller-derby-teams/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/e041c-1458243751815.jpg" alt=""&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARRG’s All Stars will jet to America to take on some of the most talented roller derby teams on the planet later this month.
Edinburgh’s top-rated team has secured a coveted place in the three-day &lt;a href="http://ecrg.com/bigo/"&gt;Big O &lt;/a&gt;tournament in Oregon on the west coast.
This will be a whole weekend of roller derby played at the very highest skill level.
Nearly 40 teams will compete, including Team USA and six of the top 10 women’s teams in the world.
Despite an unbeaten record in 2016, the team are under no illusions as to the sizable challenge that awaits them in Oregon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Stars co-captain Crazylegs said the team were travelling across the Atlantic for the challenge of playing higher ranked teams and to improve their WFTDA ranking position: it wasn't possible for the All Stars to secure any games against the D1 teams in Europe this season.
She said: “Competing in The Big O is huge for ARRG. It's one of the best tournaments out there, and it’s a massive opportunity for us, not only to play some of the best derby around but to improve our international ranking.
“It’s also a fantastic challenge as we are set to play four teams who are ranked as high as 20 places above us.
“Over three days we’ll be playing really experienced, well-practiced teams of a level we've probably not come against in recent times.
“We will face teams like original WFTDA member league Windy City (Chicago) who have been playing at the highest tournament levels since before our team existed!
“We hope that if we perform well enough we'll make it to WFTDA Play Offs this year - it was hard missing out by one point last season!
“To get that experience would be really good for our skaters, who also coach the rest of the league, so as always, we'll be passing along everything we learn."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://ecrg.com/bigo/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2015/10/THE-BIG-O_White_AS.png" alt="" width="498" height="210"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year will be the second time ARRG has travelled to the Big O. Crazylegs said the sport court skating surface had been difficult to get used to last time, so the whole team has attended special training sessions in Oldham earlier this year to prepare for the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said: “The sport court flooring does offer unique challenges, it can be unpredictable if you're not used to it - you can slide out with no warning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This year we've had a couple of 10 hour round bus trips to Oldham specifically to train on the Rainy City sport court track - we're really grateful for their support in letting us use their venue.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge though will be for the team to hold their focus against the top tier teams, Crazylegs added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"It will be a huge test to hold our focus against these tough teams when things maybe don't go our way and to keep calm and together,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’ve trained incredibly hard, developed some new approaches to our game, aiming to play smarter and consolidating key tactics. We are ready for the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Whatever happens, we're stoked to be there and we will bring the full might of Auld Reekie to the US in every game we play. We’ll get the outcomes we want from this tournament."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://arrg.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/ARRG-Logo-1024x477.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to support your local team and help Auld Reekie get to America, you can chuck us a couple of quid at the following link: &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/sponsors/donate/"&gt;http://arrg.co.uk/sponsors/donate/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazing special edition ARRG Big O merchandise is available from ARRG skater and Interplanetary Syndicate owner Jenny Gow: &lt;a href="http://www.printsyndicate.co.uk/"&gt;http://www.printsyndicate.co.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you a derby skater or official who wants to play in America yourself some day? Some of Auld Reekie’s finest skaters will be coaching at the ‘School of ARRG Knocks 5’ and SOAK5Val roller derby bootcamp at Meadowbank in Edinburgh on Saturday and Sunday May 14 and 15, where ARRG coaches will teach you everything they learned at the Big O.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;Tickets available at &lt;a href="http://soak5.bpt.me/"&gt;http://soak5.bpt.me/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://scontent.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpl1/v/t1.0-9/12985395_10156787669390224_6608699264420207234_n.jpg?oh=27c8d83d0b1cba4da9f1916ded5ebbc4&amp;amp;oe=57C09F0C" alt=""&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those interested in following Auld Reekie's progression in The Big O can do so via our handy timezone adjusted schedule: &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-big-o-2016-schedule-timezones/"&gt;scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-big-o-2016-schedule-timezones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all stars</category><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>big o</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/19/auld-reekie-roller-girls-head-stateside-to-play-worlds-best-roller-derby-teams/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 09:53:44 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>