<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about glasgow men's roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/glasgow-mens-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Glasgow ready to rock as British Champs T3 goes down to the wire</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/06/glasgow-ready-to-rock-as-british-champs-t3-goes-down-to-the-wire/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't stop believing&lt;/strong&gt; - that's the tune blasting out at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GlasgowMensRollerDerby/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; HQ where the Irn Brn are plotting a derby escape act which would make Houdini hop the apex with delight.
&lt;p&gt;This Saturday, GMRD play host to the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/133440747209468/?acontext=%7B%22ref%22%3A%222%22%2C%22ref_dashboard_filter%22%3A%22upcoming%22%2C%22action_history%22%3A%22%5B%7B%5C%22surface%5C%22%3A%5C%22dashboard%5C%22%2C%5C%22mechanism%5C%22%3A%5C%22main_list%5C%22%2C%5C%22extra_data%5C%22%3A%5B%5D%7D%5D%22%7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;final fixtures in the British Championships' Men's Tier 3 - Regional North group&lt;/a&gt; (at Glasgow's ARC Sports Centre).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD will be taking on their Celtic cousins, Men Behaving Derby (MBD), while Bairn City Rollers' Skelpies will be setting blasters to stun against Teesside Skate Invaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a decidedly Scottish-type twist, only a specific combination of results can now see GMRD qualify for the play-offs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the uninitiated, here's the short story:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April, GMRD travelled to Dublin to play the Skate Invaders, winning by 234 points to 167. GMRD were later denuded of victory due to an eligibility malfunction, with the score becoming 200-0 in favour of the Invaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD's next game against the Skelpies was then forfeited by the Falkirk team due to lack of numbers - a 200-0 win in favour of GMRD - leaving the table looking like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-20255 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/brd-table.jpg" alt="BRD table" width="1014" height="650"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, GMRD need to beat MBD on Saturday - that's a pre-requisite if GMRD want a play-off place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regardless of what flavour that victory lollipop is, the Irn Brn need to be sucking on it by Saturday evening.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Skelpies win against the Invaders then victory of any variety will be enough for the Glasgow mob.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if the Invaders win &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; GMRD win then the three top teams will be tied on six points and it goes down to scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD would need to have a better points differential than MBD to qualify for the play-offs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't worry about crunching the numbers, SRD Blog has done it for you - &lt;strong&gt;GMRD need to beat MBD by over 123 points to be certain of a play-off place.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That isn't going to be any kind of easy as MBD have already beaten both the Skelpies and the Skate Invaders this season, the latter with just 6 players!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's why Hugs &amp;amp; Kisses - GMRD's President - is sounding the rallying horn to the Irn Brn faithful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We need everyone in the West of Scotland and beyond to come out and support Saturday's double-header," he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-20254" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/18768309_10209728094985432_4231219290125343973_o.jpg" alt="18768309_10209728094985432_4231219290125343973_o" width="1600" height="1067"&gt; The Irn Brn - photo by Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"This is an amazing first for our city - a British Champs men's game at the home of Glasgow derby, the ARC sportscentre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"You are going to see two gallus games of roller derby, with the fate of three teams hanging in the balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Come out and support the Irn Brn as we attempt the great escape. We're confident we can put on a great show - don't stop believing, ken?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* Doors open at the ARC sportscentre, Glasgow, on Saturday (10 June) at 11.30am. Tickets cost £7. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/133440747209468/?acontext=%7B%22ref%22%3A%222%22%2C%22ref_dashboard_filter%22%3A%22upcoming%22%2C%22action_history%22%3A%22%5B%7B%5C%22surface%5C%22%3A%5C%22dashboard%5C%22%2C%5C%22mechanism%5C%22%3A%5C%22main_list%5C%22%2C%5C%22extra_data%5C%22%3A%5B%5D%7D%5D%22%7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Click here for more information.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teeside Skate Invaders vs Bairn City Skelpies - first whistle at 11:45&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby vs Men Behaving Derby - first whistle at 2pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>men behaving derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>teeside skate invaders</category><category>the skelpies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/06/glasgow-ready-to-rock-as-british-champs-t3-goes-down-to-the-wire/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 16:02:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire, steel and friendship - Irn Brn set sail for uncharted waters</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/22/fire-steel-and-friendship-irn-brn-set-sail-for-uncharted-waters/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The West of Scotland is renowned for forging some of the most iconic vessels and cultural objects in the world - from the QE2 to red phone boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should come as no surprise then that UK roller derby's newest team should have its roots in the industrial heart of Scotland - where history was literally forged from fire and steel - or that they call themselves the Irn Brn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby (GMRD) have already gone on a remarkable journey since they first sparked into life last summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16509" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/16825840_1347219638657375_3488843192256158535_o.jpg" alt="16825840_1347219638657375_3488843192256158535_o" width="1500" height="991"&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Duncolm-Sports-Photography-199762020069815/" target="_blank"&gt;Photo by Duncolm Sports Photography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone involved in roller derby will know that the tectonic plates beneath our sport are always moving - teams rise, teams fall, legacies are secured, old legends fade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some skaters drift away from the sport for good - others depart teams to form new alliances as they seek different horizons and chase different goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the case with the founding fathers - and mothers - of GMRD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the centre of the league is an ethos - like the nucleus at the heart of an atom - attracting skaters to it like toe-stop-hopping protons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skate, create, innovate - work hard together with friends to take on the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD pride themselves on being more than the sum of their talented parts (the roster includes a range of international-standard skaters - including seven members of the Power of Scotland training squad).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than a league, more than a team - this is a family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Irn Brn set sail next month for uncharted territory for a Scottish men's team - the 2017 British Roller Derby Championships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD will play in Men's Tier 3 North - alongside the Bairn City Skelpies (also breaking new ground for Scottish dudes), Teesside Skate Invaders and Men Behaving Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up on April 16 is a trip to the Emerald Isle, where GMRD take on the Skate Invaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD Managing Director Hugs and Kisses (aka JR) said: "We can't wait to get on track at the British Champs - it's going to be an adventure for everyone associated with GMRD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Teesside will be tough opponents and we are preparing for a very competitive game against a talented team of top skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"However, we know we have a strong team and have been training hard. It's going to be a great opening day of derby for Tier 3 North."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of GMRD have played Teesside before as members of other teams, but there have been line-up changes since then and the standard of derby is forever climbing skywards, so it will be an intriguing match-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD will be buoyed by a good run of form which saw them beat Crash Test Brummies B (Beta Test Brummies) 199-135 and Barrow Infernos 226-159.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the double-header in Dublin, the action will move to Grangemouth on May 13, when GMRD take on the Skelpies at Grangemouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third double-header will be hosted by GMRD at the ARC Sportscentre in Glasgow on June 10, with GMRD completing their fixtures with a game against Men Behaving Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top two teams in Tier 3 North will then play the two teams in Tier 3 South, with the victors of each game promoted to Tier 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugs added: "We're under no illusions - this is going to be a tough series of games, but we really can't wait. This is what we've been working hard towards since we formed the league last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Teamwork will be key. We have some very skilled individuals within the team, but our goal is to be a cohesive unit firing on all cylinders - forged in the heat of intense training sessions, scrims and games."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/GlasgowMensRollerDerby" target="_blank"&gt;Check out GMRD on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for all the latest information on games, bootcamps and special events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-16516 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/16807827_10212367238320133_3797769164188759663_n.jpg" alt="16807827_10212367238320133_3797769164188759663_n" width="960" height="424"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/22/fire-steel-and-friendship-irn-brn-set-sail-for-uncharted-waters/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 13:28:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lannthrax Talks to: Wintourope Glasgow edition</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/16/lannthrax-talks-to-wintourope-glasgow-edition/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So if you were at the Glasgow edition of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1717432861812471/"&gt;Wintourope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, you should probably by now, know your Toe Stop Pop from your Zip Zap Zop. If not, then I'm sorry, all I have for you is an interview with the lovely coaches. Scald Eagle and Lady Trample took the time to chat with me and I must admit, I felt like a fan-girl. These guys are two of my favourite skaters to watch and I'm so glad I got this opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13937 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/wintourope.jpg" alt="wintourope" width="960" height="354"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lanna&lt;/strong&gt;- “ How do you guys deal with the fame attribution that comes along with being at the top level within the sport?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scald&lt;/strong&gt;- “First of all, Fame is fleeting. What might be hot now might be day-old news next week. Saying that, I will always do my best regardless of status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The derby fame is something that you just have to deal with; I can still walk into a 7/11 and no one knows who I am, but you wouldn't see Lebron James walk into a 7/11. However, if I walk in to Rollercon, that’s a different story. Sometimes it’s hard to just make it to the bathroom and back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what I've really worked on is to put time aside and do what needs to be done but also make sure I have time to do what I need to do. It's great though: I am more than happy to have those interactions and I love it. It feels just like yesterday for me that I was waiting in line to get stuff signed and having people that I looked up to. I have a lot of patience for it and I love to do it”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trample&lt;/strong&gt;- “ One of the interesting things about, it is there is a level of responsibility, you have to be careful about what you put in the public eye. You are so accessible through social media. However, it also gives you a chance to do things for the community and opportunities to travel and share your knowledge, which I think Isn't really a thing you would see in other sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lanna&lt;/strong&gt;- “ Mental resilience is something that I personally have struggled with, how do you guys switch off that part of your brain and just get the job done?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trample&lt;/strong&gt;- “It’s something that comes with time; I had a really great coach this year and the main thing he would say to me is to back myself, so much so that I actually got a tattoo of it. It’s a nice memento that I can take with me to remind myself that I've worked hard and to trust my instincts, my pack, my offence, defence and my coaches. If your team are putting you on the line, they believe in you. It takes a little bit of self belief: I played some of my hardest games last year and once I got on that line I just had to remind myself that I've done all the training and to just let it all come into motion”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scald&lt;/strong&gt;- “I think that's where I'm at. In gameplay my cognitive part switches off and my instincts take over, I let my muscle memory do its thing. I don't know how often I have to actually tell myself to continue because it’s more like that's what I have to do, it's instinct. When I think about mental fortitude it’s about getting through practice week to week and living through the dynamics of my team at that level. When you're at that level you don't have the choice to just switch to the next team across town. If you want to play at that level I think the hardest part in my opinion is not figuring out how to deal with your opponents but how you can work well with your team mate”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lanna&lt;/strong&gt;- “ What have your highlights of the Winter Tour been so far ?”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scald&lt;/strong&gt;- “ (adopts an awkward Scottish accent) Shcotland! Och aye ye wee lass, We're in the land of Ootlander an' its ma favourite show and a cannae wait to be here. Its gonnae be a great time. (Back to American) I am super excited to be up here, I've been once before and I loved it. In the US we spent a lot of time re-visiting leagues that I had already been to so it was a lot about going and seeing old friends. We spent our time on the south west but I anticipate that next time round we will head along the east. As far as for the Wintourope Tour, my last name is Buschovik, so I’m really excited to go to Poland. I don't know much what it’s going to be like but it’s going to be an experience. The point of life is to experience new things so...”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trample&lt;/strong&gt;- “ I'm super excited to be in Europe because I've never been on this side of the world. I have a little bit of heritage in Scotland so it was cool to come and explore this place a little bit. Everywhere we are going is exciting to me and there's people who I've been talking to online for the past few years who I'm now getting to meet. They are all coming to our ramp camps and people are travelling all over the world to get to the different bootcamps. Chicks in Bowls is at close to 250 Chapters and it’s amazing I get to meet so many of the Chapter admins and members”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lanna&lt;/strong&gt;- “ And finally, What advice would you give to skaters who want to improve their game?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scald&lt;/strong&gt; - “I think that off skates training is really important, mostly from an injury prevention standpoint. You may not like going to the gym, but going to the ER is much less fun. Having strong quads helps you have strong knees and as women we have naturally weak knees so it's imperative that we strengthen the muscles around them so that they can withstand the torque we put them under. Same with ankles, there's so many baby ankle muscles and foot muscles that we need to look after. If you want to be a kick ass skater and be better than the person next to you then you need to start doing some squats with weight and different things like that. At Rose specifically one of the keys to our success, I believe, is that we have a required gym hour 2 hours a week where we all train together in the gym.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trample&lt;/strong&gt;- “ I don't really do off skates, I know, I'm bad. But I have recently been convinced by Scald that I should be hitting the gym especially to do Pre-hab. I rolled my ankle a while back and I'll do the rehab until its better but then I'm straight back on skates, and it’s not good because a few months later I'll roll my ankle again and it’s because I didn't build up the strength that I needed to help the muscles fully recover and be strong enough to stop the injury from happening again. So I am in a position now where I'm going to push myself to do it”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, there you have it. It was an absolute pleasure to interview these lovely ladies and hopefully you all take something away from my questions. Huge thanks to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GlasgowMensRollerDerby/"&gt;GMRD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for hosting a fantastic event and making sure the day was super fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Till next time
Much Love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next WinTourope is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1852698681626181/"&gt;WinTourope Poland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, this weekend (21-22nd Jan), followed by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/227698337655754/"&gt;Netherlands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/381880268819988/"&gt;France&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and finally &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/146844349126661/"&gt;England&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>chicks in bowls</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>training</category><category>wintourope</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/16/lannthrax-talks-to-wintourope-glasgow-edition/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 19:25:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs Schedule 2017</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/03/british-champs-schedule-2017/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, by now you're probably aware that the British Championships 2017 schedule is out (it's hosted here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/2017-british-roller-derby-champs-fixtures/"&gt;http://www.britishchamps.com/2017-british-roller-derby-champs-fixtures/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in a big, searchable, list).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the list is pretty long, we thought we'd pull out some key dates for you (and also tip our hand a bit as to teams and divisions we'll be focussing a little more on - Talk Derby To Me will be continuing their excellent overall Champs coverage this year for those who want to cover the whole thing):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; kicks off on the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Feb&lt;/strong&gt;ruary, with a double header featuring Tiger Bay Brawlers against newly-merged Leeds Roller Derby, and Birmingham Blitz Dames against Bristol Roller Derby hosted by TBB in Cardiff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; also begins a few weeks later in Wales, as South West Silures host the Crash Test Brummies on the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, by then, most of the other Tiers will have had their first bouts, with the whole British Champs schedule starting on the &lt;strong&gt;4th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Feb&lt;/strong&gt;ruary, as the &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 2&lt;/strong&gt; begins with Barrow Infernos hosting Southern Discomfort B (the first B team in the Men's tiers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friends of the blog, &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;, see their B-team, the Whippin' Hinnies, compete for the first time in &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 2 North&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch, in a battle of the B-teams against Rainy City Roller Derby's formidable Tender Hooligans; hosted by Wirral Roller Derby, this is also somewhat Manchester area themed, as the second bout of the fixture is hosts versus Manchester Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you'll have to wait until April to see some &lt;em&gt;Scottish Women&lt;/em&gt;'s action in the Champs, as &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; host a &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; double header on the &lt;strong&gt;22nd&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Apr&lt;/strong&gt;il. &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;' Reserves are travelling up to Aberdeen to take on the hosts, whilst Furness Firecrackers and Halifax Bruising Banditas will be coming up to play each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scottish Men&lt;/em&gt;'s Derby also has its first showing in Champs that month, as Men Behaving Derby host a &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; fixture on the &lt;strong&gt;16th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Apr&lt;/strong&gt;il; pitting &lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt;' Skelpies against the hosts, followed by Teeside Skate Invaders facing off against &lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, whilst the &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 4&lt;/strong&gt; North starts its series a few weeks earlier, we'll be following friends of the blog (and some of our first interviewees!) &lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt; - their first bout is on the &lt;strong&gt;25th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch against Wakey Wheeled Cats, in Mansfield; the second bout is hosts against Durham Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>york minxters</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/03/british-champs-schedule-2017/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 09:44:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow Men's Roller Derby... bursting onto the Scottish scene</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/09/glasgow-mens-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every year on the blog, we have a conversation which starts with the statement "well, I guess there's not going to be any more new leagues next year...". We're pretty much always wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016 has been a "good year" for new leagues, with at least 3 we're aware of in Scotland, but the most meteoric of them has been &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GlasgowMensRollerDerby/"&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (or GMRD, or, well, it stands for a lot of things, it turns out...) who have gone from a rumour to their first (closed) bout in only a few months and are holding their first bootcamp event (about which more later in the article) in only a month's time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught up with Gigantic Microbe Rodeo Directors chair, Hugs (#04), to find out more about the league's year-to-date (this also sort-of counts as our first end of year review for 2016!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-12291" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/14391001_844531515647583_5182666860266285163_n.png" alt="14391001_844531515647583_5182666860266285163_n" width="838" height="838"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beginnings are a difficult thing: let's start with those. How did Genitive Myelinated  Reinclined Dandies start?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JR: Gratuitous Mangy Radical Dingos kind of came about through necessity. It's a bit of a long story but it boils down to the fact that, at the end of the day, none of us are getting paid to do this hobby; so if things aren't working for you with your current situation then you have to change it, otherwise your hobby becomes a chore and then what's the point?
We wanted to play as competitively as we possibly could, so decided to go the way we thought was best and everything just fell into place. For myself, personally, it honestly feels like one of the best decisions I've made in a long time. We have a group of people who all have the same goals when it comes to this sport, the same dedication and urge to get better, not just personally but for the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Only months after formation, Glistening Manward Right-wing Dandies are entering British Champs, solidly in the middle of Men's Tier 3 North. It's ambitious to go straight into such a committed tournament schedule... what led to this decision?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JR: So... we joined Champs to give our training a complete focus. To give us all the motivation and discipline to give it 110% at every training session we have. Our goal is to play the game we practice week in, week out. Winning would be a bonus, but as long as we can leave every match and say "we did what we wanted to do" then we'll be mad-happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The next Gaseous Metaphorical Roving Devils event is your festive end-of-year Scrims - the Pure Huge Chrimbo Scrimbo [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1257804610950025/"&gt;event&lt;/a&gt;]. Tell us a bit about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JR: So, it was our last available training session of the year, and we were able to extend the times so we figured: why not do something fun. We're a new league but established skaters and we want to be as open to everyone in Scottish Roller Derby (and beyond) so thought we'd throw something fun just before christmas and get everyone involved.
The first part will be a scrim against Grannie's Mangled Red Dog, and the second part a black vs white Chrimbo Scrimbo, where we're gunna throw in some whacky rules and game changes like backwards jams, clockwise jams, double jammers etc.!
We have unlimited spaces; we have plenty of hall time so even if the teams are huge everyone will get track time &lt;img class="_1ift _2560 img" src="https://www.facebook.com/images/emoji.php/v6/zeb/2/16/1f642.png" alt="🙂"&gt; [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1257804610950025/permalink/1279725218757964/?ref=1&amp;amp;action_history=null"&gt;sign up details here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And that bootcamp we mentioned - Green Miscegenist Robot Deuterists are hosting the Scottish leg of Scald Eagle and Lady Trample's "WinTOURope" bootcamp series (as they sweep across Europe) [scheduled for 7 and 8th Jan 2017]. This is, to put it mildly, a bit of a coup. Whilst we know things are still being finalised, what's can you tell us about it now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JR: Oh boy did we absolutely luck out on this.
I'll start by giving a HUGE MASSIVE shout out to Heisen Bird of Southern Co-ed Roller Derby who is absolutely the mastermind behind this and got the ball rolling for Grateful Men, Ramp and Derby to host it up in Scotland.
All of the details are still getting to me thick and fast, so I don't want to say too much in case some things change. We're working out some pricing things and want to have everything locked down so we know what we'll be selling to people but it goes without saying that it's going to be amazing.
There will be a Derby Bootcamp with Scald Eagle at the helm and then a few different ramp skating classes with Lady Trample, for beginners (so if you've never done it before then there isn't a better reason to give it a shot than this!) and Intermediate (which I gather has a minimum requirement of being able to drop into a ramp and stall).
The Scottish Leg of WinTOURope can be found here:&lt;b&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1717432861812471/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1717432861812471/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bootcamps</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/09/glasgow-mens-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 19:21:22 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>