<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about glenmore reservoir dogs)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/glenmore-reservoir-dogs.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 08:59:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Tomodachi Cup Teams: Glenmore Reservoir Dogs</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/25/the-tomodachi-cup-teams-glenmore-reservoir-dogs/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As promised last week, we'll be spending some time up to the &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;in Okinawa (24th to 26th March) introducing you to the teams competing there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, competing in the Men's event, we'd like to introduce Calgary's own Men's team, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chinookcity.ca/"&gt;Glenmore Reservoir Dogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strictly, the men's team of Chinook City Roller Derby, the Reservoir Dogs are named for both (of course) Quentin Tarantino's film, and the Glenmore Reservoir, not far from their original practice space. Currently ranked at 17th position in the MRDA Rankings, and 65th in the world (men and women) by SRD Rank, the team has been competing since 2011, and an MRDA member since 2013. As well as hosting their own tournament (Flat Track Fever), Chinook City were also the hosts for the 2016 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Glenmore Reservoir Dogs will be playing the Japanese National Men's Team, NinJapan Rollers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14032 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/grd_logo_cmyk.png" alt="grd_logo_cmyk" width="200" height="102"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team's only remaining original founder member, Dev Null, was happy to answer some questions from us.
&lt;strong&gt;The Reservoir Dogs had a pretty busy 2016, at the O-Town Throwdown and the Mayday Mayhem - taking second place at the latter to the formidable Ground Control. Can you talk us through your high-points of the last season?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ground Control game was a high point I think for 2016. Stelly is an incredible jammer and we thought without him, we would have had a much better outcome for us in that game. Still, it was such an incredible game and our jammers and blockers did everything we could at the time to face them. At O-Town playing against the Hooligans, it was great for us to go up against a top 15 team and our standing against them and Montreal proved that we belong in the top 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You also hosted Argentina's ThunderQuads - probably the strongest Men's team in Latin America. How did you arrange that (possibly one of the longest distances they've travelled away), and how did it feel to be playing that kind of truly international Derby at home?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of team Argentina were ThunderQuad skaters at the time so putting the game together was pretty easy. Playing that game at home was awesome and as a precursor to MRDWC it got the whole team involved. It's incredibly difficult to get teams here because of distance and international travel, so having the community come to us we could really show our hospitality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As joint hosts of MRDWC 2016, you saw your opponents at the Tomodachi, Ninjapan Rollers, compete against some of the best skaters in the world. How are you planning for your own bouts against them?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're going to be bringing our best defensive game and coupled with the strength of our jamming crew we feel we should have some success against Team Japan. Our practises are also getting better because we've added skaters this year and have a deeper bench. We're really excited for the 2017 MRDA season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With the schedule as it is, the Reservoir Dogs are going to have a lot of derby to watch. Are there any teams you're looking forward to seeing in action?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The teams are really well matched in the WFTDA division, and I think the Tokyo vs Kokeshi game will be the one to watch. Fairbanks vs the Devil Dogs and Devil Dogs vs Tokyo will also be great games. Most of us just love watching new teams and hopefully new strategies. We'll see where we are when we get there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, after the Tomodachi, What's in Chinook's future for 2017?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 2017, we plan to build on our past success and have scheduled games at the Big O and another MRDA event prior to the end of June. Our games at O-Town Throwdown, which worked out nicely for us, and our games at Big O will hopefully see us seed well in Vancouver. In a perfect world, we'd want to come up 1 to 2 spots in MRDA for the June rankings so that we seed in at 4th or 5th place for playoffs but realistically our goal is just to make that 8 from North America. I think having 3 teams from Canada in the top 20 in MRDA is really saying something for Canadian Men's roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>glenmore reservoir dogs</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/25/the-tomodachi-cup-teams-glenmore-reservoir-dogs/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 14:31:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tomodachi Derby Tournament - The Teams</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, the Asia-Pacific Region saw its first ever Roller Derby Tournament, hosted in Okinawa. Whilst the Japan Open was a huge success, the host leagues were keen to hold another one, with even more direct control from the leagues and skaters themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14076 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tomodachi.png" alt="tomodachi" width="400" height="400"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is the result - another two day tournament, now hosted by the new Japan Derby Tournament Committee, a collective of the involved Japanese leagues. As with the previous Tournament, the Tomodachi also serves a practical benefit to all the teams involved, giving somewhat geographically isolated teams a chance to play those from other areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be bringing you more info with interviews with the attending leagues in the run up to the event on the &lt;strong&gt;24th&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt;, (at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/%E6%B2%96%E7%B8%84%E7%9C%8C%E7%B7%8F%E5%90%88%E9%81%8B%E5%8B%95%E5%85%AC%E5%9C%92/@26.3099785,127.8141462,15.5z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x76c4ab9c228dd0cb!8m2!3d26.3107468!4d127.8213143"&gt;Okinawa Comprehensive Sport Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), but we're starting (as with EuroClash) with an overview of the competitors... (a timetable is available on our technical annex, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/tomodachi2017.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;WFTDA-Sanctioned Division&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14022" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/pacificrollerderby.png" alt="pacificrollerderby" width="200" height="200"&gt;Pacific Roller Derby&lt;/h3&gt;
Pacific Roller Derby are one of the oldest of the cluster of Hawaiian teams, dating from 2008, and a member of WFTDA since 2009! Due to the geographical factor, they mostly play the other Islands teams, especially at the yearly "Battle of the Islands" tournament. Based in the Islands' Capital, Honolulu, Pacific are currently 305th in the WFTDA Rankings (344th by FTS), partly, we suspect, simply due to not having had much opportunity to play non-Hawaiian teams. The Tomodachi will be their first fixtures against non-HI leagues since 2014!
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14024" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/fairbanks_rollergirls.png" alt="fairbanks_rollergirls" width="200" height="240"&gt;Fairbanks Rollergirls&lt;/h3&gt;
Hailing from their namesake in Alaska, Fairbanks Rollergirls are another member of the "Alaskan Derby" set alongside last year's Japan Open competitors, Juneau (who memorably attended with only 6 skaters!). A WFTDA member since 2011, the league has hosted the Alaskan "United We Roll" tournament for the last two years. We rate them at 1137th out of all teams (male and female, A and B) in the World which can be rated, whilst FTS places them 331st out of all WFTDA teams (a much smaller set).
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14034" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/devil_dog_300.png" alt="devil_dog_300" width="200" height="199"&gt;Devil Dog Derby Dames&lt;/h3&gt;
Local Okinawan Derby league, Devil Dog Derby Dames, (868th SRDRank), were a competitor at the Japan Open last year, although failed to defeat the non-Japanese teams in the WFTDA Division. (Their Home Team, competing in the Unsanctioned Division, defeated exhibition team Nippon Senbatsu.) The year before that, DDDD managed a win over fellow Okinawa league Kokeshi, which they'll be looking to repeat this time.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14036" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/kokeshi.png" alt="kokeshi" width="200" height="200"&gt;Kokeshi Roller Dolls&lt;/h3&gt;
The first league in Okinawa, Kokeshi Roller Dolls, (700th SRD Rank) were hosts of the Japan Open last year, as well as organising hosting for the Tomodachi Tournament as part of the Japan Roller Derby Tournament Committee. At the Japan Open, they took a win over Alaska's Juneau Roller Derby; we will see if they managed to repeat the feat against Fairbanks this time around.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14028" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tokyo.jpg" alt="tokyo" width="200" height="200"&gt;Tokyo Roller Girls&lt;/h3&gt;
The first league in "mainland" Japan, Tokyo Roller Girls, (745th SRD Rank) faired as well as the Devil Dog Derby Dames at the last tournament. However, they've had a busy home season since then, with all three of their home teams bouting each other, and recruitment has been strong. (TRG skaters have also been behind much of the activity of Women's Roller Derby Japan, the governing body for the Japanese Women's National Team, including their impressively active outreach in the last year.)
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Men's Division&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14032" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/grd_logo_cmyk.png" alt="grd_logo_cmyk" width="200" height="102"&gt;Glenmore Reservoir Dogs&lt;/h3&gt;
Hailing from Calgary, Canada, Glenmore Reservoir Dogs (Chinook City Men's Roller Derby) are the 17th ranked MRDA team in the world (65th SRD Rank), and are the men's component of Chinook City Roller Derby. Perhaps most recently known on the international stage as hosts of the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup, the league as a whole also regularly host the annual "Flat Track Fever" (women's derby) tournament. Last year, the Reservoir Dogs themselves competed at the Mayday Mayhem (Colorado) and the O-Town Throwdown (Ontario), taking second place at the former.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14038" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/japan-logo-232x300.jpg" alt="japan-logo-232x300" width="193" height="250"&gt;NinJapan Rollers&lt;/h3&gt;
The Japanese Men's National Team, and still the only Men's league in Japan, NinJapan Rollers have fairly frequently competed against the other Japanese teams (especially Tokyo), but have rarely had the chance to play non-National teams from other locations. In the 2016 MRDWC, NinJapan placed 17th, although their performance was very close to that of Puerto Rico, one place above them. The NinJapan Rollers have also (partly due to necessity) actively promoted Roller Derby throughout Japan, and have a comprehensive "off-season" training and recruitment system to build up their pool of skaters.
&lt;h2&gt;Unsanctioned Division&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14026" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/yokosuka.png" alt="yokosuka" width="200" height="189"&gt;Yokosuka Sushi Rollers&lt;/h3&gt;
A Tokyo Roller Girls "Home Team", this is the Sushi Rollers' first appearance as a travel team, let alone their first tournament. Based in and around United States Fleet Activities Yokosuka naval base, the Sushi Rollers were the founding team of Tokyo Roller Girls, and remain one of the strongest in intraleague contests. It remains to be seen how they will fare in their first bouts away from Honshu.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14040" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/pan-asian.jpg" alt="pan-asian" width="223" height="200"&gt;Pan-Asian Spring Rollers&lt;/h3&gt;
The Pan-Asian Spring Rollers are a collaboration between the other (non-Japanese) East Asian Roller Derby leagues, with members from Beijing Roller Derby, Shanghai Roller Girls, Hong Kong Roller Derby and Bangkok Roller Derby. Several of these leagues participated in the first ever Roller Derby bout in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; last year (hosted by Beijing), and so collaboration to attend the Tomodachi seems natural.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14030" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/teamwrdj-sm.jpg" alt="teamwrdj-sm" width="250" height="154"&gt;Team WRDJ&lt;/h3&gt;
Team "Women's Roller Derby Japan" is a the open-subscription exhibition team, run by the committee for . It comprises skaters from the Neon Roller Monsters (Tokyo Roller Girls' Japanese-nationals-team), Tokyo Three Rollers (Tokyo's Open-To-All/Coed Team), Kokeshi Roller Dolls, Devil Dog Derby Dames, and a single skater from Hawaii's Echo City Knockouts (of Kailua-Kona).&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>beijing roller derby</category><category>devil dog derby dames</category><category>fairbanks rollergirls</category><category>glenmore reservoir dogs</category><category>hong kong roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>kokeshi roller dolls</category><category>ninjapan rollers</category><category>pacific roller derby</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><category>shang-hai rollers</category><category>tokyo roller girls</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>women's roller derby japan</category><category>yokosuka sushi rollers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 08:05:15 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>