<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about granite city roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/granite-city-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:34:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>BCR's Central Belters are back on track in 2018</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/30/bcrs-central-belters-are-back-on-track-in-2018/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt;'&lt;/a&gt; Central Belters are back on track and ready to kick some ass for the first time in 2018. On August 18th, they will be taking on Granite City's Fight Hawks at Grangemouth Sports Complex.
&lt;p&gt;This is the Belters' first game since early 2017 and sees a few changes to their team. Whilst some skaters have moved on or retired, the Belters have also had some new faces join their squad, including a couple of familiar faces that used to play elsewhere in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fight Hawks had a great year in 2017, winning all five of the games they played. Now in 2018 they already have 3 games under their belt, the most recent a close bout against Dundee Roller Derby's Bonnie Colliders last weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the details can be found over on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/1767150326733129/"&gt;event page here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/1767150326733129/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone wp-image-27087 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/beltvhawk.jpg?w=700" alt="Wolves vs Hawks" width="700" height="394"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2018 upcoming bout</category><category>bairn</category><category>bcr</category><category>central belters</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>gcrd</category><category>grangemouth</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>granite city</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/30/bcrs-central-belters-are-back-on-track-in-2018/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 12:29:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City host Double Header</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/24/granite-city-host-double-header/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A double header to hit Granite City on the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28th of July&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;! The &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beach leisure centre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; of &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is home to Granite City Roller Derby's &lt;strong&gt;Fight Hawks&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Northern Fights&lt;/strong&gt;; both taking on tricky opponents in this derby day duo! &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doors open at 12:30&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; with the first whistle at 1pm, entry on the door for&lt;strong&gt; £4 (under 12's go free!).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27076" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/36548337_10157716666129012_6781758626013904896_o.jpg" alt="Granite City Roller Derby" width="2048" height="1153"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start off the day it's the battle of the B teams, with the &lt;em&gt;Fight Hawks&lt;/em&gt; taking on Dundee Roller Derby's &lt;em&gt;Bonnie Colliders&lt;/em&gt;! We caught up with the captains to see how they are preparing for the weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-27075 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/37395447_1902795173120396_2721404236385484800_n-e1532295713922.jpg?w=200" alt="Image courtesy: Len Rizzo" width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fight&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Hawks Captain&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Skeevy Wonder #64&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How long skating:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;4 and a half years apparently! Time flies.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How long captaining team:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;About 8 months&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the season been for your team so far?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We're only really just kicking into gear, but it's been great figuring out our team's strengths and helping build the confidence of our newer skaters. We had a great time in Portugal, where we may not have come back with any gold medals, but we came back with heaps of goals and ideas.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have you been preparing for the upcoming game:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Following on from those pointers from our tournament in Coimbra, we've been drilling our weaknesses and honing our strengths. Practice, practice, practice!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you find playing teams within Scotland, does it change your game prep playing such a geographically close league?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;As a team, the Hawks have played teams all over Scotland, a few in England, and even teams from Spain and Portugal. We haven't played the Colliders in a long time, but being closer to Dundee and knowing more of their skaters and their styles and preferences, we have a better idea of what kind of game we are going in to. As far as I'm concerned about geographical closeness, it means I can have a proper breakfast that's not from a service station and a bit of a lie in! Boost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything in particular you say to your team to get prepped for the game? Any words of wisdom?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;As a B team, we're here to learn constantly, and get as much from every game as possible. That doesn't mean we're not competitive however, it just means win or lose we're taking away valuable experiences.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonnie Colliders Captains&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; ALLY-J &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;#92 &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;amp; Tiny Tearaway #931&lt;img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-27090" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/37711946_10156238091771068_2068850209923792896_n.jpg?w=141" alt="37711946_10156238091771068_2068850209923792896_n" width="141" height="300"&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Long Skating:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; 3 years, 6 years respectively.
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long Captaining Team&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; our first year!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the season been for your team so far?:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; It’s been a really good start, our focus skating as a team has been awesome! We constantly strive to do our very best, even if we lose a game we can still be really proud of each others performance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How have you been preparing for the upcoming game?:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; We've been pushing ourselves a lot at training. Working alongside the Tayzers to increase our knowledge of the game and to build our skills. &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you find playing teams within Scotland, does it change your game prep playing such a geographically close league?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We've played further afield against Copenhagen which was many of the Colliders' first game outside Scotland. Playing teams closer to home is just as exciting. Seeing the talent that Scotland has is incredible and being able to play alongside these people makes it all worth it. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything in particular you say to your team to get the prepped for the game? Any words of wisdom?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Don’t let the other team get into our heads! That every single person has an amazing set of skills to use, and not to forget it!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this B-team-bust-up Granite's A team &lt;em&gt;The Northern Fights&lt;/em&gt; will be taking on &lt;em&gt;Vagine Regime UK, &lt;/em&gt;a team formed by a fully inclusive community of LGBTQIA+ individuals and their supporters across the UK. We put a few questions to each of the captains to understand the teams individual run ups to games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-27098" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/37753945_1909703029096277_5673277440076546048_n.jpg?w=300" alt="Image Courtesy: Len Rizzo" width="300" height="199"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Northern Fights Captain:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Lizzee Rascal #314&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How Long Captaining?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;First year
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Long Skating?: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;5 Years&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the season been for your team so far?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;This season has been great so far. We had quite a change in the team at the beginning of the year and sadly said goodbye to old friends and welcomed some new ones. We have been focusing on British Champs, where we've been competing in Tier 3 North. It has been a fantastic challenge for us and has really pushed us to train hard. We have finished second in our tier and I couldn’t be prouder of the Fights.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have you been preparing for the upcoming game?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We've been focusing on developing and building as a team for champs throughout 2018. The upcoming game, being an exhibition game, will be a refreshing change from this, with a lot of the pressure of champs being taken off. We have still been training hard and want to bring our best game at the weekend.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you find playing teams such as VR? Does it change your strategy or prep at all?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Playing against VR is a different experience for us, as they bring a pool of talent from across the UK and will perhaps use tactics that we haven’t been up against before which will make for a challenging yet fun game.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vagine Regime captain:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Kami-Tazzy #360&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-27096 alignright" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/37825317_1875280102519140_1499359558181584896_n.jpg?w=200" alt="Image Courtesy: Nick" width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How Long Skating:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; 7. 5 years&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How long Captaining:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;First time for VR.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the season been for your team so far, do rosters change a lot?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It's been great so far. Back in April we had a tough but close game with the Rainy City C team, a great game to kick off the season with. We're really looking forward to playing Granite's awesome Northern Fights. VR UK contain a very large number of members, of all levels, from all over the UK, including some of the best players the UK can offer. Because of that, rosters are always changing, but it mainly depends on location, bout clashes, level and availability.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you prepare your skaters for upcoming games?:&lt;/strong&gt; S&lt;em&gt;ince skaters are generally from different leagues/teams it's difficult to prepare physically. Therefore communication and trust is key here. We'll have discussions on positions, and other strengths that everyone can bring. This will help the captains, LUM and Bench to come up with line up plans and strategies to fully challenge our opponents. It's certainly a bonus to have skaters on the team that have played together before, but things still may get shuffled around on the day to maximise our full potential.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How do you find putting together a mixed team to play established leagues, is there anything in particular you look for in skaters?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Depending on availability, we try to put together a strong as possible team to challenge our competitors to the max. We try to get the right mix of skaters of every position. However this is not possible at all times, we have had jammer heavy rosters in the past or vice versa. This is not really a problem, as a lot of the players are very adaptable and give it thier absolute all. We may be a challenge team but we're still a competitive team who like to rise to the challenge and aim to triumph in every game that we play.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything in particular you say to your team to get them prepped for the game? Any words of wisdom?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I ask them to bring all their focus, good sportsmanship and determination on and off the track. Additionally teamwork, integrity and to set individual as well as team goals. This sport is brilliant but it can also be mentally tough at times. One main advice I give to a lot of people is that if things don't go as planned in a jam, I encourage them to put it behind them, store it away if needed, reset and focus on the next jam. Also most importantly enjoy yourselves and embrace all the achievements, no matter how small or big they are.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;Event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/235019877294396/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;
Date: 28/07/2018
Price: £4 on the door&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was co-written by Dundee's correspondent G. Patterson and Granite's Correspondent C. Meikle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2018 season</category><category>a chat with...</category><category>aberdeen</category><category>articles</category><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>up coming games</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>vagine regime uk</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/24/granite-city-host-double-header/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:45:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fair City Rollers: Rising</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/20/fair-city-rollers-rising/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Sunday is the only time you'll see Perth's local roller derby league, Fair City Rollers, on track at home this year, due to the popularity of their excellent local venue, Bell's Sport Centre. As a result, for those following the team, it's an opportunity not to be missed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-26879" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/fcr_map-layered.png?w=1024" alt="FCR_map-layered" width="1024" height="948"&gt; Fair City, and the leagues combining to face them as "Scotland's Rising Stars"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fear Maidens, Fair City's travel team, will be facing a mixed exhibition team drawing newer skaters from Ayrshire Roller Derby, Bairn City Rollers' Central Belters, Dundee Roller Derby, Granite City Roller Derby, Lothian Roller Derby and Mean City Roller Derby. Coming together as "Scotland's Rising Stars", these skaters represent some of the best new talent in Scottish roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fear Maidens have played one previous bout this year, losing away to Dundee's B team, the Bonnie Colliders, back in &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/8969"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Due to way Flat Track Stats' rating changes are applied (always equally, but oppositely, to both teams), this has almost certainly underrated the Perth team at present, due to both Dundee teams' considerable strength gains year on year. Whilst this game against an exhibition team will not compensate in the ratings, we're confident of a strong showing from Perth's only roller derby team at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City's Invader Zoom told us, "We are so excited to be playing at home again and can't wait for the people of Perth to see some of our new recruits in action. Our last home game was a nail biter that had the audience on the edge of their seats all game, and we are sure this game will be just as thrilling with a challenge team of skaters from 6 different Scottish leagues!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as Roller Derby action on track, there will be the usual collection of stalls, including an opportunity to support the charity &lt;a href="http://www.clicsargent.org.uk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CLIC Sargent in Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, raising money to help Young Lives versus Cancer. Fair City Rollers will be participating in CLIC Sargent's Rainbow Assault assault course event in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City Rollers' "&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1869400046436599/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pack to the Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;" is at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/Sty37VvYGx92"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bell's Sports Centre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Perth, on the &lt;strong&gt;24th June&lt;/strong&gt;, 2018. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>fear maidens</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/20/fair-city-rollers-rising/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 13:36:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City's Hawks off to Fight in Portugal!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/15/granite-citys-hawks-off-to-fight-in-portugal/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As well as the exciting home games in Scotland this weekend, there's also an equally exciting away game, as Aberdeen's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GraniteCityRollerDerby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; send their B team off to Portugal to play in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/596021074083791/"&gt;Quad Cup 2018!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second iteration of the Quad Cup, the 2017 version seeing hosts, Coimbra's Rocket Dolls Roller Derby, play Black Thunders Roller Derby of Madrid, Lyon Roller Derby B team, Gones'n'Roses, and the exhibition team Liberty Rebellion in a 2 day round robin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26858" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/quadcup2018.jpg" alt="QuadCup2018" width="2048" height="1071"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This 2018 iteration of the European tournament pits the Fight Hawks against the returning teams of the hosts, and Black Thunders Roller Derby in a round-robin format in one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These will be the first games for the Fight Hawks this year, after their final bout in 2017, an extremely closely fought &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/98576"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 point win&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; against York Minxters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their opponents, meanwhile, have had one or two bouts already this year: Black Thunders playing Las Palmas to an overwhelming win early in the year; and both teams having faced As Brigantias (A Coruña, hosts of the upcoming WFTDA Playoffs in August). Whilst neither team defeated A Coruña's finest, the Black Thunders did considerably better than Coimbra, with a mere 34 point loss on an overall low-scoring game. As the Madrid team also defeated all comers in the 2017 Quad Cup, they must be the favourites this time around as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flat Track Stats agrees, with their European rating (at the time of publication), giving Black Thunders a 91% chance of victory over the hosts, and a 95% chance of victory over the Fight Hawks, who come in as the underdogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of these, however, the Fight Hawks are also the clear wildcards - with few close connections between their rating games and those of the two Iberian teams, they have the highest uncertainty in their performance; and their "rating momentum" was upward for the entirety of last year. With even FTS's pessimistic prediction giving Granite City B an expected 21:25 score ratio against the hosts (translating to perhaps a 20 to 30 point final score difference), it seems very possible for Aberdeen to provide the upsets this weekend. Given the disruptive behaviour of their namesakes, what would be more appropriate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Quad Cup 2018 will be held in the &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/qnbiz2Jpvh62"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pavilhão Multiusos de Coimbra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Coimbra, Portugal, with the first bouts starting at &lt;strong&gt;11am&lt;/strong&gt; (WEST, BST) on the &lt;strong&gt;17th June&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coimbra</category><category>european derby</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>rocket dolls roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/15/granite-citys-hawks-off-to-fight-in-portugal/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 10:11:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City Roller Derby update: British Champs T3 and beyond</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/22/granite-city-roller-derby-update-british-champs-t3-and-beyond/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've been a little remiss with our &lt;a href="https://www.britishchamps.com"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;British Champs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Northern Divisions updates since the middle of the season, so we're back a with a special catchup with our teams from each Tier, continuing with Tier 3's Granite City Roller Derby!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-22709" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/gcrd.png?w=300" alt="GCRD" width="300" height="300"&gt; GCRD!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City's Northern Fights had an exceptional 2016 in Champs, entering Tier 3 in 2017 by promotion after topping the table. They've continued their excellent Champs performance in Tier 3 - they currently top the table here as well, unbeaten, with extremely strong victories in 3 of 4 of their games so far. (The only close game was their first, against Halifax's Bruising Banditas.)
The rest of the Tier 3 Champs table is more even at the moment with, tentatively, Auld Reekie's Reserves and the newly-rebranded North Wales Roller Derby in the most likely places to take the second top spot. We'll know more after the second-last fixtures of the Tier, today, hosted by North Wales, with the final bouts happening August in Edinburgh as Auld Reekie host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Northern Fights co-Captain, Berocca Bama had the following to say: "2017 Tier 3 North has been a very exciting and challenging time for the Northern Fights of GCRD. As a result of hard training and solid dedication of the players and league, we have really grown and bonded as a team since Tier 4 in 2016 which meant we felt strong to compete in Tier 3 North 2017 and the results so far are far beyond our wildest dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have had so many enjoyable games, the most thrilling of which was against ARRG B. The team that ended our winning streak in 2016, we knew ARRG were going to be really tough opponents. We are sure anyone who was there to see this Champs game would agree it was a nail biter to the end!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking forward to playing the Furness Firecrackers in the final Champs game in August; we know they'll bring it! It's a very important game for us, as a victory here should see us through to play-offs, if our maths is right..."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City are also hosting events outside of Champs, starting with their very own tournament in a weeks time, the &lt;strong&gt;29th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;July&lt;/strong&gt;! &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Sevens&lt;/strong&gt; will be the most heptamerous of Sevens tournaments, with seven co-ed/OTA teams competing, each with the traditional seven skaters, in 21 minute games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And after Champs Tier 3 North comes to an end in August (except for the Tier 3 promotion playoffs, 16/17 September), the Northern Fights will be hosting 2 games of their own, up in Aberdeen. These will also be great opportunities to see GCRD's B team, the Fight Hawks, as both events are double headers!
We don't have dates for these events yet, but of course we will feature them as soon as we have more information...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;British Champs Tier 3 N Fixture (&lt;strong&gt;22 July Today&lt;/strong&gt;!): &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/863580253744360/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/863580253744360/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;British Champs Tier 3 N Final Fixture (&lt;strong&gt;12 Aug&lt;/strong&gt;, Edinburgh): &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/479889502352774/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/479889502352774/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City Roller Derby host Scottish Sevens (&lt;strong&gt;29 July&lt;/strong&gt;): &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1468759543169257/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1468759543169257/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>british champs</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>derby sevens</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>northern fights</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/22/granite-city-roller-derby-update-british-champs-t3-and-beyond/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 07:39:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs North Update 23 March:York Minxters, Whippin Hinnies and more</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/22/british-champs-north-update-23-marchyork-minxters-whippin-hinnies-and-more/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our second update on the Northern Tiers of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/"&gt;British Champs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. We're aiming to do approximately monthly updates on the Tier 1, Tier 2 North, Tier 3 North and Tier 4 North, partly through the lens of specific teams in each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the last update, the &lt;strong&gt;Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; saw our advertised bout between&lt;strong&gt; Leeds Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; and Tiger Bay Brawlers end in an impressive win for the Cardiff team (294:44). Performance stats show that at least some of this seems to have been "first game" syndrome for LeedsRD, who significantly improved their performance in the second period (scoring 70%  of their points in period 2, as well as taking less penalties). If they perform at their period 2 level, or continue to improve, they'll be a significant force in the Tier in future games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Tier 2 North&lt;/strong&gt; has seen another round of bouts, with our tracked team, Newcastle Roller Girls' &lt;strong&gt;Whippin Hinnies&lt;/strong&gt; facing the formidable Rainy City Tender Hooligans, with the Hooligans taking the win, 348:62. This is a approaching half the score ratio than Rainy B managed against Wirral, which looks promising for the Hinnies' next bout in the tier. Looking at the stats (not published yet), this was a tough game for the Hinnie's jammers, with only Ania Marx achieving lead jammer status against Rainy's exceptional blocking. Hosts Wirral also played, losing to Manchester Roller Derby with the score 101:248.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; saw our tracked team &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; win a pretty closely contended game against Halifax Bruising Banditas - finishing 130:117. The stats show particularly strong jamming performances by GCRD's Lizzie Rascal (75% Lead Jams!), Team Scotland's Udder Mayhem, and Kami-Tazzy; blocking-wise, high VTARs are with Crimson Chaos, Team Scotland's Rock'N Riot, and Pert Hits.
North Wales convincingly defeated hosts Furness Firecrackers in the other bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first &lt;strong&gt;Tier 4 North&lt;/strong&gt; bouts saw tier-champions favourites Mansfield crush Durham City Rolling Angels 398:38, and the second Durham team, Durham Roller Derby, lose to Grimsby Grim Reavers 198:110.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tier 4 North is coming around again for another set of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1002205086551977/"&gt;bouts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; this weekend, and features the &lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt;' first ever bout in British Champs (as well as hosts Mansfield versus Durham). In honour of the occasion, we caught up with their Captain, Gem O'Cide to see how they're feeling:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, let's start by talking about last year, which was a big year for the Minxters. After several years of just playing a few bouts, 2016 saw the team play 7 over the season, with some pretty challenging opponents. What lead to this surge in activity, and has it been a good thing for the team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016 was a year of practice, practice and more practice. We had a lot of changes in the team and a lot of up and coming skaters joining the rostered team- this meant our dynamics changed and we needed to learn how to play together. We very much wanted to take the "Win or Learn" approach and felt some real time game play - working as we would on game day- would be best to learn this. Everyone loves scrimming and it helped us grow confidence and learn how each other work, where our strengths lie and what we needed to improve on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After missing the first two years of British Champs, you're entering this year for the first time. Why now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to get started on the Champs journey! We've had a massive new skater intake and great retention and it would be awesome to get the ball rolling and have something yearly to aim for! Something to show everyone what we are working towards...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You're entering into the tournament in Tier 4 North. Flat Track Stats and us agree that you're pretty much in the middle of the Tier in terms of expected performance - but there's a lot of unknowns, as you've only played one of your competitors before (Grimsby's Grim Reavers). How are you preparing for the tournament&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off shout out to Reavers. We love those guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are playing and training to our strengths. We've had some great input from Rule 56, as well as other guest coaches who have analysed our play. This had helped massively in preparing by knowing what we focus on from A-team players and what direction to take our training in. This has given us concrete goals and really solidified our skills and tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your first bout in Champs looks like being a tough one - Wakey Wheeled Cats are one of the strongest teams in this Tier! What are your aims for this particular game?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Wakey game, we are going into a tough one! But this is a great challenge to practice what we have learnt, and are continuing to learn, in training. For me as Captain, all I ever want to see for my team is that they are working hard as a team and putting our training into practice. We go into and leave this as a team who wins or learns!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As well as British Champs itself, what other plans and events do York Minxters have in store for 2017?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have lots of fun things planned for our newer skaters after Champs - they have helped out with NSO roles and August will be and time of fun and folly for everyone! After Champs we will be having a bit of fun for the team, then looking at some more challenges to prepare for 2018!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upcoming bouts in other tiers are:
&lt;strong&gt;Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; - our tracked team, Leed Roller Derby, host a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/288187818265184/"&gt;massive triple header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;April 8th&lt;/strong&gt;, where they will play Bristol Roller Derby, London Brawl Saints will play Tiger Bay, and newly-rebranded Middlesbrough Roller Derby will take on Birmingham Blitz Dames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next &lt;strong&gt;Tier 2&lt;/strong&gt; bouts are on &lt;strong&gt;22nd April&lt;/strong&gt;, where Newcastle host a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1886091588294805/"&gt;double header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, with the Whippin Hinnies playing Manchester Roller Derby (which should be their closest bout yet), and Liverpool Roller Birds bouting Wirral Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tier 3&lt;/strong&gt; also plays next on &lt;strong&gt;22nd April&lt;/strong&gt;, with Aberdeen the venue, as hosts Granite City Roller Derby play the other Scottish team in the tier, Auld Reekie Roller Girls' Reserves; and Furness Firecrackers playing Halifax Bruising Banditas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>whippin hinnies</category><category>york minxters</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/22/british-champs-north-update-23-marchyork-minxters-whippin-hinnies-and-more/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 10:50:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs North Update 23 Feb</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/24/british-champs-north-update-23-feb/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we've previously mentioned, we're planning on tracking events in the Northern divisions of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/"&gt;British Championships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; this year (that is: the Tier 1, Tier 2 North, Tier 3 North, Tier 4 North, as well as the Men's Tier 3 North), partly via particular teams in each one (Leeds Roller Derby, Newcastle's Whippin Hinnies, Auld Reekie's Reserves and Granite City Roller Derby, York Minxters, and Bairn City's Skelpies and Glasgow Men's Roller Derby respectively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of this, this is one of our regular updates, after some of the teams have played, and as others prepare to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-15248 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/02/britishchamps.jpg?w=263" alt="britishchamps" width="263" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Whippin' Hinnies are the first team we're tracking to have played, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/88843"&gt;last weekend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; facing Cambridge Rollerbillies in Tier 2 (we talked to them &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/02/14/newcastles-hinnies-off-to-champs/"&gt;about the challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; beforehand). Whilst not managing to defeat their opponents in Manchester, the Hinnies did improve on their expected performance.
Statswise, full statistics are not available yet for the bout, but Co-captain Ania Marx and Miss Wired stand out at the top jammers (by points-per-jam) for the Newcastle team, with other Co-captain Method Mam, Marie Bayonet (also jamming) and Victoria Deck'em the most significant blockers by VTAR (a measure of the relative performance of the team whilst they were on track).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Whippin' Hinnies' next fixture will be against Rainy City Roller Derby's Tender Hooligans on the &lt;strong&gt;11th of March&lt;/strong&gt;, hosted by Wirral Roller Derby. The Tender Hooligans themselves had their first game last weekend, defeating Wirral significantly better than expectations. [Full stats are available for this game, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/88842"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up this &lt;strong&gt;Sunday&lt;/strong&gt;, we have the first Tier 1 bout we're tracking, as Leeds Roller Derby play their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/241620336288289/"&gt;first game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of the season against the formidable Tiger Bay Brawlers (who are also hosts). Flat Track Stats sees LeedsRD as the underdogs here - and TBB are a strong team - but FTS is basing its rating on the performance of only half of Leeds Roller Derby, inheriting their ranking from the old pre-merger Leeds Roller Dolls. It remains to be seen what the new team, with the infusion of skaters from Hot Wheel Roller Derby, is like on track - having just announced &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/WeAreLeedsRD/photos/a.1199876556747521.1073741828.1192281080840402/1255594731175703/"&gt;their roster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the bout this week.
We talked to LeedsRD about their feelings on the year for EuroClash &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/02/15/euroclash-interviews-leeds-roller-derby/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also this &lt;strong&gt;Sunday&lt;/strong&gt;, Aberdeen's Granite City Roller Derby are playing their first Tier 3 North bout, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/297370800677088/"&gt;hosted by&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Furness Firecrackers, and facing Halifax Bruising Banditas. Granite City are the clear favourites here, having had a superlative 2016 ending in promotion to the Tier from Tier 4 unbeaten by all contenders.
Speaking about their challenge, GCRD's Kami-Tazzy told us: "We are all feeling really excited about being back in Tier 3 and have been working really hard since Champs finished last year. We are hoping to bring what we did last year plus something a bit extra, as we have some tough opposition and hope to progress further than 2 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have faced Halifax Banditas on two occasions already and have been successful. However with all teams continuing to grow and progress we shall never underestimate any of our opponents. Halifax are going to bring their A game and so are we. We're going to bring all our fight till the last whistle blows."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully both teams will have a successful weekend for us to discuss when we return for our next Champs update!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>whippin hinnies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/24/british-champs-north-update-23-feb/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 10:26:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs Schedule 2017</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/03/british-champs-schedule-2017/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, by now you're probably aware that the British Championships 2017 schedule is out (it's hosted here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/2017-british-roller-derby-champs-fixtures/"&gt;http://www.britishchamps.com/2017-british-roller-derby-champs-fixtures/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in a big, searchable, list).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the list is pretty long, we thought we'd pull out some key dates for you (and also tip our hand a bit as to teams and divisions we'll be focussing a little more on - Talk Derby To Me will be continuing their excellent overall Champs coverage this year for those who want to cover the whole thing):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; kicks off on the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Feb&lt;/strong&gt;ruary, with a double header featuring Tiger Bay Brawlers against newly-merged Leeds Roller Derby, and Birmingham Blitz Dames against Bristol Roller Derby hosted by TBB in Cardiff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; also begins a few weeks later in Wales, as South West Silures host the Crash Test Brummies on the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, by then, most of the other Tiers will have had their first bouts, with the whole British Champs schedule starting on the &lt;strong&gt;4th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Feb&lt;/strong&gt;ruary, as the &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 2&lt;/strong&gt; begins with Barrow Infernos hosting Southern Discomfort B (the first B team in the Men's tiers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friends of the blog, &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;, see their B-team, the Whippin' Hinnies, compete for the first time in &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 2 North&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch, in a battle of the B-teams against Rainy City Roller Derby's formidable Tender Hooligans; hosted by Wirral Roller Derby, this is also somewhat Manchester area themed, as the second bout of the fixture is hosts versus Manchester Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you'll have to wait until April to see some &lt;em&gt;Scottish Women&lt;/em&gt;'s action in the Champs, as &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; host a &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; double header on the &lt;strong&gt;22nd&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Apr&lt;/strong&gt;il. &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;' Reserves are travelling up to Aberdeen to take on the hosts, whilst Furness Firecrackers and Halifax Bruising Banditas will be coming up to play each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scottish Men&lt;/em&gt;'s Derby also has its first showing in Champs that month, as Men Behaving Derby host a &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; fixture on the &lt;strong&gt;16th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Apr&lt;/strong&gt;il; pitting &lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt;' Skelpies against the hosts, followed by Teeside Skate Invaders facing off against &lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, whilst the &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 4&lt;/strong&gt; North starts its series a few weeks earlier, we'll be following friends of the blog (and some of our first interviewees!) &lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt; - their first bout is on the &lt;strong&gt;25th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch against Wakey Wheeled Cats, in Mansfield; the second bout is hosts against Durham Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>york minxters</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/03/british-champs-schedule-2017/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 09:44:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls: Home and Away</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/18/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-and-away/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With winter fast approaching, Edinburgh's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.arrg.co.uk"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are not slowing down in their schedule one bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend,&lt;strong&gt; October 22nd&lt;/strong&gt;, Auld Reekie travel down to Newcastle to play the second "double fixture" of the month. On the 8th, ARRG A and B took on London B and C; this time, Auld Reekie's A and B teams &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1775971736017021/"&gt;will be playing their opposite numbers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from British Champs Premier Tier Champions (2016), &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.org.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-9658 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14324272_1145590692150681_7010713698933643507_o.jpg" alt="14324272_1145590692150681_7010713698933643507_o" width="3366" height="1245"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our ranking scheme, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/08/ranking-the-world-and-other-fts-visualisations/3"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, places Auld Reekie's All-Stars and Newcastle's Canny Belters at very close rank indeed (107th and 101st in our international, cross-gender rankings, in fact), and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85476/rankings"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; agrees, giving Newcastle A just a 53% chance of winning using the larger European dataset.
The B bout might be a fraction safer for the home team - we rank the Whippin' Hinnies at 39 spots above ARRG B, and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85477/rankings"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; suggests that the hosts have an 87% probability of victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can make it down to Newcastle's&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Walker+Activity+Dome/@54.968707,-1.5582607,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487e7068944e76d1:0xe1a6394d9f25325!8m2!3d54.968707!4d-1.556072"&gt; Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, then doors open at &lt;strong&gt;11:45am, &lt;/strong&gt;tickets &lt;strong&gt;£10 for two&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.org.uk/buy-tickets/22-oct-canny-belters-vs-arrg-a-whippin-hinnies-vs-arrg-b"&gt;online from the NRG website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;£7 each&lt;/strong&gt; on the door (under 12s free).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, only a few weeks later, the All-Star Reserves will be playing again, this time hosting &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.granitecityrollerderby.co.uk/"&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s Northern Fights on &lt;strong&gt;November 5th&lt;/strong&gt; at their usual venue,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Meadowbank+Sports+Centre/@55.956619,-3.1584973,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4887b86eb150070f:0x6955a8c9b9a10cc5!8m2!3d55.956619!4d-3.1563086"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The Fights, GCRD A, have had an exceptional year, topping the British Champs Local North tier and earning promotion to Tier 3 in 2017. (You can read more about their year &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/08/23/granite-citys-sparkling-year-peaks-with-glasgow-rematch/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-9663 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14581343_10157587090110224_3258736097020786394_n.jpg" alt="14581343_10157587090110224_3258736097020786394_n" width="784" height="295"&gt;
Whilst Granite City will be looking to maintain their 14 month win streak, the Reserves will be keen to defend the honour of Edinburgh, after a narrow loss to Dundee earlier in the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The statistics are on Granite City's side - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/08/ranking-the-world-and-other-fts-visualisations/3"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; places them more than 200 places above the Reserves, and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85859/rankings"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; gives them a 88% probability of victory. However, Auld Reekie tend to dig especially deep when playing at home, so we're not going to rule out an upset, especially for their last bout of the season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this event, the event page is: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1594409394188095/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1594409394188095/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;1.20pm&lt;/strong&gt;, with tickets &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; (plus booking fee) &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2684699"&gt;online from Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;£8&lt;/strong&gt; on the door (concessions available, and under-14s free).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/18/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-and-away/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 10:35:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bairn City's co-ed bout to celebrate their 4th birthday</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/05/bairn-citys-co-ed-bout-to-celebrate-their-4th-birthday/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bairn City Rollers became Scotland's first co-ed league back in 2012. Now as they approach their 4th birthday they are kicking of celebrations and ending their 2016 season in the best way they could, a co-ed game. Their opponents will be the Brawler Buddies, who are made up of skaters from &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/granitecitybrawlers/"&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GraniteCityRollerDerby/"&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/dundeerollergirls/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In change from the norm, there will be no advanced ticket sales for this event. Instead in celebration of their 4th birthday BCR are inviting spectators to pay what they want on the day. That's right, &lt;span class="_4n-j fsl"&gt;just turn up on the game and pay whatever you like.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game will take place at Grangemouth Sports Complex on Saturday the 15th of October, doors will be open from 2.15pm and first whistle will be at 2.40pm, for more information &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/527945357409228/"&gt;visit the event page here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/527945357409228/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-9205" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/bcr-banner.jpg?w=700" alt="bcr-banner" width="700" height="259"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bcr</category><category>central belters</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>grangemouth</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>skelpies</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/05/bairn-citys-co-ed-bout-to-celebrate-their-4th-birthday/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 19:38:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>