<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about granite city brawlers)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/granite-city-brawlers.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Silver City Cup: Scotland's first MRDA Tournament</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/14/the-silver-city-cup-scotlands-first-mrda-tournament/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would be remiss of us to run a series on Tournaments which deserve more attention without covering Scotland's own example of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst there have been many tournaments run in Scotland, there have been relatively fewer "Men's Derby" focussed events. Given the lack of MRDA member leagues in Scotland until almost a year ago, when Granite City Brawlers were accepted, it was also impossible for there to have been any "officially" sanctioned tournaments at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, though, with two MRDA member teams (Glasgow Men's Roller Derby having quietly unofficially joined a few months ago, in June, although only officially announced by MRDA this week), the time is right for an international Men's Roller Derby tournament, and where better than the home of the first MRDA members in the country, Aberdeen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Silver City Cup - named for the poetic description of Aberdeen as the "Silver City, with the Golden Sands", possibly dating to an early guide to the city* - will host 6 teams from across Europe, in a group+placement format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we reported on the Men's European Cup, we noted that several of the teams involved were also facing each other in other MRDA sanctioned events this year. Conversely, the Silver City Cup seems to have attracted all the teams who aren't appearing as much elsewhere... so this is a great opportunity to see some matchups you can't get elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27437" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/09/silvercity_map_out.png" alt="Silvercity_map_out" width="1332" height="1436"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;England: Super Smash Brollers (Nottingham), Crash Test Brummies (Birmingham)
Finland: Tampere Rollin' Bros (Tampere)
France: Kamiquadz (Montpellier)
Scotland: Granite City Brawlers (Aberdeen)
Wales: South Wales Silures (Cardiff)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Structure&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;GROUP 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;GROUP 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Granite City Brawlers [661]{2.94}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Crash Test Brummies [618]{2.92}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;South Wales Silures [706]{3.24}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;KamiQuads [737]{3.8}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Tampere Rollin' Bros [777]{2.9}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Super Smash Brollers [612]{2.5}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="2"&gt;[FTS MRDA rating**]{SRDRank May 2018 rating}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
Within each group of 3, the teams will play round-robin (3 games per group), to produce a final group-ranking.
The 1st place winners in each group will play each other for Tournament 1st Place, whilst the 2nd places in each group will play for overall Tournament 3rd, and the bottom teams in each group will play for Tournament 5th.
&lt;p&gt;Looking at Flat Track Stats' "MRDA" ratings (which are derived only from MRDA sanctioned games played by teams), there's a pretty wide spread in predicted strength across the groups - second-highest-rated contenders, DCCLM's Kamiquadz are expected to beat lowest-rated contenders, Super Smash Brollers, by around a three-to-one points ratio! Ironically, the hosts have given themselves the harder of the two groups, based on prediction: they will be playing FTS' 1st and 3rd ranked teams of the tournament, as FTS' 4th ranked team themselves. In order to achieve their "rightful" position, they'd need to defeat the fearsome SWS in their group, before taking on the 2nd place team from Group 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at pure history, rather than ratings, the Kamiquadz are really the wildcards here. Most of their past bouts on record are, understandably, given the geography, against French men's teams, or teams from nearby Barcelona in Spain. As far as we can tell from their FTS record, the Kamiquadz have never played outside of mainland Europe before, so this will be a big change for them - the weather in Aberdeen will be a bit of a change to Montpellier! On the basis of their performances in France, however, we have no hesitation in considering them the favourites to take the 1st place in this tournament overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only slightly less of an historical wildcard for the other teams, Tampere Rollin Bros actually did play the Kamiquadz - way back in 2015 - but also have a more extensive set of travel experiences under their belts (being based in Finland forces that upon you, to some extent). In recent years, Tampere's bouts have not been MRDA-sanctioned (according to FTS), and so have not factored into their estimated strength*** - we'd actually say Tampere are somewhat overranked at present, going by their performance in their last tournament in 2017. [On the other hand, that tournament was in Barcelona, one of the most distant places Tampere have played, so it almost certainly represents a lowest bound on their expected strength at the time.]
The SRDRank ratings, which do include those games from 2017, tend to agree, placing Tampere in the same "closely-competitive" group as the rest of the field excluding KamiQuads and SWS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the UK based teams, Wales's South Wales Silures have had the strongest, year to date, although far from the busiest. Despite losing 2 of their three games in May (to Manneken Beasts, and, by 2 points only!, Gothenburg Salty Seamen), their incredibly strong first game performance against the Crash Test Brummies has kept their overall performance estimate high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aforementioned Brummies have, along with Nottingham's Super Smash Brollers, been extremely busy this year - with fixtures in British Champs MRDA-side (Tier 1 for the Brummies, and 2 for the Brollers) at the start of the year, and MRDA Qualifiers for the Super Smash Brollers as well. Fittingly, perhaps, the most recent bout for the two teams to date is against each other, a narrowish win for the higher-rated Brummies (162 to 199). The two teams will get to repeat that match-up again in their Group 2 bouts, almost certainly deciding which plays for 3rd and which for 5th overall in the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the hosts, Granite City Brawlers, have been stepping on the gas in terms of bout scheduling since getting MRDA membership - meeting the activity requirements to be ranked in the official rankings is a strong incentive for all members of official governing bodies. They, also, have played one of the other contenders most recently: a repeat matchup with the Super Smash Brollers resulting in a second win in a row for the Aberdeen team. FTS's MRDA rating for them, based on their past 4 games, is still trending upward, but it's not clear if it is "really" above the 700-odd mark needed to beat the Silures in their group - however, if Tampere really is as overranked as we think, the Brawlers may only need to be slightly stronger than they're currently rated to be to take their groups' 2nd place spot, and play for a likely 3rd overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Silver City Cup will be held at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/3fr8ugyweUs"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Beach Leisure Centre, Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;; &lt;strong&gt;22-23 September&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
Event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/616684768693015/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/616684768693015/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Tickets are available from Brown Paper Tickets: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/3446103https://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/3446103"&gt;https://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/3446103&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The "Silver" here is generally considered a reference to the "silver darlings", the herring which formed the basis of Aberdeen's historic fishing industry.
&lt;strong&gt;Flat Track Stats' MRDA Rating as of &lt;span class="lighter smaller notbold"&gt;9/4/18 [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/mrda/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/mrda/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;Only &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; of Tampere Rollin Bros' bouts are listed as MRDA Sanctioned, both in 2016, and those are the only source for FTS's MRDA rating for them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>crash test brummies</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>kamiquadz</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>silver city cup</category><category>south wales silures</category><category>super smash brollers</category><category>tampere rollin' bros</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/14/the-silver-city-cup-scotlands-first-mrda-tournament/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 19:30:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Silver City Cup - A Brawling Interview</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/06/silver-city-cup-a-brawling-interview/</link><dc:creator>davidlewis8891</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen, September 2018&lt;/strong&gt; - Granite City Brawlers are making history with their very own MRDA sanctioned tournament called 'Silver City Cup'. Whilst MRDA has Champs and Playoffs, there has never been a sanctioned tournament held in Scotland. Granite City Brawlers, Super Smash Brollers, Crash Test Brummies, Kamiquadz, South Wales Silures and Tampere Rollin' Bros are all looking to take the inaugural 'Silver City Cup'. With the Brawlers hoping to make their mark in the MRDA rankings, we took some time to speak to GCB's Co-Captain, Pudz (Chris Mathieson) about the upcoming tournament.
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27393" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/09/34909209_2057023227701408_2544234365819289600_o.jpg" alt="34909209_2057023227701408_2544234365819289600_o" width="1920" height="1280"&gt;
Photo by: Len Rizzo&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Straight off the bat, tell us how this tournament came about?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We joined the MRDA last September and as part of this the team is required to play 5 sanctioned games a year in order to gain ranking. The bigger teams can get their games quite easily in a tournament weekend through Champs and Playoffs, however there wasn’t much opportunity for the lower seeded teams. So we put our organisational heads together and decided to put on a tournament weekend for those below 40 or unranked in the MRDA. This allows 6 teams (including Brawlers) to gain 3 of their games in a single weekend!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does it feel to be able to host/create the first MRDA tournament in Scotland as well as it having quite the international flavour to it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are over the moon at having 6 teams coming from 5 countries to our little tournament in Aberdeen. We even been working with some local bodies to promote the tournament and the city. VisitAberdeenshire have even put together a web portal (&lt;a href="https://www.visitabdn.com/cp/silver-city-cup"&gt;https://www.visitabdn.com/cp/silver-city-cup&lt;/a&gt;) full of information to help our tourist friends. A lot of people see Aberdeen as this grey city with not much going on but there is such a history to it! Three top things to check out on your visit would be Dunnottar Castle (for the Game of Thrones fans), Footdee (a small area of quirky houses, 5 minutes from the venue) and Slains Castle (the backdrop of our fab logo, you might even see one of the ghouls).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As for this being the first MRDA tournament in Scotland we are delighted to showcase to the rest of our international association just what Scotland has to offer and that we can put on one hell of a tournament!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think we all want to know, how do you think GCB will fair given the tough competitors and the grueling nature of a tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is GCB’s first ever tournament and as such we’re going to need to bring our A game up against some tough opponents! With a few Scotland skaters at the helm, we have some tournament experience that will hopefully help the rest of the team prepare mentally and physically. We’ll be aiming for the win and to keep the Silver City Cup in the Silver City but every team has a good chance of taking that trophy home, the very nature of a tournament weekend is that anything could happen!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You say you’ve been preparing for the tournament, how have you done this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last month we hosted a double scrim with skaters from almost every league in Scotland. This allowed us to prepare for back to back games against some high level skaters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We also have our weekly outdoor fitness sessions with Intrepid PT, these have worked doubly as both exercise and team bonding. Though its been a year and we all still hate burpees!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Should the tournament fair well, could we be seeing an annual Silver City Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ask me when its over! Maybe not an annual tournament in Aberdeen but we’d love to see a division two type structure appear within the MRDA as it continues to grow. Obviously our end goal is MRDA Champs but that’s a few years away yet!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any final words that you would like to share with us?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We really want to put on a good tournament, representing all of Scotland and we’d love a big Scottish home crowd behind us – get your tickets now - &lt;a href="https://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/3446103"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/3446103&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some inspiring words from Granite City Brawlers own, Pudz. From the sounds of it, this will be an exciting weekend of roller derby so make sure you get your tickets and be a part of Scottish history on &lt;strong&gt;September 22-23 at the Beach Leisure Centre in Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;! You can check out further information at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/616684768693015/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/616684768693015/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27394" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/09/35151282_840046892864311_5399712130972778496_n.jpg" alt="35151282_840046892864311_5399712130972778496_n" width="810" height="450"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Article written by Brawlers correspondent HaJuken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>crash test brummies</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>kamiquadz</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mrda</category><category>silver city cup</category><category>south wales silures</category><category>super smash brollers</category><category>tampere rollin' bros</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/06/silver-city-cup-a-brawling-interview/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 11:21:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City Brawlers make Derby History</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/26/granite-city-brawlers-make-derby-history/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/img_0069-1.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-24500" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/img_0069-1.png" alt="" width="275" height="392"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/img_0070-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-24501" title="" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/img_0070-1.jpg" alt="" width="360" height="360"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
September has been an awfully exciting month for the Granite City Brawlers (GCB); they became the first Scottish league to achieve MRDA membership AND won the first MRDA sanctioned game to be held in Scotland (against Nottingham's Super Smash Brollers, 209 to 190). Pretty exciting stuff!
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/img_0071-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-24502" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/img_0071-1.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
I had a wee chat with GCB chairperson Pudz about the league application to MRDA and what this means for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;
Can you tell me a little about the MRDA application process? &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application process involves playing 5 games with at least one of these against an MRDA opponent and 2 letters of recommendation from an MRDA league and an MRDA recognised official. There are a few other boxes to tick and then your application is sent to MRDA for review. Once reviewed the application is put to vote by MRDA leagues and officials to decide if you are to be admitted to membership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;
What made GCB decide to become MRDA affiliated?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years we have grown naturally as a league. Starting from scratch with getting skaters through mins up to having a bouting team playing at home. We set MRDA status as one of our goals at our AGM last year as it felt like the natural progression for the club and we are delighted to present this as a completed project at our upcoming AGM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;What does MRDA membership mean for the Brawlers? What changes can we expect? Fancy riders for game day?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means the world to Brawlers, we have put our country on the map as the first league in Scotland to achieve this status.
Hopefully this means we can play a wider range of teams as opponents look for sanctioned games for ranking and tournament purposes.
[Plus] A bottle of rum in the changing room after games maybe 😉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;
Who is your dream MRDA opponent?, let's make it happen.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd personally love to play an Australian MRDA team like Sydney SMASH as I love the way they play derby. We'd also love to play in a tournament like MEC [Tyne and Fear's Men's European Cup] one day, that’s the dream!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Pudz!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm sure you're wondering where you can watch Scotland’s premier MRDA league play. Well get your diary out and make sure you keep &lt;strong&gt;25 November&lt;/strong&gt; free for a cheeky home game. GCB will be hosting an International Double Header where GCB will take on &lt;strong&gt;Team Poland&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; will also take on Poland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GCB will be playing an away game on 28 October too, more details shall be announced soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granite City Brawlers are currently one of thirty clubs in Scotland competing for a Grassroots Giving Grant from Skipton Building Society. You can help them win by clicking the link&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skiptongrg.co.uk/apply-for-funding/2017-shortlisted-groups/Scotland/granite-city-brawlers"&gt;http://www.skiptongrg.co.uk/apply-for-funding/2017-shortlisted-groups/Scotland/granite-city-brawlers&lt;/a&gt;
Congratulations GCB on making history!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/img_0040.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22169" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/img_0040.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="682"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mrda</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/26/granite-city-brawlers-make-derby-history/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 13:14:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>We're All Going on a Summer Brawliday</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/11/were-all-going-on-a-summer-brawliday/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/granitecitybrawlers/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (GCB) are preparing for their next game. This one promises to be extra special, not only is this the first Brawlers game outside of Scotland BUT it's also the first Brawlers game outside of the U.K.! The Brawlers are heading to Tenerife to play against &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Tibicenas-Mens-Roller-Derby-796092177146242/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tibicenas Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (TMRD).
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22166" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/img_0039.jpg" alt="" width="724" height="1024"&gt; Bout Poster courtesy of Tibicenas Men's Roller Derby&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to check  in with captains Pudz and Momo to ask about how the team are preparing for their next game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TMRD have previously played Madrid MadRiders but despite some serious snooping, I can't find any teams to link GCB to TMRD. Since this makes it super hard to make any predictions about the game, there is additional excitement. [&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRankv2.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SRDRank&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; gives the Brawlers the advantage over their hosts, but with low certainty - Ed.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;You played Oldham earlier this year and were victorious, how are you feeling about taking on Tibicenas Men's Roller Derby? &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Have you seen them play before or met any of the players during your World Cup experiences?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pudz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nervous but excited at the same time. We've scoured the internet for footage to watch but come up short so are going into this game a little bit blind as to our opponent's style. Unless you count their uploads of the T Rex on skates, if the dinosaur gets rostered we'll be facing a new challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Momo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We trained really hard on the run up to the Oldham game, I think we stepped up drastically from our previous game last year. We went back through the previous game and pin-pointed every weakness and focused heavily on certain aspects that were lacking; we're not perfect yet but the guys really worked hard and for the first time at the Oldham game we had in all sense's of the word: a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tenerife is a complete wild card! None of us know what to expect from the team and I think a lot of the guys are underestimating how hot it's going to be; myself and Pudz have a good idea how hard it's going to be after playing in Canada [at MRDWC] last year. TMRD will have the advantage being used to playing in the heat, and I think we are only playing with 9* so it's going to be seriously tough. Whatever happens we'll do all we can do and have fun knowing we have a holiday after the game as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We haven't seen the roster yet and I'm not sure if anyone played in the World Cup but it's obviously quite possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*GCB will now be playing with 10 skaters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tell me about your fundraising efforts to get the team and crew over to Tenerife &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pudz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five of our Brawlers are doing a sponsored leg wax to help cover the costs of skater insurance and the bus to the game in Tenerife. Whichever Brawler has the most money against their name will be getting a nice pre holiday leg wax. #waxonwaxbrawff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoever has the highest funds against them is going to have an itchy time in the crazy heat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/img_0038-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22170" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/img_0038-1.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/waxonwaxbrawff"&gt;http://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/waxonwaxbrawff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;What sort of special preparation are you doing as a team/individual for playing in such a super warm place?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pudz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team have been doing "jumper scrims" in preparation for the game to try and adjust to the heat. These have been met with sad faces from our peely wally Brawlers but have been good fun and shown off Raffers' fine selection of Christmas Jumpers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also invited some guests to scrim against the Brawler Tenerife roster as a warm up which went very well. Our Brawlers' hard work is paying off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Momo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've been training with jumpers on during scrims to help with heat training and our scrims are generally quite intense, almost "iron man" if you like, so it's good for the endurance, especially since we're playing with 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a scrim with the "Tenerife 9" vs the rest of the Brawlers, some GCRD members, and some Bairn City members last weekend, a good mixed bunch to help us prepare. They were great, totally mixed it up and they didn't take it easy on us! It went well and gave us a few more things to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;How does preparation for an international game differ to preparing for a local game?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pudz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to think about things like jet lag [not to Tenerife though! - Ed], lower roster numbers due to the distance travelled and, most importantly, the bar order; "Tres sidras por favor!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a team we are very excited to represent Scottish roller derby on an international scale, strengthening the roller derby community even further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Momo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preparing for Tenerife seems a lot more labour intensive from an organising point of view. If it wasn't for Nikki, Brawlers' Bench Manager, sorting the entire thing out I think we'd be walking from one end of the island to the other to get to the game. I did my bit as well though: I organised a rainbow of the best beach towels Scotland's ever seen! We're obviously doing our heat training and some of us have been working on our after party stamina to last the entire holiday, I guess maybe some of the guys have been working on their beach bods, not likely but maybe....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've lost a few skaters at the start of this year/ tail end of last year but we've gained some new young blood with loads of potential and honestly the Brawlers are the strongest we've ever been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're looking forward to what we have planned for the rest of 2017 and can't wait to see what 2018 brings!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22169" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/img_0040.jpg" alt="img_0040" width="1024" height="682"&gt; Photo Credit: Len Rizzo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge 'thank you' to Pudz and Momo for taking the time to answer my questions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, for one, am so excited for the first GCB international game and wish the team loads of luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, there's still time to donate and nominate your favourite brawler for a cheeky leg wax! &lt;a href="http://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/waxonwaxbrawff"&gt;http://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/waxonwaxbrawff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Brawlers/Tibicenas bout is in just 10 days - &lt;strong&gt;22 July&lt;/strong&gt;. The Facebook event is: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1910383885902598/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1910383885902598/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>tenerife</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/11/were-all-going-on-a-summer-brawliday/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 08:00:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City Brawlers Debut Home Game</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/12/granite-city-brawlers-debut-home-game/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's November, the winter duvet has been brought out of hibernation and it is rather chilly up here in Aberdeen. You may be thinking that the time for fun things is gone and that you will have to wait till next year for more roller derby up in Aberdeen (or south, I don't know who is reading this or from where, I'm hedging my bets here). Well, you are wrong. Very wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;b&gt;Saturday 19th &lt;/b&gt;November, Granite City Brawlers will take on Birmingham’s Crash Test Brummies B team for what promises to be a memorable game of roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11281" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/image.jpeg" alt="image" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why so special? Well...this is a very special game for a myriad of reasons, the biggest one being that it will be the FIRST EVER HOME GAME of GCB!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you may recognise a few faces and names, the brawlers have never played a public home game as a team. The brawlers did take on Bairn City Rollers’ Skelpies last year in Grangemouth but that was different, this time it's home turf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Brawlers have been preparing for their home debut for quite some time and a lot of people have been waiting eagerly. Well now the time is here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important facts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who? &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/662329417258500/?ti=cl"&gt;Granite City Brawlers vs Crash Test Brummies B&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What? Some first class roller derby. Considering the skaters taking part, I am expecting nippy footwork, hard hitting, near impenetrable walls and excellent sportsmanship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where? The &lt;b&gt;Beach Leisure Centre&lt;/b&gt;, Sea Beach, Aberdeen, AB24 5NR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When? Saturday 19th November 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at &lt;b&gt;2.15pm&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First Whistle at 2.45pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? Because roller derby is excellent and both of the teams playing are fabulous and it promises to be a good game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How? Entry is a bargain at £&lt;b&gt;4.00&lt;/b&gt; per human. Although under 12s get in free if accompanied by a paying adult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have heard rumours of there being a raffle...not rumours, it's totally true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So come and see some local roller derby history being made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11282" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/image1.jpeg" alt="image" width="665" height="960"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>crash test brummies</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>team scotland</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/12/granite-city-brawlers-debut-home-game/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 10:25:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bairn City's co-ed bout to celebrate their 4th birthday</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/05/bairn-citys-co-ed-bout-to-celebrate-their-4th-birthday/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bairn City Rollers became Scotland's first co-ed league back in 2012. Now as they approach their 4th birthday they are kicking of celebrations and ending their 2016 season in the best way they could, a co-ed game. Their opponents will be the Brawler Buddies, who are made up of skaters from &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/granitecitybrawlers/"&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GraniteCityRollerDerby/"&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/dundeerollergirls/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In change from the norm, there will be no advanced ticket sales for this event. Instead in celebration of their 4th birthday BCR are inviting spectators to pay what they want on the day. That's right, &lt;span class="_4n-j fsl"&gt;just turn up on the game and pay whatever you like.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game will take place at Grangemouth Sports Complex on Saturday the 15th of October, doors will be open from 2.15pm and first whistle will be at 2.40pm, for more information &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/527945357409228/"&gt;visit the event page here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/527945357409228/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-9205" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/bcr-banner.jpg?w=700" alt="bcr-banner" width="700" height="259"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bcr</category><category>central belters</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>grangemouth</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>skelpies</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/05/bairn-citys-co-ed-bout-to-celebrate-their-4th-birthday/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 19:38:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>