<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about granite city roller girls)</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/granite-city-roller-girls.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:54:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Granite City Roller Derby- A Roundup of 2015</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/21/granite-city-roller-derby-a-roundup-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-wp-1447877216475.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img title="wp-1447877216475" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-wp-1447877216475.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2015 was a crazily busy and exciting year for Granite City roller Girls. We took part in British Championships for the first time, gained an accredited NSO, some of our members left to pursue new adventures, we expanded our league and at the end of 2015, we changed our name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Northern Fights took part in British Championships which was so exciting for the entire league! We were placed in Tier 3, Regional North; along with our good pals Dundee Roller Girls as well as Sheffield Steel Rollergirls, Furness Firecrackers, Liverpool Roller Birds and Halifax Bruising Banditas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first game in February saw us playing against Dundee Roller Girls. A fierce first game of the season and Champs! Dundee took the win with 366 to 58.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There wasn't long to wait until our next game in March where we were paired up against Sheffield Steel Rollergirls. The game was close and moments were tense, too tense. My poor wee heart! Final scores were GCRG 144 and SSRG 186.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June it was our turn to play Liverpool Roller Birds who scored 284 to our 111 with our next game just around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;July saw GCRG take on Furness Firecrackers who won our game with 325 to 112.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-fb_img_1447877829715.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1447877829715.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-fb_img_1447877829715.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo credit: the lovely  Ian McCreadie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August the Northern Fights played their last game of 2015 British Championships against Halifax Bruising Banditas. We won our final game of the year with a score of 226 to 72.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spoke to Berocca Bama, the Northern Fights co-captain for 2015, about taking part in British Championships.
&lt;em&gt;
"The Northern Fights had the privilege of taking part in the 2015 British Championships. It was an exciting year and although we started off with many skaters who were new to the team, every single one stepped up to the challenge and we went from strength to strength, surprising ourselves and others along the way. The dedication and drive of each sportswoman on the team makes me very proud to have played alongside them this season and fills me with excited anticipation for all that 2016 holds. Go Fights! "&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we had a record breaking, based on no fact at all other than it seemed a huge amount, number of skaters coming up from fresh meat together. One intake generated 12 new league skaters. 12! That’s almost an entire team. This increase in mins passed skaters is a combination of all of the hardwork put in by our fresh meat training squad (namely Shan, Krusty, Berocca Bama and Nikki) and the hardwork and determination that our ‘noobs’ bring with them to training each and every week. As a mentor I get to witness this first hand…and yes…I have cried many a proud tear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-wp-1447876987607.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img title="wp-1447876987607" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-wp-1447876987607.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo above: 11 of our 12 strong mins passed skaters from the start of the year, followed by 6 more later in the year &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This increase in mins passed skaters necessitated the need to introduce a second team. So, in 2015, Granite City Roller Girls welcomed their B Team. The Fight Hawks. Kakaw!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hawks played their first game in September against Lothian Derby Dolls. It was a tense game and I think we all learned never to start celebrating a win until the score says ‘Official’. A win was taken and fun was had all round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October the Hawks played Mean City. A loss was taken this time around but so much was learned and again, great times were had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spoke to Fight Hawks' co-captain Whips 'n' Lashes about our newest team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt; "2015 was an exciting year for GCRD with the creation of our B team – The Fight Hawks. Fierce and determined we rose to the challenge, with our first game together being a nail biting win. For a lot of our ladies this was their first ever public outing and the professionalism, attitude and energy they showed made our league and support very proud! 2016 is already looking like a good year and we hope to continue our development not only as a team but as a league and we are looking forward to the next lot of skaters coming up. Kakaw!"&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-fb_img_1447877532971.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1447877532971.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-fb_img_1447877532971.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo credit: the glorious Dave McAleavy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some say ‘you learn more in defeat that victory’, I can’t speak for everyone but I feel this is true. We may not have had an amazing win streak this year but after every game we have learned about ourselves and our team. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;December will see the annual GCRG Christmas ceildhi where we will celebrate our achievements of the year. Through the medium of dance and good times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision was made this year to rebrand. I, for one, am ridiculously excited about our new colour scheme. As a league and as skaters we are growing and we voted to change our name from Granite City Roller Girls to Granite City Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-bz4tbsp92ovcwuqx4vpjtodas6auvqgnsen4sztbxcw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="bZ4TBsp92oVCWUqx4VpjTODas6auVQgnsEN4SZtbxcw.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-bz4tbsp92ovcwuqx4vpjtodas6auvqgnsen4sztbxcw.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture above: our super amazingly fantastic new logos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge thank you goes out to everyone who has helped us to have an amazing 2015; referees and NSOs,  we couldn’t do any of this without you, announcers and photographers, our wonderful training team, everyone who has helped make bout days happen, our fans for never failing to keep our spirits high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here’s to 2016 and GRANITE CITY ROLLER DERBY!!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>gcrd</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/21/granite-city-roller-derby-a-roundup-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 10:49:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fight Hawks at the Trawler: GCRG's B Team speak.</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/31/fight-hawks-at-the-trawler-gcrgs-b-team-speak/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coming soon to Edinburgh, &lt;a href="http://lothianderbydolls.com/"&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; will play Aberdeen's second ever derby team, as &lt;a href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/"&gt;Granite City Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; launch their B-squad, the &lt;em&gt;Fight Hawks&lt;/em&gt;. We caught up with Fight Hawks Bench Manager, Pert Hits, to find out a bit more. (Season Tickets for &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/346223992230568/"&gt;the bout on the 12th&lt;/a&gt;, and LDD's two subsequent games, can be obtained from &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/1820858"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City are only the fourth Scottish league to form a B-team (after ARRG, GRD and DRG). How does it feel to be able to launch a second travel team? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels natural.  With the roster sort of set for the Northern Fights, it had left a fair few of our skaters with no games to play, which was a real real shame given the calibre of skaters we are seeing coming through our fresh meat course (a number of whom completed the 3 month course and passed all mins first time!).  As the number increased over the course of the year, it just felt like the right time for it to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you tell us a little about the makeup of the team, and the selection process? Are these all new skaters to GCRG fans?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a look at the sheer number of mins passed skaters we had that were not dedicated to the British Championships and who were game ready.  Various things were looked at, perhaps the more important factors were attendance to training and scrim practice.  The team selection will be quite fluid as time goes on with different players perhaps being selected for each game.  Of the 14 skaters submitted for our first game, only 4 of them will be familiar faces to GCRG fans.  The rest may have been spotted in various "cherry poppers" across Scotland to those with a keen eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GCRG B are named 'The Fight Hawks'. Obviously, this continues the 'Fight' theme with GCRG A 'Northern Fights', but which Night Hawks (the painting, perhaps?) were you inspired by, and what do you hope it says about you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are actually named after a local term for seagulls, which we have in Aberdeen in abundance.  A quick youtube search and you can see why we went with this name; they're brash, brave and persistent.  And we will steal your chips when you're not looking.  But we do pay for Doritos, so please feel free to invite us for game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your first bout is away against Lothian Derby Dolls, down in Edinburgh. How are you preparing for the bout? What result are you hoping for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With British Champs winding down for the Northern Fights, we are in a good position to have our training sessions tailored directly towards the Hawks' needs. As bench and line-up, myself and Krusty have been watching like... hawks... as the girls train and giving feedback to our training committee, who have been very good at taking it into account and getting the right drills we need. We have also been doing "Hawks vs the rest" at scrim practices just to ensure the team meld and we get a good hive mind.
We are heading down to Edinbrugh looking to score more points. Perhaps the more important win, however, is knowing we gave 100% and played well as a team. Even defeats on the score board feel like wins if you know you did your best and worked well as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What're the Hawks' plans for the future? With GCRG A committed to British Champs, will you guys be taking on more eclectic teams?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not entirely certain what the future holds for us. I would certainly be expecting a good jaunt around Scotland in 2016, playing various teams, and with the right amount of fundraising taking our team a little further afield would a dream!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>b-teams</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/31/fight-hawks-at-the-trawler-gcrgs-b-team-speak/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 14:42:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Final Champs game for DRG</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/04/final-champs-game-for-drg/</link><dc:creator>julezw</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girls Silvery Tayzers will travel to Sheffield this Saturday (8th August) to compete in the final triple header of the British Championships T3 Regional North. After securing victory against Sheffield Steel Roller Girls in July, Dundee have left themselves in a great position to secure a play-off spot. Victory against Furness Firecrackers will see Dundee progress but with three teams still in with a chance (Furness Firecrackers, Liverpool Roller Birds and Dundee), it’s all to play for. Last time the teams met, Dundee emerged victorious and will be looking for a similar outcome this time round.
In the days other games, GCRG take on Halifax Bruising Banditas and hosts Sheffield take on Liverpool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ssrg.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4836" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ssrg.png?w=214" alt="SSRG" width="214" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come down and join the fun!
Concord Sports Centre, Shiregreen Lane, Sheffield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors 9.30am.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/04/final-champs-game-for-drg/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 16:32:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Helgin Roller Derby: Scotland's Northernmost League!</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/23/helgin-roller-derby-scotlands-northernmost-league/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New Roller Derby leagues are still popping up over Scotland, as we saw recently in our interview with &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/29/a-wee-chat-with-wee-county-roller-derby/"&gt;Wee County&lt;/a&gt;. Now we're catching up with a new league in another part of the country entirely, Elgin's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HelginRollerDerby"&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/21091_1426672460962596_502025641894684557_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-4830" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/21091_1426672460962596_502025641894684557_n.jpg?w=660" alt="Helgin Roller Derby logo by Brett Tucker" width="660" height="660"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Helgin Roller Derby logo by Brett Tucker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helgin Roller Derby is now the northernmost mainland Scottish league, thanks to the curve of the coast near Lossiemouth. Can you tell us a little about who you are, and why you decided to found a new league?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helgin Roller Derby was started by our chairperson, Angela Ellis, in February 2014. She had relocated to Elgin from Dingwall and was looking for a way to meet new people and have fun whilst doing it. Having always been a fan of Roller Derby, starting her own team in Elgin seemed like the best way to do this. Angela used social media to garner interest and by November 2014 Helgin Roller Derby was finally a reality when 5 girls got together and started skating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like Wee County, who we spoke to recently, Helgin is a co-ed league from the start. Do you think Co-ed derby is the future of the sport, and if so, why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Wee County, we are also based in a somewhat wee county – Moray has a population of only 93,295, spread across a huge area stretching 2,238 km2 from Cairngorm National Park to the Moray Firth. We think it’s important in areas such as these to be as inclusive as you can. We didn’t want to be turning away members because of their gender. We didn’t even turn away someone because of her age and we now allow people aged 16+ to train with the adult team. In Scottish Law, the age of majority is 16, and if you can get married at that age, why shouldn’t you be allowed to play derby?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think that co-ed is a good starting point, and hope that in the future, we’ll attract enough members to have a co-ed roster, a female roster, a male roster, and a junior roster, giving everyone in Moray the opportunity to play derby… but that will be a few years down the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/wpid-wp-1437680568432.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-4828" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/wpid-wp-1437680568432.jpeg?w=660" alt="Helgin at practice!" width="660" height="440"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Helgin at practice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ve already held a few fundraisers and promotional events, including a pub quiz with some impressive prizes. How has your awareness and recruitment been like in the area?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been brilliant! We’ve got 283 likes on Facebook, and have attracted 15 regular skating members to the team already – not bad for a team that’s been going less than a year! Each Fresh Meat session we hold attracts more people each time, and we’re looking forward to hosting another in September. Everyone on the team is really proud to be part of it and are fantastic promoters of the team, telling everyone they know how great derby is and how much fun they have taking part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Pub Quiz was great fun, and we’re extremely grateful to all the local businesses for their support. Our top prize was a tour and tasting at local craft brewery, Windswept, and we also had fantastic raffle prizes from Ben Romach whisky, local pizza restaurant Scribbles, and Walkers Shortbread. We’ll definitely be holding more social events in the future, as they are not only good for raising funds, but also for raising awareness of the club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helgin Roller Derby’s logo is a rather strikingly blue Nordic lady with a big axe. What inspired your choice of logo, and was it produced by members of the league, or outside talent?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is said that the town of Elgin was founded by the Norse General, Helgin in the 10th Century when Vikings invaded Scotland. We thought that ‘Helgin’ had a nice ring to it, invoking the idea of Hell and fitting well with the punk aesthetic generally associated with Roller Derby, so this became the team’s name. It seemed only appropriate that our logo reflect the name’s true Viking origins, and our current logo was designed by a supporter of the club, who is an artist for a games design company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We see that Inverness City Roller Derby and Granite City Roller Girls have both provided assistance to Helgin in starting up. What’s your relationship been like with the Scottish Derby community so far?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re extremely grateful to the support we’ve received from &lt;a href="http://www.invernessrollerderby.com/"&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/"&gt;Granite City Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;. We try and train with ICRD at least once a month, as Natorious Red is a fantastic coach and really gives us a good workout, improving our skills. She also helps inspire us to improve our own coaching for those who have joined us after a Fresh Meat, and we take away a number of great drills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City Roller Girls support us through all of our Fresh Meat sessions, providing all the kit we require and two great coaches in Krusty Thud and Frost Damage. They coach the GCRG newbies, so they really know how to enthuse people about Derby, and make them fall in love with the sport!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, we’ve received great feedback and advice from most of the bouting leagues across Scotland, and we’re really excited to be part of such a fantastic community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Starting out, many leagues seem to find practice space the most difficult thing to find. You’ve already had one move of location, I believe - but you seem to have plenty of suitable locations to fall back on. What’s been your experience of this?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most leagues, we have struggled to find a space big enough to fit a full-size roller derby track, and it looks unlikely that we will be able to host a bout anywhere in the whole of Moray in the near future. We’ve bounced around between four halls, but finally have two spaces large enough to lay out a full-size track, in the games halls in Elgin Community Centre and Milne’s High School in Fochabers, where we train on Saturdays and Tuesdays, respectively. There is also positive discussion in Elgin about a new sports facility being built, which we hope will have a space large enough for the full track, the required safety zones and room for spectators, allowing Helgin Roller Derby to host bouts in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, what are your plans for the rest of the year?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve got another Fresh Meat planned for September, and will have at least one more social fundraiser towards the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re finishing up our business plan and sorting out a team bank account, so will also be applying for funding in the near future, and hope to be able to buy more of our own kit, so we’re not as dependent on GCRG’s kit for Fresh Meat sessions, and so we have more kit to hire to people who are waiting for theirs to arrive after Fresh Meats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re hoping to be able to move into doing on-skates contact training soon, and will hopefully have some skaters minimum skills passed by early 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>hrd</category><category>interviews</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/23/helgin-roller-derby-scotlands-northernmost-league/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 19:51:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls British Champs Game Four</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/03/dundee-roller-girls-british-champs-game-four/</link><dc:creator>julezw</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girls Silvery Tayzers host their first, long awaited home game of the season on July 11th at Dundee International Sports Centre. This game sees the Tayzers take on Sheffield Steel Rollergirls (featuring ex-DRG alumni Carnage T800), in Game four of DRG’s British Championships season. With both teams sitting on six points and with 2 wins and 1 defeat under their belt this is a must-win game for the Tayzers as their final game sees them take on league leaders Furness Firecrackers in a triple header in August.
The game at DISC is a double header with Granite City Roller Girls taking on Furness Firecrackers, giving DRG an insight into what’s in store for their final game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/110715.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4783" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/110715.png?w=212" alt="110715" width="212" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 12.30pm, first whistle at 1pm. Advance tickets £5 available from &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/1766026"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, tickets available on the door £6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join the Facebook event using this &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/upcoming?action_history=null"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/03/dundee-roller-girls-british-champs-game-four/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 20:54:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City Roller Girls - A Roundup of 2014</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/30/granite-city-roller-girls-a-roundup-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I transferred to Granite City Rollergirls in February 2014 and have been lucky enough to spend a fun filled (almost) year with the league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a busy year for GCRG! We have had a few changes to the league, some friends left for pastures new, some returned and we got some amazingly talented new teammates and referees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been many promotion opportunities for us including the Discover Aberdeen dolphins and live demonstrations in the Bon Accord Centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/gcrg.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4487" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/gcrg.png" alt="Granite City Roller Girls  official logo" width="335" height="151"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Granite City Roller Girls official logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our final game of 2014 against Bedforshire's Rebellion Roller Derby was a fantastic game to watch. The team really pulled together and used every skill that they had been working on and ended our bouting year on a high with a win of 184 to 155.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the whole league will agree that one of our highlights of 2014 was cheering our wee hearts out for Jill Stephen (Fight Cub), Jill Simpson (Rock n Riot), and Carolyn Mackenzie (Clinically Wasted) when they represented GCRG in Team Scotland at the Blood and Thunder Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended 2014 with an annual Skateroonie where fights, refs and newbies got together to play games, eat food and more importantly, play tug of war (the girls took victory ). This was followed a few days later with a league night out to end 2014 appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My own highlight for 2014 was playing my debut game as a Northern Fight against Hull. There was a great atmosphere and I was super proud to represent the Fights for the first time. Any occasion where we get together whether to skate or just have a nice time is always a highlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10571952_10154540553565160_2015222088721681186_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4479" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10571952_10154540553565160_2015222088721681186_o.jpg" alt="Photo credit: Caroline Allison" width="614" height="461"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photo credit: Caroline Allison&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a mentor for our fresh meat I have the luxury of seeing our newbies turn from timid wee lambs into confident team mates. The structure of fresh meat training has changed so you can really see the progress from one week to the next. I'm so excited to see what the future holds for our newbs! They will be taking part in their first team scrimmage in January and I for one will be beaming with pride...and just a wee warning that I shall probably cry proud little tears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year promises to be an exciting whirlwind for GCRG as we will be taking part in British Championships Heartland series! Some of our eagle eyed readers may have seem the recent announcement of GCRG's B team. There is so much to come and I'm excited!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I spoke to GCRG's captain for 2015, Mental, about what the roller derby community can expect from GCRG next year;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"From the start of 2015 we have entered the British Championships, these are very exciting times for GCRG. For me personally I've got big boots to fill but I believe if you put in 100% you get 100%. I can see a more focussed, determined and stronger team for 2015"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10460596_10203580393204655_5761820161661248642_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4480 size-full" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10460596_10203580393204655_5761820161661248642_o.jpg" alt="Photo credit : Andy Morris" width="614" height="410"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photo credit: Andy Morris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/30/granite-city-roller-girls-a-roundup-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Scotland</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/16/world-cup-interview-team-scotland/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Team-Scotland-Roller-Derby/235701999922927"&gt;Scotland&lt;/a&gt; competed in the 2011 &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; and secured 11&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; place, after a difficult placement group with the USA and New Zealand.  Jill Stephen represented Scotland last time (skating as Fight Cub) and is back for more. She was kind enough to let me interview her.
&lt;p&gt;This weekend Scotland will be competing in &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/724704624268299/?fref=ts"&gt;The Road to Dallas&lt;/a&gt; alongside Team Ireland, Wales and West Indies, having already played two warm-up bouts (against the &lt;a title="Team Scotland v Euro Stars – This Saturday!" href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/03/team-scotland-v-euro-stars-this-saturday/"&gt;Euro-Stars&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="Are they HOT or WOT? Team Scotland’s latest challengers speak." href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/12/are-they-hot-or-wot-team-scotlands-latest-challengers-speak/"&gt;Hot or WOT&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/team-scotland.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4001" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/team-scotland.png?w=300" alt="Team Scotland logo" width="300" height="246"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Team Scotland logo by Admiral Attackbar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the topic of team selection - Can you tell me a bit about how your team selection process worked?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a long and thorough process. There were round one tryouts, round two tryouts and a final top 20 training team picked as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tryouts were open to anyone and were a great way to practice with people from leagues all over the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It never felt tense or pressured and everyone was very relaxed. The scrims were great fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it difficult having people from different leagues get together for training?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having skaters from various leagues undoubtedly makes it tricky to all meet up and practice but we’ve managed to get a good few practices in so far with more planned before the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The training sessions have been tough but excellent. It’s such a privilege to be skating such talented women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have very packed derby calendars as it is so free weekends are like gold dust!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have you been personally preparing for the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a complete diet overhaul since selection which has made a huge difference to my fitness and agility. I’ve also been working on upper body strength at the gym.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mental preparation has also been a big part of my training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flying to the USA from anywhere is expensive as a team, how have you been fundraising and achieving sponsorship?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have some wonderful sponsors including S1 helmets and Atom wheels. There have been a few fundraisers including bouts, a bootcamp and some fabulous merch! We’ve also received extremely generous donations over at &lt;a href="http://gogetfunding.com/project/get-team-scotland-to-dallas"&gt;http://gogetfunding.com/project/get-team-scotland-to-dallas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We still have a few events up our sleeves before we head out as well. Keep your eyes peeled!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What teams are you most looking forward to playing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would LOVE to have the opportunity to play any of the top 3 finishers from the last world cup (USA, Canada, England).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You always learn so much from a really tough game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you most looking forward to about the World Cup this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching the new teams that have entered this year will be awesome. Also, playing and hanging out with all my Team Scotland team mates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You skated in the World Cup in 2011; has this had an impact on your training for December?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like Roller Derby is still changing in such a way that all you can ever do is work as hard, focus and train. Nobody will really know what to expect until we get there and it will be a million miles away from the derby we were playing 3 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Team Scotland roster&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;0 Louise Kerr&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;09 Jill Simpson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;11 Parry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;111 Mackenzie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1111 Jenny Gow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;182 Jill Stephen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;22 Grace Maclean&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;28 Lauren Bianchi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;210 Rogue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3 Cider&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;39 Davis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4 Megan Hyndman&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;69 Laura Liston&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;85 Skinner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;87 Caitlen O'Carroll&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;931 Rebecca Ryan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;F104 Marshall Lawless&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bench coach - Coach Noble&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Line up Manager - Murphy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Manager - Jill Antonic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/16/world-cup-interview-team-scotland/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 09:19:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>GCRG Rock Night</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/23/gcrg-rock-night/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Friday 17th October Granite City Roller Girls are hosting the next long awaited Rock Night!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A night of Rock music featuring some homegrown talent, a booze raffle and other awesome prizes up for grabs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/gcrg-rock-night.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/gcrg-rock-night.jpg" alt="GCRG rock night" width="614" height="868" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3859"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lineup includes;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking Sideways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A local band from Aberdeen heavily influenced by Biffy Clyro
&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/talkingsideways" rel="nofollow"&gt;www.facebook.com/talkingsideways&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miss Lucid
&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;Miss Lucid offer their own style of 'in your face' rock, driven with the punk/grunge undertones of bands such as The Clash and Nirvana, blending large sonic sound scapes and crafted melodies reminiscent of Placebo and Manic Street Preachers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MissLucid" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/MissLucid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
Guttergodz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;An eclectic mix of influences in the band such as Thin Lizzy, The Wildhearts, Elvis Presley, Backyard Babies, The Clash and so on. In 2010 they made it into the shortlist of bands rated 'particularly awesome' by Kerrang radio and at the start of 2013 they were crowned 'Best Rock Band' at the Fudge awards in Aberdeen and made it to the final of Cafe Drummond's battle of the bands to win £2000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/guttergodz" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/guttergodz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 8pm with £8.00 entry. An absolute bargain!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus booze raffle!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...did I already mention booze raffle? I'm just pretty excited about somebody winning a hamper of booze and rocking out to some great music&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So come on down to Downstairs at 82 Holburn Street and start your weekend off on a high!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fundraiser event</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/23/gcrg-rock-night/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 21:04:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City Roller Girls &amp; Granite City Brawlermen Recruitment Day</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/22/granite-city-roller-girls-and-granite-city-brawlermen-recruitment-day/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/gcrg-recruits-6-september-2014.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-3611" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/gcrg-recruits-6-september-2014.jpg?w=212" alt="GCRG recruits 6 September 2014" width="212" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/gcb-recruitment-6-september-2014.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3612" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/gcb-recruitment-6-september-2014.jpg?w=212" alt="GCB recruitment 6 September 2014" width="212" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City Roller Girls and Granite City Brawlermen are recruiting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday 6th September is an exciting day for Roller Derby Recruitment in Aberdeen with not one but two intakes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, Granite City Roller Girls are holding their intake day at Aberdeen Lads Club (Dill Road) from 11:00-13:00. Then from 13.30 to 15.30 the Brawlermen will be welcoming new recruits as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both GCRG and GCB have experienced coaches who can teach people of all levels so no skating experience is necessary and we can provide equipment - please drop us a message on Facebook to let us know what shoe size you take so we can make sure we have skates for you on the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GCRG are also on the lookout for referees so any ladies or gents who would like to get involved with this aspect of the sport should pop along too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby is a brilliant way to get fit and meet new people! All we ask is that you’re over 18 years old, wear non restrictive clothing and bring plenty of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put on some skates, be your own hero!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information please email newrecruits@granitecityrollergirls.org.uk or granitecitybrawlermen@gmail.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also find our Facebook events at
&lt;a title="GCRG Fresh Meat" href="http://www.facebook.com/events/711800382227020/"&gt;www.facebook.com/events/711800382227020/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/311415489033203/?fref=ts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fresh meat</category><category>gcb</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/22/granite-city-roller-girls-and-granite-city-brawlermen-recruitment-day/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 22:32:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee and Granite City - A Retrospective.</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/03/23/dundee-and-granite-city-a-retrospective/</link><dc:creator>clinicallywasted</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the 29&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of March 2014 Granite City Roller Girls will face off against Dundee Roller Girls’ Silvery Tayzers. This will be the third time the teams have played each other in the space of 4 years – a period of time that has seen a change in the look, the feel and the integrity of our sport and as such, a change in The Fights and The Tayzers. Clinically Wasted and Milky offer an interesting retrospective into how their leagues have developed in this time, and their aspirations for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City and Dundee were the first younger leagues to spring up in Scotland after the teams on the central belt had become more established. As a result, the leagues formed a symbiotic relationship, assisting each other wherever they could.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;-Roller derby in Dundee has always been close with GCRG. They made the journey week after week to help us with every aspect of derby - from putting us through our minimum skills to helping us structure our league. It's fair to say that we wouldn't be the team we are without the help they gave us in the start, and their continuing support.&lt;/em&gt; (Milky)&lt;em&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;-The relationship between Aberdeen and Dundee goes back along time, before I had even put on a pair of skates myself. The maturing of both leagues has ran side by side, and for a while it almost felt like we had a conjoined league of Dundeen where we would attend each others training and in fact GCRG’s first ever closed door bout featured a few of the Dundee girls.&lt;/em&gt; -(Clinically Wasted)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/935888_10153084748090392_1488004219_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3344" alt="Courtesy of Zenspirations Photography" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/935888_10153084748090392_1488004219_n.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Courtesy of Zenspirations Photography&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Riding off the back of Highland Fling, Dundee hosted their first ever home game in November 2010. Their opponents - GCRG's Northern Fights.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;-A select few of us remember bouting GCRG  - our first home bout as Dundee Destroyers. We didn't have any tactics really, we were just ecstatic to be sharing the track with our big sister league. We didn't take ourselves or the bout too seriously. As newbies we were all still caught up in the novelty of bouting - I think the majority of our time was spent considering uniforms, chants and face paint. Needless to say, GCRG had the edge on the day and took home the win. &lt;/em&gt;(M)&lt;em&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;-We were flying high with all the good intentions and in our fishnets, high socks and pants we were ready to kick butt. Dundee so kindly got somebody to film the occasion so it can eternally be watched. The video always makes me smile, because I remember how much fun we had that game, playing against our sisters. &lt;/em&gt;(CW)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/gcrgvsrk1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3346 " alt="Courtesy of Andrew Leatherbarrow." src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/gcrgvsrk1.jpg" width="614" height="407"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Courtesy of Andrew Leatherbarrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you haven't seen it already, here is a link to the video by Dylan Drummond: &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IPylGsXKJAE" target="_blank"&gt;Northern Fights vs Rippin Kittens 2010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time marched on. Outside of these two league's UKRDA were fighting for recognised sport status, London RollerGirls had joined WFTDA, people were taking knee down starts…remember them? Our sport evolved. And then these sister leagues played again, this time in Aberdeen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;-By our return bout the following year, we were now Dundee Roller Girls. Skating under a new name and colour and with new ambitions and values. The team was much more focused - we'd spent months studying our tactics, rules and honing our skills. The atmosphere for us was a little more tense this time as we were aiming for a win. The bout was hard fought from both sides, but again GCRG just pipped us in the final minutes. It was the best we'd skated as a team and the closest we'd come to victory. We finished proud of ourselves and incredibly proud of our friends in GCRG who had grown so much and who continued to teach and support us.&lt;/em&gt; (M)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- The game was hard, well fought, close and most of all fun. The level of derby and strategy had changed, but that buzz of seeing your friends play well made it all worth while. (CW)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/nfvsst.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3348" alt="Courtesy of Granite City Roller Girls" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/nfvsst.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Courtesy of Granite City Roller Girls&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fast forward to now, in 2014. DRG and GCRG have both had an incredible few seasons. Both teams are serious about progressing our sport and promoting the athleticism and empowerment they've worked so hard to achieve. Each team has changed vastly since they first lined up against each other in 2010; Dundee are in fact a completely different league with only 4 rostered skaters playing from the original line up, and Granite City only having 3 original Fights playing. Despite all the changes the two teams have experienced, they've continued to meet on track throughout the years, together and as opponents, still supporting our derby sisters and always proud of each teams acheivements.
&lt;/strong&gt;
-&lt;em&gt;We've remained each other's biggest fans. For me, I still frantically follow Twitter feeds for away scores as if it were for my own league. Regardless of the outcome of our upcoming bout, there's not a team in the world I'd rather share a track with, and not a team in the world I'd rather drag my battered body to share a pint with afterwards! &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;(&lt;/em&gt;M)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;em&gt;We always love catching up with the Dundee girls, and when we hear of their upcoming games it's as if we are skating with them! Tentatively waiting for scores on twitter and facebook! &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;People have come and gone and attitudes have changed but I know for certain one thing; at the final whistle, we will all hug, we will go grab a beer and we will all party like it’s 2010! (&lt;/em&gt;CW)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Girls play Dundee Roller Girls Saturday 29th of March 2014 at the Beach Leisure Centre in Aberdeen. Doors at 2.00pm for 3.00pm. Free Entry.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/blamming-season.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3347" alt="Courtesy of Granite City Roller Girls." src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/blamming-season.jpg" width="614" height="868"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Courtesy of Granite City Roller Girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>aberdeen</category><category>articles</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>pictures</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>video</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/03/23/dundee-and-granite-city-a-retrospective/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 19:50:43 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>