<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about grd)</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/grd.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:54:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>June 11th's Packed Scottish Derby Schedule...</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The weekend of the 11th is another extravaganza for high level Scottish Roller Derby, with both Auld Reekie Roller Girls and Glasgow Roller Derby engaged in multiple bouts across the weekend, and Fierce Valley playing away in the continuing British Champs Tier 3 North fixtures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Glasgow and Fierce Valley playing away, the Scottish home games are happening at Auld Reekie's traditional venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Meadowbank+Sports+Centre/@55.956622,-3.1585026,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4887b86eb150070f:0x6955a8c9b9a10cc5!8m2!3d55.956619!4d-3.1563086"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, doors open at &lt;strong&gt;2:20pm Saturday 11th&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-7441" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13235130_10156950736565224_2994993262049877442_o.jpg?w=1024" alt="13235130_10156950736565224_2994993262049877442_o" width="1024" height="385"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heading up &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/350352705088707/"&gt;the double-header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Auld Reekie's All-Stars are taking on Kallio Rolling Rainbow, one of Finland's finest teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After their usual impressive performance at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-big-o-2016-schedule-timezones/"&gt;The Big O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Oregon, Auld Reekie are riding high, ready for another challenge - Kallio are slightly higher ranked than they are (FlatTrackStats &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/79684/rankings"&gt;predicts a win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the Finns, albeit with some uncertainty). This will be a WFTDA Sanctioned bout and contribute to both teams' rankings, so it will be an especially hard-fought contest, as both teams will want to reach Division 1 (or remain in Division 2) of the WFTDA Rankings in order to qualify for Playoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other bout is no less exciting in its own way, marking the debut of ARRG's new 'C'-team, the 'All-Star Rookies'&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/#sup"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as they take on Granite City Roller Girls B, the Fight Hawks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, with a team debut, it's hard to make predictions as to the result of the bout; this will be a contest between Auld Reekie's new skater training and the experience gained by the Fight Hawks over the last year. (Having seen some of ARRG's rookies in "rising stars" bouts in the last few months, however, there's some very impressive performers there...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets on the door will be £8 (just £4 per bout), or £5 online via &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2553305"&gt;BrownPaperTickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Concessions tickets will be just £6 on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Glasgow Roller Derby are apparently the stars of the show down in Oldham, as Rainy City Roller Derby are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://rainycityrollerderby.com/event/euro-weekender/"&gt;hosting a weekend of derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, in which Glasgow feature in 3 out of 4 bouts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a Scotland versus Wales playoff, Glasgow's A team, the Irn Bruisers, will be taking on Tiger Bay Brawlers' A; and their B team, the Maiden Grrders will also be facing off against TBB's B-Bombs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FlatTrackStats predicts an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/7953/7929"&gt;incredibly closely-matched bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; between the A-teams (the result depends on which team you give "home-team advantage" to). The B-teams are almost as close in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/10262/11067"&gt;FTS's predictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, although it looks like their stats very narrowly favour the Welsh team (albeit by only a few percent). With only one exception, match-ups between GRD and TBB have been hard-fought, high-level affairs, so we do anticipate some great derby here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Rainy City Roller Derby are scheduled against simply "Glasgow Roller Derby", which we might guess is the A team... Last time they faced each other, Glasgow came out with a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/59869"&gt;convincing win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;; but Glasgow's significant team changes this year have FTS &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/10262/11067"&gt;predicting a win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the home team this time around. Glasgow will have to pull out something special to keep the win record on their side...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the rankings of Tiger Bay Brawlers A, and Rainy City Roller Derby, these bouts also fill in a chunk of the higher-level UK matchups missing from British Champs this year. With the results from these games, we'll be publishing an "extended" BC Tier 1 ranking, extrapolating where some of the teams not competing in T1 might have ended up, this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[On the Sunday, Kallio Roller Derby are also featuring in this derby weekend, so presumably there's some exciting train travel in Kallio's Sunday morning schedule...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://britishchamps.com"&gt;British Champs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, after an extended period &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/17/british-champs-at-dundee/"&gt;hosted in Scotland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the Tier 3 North fixtures continue in the North of England, with Hallam Hellcats hosting a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/587023974805101/"&gt;double-header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of bouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7445" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13267947_1010255862421996_6895825634478283487_n.jpg" alt="13267947_1010255862421996_6895825634478283487_n" width="530" height="750"&gt; Hallam's bout poster was also available as a limited edition physical print! (Design by Ed Syder) &lt;a href="http://edsyder.tumblr.com/"&gt;http://edsyder.tumblr.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hosts will be taking on Preston Roller Girls, while Scotland will be represented by Fierce Valley Roller Girls taking on Manchester Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FVRG will be hard pressed to defeat currently unbeaten Manchester, but a loss will keep them at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/womens-tables-2016/"&gt;bottom of the table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and in danger of relegation. Meanwhile, Hallam and Preston will be fighting it out to avoid the second-from-bottom spot in the table - there's not much to call between them, but FTS believes that home-team advantage gives the hosts &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/25963/8972"&gt;a slight edge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="sup"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;the Auld Reekie current team naming scheme is a bit confusing - the A team are simply "All-Stars", whilst the B team append "Reserves" and the C team "Rookies". This makes it a bit hard to unambiguously form acronyms for the two, but we're working on this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>auldreekierollergirls</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>fvrg</category><category>gcrd</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>hallam hellcats roller derby</category><category>kallio rolling rainbow</category><category>manchester roller derby</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 11:04:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ARRG and Glasgow Home Seasons Final!</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/23/arrg-and-glasgow-home-seasons-final/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Saturday (&lt;strong&gt;28th November&lt;/strong&gt;) sees Home Teams Tournaments on both coasts, as &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/23/arrg-and-glasgow-home-seasons-final/www.glasgowrollerderby.com"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; both host extravaganzas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4565" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/grd.jpg" alt="grd" width="960" height="349"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby are rolling their entire &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1507855322868655/"&gt;Home Season&lt;/a&gt; into one giant event, with the &lt;em&gt;Bad Omens&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Death Stars&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;T-Wrecks&lt;/em&gt; playing each other in a 5 hour triple header tournament. Last year, the Bad Omens took the trophy, but nothing is certain with the new format! As well as GRD skaters, the teams will be filled out by a few guest skaters from other leagues. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;11:30am&lt;/strong&gt;, for team skateouts at 11:50, and first whistle for Bad Omens v Death Stars at 12midday. As always, sponsors Pinto will be hosting the post-event food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are available from &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/glasgow-roller-derby-home-teams-2015-tickets-19466660305"&gt;Eventbrite&lt;/a&gt; (£5), or on the door for £7. As always, the venue is the &lt;strong&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/strong&gt; at Glasgow Caledonian University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5127" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/12187986_10156212279470224_6004105078402073441_o.jpg" alt="12187986_10156212279470224_6004105078402073441_o" width="2048" height="761"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, on the other coast, Auld Reekie's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1640621156210592/"&gt;Home Season&lt;/a&gt; will be coming to a triumphant conclusion with the Home Teams Final Double Header. As well as the Final itself, which sees the &lt;em&gt;Leithal Weapons&lt;/em&gt; play off against &lt;em&gt;The Skatefast Club&lt;/em&gt; for the 2015 trophy, third-place team the &lt;em&gt;Cherry Bombers&lt;/em&gt; will take on mysterious guest team &lt;em&gt;The Rolling Bones&lt;/em&gt;. Last year, The Skatefast Club managed to take the win over the Leithals, so this year's repeat should be even harder fought, as the Leithal Weapons seek to redress the balance. (The event will also be preceded by the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/528300763986400/"&gt;Auld Reekie Derby Taster Session&lt;/a&gt;, so those interested in seeing what Roller Derby is all about can make a whole day of it!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARRG has arranged a special license for a bar, and there will be both half-time entertainment and a charity fundraising raffle. There will also be separate seating areas for families and young children, and a children’s craft corner to keep the youngest fans amused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are £6 in advance, £8 on the door, available on &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2252540"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt;. Unwaged and Senior (over 65's) fans can enter for the discounted rate of £5 per ticket,  and disability leisure card holders and a carer may enter free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, the event will be held at &lt;strong&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/strong&gt;, on London Road. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt; for a 1:30 start.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bad omens</category><category>cherry bombers</category><category>death stars</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>home season</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>home teams</category><category>leithal weapons</category><category>skatefast club</category><category>t-wrecks</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/23/arrg-and-glasgow-home-seasons-final/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 16:34:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow Roller Derby - British Champions</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/24/glasgow-roller-derby-british-champions/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby have been crowned British Champions after a stunning set of performances which saw them go on a five-game winning streak.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRD’s all-star team won the inaugural British Roller Derby Championships – with emphatic wins over teams from Edinburgh, Cardiff, Manchester, Birmingham and Middlesbrough.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The competition culminated in a two-day derby extravaganza – held in Glasgow – on May 30 and 31.&lt;/p&gt;
Hundreds of fans crowded into the ARC sports centre to cheer on their heroes and were treated to an amazing display of sporting prowess, skating skills and blistering action.&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-4717 alignright" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/glasgow_roller_derby_3_color_logo.png?w=185" alt="Glasgow_Roller_Derby_3_Color_Logo" width="185" height="300"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tribute has been paid to the all-female Glasgow league for flying the flag for Scottish sport – continuing the legacy of sporting achievement which put the city on the world’s centre stage during the Commonwealth Games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby are first in the UK Roller Derby Association rankings and second in Europe (outside of London Rollergirls) – a remarkable achievement for Scotland’s first roller derby league, started by the skaters themselves in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRD co-captain Grace Maclean – aka Mona Rampage - said: “I am so proud of my league and my team. We went unbeaten throughout the British Championships – winning all five of our games against the cream of the crop in UK roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To lift the trophy with my friends and league-mates was something I will never forget. We’ve worked so hard as a team and an organisation – it genuinely means a lot for us, our friends and our fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Winning the championship is the culmination of months of hard work from everyone involved with GRD. I hope we’ve done Scotland proud and that everyone can draw inspiration from what we’ve achieved together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first year of the British Roller Derby Championships – which featured four tiers of female teams, comprising 13 divisions. There were also three tiers for male teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow was in the top tier – alongside elite teams such as Auld Reekie Roller Girls from Edinburgh, Middlesbrough Milk Rollers, Tiger Bay Brawlers from Cardiff, Birmingham’s Central City RollerGirls and Rainy City Roller Girls from Oldham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow went into the final weekend at the top of the table, with three wins from three games – knowing two wins would secure the inaugural trophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the leagues at the other end of the table were fighting to avoid the drop into the second tier – with two teams destined to be relegated.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;That set the scene for a pulsating weekend of derby action – featuring thrills, spills and more than a few skills from all the skaters involved.&lt;/p&gt;
Thanks have been given to Glasgow Sport for its support towards the staging of the event, as well as everyone at the British Champs, UK Roller Derby Association and Derby Duck Productions.
&lt;p&gt;Saturday saw Central City RollerGirls (CCR) narrowly defeat Rainy City (RCRG) 129-124 in a fantastic opening game, with both teams desperate to win in a bid to juke around relegation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRD then took to the ARC track knowing a win would put them within a toe-stop of the British Championship. In the end they won convincingly – beating Middlesbrough Milk Rollers (MMR) 205-119.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls (ARRG) and Tiger Bay Brawlers (TBB) supplied the action for the final game on Saturday, with the Edinburgh team taking the win and all three points to remain second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Into Sunday and GRD had an early start against Rainy City. But any hopes that the Gallus Glaswegians would be caught napping were quickly put to bed as the all-stars won 227-131.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game two then served up a cracking, evenly-matched contest as Tiger Bay took on Middlesbrough. Potentially both teams had a chance of snatching second – although a massive points swing would have been needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a nail-biter the whole way – with the lead changing hands repeatedly as both teams competed brilliantly on the track. It seemed MMR had edged it in the final seconds with a dramatic 164-163 win, but a point had been missed and the readjusted final score was 164-164 – meaning the contest had to go to an overtime jam to decide the winner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone watching in the hall – and around the world via the live stream – were then treated to two minutes of action they would never forget. Both teams scored in the breathtaking final jam, but MMR edged it – just - 183-178.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;That put MMR on nine points – equal with Auld Reekie, but behind on points scored and conceded. The Edinburgh team then consolidated their second-place position against CCR, winning 168-152 in another closely-fought contest that went the full distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-4718" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/t1-table.jpg?w=300" alt="T1-table" width="464" height="174"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Glasgow co-captain Grace Maclean said: “Six sensational games took place on Saturday and Sunday – involving around 80 skaters, dozens of referees and non-skating officials, and hundreds of fans.
&lt;p&gt;“The games were also broadcast live on the Internet and watched across the world, so it genuinely was a team effort from everyone involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I want to say a massive thank-you to all who supported the event and helped to make it happen – especially the roller derby fans who provided such an amazing atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was a genuine thrill to be involved and to host the final weekend of action in the first year of the competition. To win the trophy unbeaten is a fantastic achievement for everyone associated with Glasgow Roller Derby and we hope we’ve done our city – and our country – proud.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adventure doesn’t stop there for GRD. They hope to compete again in America soon – flying the flag for Scotland in the country where modern-day roller derby was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meteoric rise of Glasgow is no fluke – it’s the culmination of years and years of training, practice scrims, skills sessions, endurance work and league organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the league, visit &lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com"&gt;www.glasgowrollerderby.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>in the news</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/24/glasgow-roller-derby-british-champions/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 17:46:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Scotland heads the Premier Tier of British Champs!</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/05/31/scotland-heads-the-premier-tier-of-british-champs/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As of only a few hours ago, the first ever &lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/tables-and-fixtures-ukrda-premier/"&gt;British Champs Premier &lt;/a&gt;Tier tournament ended, with the 15th and final bout of the series a surprisingly tight and tense bout between Auld Reekie Roller Girls and Central City Rollergirls.
With ARRG emerging victorious, the final placings for the 6 teams in Premier Tier are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Glasgow Roller Derby
2 Auld Reekie Roller Girls
3 Middlesbrough Milk Rollers
4 Tiger Bay Brawlers 
5 Central City Rollergirls
6 Rainy City Roller Girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scottish teams therefore take both 1st and 2nd place in the Tier, and CCR and RCRG will unfortunately relegate to the National Tier for the 2016 season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully we will have more from Glasgow and Auld Reekie on their placement later. For now, some initial stats are available &lt;a href="http://aoanla.wordpress.com/2015/05/31/british-championships-premier-tier-some-statistics/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>competition</category><category>grd</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/05/31/scotland-heads-the-premier-tier-of-british-champs/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 19:54:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow Roller Derby:  Next Level Bootcamp &amp; Guest Coaching Available</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/02/02/glasgow-roller-derby-next-level-bootcamp-guest-coaching-available/</link><dc:creator>paingrrl666</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img id="featured-image" class=" aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/getattachment.jpg" alt="Featured image" width="273" height="163"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby had an exciting year last year, and now we are looking to share our learning with other leagues!
We have lots on offer, both for leagues and for individual skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sat 21st March, we are hosting our ‘Next Level Bootcamp.  This is a fully co-ed bootcamp, which is aimed at two levels – people wishing to learn basic skills for passing minimums (stops/stride/laterals), and then people who have passed minimum skills and are aiming to become bout ready (agility, edge work, hockey stops etc).   The bootcamp is being offered at the super reasonable price of £25 on-skates, and £15 off-skates.  We will also have our very special Roller Grrls t-shirts available for sale which are unavailable for general purchase, as well as a range of other Grd merch.  You can book a place on the bootcamp &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/787419911313296/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also available to leagues who would like some guest coaching, and have developed a training menu which will cater for league at any level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have coaches available to cover sessions such as:-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;all levels of skills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;all levels of strategy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nutrition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;off skates fitness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mental conditioning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;league morale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;team building&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;scrimmage/bout footage reviewing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to take advantage of this opportunity, please contact &lt;a href="mailto:interleagueliaison@glasgowrollerderby.com"&gt;interleagueliaison@glasgowrollerderby.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to meeting you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/grd.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4565 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/grd.jpg?w=300" alt="grd" width="310" height="119"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>grd</category><category>roller derby bootcamp</category><category>roller derby bootcamps</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/02/02/glasgow-roller-derby-next-level-bootcamp-guest-coaching-available/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 15:57:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Exciting bouts ahead for Glasgow Roller Derby</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/12/exciting-bouts-ahead-for-glasgow-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next couple of weeks are an exciting time for fans of Glasgow Roller Derby, with all three travel teams set to bout in the next month!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, GRD's A-team, the Irn Bruisers, will take on Middlesbrough Milk Rollers in what is sure to be an exciting bout (the Maidens and MMR have are closely in UKRDA's UK rankings, but Flat Track Stats &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/55057/rankings"&gt;predicts&lt;/a&gt; a GRD home win).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/middlesbrough.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3748 aligncenter" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/middlesbrough.jpg" alt="GRD B v MMR bout poster" width="400" height="569"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/content/grds-irn-bruisers-vs-middlesborough-milk-rollers"&gt;http://glasgowrollerderby.com/content/grds-irn-bruisers-vs-middlesborough-milk-rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, only two weeks later (leaving a gap for &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1460050400931616/"&gt;Team Scotland's Bootcamp &lt;/a&gt;on the 20th), Glasgow B, the Maiden Grrders, will take on London Rollergirls' imposing C team, Batter C Power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this fixture is not yet listed on Flat Track Stats, their &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/10262/7939"&gt;predictor&lt;/a&gt; expects a very close bout, with only a 10% score difference between win and loss. Tickets will be only £5 online, so it's definitely worth buying ahead of time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/content/maiden-grrders-v-batter-c-power-london"&gt;http://glasgowrollerderby.com/content/maiden-grrders-v-batter-c-power-london&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, on the 4th of October, we are informed that Glasgow C-team, the Canny Gingers, will be taking part in a double-header with Mean City Roller Derby.  Their opponents will be Bairn City Rollers' Central Belters.  It is probably true to say that the Gingers would like very much to take home a win from this match up, but the Central Belters will not go easy on them. (FTS gives the home team the advantage, based on &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/45330/25958"&gt;stats&lt;/a&gt;, but since both teams will probably have an altered composition, there's still all to play for.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/718678178181099/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/718678178181099/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these bouts are, of course, listed on our &lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/scottish-bouts/"&gt;Scottish Bouts &lt;/a&gt;page here on the blog.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>batter c power</category><category>bcr</category><category>canny gingers</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>irn bruisers</category><category>london rollergirls</category><category>lrg</category><category>maiden grrders</category><category>middlesbrough milk rollers</category><category>mmr</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/12/exciting-bouts-ahead-for-glasgow-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 12:43:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Close Encounters of the Thrilled Kind - derby double header</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/26/close-encounters-of-the-thrilled-kind-derby-double-header/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/3xo4jhp-imgur.png"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-3550 aligncenter" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/3xo4jhp-imgur.png?w=300" alt="3xO4jHP - Imgur" width="422" height="163"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow is bracing itself for a close encounter of the ‘thrilled’ kind as some of the grooviest skaters in Scotland and England clash as part of a unique sporting double-header.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city’s first men’s roller derby team – Mean City – will host the special event on August 23 at the ARC sports centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City will be playing Teeside’s Skate Invaders – the first time the two teams have clashed – in an all-male, action-packed contest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space will be a premium as the Invaders beam into Glasgow – hoping they can blast their way to victory against the MCRD troopers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The double bill will also see Glasgow Roller Derby’s Cannie Gingers compete against Fierce Valley Roller Girls’ Parma Violents in an all-female thrill-fest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jim Whyte, Chairman of Mean City Roller Derby (MCRD), said: “We can’t wait for this very special double-header. The skating will be out of this world with four great roller derby leagues going toestop to toestop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Mean City is Glasgow’s first and only men’s roller derby league and has been going from strength to strength since it was formed in 2012. We’re genuinely thrilled to be welcoming three amazing squads to Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Skate Invaders are a great team and a terrific bunch of lads – we can’t wait to line up against them. Mean City features some of the best skaters in Scotland and we will be giving our all to ensure the super summer of sport continues in Glasgow.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby (GRD) – Mean City’s all-female sister league – is renowned throughout the roller derby world. Its A team – the Irn Bruisers – recently stormed America, while its B team – the Maiden Grrders – are also a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such is the strength in depth at GRD that a third travel team has been formed – the Cannie Gingers – who made their competitive debut against Fierce Valley in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jim added: “Fierce Valley had the edge in the first encounter, but Glasgow will be keen to win on home soil. It’s going to be another cracking encounter between two brilliant teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Get your tickets now – just £5 in advance for two amazing full games of roller derby starring four interstellar teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s going to be a great showcase of all that roller derby has to offer – an action-packed afternoon of skating, scoring, skills, thrills and spills.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby has been developing as a league since its formation in 2012. Men’s roller derby is a fledgling off-shoot of the modern day all-female sport of roller derby – with the game rising in popularity with people of all genders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City train regularly in the Glasgow area and new members are always welcome to give the sport a go in a supportive environment. Equipment can be provided – just get in touch in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby"&gt;www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby&lt;/a&gt; to buy tickets for the event and to find out more about joining the revolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cannie gingers</category><category>fvrg</category><category>grd</category><category>mcrd</category><category>parma violents</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/26/close-encounters-of-the-thrilled-kind-derby-double-header/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 22:59:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow Roller Derby Season 5 Opener</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/04/16/glasgow-roller-derby-season-5-opener/</link><dc:creator>paingrrl666</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/04/home-teams.jpg"&gt;&lt;img id="i-3375" class="size-full wp-image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/04/home-teams.jpg?w=650" alt="Image"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even hotter than the release date of the new OITNB, we're now hotting up for SEASON 5 of Glasgow Roller Derby's Home Teams!!! Saturday 26th April sees Glasgow's 4 home teams come together in a fantastic season opener, aiming to rack up some serious points that will put 2 lucky teams in good stead for a place in the much-coveted final!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;Doors open at 11.30am, so get down early to secure a suicide line seat and purchase some yummy cake/merch/raffle tickets and watch what promises to two full bouts of stunning derby strategy, skills and strength.  And just to mix things up a bit for you, there have been some roster changes that will keep you on the edge of your seats!Bout 1 sees the Bad Omens take on the T-Wrecks - a mighty clash indeed, as the Omens took 4th place last season and the T-Wrecks claimed second place.  The Omens are out to show they are no one's number 4, whilst the T-Wrecks will be going all out to scoop the illustrious first place this year.  This bout will be made particularly interesting as there has been a skater swap -  the powerful Splat, formerly a T-Wreck, is now playing for the Omens - and the jukey Suffra Jett will be donning green and playing for the Wrecks! It's all to play for - this is going to be rivetting!!Bout 2 will see the Helles Belles play the Death Stars.  Again, this will be a fight to the finish as the Death Stars will be fighting to keep a firm hold of their win over the last season, whilst the Belles will be anxious to beat their third place position from Season 4.  The Death Stars will feature some new faces to Grd's home teams, as will the Hells Belles - so watch out for some awesome new talent to admire!  Everyone loves a dark horse!
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are available in advance, however if you're flying by the seat of your pants, they will also be available on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>home teams</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/04/16/glasgow-roller-derby-season-5-opener/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 12:21:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Interview With Elliot Fress</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/27/an-interview-with-elliot-fress/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next up in line in our announcer interviews, Glasgow Roller Derby's Elliot Fress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/img_20131126_0083258.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/img_20131126_0083258.jpg" alt="Photography by Dave McAleavy" width="614" height="408" class="size-full wp-image-3066"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photography by Dave McAleavy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you get started announcing for Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many life-changing events, it involved a photocopier; some office gossip; and a man named Helliverance...  He and I pretend to work in the same building, and one day about three years ago, he cornered me by said copier and asked if it was true that I was previously involved with professional wrestling.  This was true - I'm a former manager/commentator for the Scottish Wrestling Alliance.  As I was comfortable with crowds and microphones, would I be interested in trying my hand at live Roller Derby commentary with him?  A fee was negotiated, and a few weeks later I was at the ARC, making vaguely human noises over the first GRG home teams bout of the season.  From then on, I was never to look forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Announcers all have different styles, how would you describe your style and how has it evolved since you started?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I can call it a style, it's irreverence, with ignorance firmly in mind.  Derby's complex and unique.  Anyone coming to see it fresh is in for a lot of confusion as a lot happens and there's no other sport you can refer to for an easy comparison.  It's important to keep that in mind and try to keep the watching newbie in mind when things happen on track.  "Why?" is as important as "What?" when you're talking about a sending off, or why a team has slowed everything down during a powerjam, for example.  The rest of the time, I just quote dead comedians and joke about skater's names, while I'm sure they're not listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been training as a skater with Glasgow's Mean City Der-boy team for the last six months.  The training and generally spending more time around skaters has given me a lot more material to work with, regarding techniques and tactics; but the bulk of what I do is still aimed at the people struggling to make sense of what they're seeing.  As I told a crowd recently, Derby seldom reveals her charms quickly, or all at once.  It can take a few bouts for someone to learn where they need to be looking, and a commentator needs to be there to help them along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you prepare for bouts and how much work do you have to do on the fly?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more sterile prep is reviewing the rules in the week running up to a bout and trying to get familiar (in a nice way, I mean) with the line-ups before a bout starts.  Just about everything I watch, think or hear goes through a filter to see if it can one day be usable in a Derby context.  If I hear a song lyric a skater's name can be slipped into, then it gets filed away.  While it's underway, a good bout can almost describe itself.  But, if you're faced with a 50-odd minute time-out - you better be able to talk some shite to distract folk from heading for their bus!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skaters have skate heroes, do you have any announcer heroes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the "Bulldog" question, yes?  I've been lucky enough to work with the man and be stunned by his play-by-play commentary.  Knowing the limits of the rhythms of my own speech and my diction, though, it would serve nobody for me to try to emulate him.  I'm happiest working with anyone who can hear what I'm saying more than half the time, and are prepared to have the occasional spot of harmless fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which has been your favourite bout to call and what are you looking forward to calling in the future?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard to pick a favourite bout, but generally any time a scoreline stays close for the bulk of the game makes it easier to stay invested.  For that reason, I look forward to GRD going back up against Berlin and Stockholm after this past season's nail-biters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>announcers</category><category>grd</category><category>interviews</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/27/an-interview-with-elliot-fress/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 19:29:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hell Hath No Fury!</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/18/hell-hath-no-fury/</link><dc:creator>paingrrl666</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/hell-hath1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-3048" alt="Image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/hell-hath1.jpg?w=470"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feminism and roller derby – two great life passions will be combined for many Scottish skaters on Saturday 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Dec!  As many of the country’s leagues commence their ‘off season’, this is a great way to mark the end of what has been a monumental year for all Scottish leagues in one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ‘Hell Hath No Fury’ charity bout is the brain child of Glasgow Roller Derby’s Maiden Grrders skater, Trucks Norris.  The bout will raise awareness of the &lt;i&gt;16 Days of Action for the Elimination of Violence Against Women&lt;/i&gt; campaign; a global phenomenon which runs from 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Nov to 10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Dec.  Organisations across the world will organise events during this period to raise awareness of violence against women. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All proceeds of this bout will go toward local Glasgow organisation ‘&lt;i&gt;Womens Support Project’&lt;/i&gt;, a feminist voluntary organisation which works to raise awareness of the extent, causes and effect of male violence against women.  It also works to provide improved services to those affected by violence, and highlights the links between different forms of male violence and promoting interagency responses to the abuse of women and children.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bout will take place at the Arc Sport Centre in Glasgow, and will feature skaters from Glasgow Roller Derby, Granite City, Fierce Valley, Dundee, Lothian Derby Dolls and Auld Reekie.  The bout also takes place on the same day as Team Scotland Try-Out 2, so if you do find yourself at a loose end then show your support for this great cause and go see some killer roller derby into the bargain!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sat 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Dec, doors at 12.30pm    &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/212345205605145/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/212345205605145/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/trucks.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-3050" alt="Image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/trucks.jpg?w=324"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This bout is the brainchild of former Womens Support Project Worker Trucks Norris (above)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/18/hell-hath-no-fury/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 10:23:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>