<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about guest post)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/guest-post.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>We Need You! </title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/04/we-need-you-2019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby is a worldwide sport, and there's far too much to cover just with our internal posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a reminder, then, that the Scottish Roller Derby Blog is happy to host guest posts from anywhere in the world of Roller Derby.
(We'd prefer English-language, but we would also consider content in other languages, especially if this raises awareness of a particular community.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already host a regular Guest column with Speedy Convalesce... but we'd like to see more people writing, especially from places which need more attention: Latin America, Asia, New Zealand, and Africa.
(If you're not on one of those regions, that doesn't mean we're not interested, but those regions are particularly in need of representation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd also value more input from the Scottish community where we're hosted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the new format and hosting of SRD, there are lots of ways to get guest posts to us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can link us to a Google Doc with your article in it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can send us a link to a PDF or a Word document with your article (we'd prefer PDF).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can send us a document in Restructured Text or Markdown format, with attached images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or you can contact us directly by email, or social media, to discuss your idea for an article, and work with us on how best to produce it. (Our &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;email address&lt;/a&gt; is at the bottom of every page of the blog, and we're available on
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/scottish.rollerderby/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/scottishrollerderby/"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; and WeChat (id: sskipsey) )&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>guest post</category><category>international derby</category><category>we need you</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/04/we-need-you-2019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 11:09:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>