<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about helgin roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/helgin-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>2017: the year of (more) Scottish Derby?</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/08/2017-the-year-of-more-scottish-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we previously flagged, while the number of Scottish Leagues had been growing recently, the conversion of those leagues into bouting leagues had been a little slower... until 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most prominently, Perth's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/FairCityRollers/"&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (who are effectively a new league after their hiatus led to a large changeover of members) and Scotland's second-northernmost league, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://helginrollerderby.wordpress.com/"&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, will be joining forces to take their first bout together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-15876 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/packfromthedead.jpg" alt="PackFromTheDead" width="1702" height="630"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;April 16th&lt;/strong&gt;, in Perth's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Live+Active+Bell's+Sports+Centre/@56.4029941,-3.437384,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48863b152b41b60b:0x2b806df2e1d11749!8m2!3d56.4029912!4d-3.43519"&gt;Bells' Sport Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (famous for its domed roof and exceptionally shiny floor surface), &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/254873508256762/"&gt;the event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, going by the name "Pack from the Dead", will kick off as doors open at &lt;strong&gt;1pm &lt;/strong&gt;for a&lt;strong&gt; 1.30pm &lt;/strong&gt;start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking to us, Fair City said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce FCR’s comeback bout will take place in Perth on Sunday 16th April. After having a break of almost 5 years from competing, we’re back! We’ve created a brand new team of dedicated players, who’ve worked their butts off to get bout ready. FCR will be playing against Elgin’s team ‘Helgin’ at Bells Sports Centre and we want to welcome them to Perth for what will be a fantastic game. We’ve trained hard and played friendly matches against some fantastic teams, all with the aim of getting us bout ready…and now we want to shout out ‘bring it on’! 'Pack From The Dead' was the perfect name; FCR have been resurrected. Everyone is welcome, under 12s are free, please get your tickets now. Looking forward to seeing you all there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helgin Roller Derby are equally excited, with their Mane-iac telling us: "I'm very proud of how far Helgin has come as a club over the last two and a half years. We've come a long way from our very first days as a group of 4 girls attempting to skate in a small hall, to having a team of mins-passed skaters and preparing to play in our first game. Just thinking about playing in this game gives me butterflies, it's such an achievement for the club, and an exciting and momentous day for all the skaters. I can't wait to put on my Helgin uniform, skate on track as a team and show everyone what Helgin's made of!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fellow skater Bruteyvicious agrees, "It's a pretty momentous occasion. It was just a fantasy for us a year ago, but we moved steadily and grew together until we reached this point. We've played in many scrims between us but actually playing as a team together is really going to feel special! This is why I joined Derby, to play alongside my team in a sport I love. We will give 100% and will continue to do so and strive to keep playing and improving. I'm confident we can hold our own in our first bout. I can only imagine the adrenaline I'll feel on the day, I really can't wait."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it's not just Helgin and Fair City who are planning to hold their first bouts this year.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.invernessrollerderby.com/"&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are also planning to bout before 2017 is out, with a date scheduled for 19th August. Whilst we know ICRD will be hosting the bout, almost everything else (including their opponent) is not public at this time - as soon as there is an official announcement to be made, we will be highlighting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the other end of the country, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DoonhameDerbyDolls/"&gt;Doonhame Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, of Dumfries, are also planning their first public bout, although even less details are available than for ICRD. We hope to bring you details in the second half of the year!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>doonhame roller derby</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/08/2017-the-year-of-more-scottish-derby/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 14:01:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Upcoming Events Roundup!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/13/upcoming-events-roundup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scottish Roller Derby is just starting to emerge from its traditional month of hibernation, and there's already a lot of derby events scheduled for the next few weeks. To get you started on your next year of Derby, we've collected them together in one place for you with handy links!
We’ve already covered most of the derby recruitment events &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/03/start-derby-in-the-new-year/"&gt;in a previous post&lt;/a&gt;, so here we present mostly bouts and fundraising. We should note, however, a few addenda to the fresh meat article:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Firstly, &lt;strong&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; have completely filled up their attendance list for their fresh meat, and are now closed for additional skaters until their next recruitment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Secondly, just missing out on our article, &lt;strong&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; also have a recruitment event scheduled for &lt;strong&gt;Tuesday 26th January&lt;/strong&gt;, starting at &lt;strong&gt;7pm&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;Magnum Leisure Centre, Irvine&lt;/strong&gt;. There is some kit available, but you are advised to contact ahead of time &lt;a href="mailto:ayshirerollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;ayshirerollerderby@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/strong&gt; also announced recruitment very recently, with a session planned for &lt;strong&gt;31st January&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Musselburgh Sport Centre&lt;/strong&gt;, starting at &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt;. You are advised to contact &lt;a href="mailto:newskaters@lothianderbydolls.com"&gt;newskaters@lothianderbydolls.com&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The Scottish Derby bout calendar starts on the &lt;strong&gt;30th of January&lt;/strong&gt;, with 3 bouts occurring:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; A and B are taking on Vagine Regime UK in a double-header hosted in the Lagoon Centre, Paisley. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/440385519419560/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/440385519419560/&lt;/a&gt; There's also the second annual GRD Drag Party planned after this event, for which details &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/156611594708195/"&gt;go here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Over in Edinburgh, &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; are also holding their first bout of the year, with the Reserves taking on Roller Derby Dresden. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/918798478210693/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/918798478210693/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Meanwhile, down in Newcastle, Men's National Team &lt;strong&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; are taking on Tyne and Fear B as part of a double header with Newcastle Roller Girls. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1829763710583763/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1829763710583763/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The action doesn't stop the week after, as the &lt;strong&gt;6th of February&lt;/strong&gt; sees:
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; host a 12-team Charity Sur5al tournament at The Peak, Stirling. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/908140529265523/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/908140529265523/&lt;/a&gt; There's also an &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1507929376179373/"&gt;afterparty event&lt;/a&gt; for the tournament, which is sure to be well attended!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Also on the 6th, Power of Scotland have a fundraiser up in Aberdeen, as &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Brawlermen&lt;/strong&gt; host a Quiz Night in Sinatra's Bar. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1711963732359161/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1711963732359161/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The &lt;strong&gt;13th of February&lt;/strong&gt; continues to be lucky for derby enthusiasts, as we have another two events to choose from:
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;In Edinburgh, &lt;strong&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/strong&gt; take on Dundee Roller Girls' Bonnie Colliders at the Jack Kane Centre, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1537726313212932/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1537726313212932/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Meanwhile, playing away at Eston Leisure Centre,Middlesborough, &lt;strong&gt;Mean City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; take on Teesside Skate Invaders in a double header hosted by Middlesborough Milk Rollers. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/370810093043423/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/370810093043423/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/13/upcoming-events-roundup/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 20:54:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Start Derby in the New Year</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/03/start-derby-in-the-new-year/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a New Year, and one resolution that you might have made is to Try Roller Derby. Certainly, many leagues across the country traditionally run a fresh meat recruitment in January or early February just to take advantage of any newly enthused skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, there's a good distribution of Fresh Meat sessions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, and a bit urgent for those who want to be involved - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/750196985110434/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are holding their Fresh Meat session on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 10th January&lt;/strong&gt; - just a week away! You'll need your own skates and pads to take part, and of course GRD recommend &lt;a href="http://www.5thblockerskates.co.uk/"&gt;5th Blocker Skates&lt;/a&gt; to get you the right kit. The initial signup session will be held at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Glasgow-Club-Drumoyne/190810237616343"&gt;Glasgow Club Drumoyne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;and entry is free for the first session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up in time, Edinburgh's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1652424528374019/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are holding their Fresh Meat session a week later on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 17th January&lt;/strong&gt;. You only need to a mouthguard to attend their session, for hygiene reasons; ARRG will supply kit for the initial tryout session. The initial sesson, and all subsequent training is at the&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Jack-Kane-Sports-Centre/152896351412178"&gt; Jack Kane Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and entry to the initial session is just £5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elgin's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/168691136822816/"&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are holding a "learn to skate" session, co-hosted with Aberdeen's Granite City Roller Derby, on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 30th January&lt;/strong&gt;. As with ARRG, you'll need to bring a mouthguard, but other kit will be provided. The session will be held at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Elgin-Community-Centre/286953997983978"&gt;Elgin Community Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and entry is free. This is a &lt;em&gt;co-ed&lt;/em&gt; session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Livingston's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/636910396412245/"&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; have an extensive array of taster and meetup sessions across January and February. There's a chance to &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/551015165051330/"&gt;Meet The Skaters&lt;/a&gt; in a pub setting on &lt;strong&gt;Friday January 22nd&lt;/strong&gt;, in the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Wetherspoons/105356126214627"&gt;Wetherspoons&lt;/a&gt; in the Almondvale Centre . The actual taster session for would-be-skaters is on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday February 6th&lt;/strong&gt;, in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Blackburn-Community-Centre/298761240230260"&gt;Blackburn Community Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. NTRG request that attendees message them before the event to allow arrangements to be made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the North, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1732447053650457/"&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are holding a fresh meat/beginners session on &lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 3rd February&lt;/strong&gt;. Again, you'll need to bring a mouthguard, but some kit will be available (although you're advised to contact ICRD ahead of time with your shoe size). The initial session will be at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Hilton-Community-Centre-918990224784740/"&gt;Hilton Community Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;; we have no information in entry fees, but the session is &lt;em&gt;co-ed,&lt;/em&gt; as with Helgin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for guys who want to play Derby in the Aberdeen area, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1708084226107265/"&gt;Granite City Brawlermen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are holding their intake on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 6th February&lt;/strong&gt;. You'll probably want to bring a mouthguard, but if you contact GCB ahead of time, they can arrange a loan of the rest of the kit. The session will be held at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Aberdeen-Lads-Club-209093469130951/"&gt;Aberdeen Lads Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, there is no information on entry fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also know that several other leagues are planning intakes in the next few months; we'll keep you informed as and when those are announced!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>new town roller girls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/03/start-derby-in-the-new-year/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 10:26:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-bouting Leagues Roundup of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/30/non-bouting-leagues-roundup-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year has seen another uptick in the number of new leagues in Scotland, with both &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HelginRollerDerby"&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/WeeCRD"&gt;Wee County Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; joining the ranks of &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/InvernessCityRollerDerby/"&gt;Inverness City&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/FairCityRollers/"&gt;Fair City&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Ayrshire-Roller-Derby-Official-618921518215712/"&gt;Ayrshire&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DoonhameDerbyDolls"&gt;Doonhame Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; as leagues making the journey towards their first public bout. As traditional, we're covering all of these leagues together in a Review of the Year, as usually bouts are a big part of what the bouting leagues cover about in their own articles. Since we have so many non-bouting leagues this year, however, we're splitting this article over several pages for readability - click the links at the bottom of each page to move between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every league forms its own relationships with the wider derby community when starting out, but some of our non-bouting leagues have developed particularly close ties.
Inverness City Roller Derby were very happy that Helgin Roller Derby started up nearby in Elgin, and the two have been combining resources:
"Helgin are fantastic and are growing so fast.
We try to go through as often as possible to coach them and help them with anything they may need help with and they often come through to us for a session and with such a big turn out at these sessions it boosts team morale."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5376" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/pudz.jpg" alt="PuDz" width="960" height="540"&gt; Power of Scotland's PudZ, selfie with combined Inverness and Helgin skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helgin are equally happy with the relationship, as they benefit from ICRD's experience and numbers. "All of our skaters rave about Nat from ICRD’s sessions for days afterwards – she really works us hard and we learn a lot! […] We’re looking to link up with ICRD at least once a month in 2016, so that we can all get a bit more contact and pack skills practice – something that can prove difficult if you’ve got a session with low numbers."
Of course, Helgin have also been keeping up their connections with the team to the East of them, and Granite City have been as supportive as they were at Helgin's founding, even donating kit and support for their fresh meat sessions. The Brawlermen also donated Power of Scotland's PudZ for a training session, "Our session with PudZ from Power of Scotland was brilliant – it was our first proper session where we got to practice game tactics and we learned so much!", which also included ICRD, "we had PudZ from POS run a session on walls and pack work which was also tremendously good fun."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, at the south end of the country, Dumfries' Doonhame Derby Dolls made the fortuitious discovery of nearby Carlisle's &lt;a href="http://www.bordercityrollers.com/"&gt;Border City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;, who are newly founded this year. The two leagues have quickly become quite attached, as Doonhame noted: "We only recently discovered that Carlisle had a team on the go through Facebook, one of our girls is from the area and she never even knew haha! This is now the closest team to us! We got in touch and done our own first ever guest coaching with 3 of our girls travelling down to their training night and they couldn't have been more welcoming, they're a great bunch of guys as we expected and they were so pleased to learn and understand where to go from where they'd got to. Georgie and Chloe Holmes helped start is up and have done well starting from scratch. We have kept in touch and they have been along to support us at games in Newcastle and Glasgow, making wee banners and being total fangirls which is amazing (it's usually us fangirling others!). "
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h6&gt;RECRUITMENT AND TRAINING&lt;/h6&gt;
All of the non-bouting leagues have been focussing on the three most important things for any newer league: recruiting skaters, training them to pass mins, and raising money to support all of this.
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, &lt;em&gt;Helgin&lt;/em&gt; held several successful fresh meats this year, recruiting 19 since we &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/23/helgin-roller-derby-scotlands-northernmost-league/"&gt;interviewed them last&lt;/a&gt;, and have also gained some transfers from other leagues "We’ve gained another few regular skaters, including some skaters formerly of Granite City Roller Derby, New Town Roller Girls and Belfast City Rockets, and we’ve now got enough people training on a regular basis to be looking to put a team together". They also have a tremendously organised public training plan, as anyone can see from the regular updates on their Facebook page, "This started back when we were chopping and changing venues a lot, as we were still trying to find permanent training locations, and we needed to keep people informed of where the sessions were. Many people commented that they liked knowing what was coming up, so we just kept it going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We like to be organised, and have a progressive training plan so that we can see the development of our Fresh Meat – sometimes sessions go to plan, sometimes you’ve got an odd number of people there and the ‘paired work’ session plan goes out the window! Slowly but surely we’re working it all out, and we hope to get our next batch of Fresh Meat minimum skills passed much quicker."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They've also been doing quite well at fundraising, having entered multiple grant shortlists, and also "doing rather well with community fundraising, and held another successful pub quiz at the end of August, keeping us afloat for a bit, and we’re looking to put on another at the end of January or beginning of February, to boost funds for 2016."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inverness&lt;/em&gt;, being one of the more established leagues in this article, has been growing a little more slowly, "We've had a few intakes but the struggle to find new members in Inverness is ongoing, we've lowered the age limit to 16 to try grow the team a little, we've got a few new(ish) faces and everyone is coming on leaps and bounds, and we should fingers crossed have them all mins passed just after the new year."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perth's&lt;em&gt; Fair City Rollers&lt;/em&gt; have had an interesting year, given that we reported last year that they were aiming to bout in 2015. Instead, this year has been one of introspection and consolidation. "Over the past year we've redefined ourselves as a team; who we are, what we do and where we're headed.  Our direction has become more bout focused and we've started to work towards becoming an actual bouting team again.
Over the past year we've worked on aligning focus and skills, and recruitment.  We're currently about halfway through our training programme of the new skaters we recruited in September, and are aiming to bout in 2016"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-5372" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/11880588_901492176606579_4883872526247151434_n.jpg?w=300" alt="11880588_901492176606579_4883872526247151434_n" width="300" height="300"&gt; The Wee-County Golden Gauntlet logo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clackmannanshire's &lt;em&gt;Wee Country Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt; have been attempting to retain the momentum from their initial launch (which we interviewed them about &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/29/a-wee-chat-with-wee-county-roller-derby/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), partly by launching their distinctive gauntlet logo,
We really wanted our logo to describe the fight we have for derby, and our community spirit rolled into one. Its our take on the clackmannshire logo of the gauntlet, with 'Look Aboot Ye' as a tag line. It works as a double meaning, having to be aware at all times who and what is around you on track.
There was a real buzz around the team in the beginning, it was great: lots of attention and press coverage. We had a strong initial recruitment and kept a steady flow of interest, with word of mouth travelling fast. It has been a challenge to form a solid basis for the team, but we have a great foundation of members now. Its been a tough year, of trial and error and lots of personal growth. We were overwhelmed by the support and commitment of the members we do have, as they get stuck in and really help to make our team a family.
Looking at how far we've come and comparing it to how far we have to go to allow us to have our debut bout is quite a step, but were confident that we have the determination and the strong mind set to make it happen."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5381" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/11050639_820246781416517_7188774811881300574_n.jpg" alt="11050639_820246781416517_7188774811881300574_n" width="540" height="960"&gt; Coach Graeme Gow keeping a watchful eye on the paceline at Ayrshire Roller Derby (Credit: Sally Wilkes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt;, meanwhile, have enough mins-passed skaters that they're starting to attend scrims and the like. "ARD have had an excellent year. We were joined by coach Graham Gow of Power of Scotland and Mean City fame. Our team may be small at the moment but it is growing all the time! Our mins passed players are regularly participating in open scrims and learning all they can. We would really like to thank all  the local teams that have helped and supported us this last few months." In addition, ARD have been at a whole host of fundraising and publicity-related engagements, including a stall at their local Christmas Fair. They've also had enthusiastic spectating presence at many bouts this year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, to the south, &lt;em&gt;Doonhame&lt;/em&gt; have been growing strong,
"Recruitment was a challenge to start, with maybe 6-10 people showing up at the start of the year, we then took a break from 'Fresh Meat' open nights and 're-evaluated our training / introduction methods. We then went on to having 2 of our most successful openers in Sept and October with a full house (of 30odd) both nights, and around half of that number dedicating and joining the team! Its the keeping them excited and committed that's the harder bit. We try to encourage everyone to the best of their ability and push those wishing to be pushed, but at a pace that's comfortable with them. We have been very lucky to be able to have a lot of amazing players come along and guest coach for us. To be able to have such a high profile skater like Stefanie Mainey come and guest at our bootcamp in May 2015 was amazing! She was brilliant  and really put us through our paces on the track and giving us some great insights! We love learning new stuff and stretching our mindsets."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5368" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/received_10153711888193956.jpeg" alt="received_10153711888193956" width="600" height="339"&gt; Doonhame's 7 cherry popping skaters at Bristol Roller Derby's event. (Credit: Andy Jardine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Ayrshire, Doonhame have a strong core of mins-passed skaters now, but they've been seeking out public cherry-popper bouts as well as scrims. Most notably, they even managed to appear on film in their first ever appearance (at Bristol Roller Derby's Summer Double Header): "There was 7 of us that popped our cherries in Bristol. It wasn't just any normal cherry popper though, we were filmed by the BBC 'See, hear' programme to promote the abilitly to skate with deaf / hoh players. What a rush! It was so nerve racking, exciting and hundreds of miles away from home, but we did it!
After we got the taste, we actively started to look for cherry poppers, charity games, closed scrimms, anything to let us get out there to play. Its really difficult, frustrating, when you have a handful of players passed skills, gagging to play, but not enough players yet for a full team! Which leads to all of these brilliant events opening up their doors to us, where you learn just how special roller derby is. This has meant us travelling to Edinburgh, Dundee and Newcastle for scrimms and bouts to join other teams. The friendships and camaraderie throughout playing with other teams would be the highlight of travelling, and of course gaining the experience and playing along side some awesome derby gals. "
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h6&gt;PLANS FOR NEXT YEAR&lt;/h6&gt;
We asked each of the leagues about their plans for next year, and it looks like most of them have the same aim in mind: getting on track for their first public bout!
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doonhame&lt;/em&gt;: "All in all I think 2016 is going to be amazing for DDD as we are pushing our girls hard to try and bag a full team line up to finally play as a proper DDD full team. Until then though the girls that have passed will be playing in mixed scrim and bouts when they can and it's great we're always thought of to take part. 2016 will just be Onwards and upwards for DDD. Watch this space!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ayrshire&lt;/em&gt;: "We reckon we will be putting a team together at the beginning of next year and we REALLY cant wait to get stuck into playing!
I feel like it will be next year's [update] that has all the exciting stuff in it!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fair City&lt;/em&gt;: "[We] are hoping to pop our collective team cherry at the start of March 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, within the year of the restructure, we'll be back on track and competing against other teams.  Exciting times for the FCR!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wee County&lt;/em&gt;: "For next year we're hitting training and promotion head on, really pushing ourselves to the limits i know we can achieve. New and improved training programmes will be put in place to fully structurise the fresh meat members, also one for the more advanced skaters.
Were looking to get into the community in a big way, and doing our bit for local charities.
Our goal for 2016 is to integrate roller derby into the Wee County in a big way, so as always, look aboot ye."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Helgin&lt;/em&gt;: "Well, fingers crossed, we get all of our current skaters mins passed in early 2016, and then we’re going on the road to join some boot camps and open scrims to get a bit more experience in game play.  This, along with regular training with ICRD will hopefully have us bout-ready by the end of the year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re planning to hold three more Fresh Meat intakes – probably around February, May and September to keep our skater numbers up, and probably a similar number of fundraisers to keep us going financially. We’re also hoping to get our Business Plan finished over the Festive period (since our training venues are closed and we can’t skate :() and will be able to widen the net of the funds we can apply to, so that we can get scrim vests, more hire kit, more people first aid trained, and even cover our hall hire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve also been in discussions with Moray Sports Centre (a new state-of-the-art sports centre planned to be built on the southern boundary of Elgin) and things are looking hopeful that we may well have a new home in the future – one large enough to host bouts!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inverness&lt;/em&gt;: "We are looking forward to 2016 and having a team ready to start playing after all these years, we will be frequenting Dundee's open scrims with everyone learning to nso's for a couple of turns and then scrimming when mins passed, also we will have a regular session every month with Helgin to keep building on pack skills and game play.  Fingers crossed that later in 2016 Icrd will hit the track as a team!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all goes to the plans above, it's quite possible that next year, there will be no non-bouting leagues roundup, as there'd only be one or two leagues left to cover in it! As always, it's an exciting time with the growth of Scottish derby, and 2016 might see the next big wave of leagues entering the bouting world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>review of the year</category><category>wee county roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/30/non-bouting-leagues-roundup-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 12:29:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Helgin Roller Derby: Scotland's Northernmost League!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/23/helgin-roller-derby-scotlands-northernmost-league/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New Roller Derby leagues are still popping up over Scotland, as we saw recently in our interview with &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/29/a-wee-chat-with-wee-county-roller-derby/"&gt;Wee County&lt;/a&gt;. Now we're catching up with a new league in another part of the country entirely, Elgin's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HelginRollerDerby"&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/21091_1426672460962596_502025641894684557_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-4830" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/21091_1426672460962596_502025641894684557_n.jpg?w=660" alt="Helgin Roller Derby logo by Brett Tucker" width="660" height="660"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Helgin Roller Derby logo by Brett Tucker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helgin Roller Derby is now the northernmost mainland Scottish league, thanks to the curve of the coast near Lossiemouth. Can you tell us a little about who you are, and why you decided to found a new league?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helgin Roller Derby was started by our chairperson, Angela Ellis, in February 2014. She had relocated to Elgin from Dingwall and was looking for a way to meet new people and have fun whilst doing it. Having always been a fan of Roller Derby, starting her own team in Elgin seemed like the best way to do this. Angela used social media to garner interest and by November 2014 Helgin Roller Derby was finally a reality when 5 girls got together and started skating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like Wee County, who we spoke to recently, Helgin is a co-ed league from the start. Do you think Co-ed derby is the future of the sport, and if so, why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Wee County, we are also based in a somewhat wee county – Moray has a population of only 93,295, spread across a huge area stretching 2,238 km2 from Cairngorm National Park to the Moray Firth. We think it’s important in areas such as these to be as inclusive as you can. We didn’t want to be turning away members because of their gender. We didn’t even turn away someone because of her age and we now allow people aged 16+ to train with the adult team. In Scottish Law, the age of majority is 16, and if you can get married at that age, why shouldn’t you be allowed to play derby?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think that co-ed is a good starting point, and hope that in the future, we’ll attract enough members to have a co-ed roster, a female roster, a male roster, and a junior roster, giving everyone in Moray the opportunity to play derby… but that will be a few years down the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/wpid-wp-1437680568432.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-4828" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/wpid-wp-1437680568432.jpeg?w=660" alt="Helgin at practice!" width="660" height="440"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Helgin at practice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ve already held a few fundraisers and promotional events, including a pub quiz with some impressive prizes. How has your awareness and recruitment been like in the area?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been brilliant! We’ve got 283 likes on Facebook, and have attracted 15 regular skating members to the team already – not bad for a team that’s been going less than a year! Each Fresh Meat session we hold attracts more people each time, and we’re looking forward to hosting another in September. Everyone on the team is really proud to be part of it and are fantastic promoters of the team, telling everyone they know how great derby is and how much fun they have taking part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Pub Quiz was great fun, and we’re extremely grateful to all the local businesses for their support. Our top prize was a tour and tasting at local craft brewery, Windswept, and we also had fantastic raffle prizes from Ben Romach whisky, local pizza restaurant Scribbles, and Walkers Shortbread. We’ll definitely be holding more social events in the future, as they are not only good for raising funds, but also for raising awareness of the club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helgin Roller Derby’s logo is a rather strikingly blue Nordic lady with a big axe. What inspired your choice of logo, and was it produced by members of the league, or outside talent?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is said that the town of Elgin was founded by the Norse General, Helgin in the 10th Century when Vikings invaded Scotland. We thought that ‘Helgin’ had a nice ring to it, invoking the idea of Hell and fitting well with the punk aesthetic generally associated with Roller Derby, so this became the team’s name. It seemed only appropriate that our logo reflect the name’s true Viking origins, and our current logo was designed by a supporter of the club, who is an artist for a games design company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We see that Inverness City Roller Derby and Granite City Roller Girls have both provided assistance to Helgin in starting up. What’s your relationship been like with the Scottish Derby community so far?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re extremely grateful to the support we’ve received from &lt;a href="http://www.invernessrollerderby.com/"&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/"&gt;Granite City Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;. We try and train with ICRD at least once a month, as Natorious Red is a fantastic coach and really gives us a good workout, improving our skills. She also helps inspire us to improve our own coaching for those who have joined us after a Fresh Meat, and we take away a number of great drills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City Roller Girls support us through all of our Fresh Meat sessions, providing all the kit we require and two great coaches in Krusty Thud and Frost Damage. They coach the GCRG newbies, so they really know how to enthuse people about Derby, and make them fall in love with the sport!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, we’ve received great feedback and advice from most of the bouting leagues across Scotland, and we’re really excited to be part of such a fantastic community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Starting out, many leagues seem to find practice space the most difficult thing to find. You’ve already had one move of location, I believe - but you seem to have plenty of suitable locations to fall back on. What’s been your experience of this?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most leagues, we have struggled to find a space big enough to fit a full-size roller derby track, and it looks unlikely that we will be able to host a bout anywhere in the whole of Moray in the near future. We’ve bounced around between four halls, but finally have two spaces large enough to lay out a full-size track, in the games halls in Elgin Community Centre and Milne’s High School in Fochabers, where we train on Saturdays and Tuesdays, respectively. There is also positive discussion in Elgin about a new sports facility being built, which we hope will have a space large enough for the full track, the required safety zones and room for spectators, allowing Helgin Roller Derby to host bouts in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, what are your plans for the rest of the year?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve got another Fresh Meat planned for September, and will have at least one more social fundraiser towards the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re finishing up our business plan and sorting out a team bank account, so will also be applying for funding in the near future, and hope to be able to buy more of our own kit, so we’re not as dependent on GCRG’s kit for Fresh Meat sessions, and so we have more kit to hire to people who are waiting for theirs to arrive after Fresh Meats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re hoping to be able to move into doing on-skates contact training soon, and will hopefully have some skaters minimum skills passed by early 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>hrd</category><category>interviews</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/23/helgin-roller-derby-scotlands-northernmost-league/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 19:51:42 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>