<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about in the news)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/in-the-news.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:36:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Short Track Worldwide Update (2019 Feb)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/03/01/short-track-worldwide-update-2019-feb/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderby.wordpress.com/2018/10/26/short-track-roller-derby-a-first-scottish-test/"&gt;first article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://rollaskateclub.com/lets-rolla/"&gt;Short Track Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, back in 2018, the new ruleset has continued to spread, in almost all the places in the world where Roller Derby is played.
As such, we thought we’d follow up, just 4 months later, with some of the exciting developments in Short Track worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, as readers of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://whataboutmagazine.com/"&gt;What A Bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; magazine will already know, Short Track Roller Derby has spread further-and-wider than we could have hoped: to Russia, and Dubai, in the United Arab Emirates, already. You should read the full article in WAB &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://whataboutmagazine.com/2019/01/20/what-a-bout-issue-3-winter-2019/"&gt;Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for full details, but look out for several Short Track tournaments in Moscow, and other Russian cities later in the year. Dubai’s interest in Short Track has also led to bigger things which we’ll get to later in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short Track is continuing to enable more teams to play derby, even now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Poland, Gdańsk’s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/551140512034275/"&gt;Chrome Sirens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are playing their first ever public game, thanks to Short Track rules enabling them to put together two competitive teams (and use more accessible venues). This double-header event will be coming to the city in the middle of next month - March 16th!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Americas, Short Track Derby is also taking off: ruleset creators Rolla Skate Club having provided initial impetus with a comprehensive series of trial sessions across Canada and the North-west of the USA. In Latin America, meanwhile, there is interest in Buenos Aires, Argentina, in exploring the ruleset, as it solves several of the challenges of the many teams in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27916,"width":600,"height":426,"linkDestination":"custom"} --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Illinois Valley Vixens Roller Derby during their first public bout under Short Track Rules.(Photo used by permission of Dave Schrader under license. [not covered by site CC license] )" src="https://scottishrollerderby.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/img_6131-crop-1.jpg" title="Illinois Valley Vixens Roller Derby during their first public bout under Short Track Rules.(Photo used by permission of Dave Schrader under license. [not covered by site CC license])"&gt;Illinois Valley Vixens Roller Derby during their first public bout under Short Track Rules.(Photo used by permission of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/korfan/collections/"&gt;Dave Schrader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; under license. [not covered by site CC license] )
&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the USA, though, public bouts have already started, with the ruleset enabling teams to play their first games in years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/IVVRD/"&gt;Illinois Valley Vixens Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, who played their first public bout for 3 years thanks to Short Track back in February, the ruleset has been a revelation. Whilst some venue issues meant that they had to modify the track slightly, the bout was a complete success - despite only using word of mouth and social media for advertising, they managed to fill all the available seating. Speaking for the league, Lemon Squeezer told us : “We now know that a smaller track definitely does not mean less exciting or intense, quite the opposite! I can't remember a time I have heard a crowd this engaged before and the feedback from spectators was that they are looking forward to the next one and bringing friends. We also had several former skaters come to check it out that are now interested in coming back.”. 
I.M.GROOT added, “The fact that all players have to both jam and block really takes you out of your comfort zone. It pushes you to use all the skills you have learned, not just the ones you prefer. Short Track has the ability to really push skaters to be stronger, better and more adaptable in game play.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an even more striking mode, the USA has also brought us the first ever “Short Track” league: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pstrollerderby.com/"&gt;Pittsburgh Short Track Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, founded by a group of skaters who retired from “competitive” Roller Derby, but still wanted to play a friendlier version of the sport. Their league aim, as expressed on their website and Facebook page, “We are a group of friends who wanted to create a safe, stress free environment to get together and skate. Community over competition.” encapsulates the entire point of Short Track as a ruleset and community. (You can find out more about them on social media and their website.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further in the future, there’s also exciting news of potentially the first ever international Short Track Roller Derby Tournament.  The newly created &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/UAERollerDerby/"&gt;UAE All-Stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the United Arab Emirates’ official travel team, are exploding onto the scene, and one of their first public plans is to play Short Track Derby! Formed of skaters from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DubaiRollerDerby/"&gt;Dubai Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ADRollerDerby/"&gt;Abu Dhabi Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the team plan to play all kinds of Derby, but Short Track is definitely a solid component of their goals. [We have more about UAE All-Stars themselves in another new article here, which we’re going to publish soon - and their first ever public game &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/495068457564329/"&gt;will be this weekend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, 2nd March, in Hong Kong, as part of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27917,"width":576,"height":384} --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="UAE Roller Derby All-Stars practising on the Short Track [courtesy of UAE All-Stars]" src="https://scottishrollerderby.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/53180456_272367973677005_4491993895592263680_n-e1551445852446.jpg" title="UAE Roller Derby All-Stars practising on the Short Track [courtesy of UAE All-Stars]"&gt;UAE Roller Derby All-Stars practising on the Short Track [courtesy of UAE All-Stars]
&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the support of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gogogent.be/en/home-default/"&gt;GO-GO Gent Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, who had been investigating hosting an experimental Short Track clinic for several months, UAE All-Stars will be travelling to Belgium on the 1st and 2nd of June. The first day will be a Short Track Roller Derby training workshop, allowing the experienced skaters from Dubai’s testing of the rules (and potentially other skaters who’ve tried Short Track from the rest of Europe) to explain and demonstrate the potential of the ruleset to attendees.  
The second day will be a tournament event: the structure of which is still under development. Teams are welcome to participate from across Europe, and we know that there’s been interest from several regions already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even further in the future, there’s the possibility of Short Track bootcamps in other parts of Europe, including the UK, and other plans afoot about which we can’t speak at this time. Stay tuned for further updates as they occur!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dubai roller derby</category><category>in the news</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><category>polish roller derby</category><category>short format tournaments</category><category>short track roller derby</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/03/01/short-track-worldwide-update-2019-feb/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 13:12:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Jewish Roller Derby: shining a light.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/29/jewish-roller-derby-shining-a-light/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;From almost its inception, Roller Derby has been a fertile ground for "exhibition" teams built around a common experience, from the light-hearted ("Tall and gangly skaters") through the more heartfelt ("surviving a serious injury", "possessing a hidden or invisible illness"). National Teams are themselves built on the same concept: an expression of a common aspect of identity, drawn from a sense of belonging to or of a particular geographical region, culture or ethnicity.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;A positive effect of all such teams is that they can give visibility to the concerns and experiences of the community they represent; this can be, and commonly is, the founding aim of such a team. This is certainly the case for the newest such project: the Jewish Roller Derby team, which launched only a few weeks ago.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We talked to Jewish Roller Derby's founders, Tiggz and Jodi Bon Jodi, both from Rose City Rollers, about their aims for the team, and how you can be involved.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Tiggz was drawn to form the team partly from her experience within another team drawn from shared history: the 2018 Team Russia Roller Derby. Whilst she enjoyed her time in a National Team and at the World Cup, she was conscious that she didn’t experience the same level of shared-history as the rest of the team did with each other. As the only team member qualifying via a relative with Russian-Jewish heritage, Tiggz was drawn to think about the importance of that other aspect of her culture.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;This experience was, perhaps, emphasised by living and working in Portland, itself a city with a very small Jewish population (as Jodi noted to us, “if I played for Gotham, maybe I’d not have felt the same need to make a team to represent Jewish people”, given New York’s ownership of the largest Jewish community outside Israel).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;But, more than that, it was also the feeling that this was a time when Jewishness needed more voices to counter rising bigotry which drove the pairs’ final decision to make the team.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;It would take considerable ignorance of history to not be aware of the long-standing spectre of anti-Semitism across the world. Whilst many vocal proponents of this insidious bigotry became quieter in the later half of the 20th century, over the last few decades (and especially the last few years), anti-Semitic speech and conspiracy theories have once again become a dangerous thread in politics, on both sides of the Atlantic Ocean, and elsewhere. Only a few days ago, for example, a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://edition.cnn.com/interactive/2018/11/europe/antisemitism-poll-2018-intl/"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;CNN International poll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; reported that around a quarter of Europeans polled believed that "Jews have too much influence in business and finance" and "have too much influence in conflict and wars worldwide", and similar figures are reported from the USA. Coupled with dog-whistle attacks from powerful world leaders, and an alarming increase in anti-Semitism motivated murders and assaults worldwide, it's an increasingly dangerous and difficult time to be Jewish.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;One way in which we can counter bigotry is to educate and shine a light on those groups discriminated against; bigotry stems from ignorance, and merely being more visible can help to fight fear and intolerance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The word and concept of "Jewishness" incorporates, inherently, a number of interrelated-yet-distinct qualities - belief in (and or practice of) a particular religion, participation in a particular culture, possession of a particular ethnicity or lineage - which any particular Jewish person may participate in all aspects of, or only some or one. (Indeed, there are multiple ethnic divisions within the overall “Jewish ethnicity”, with distinct traditions and languages.) As such, Tiggz and JBJ consider the question of "eligibility" of applicants to be one that should be settled by the applicant themselves, not imposed by a strict definition.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"I'd say to someone wanting to know if they can apply: ask yourself, 'what would it mean to you to be part of a Jewish Roller Derby team?', and decide based on that", says Tiggz.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;In fact, the founders are excited to see what a spectrum of Jewishness sign up for the project: from people of the Ashkenazi heritage who form the basis for much of Europe’s idea of “Jewish”, through Sephardim, Mizrahim, Maghrebhim and others; and to take opportunities to educate both each other and the Roller Derby community about their diversity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The first "competitive aim" for the Jewish Roller Derby project is to field a WFTDA-gender-policy team at the next Rollercon, against an opponent to be decided. After that, the founders have no concrete plans, although there's always more teams that can be challenged; from National teams to others attached to important campaigns.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;More importantly, of course, the Jewish Roller Derby project aims to, whatever bouts it participates in, provide both a space in which Jewish skaters can find community with one-another, and a space and platform for educating and advocating for the Jewish community, at a time when it is needed once again. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The Jewish Roller Derby project can be contacted via Facebook on their page: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/jewishrollerderby/"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/jewishrollerderby/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; and by email at:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:jewishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; jewishrollerderby@gmail.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;If you want to apply to be in the team for the exhibition bout at Rollercon 2019, you can do so via this form: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfEUYxozZdqzMXfPFQsJe2K4I3ZaD411U0NZSVApkWHMMv5Cg/viewform"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfEUYxozZdqzMXfPFQsJe2K4I3ZaD411U0NZSVApkWHMMv5Cg/viewform&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>in the news</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>jewish roller derby</category><category>rollercon</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/29/jewish-roller-derby-shining-a-light/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 11:48:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Big Blether 2: Mean City host the return of the Scottish Derby community meetup.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/06/big-blether-2-mean-city-host-the-return-of-the-scottish-derby-community-meetup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, the Scottish Roller Derby Community made a bit of history, by finally getting together in one place for a &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/18/the-big-blether-scotland-together/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big Blether&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This wasn't just a disorganised chat, of course: this was the first ever Roller Derby Conference for Scottish derby, on the model of the European "EROC". On the 7th of October 2017, the vast majority of active Scottish leagues were represented by pairs of delegates [and all but one of those who couldn't make it sent statements by proxy], actively engaged in process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-24409 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/screen-shot-2017-09-13-at-16-17-08.png" alt="Screen Shot 2017-09-13 at 16.17.08" width="335" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the first Big Blether was the brainchild of Auld Reekie Roller Girls' Crazylegs and Skinner, and Glasgow Roller Derby's Head Referee, Candy Moho, it was also agreed that future convocations would pass the torch onto other leagues around the country, spreading the democratic work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as it goes, the first volunteers to do the hard thing of repeating previous success were Glasgow's All-Gender league, Mean City Roller Derby. Very slightly more than a year later, their iteration of the conference, Big Blether 2, is coming to central Glasgow on the 20th October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principal task of a repeat convention is more nuanced than that of a first meeting. The first Big Blether did great things in generating conversation; in spreading knowledge [we personally enjoyed the group discussion elements, and how well they were orchestrated] and sharing problems. &lt;em&gt;More importantly&lt;/em&gt;, it generated actions - foci for future progress and development, mutually agreed by all those present. (It also gained Scottish derby a little bit of publicity, via an article in Five On Five magazine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second Big Blether will have the equally hard task of looking at those actions, a year later, and seeing what has been done, what has not; correcting course, potentially, or pushing forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it might do us well to look at what actions the first Big Blether produced, across the multiple sessions it held (these were scheduled as pairs of parallel sessions, run as facilitated group discussions):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby Oversight&lt;/strong&gt; spread some useful information (and quashed some misapprehensions) about the existing governance structures in Roller Derby. The action produced was to develop a "&lt;strong&gt;Scottish Derby Lobbying Group&lt;/strong&gt;" to provide a unified voice for the Scottish community in representing our needs and desires to larger entities.
We followed up on this, and believe that at least some work was done towards this aim, but as yet there is no formal group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Game Scheduling&lt;/strong&gt; produced some frank discussion between leagues about competition for resources; the low ratio of leagues to halls and fans (as well as to officials), the network effects which mean that smaller leagues can be accidentally outcompeted by older, more established clubs, and so on. The actions for this session were to more strongly adopt the shared &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby Schedule&lt;/strong&gt; for scheduling bouts and events (this common document is hosted on Google Docs, and made available via links in the Scottish Derby Facebook group) and to consider &lt;strong&gt;Sharing Fixtures with Other Leagues&lt;/strong&gt;.
We've seen use of the Schedule increase significantly since the first Big Blether, and there have been a number of "shared fixtures", so we think these actions have been broadly successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Officiating&lt;/strong&gt; involved some extensive discussions about the widespread issues of officials recruitment and training (and respect within leagues). The action for this session was to promote more central training and learning opportunities for Officials (on and off skates) - a &lt;strong&gt;Ref School&lt;/strong&gt; to be run by Glasgow Roller Derby - and for leagues to work towards giving their officials a more "cohesive identity" to form around and generally &lt;strong&gt;treat them as first class citizens&lt;/strong&gt; of the sport.
The Glasgow Roller Derby Ref School has run a few sessions (and Dundee have continued to run their own series of Officiating bootcamps, extant before Big Blether); and the branding of several league's officials as their own "teams" seems to represent a start of the second action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Access to Scottish Derby&lt;/strong&gt; revolved around the perennial issues of costs, access to halls and training certifications; as well as problems with providing kit, and burnout in "highly active" members of the community; and the less discussed issues with cultural homogeneity in derby. This session produced a lot of "personal actions" for leagues to &lt;strong&gt;Share More Resources&lt;/strong&gt;, and investigate community Volunteering Schemes.
It's difficult to measure how well this has been progressed without hearing from all the leagues - so this will be a point of discussion in October!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting as a whole also produced actions to produce and maintain a &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby Ranking&lt;/strong&gt;, which would enable a &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby National Tournament&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Scottish League or Championships&lt;/strong&gt;.
These have progressed very slightly (there's an initial Scottish Derby Ranking derived from Flat Track Stats Europe ratings), but on the meat of the matter - an organised competitive structure - there's a lot of work to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The second ever Big Blether will give those actioned a chance to report on their progress, as well as discussing any new topics which have developed in the past 12 months - since that year has seen three World Cups, a changing structure in other International Gameplay, and at least one new style of Roller Derby, we’re sure that there will be lots to talk about.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2nd Big Blether will be hosted on the 20th October 2018, in &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/bsRwxpsb6Do"&gt;Glasgow Quakers Meeting House, Elmbank Crescent, Glasgow. G2 4PS&lt;/a&gt;. Final timings to be decided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams can register representatives (as can independents) here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSf5LLsKjK3egYsLrcJNX8vWnnoRV5DRErii42kKAsANWbbP-w/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSf5LLsKjK3egYsLrcJNX8vWnnoRV5DRErii42kKAsANWbbP-w/viewform&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;REGISTRATION CLOSES 1 OCTOBER.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can contribute to the discussion topics on offer, and shape the schedule, via this form here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeiKb3UVcj1mKjVAeZmUVUY5krWkziPGH7HKCR4OQirmRKATQ/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeiKb3UVcj1mKjVAeZmUVUY5krWkziPGH7HKCR4OQirmRKATQ/viewform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>communication</category><category>in the news</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>officials</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>team scotland</category><category>the big blether</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/06/big-blether-2-mean-city-host-the-return-of-the-scottish-derby-community-meetup/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 10:00:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UKRDA Elections Update: your new Directors!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/26/ukrda-elections-update-your-new-directors/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a democratic organisation, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://ukrda.org.uk/"&gt;UK Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; undergoes a yearly AGM, in which vacancies for its Directorships can be filled by vote within the member leagues. The most recent AGM was held this month, 5th of June, and resulted in a particularly large number of changes to the Directorships, due to retirements and the filling of previously empty posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're giving you a quick overview of the current Directorships and their holders, to help you get to know your organisation.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26918" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/ukrdadirectors2018.jpg" alt="UKRDADirectors2018" width="960" height="720"&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Halo Jones - Secretary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halo Jones remains in the position of Secretary for UKRDA from before the AGM. Outside of UKRDA, she is well known in the world of NSOing around the Oxford area (especially for &lt;a href="https://www.oxfordwheelsofgory.co.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oxford Wheels of Gory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), and beyond. A nominee for the Talk Derby To Me NSO Listener Awards in 2017 and 2016, she has officiated at multiple high level events, including the 2017 MRDA Championships, and both the Roller Derby World Cup and the Men's Roller Derby World Cup 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maw Deuce - Director for Internal Communication&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maw Deuce continues in her role as Director for Internal Communication from the last elections. The longest term member of the UKRDA family, Maw previously served as the UKRDA National Squads chair, responsible for interactions with and support of the affiliated national teams, and has held additional roles before then.
Outside of UKRDA, Maw is a member of &lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and a referee and official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rollin Rat - Director for Officials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rollin Rat continues as a Director from before the AGM, moving from the position of Director of Policy &amp;amp; Strategy to Director of Officials. Outside of UKRDA, he is a Referee for &lt;a href="https://centralcityrollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Birmingham, and has refereed at many high level events, including the Roller Derby World Cup 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stat Man - Director for Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stat Man has a long history in Roller Derby, as both an Announcer and an Official. As well as starting one of the first attempts to rate and rank European teams, he was one of the individuals responsible for establishing the ongoing &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;s, of which he remains the Chair of the Organising Committee. He may also have been involved in the short-lived attempt to have a roller derby team based in Sealand. He has also continued to announce at high level events, including both World Cups this year.
Stat Man has also previously served as Executive Director of Sanctioning and Games for the MRDA (2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smacktivist - Director for Communications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smacktivist is new to the Director of Communications role. She hails from &lt;a href="http://rollerbillies.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cambridge Rollerbillies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where she's currently Line Up Manager for their B-Team, the Punt Rockers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dorkmistress - Director for External Engagement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dorkmistress has a very strong history in Roller Derby, as both an Announcer and an Official. She has previously Managed several iterations of Team Wales Roller Derby, as well as announcing for &lt;a href="http://www.swanseacityrollerderby.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swansea City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and announcing and officiating for &lt;a href="http://www.sws.pizza/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;South Wales Silures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; she's also been seen announcing across a gamut of high level events, including the most recent Men's Roller Derby World Cup, and Newcastle Roller Girls' EuroClash tournament.
As well as UKRDA External Engagement, she currently holds the position of &lt;a href="http://www.rollerderbynationscommittee.org/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roller Derby Nations Committee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Regional Representative for Northern Europe, representing all the World Cup Nations from that region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buckfast - Head of Tech&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buckfast is new to the role of Head of Tech (which is not a Directoral role, and has been semi-empty since the last AGM). He's relatively new to Roller Derby - having recently begun Bench Coaching at &lt;a href="https://www.yorkminxters.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>agm</category><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>in the news</category><category>news</category><category>ukrda</category><category>ukrda directors</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/26/ukrda-elections-update-your-new-directors/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 11:22:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Directory: a new (UK-focused) resource for growing the sport.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/21/derby-directory-a-new-uk-focused-resource-for-growing-the-sport/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A perennial question from people starting derby: from rookies joining a new team, through to the most scary challenge, people starting an entirely new league or team, is "how do I do this?".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst there are actually a lot of resources out in the wild concerning various aspects of roller derby, they're often fairly disorganised and dispersed, or strewn across various Facebook and other social media groups which aren't necessarily the easiest to find. (The original roller derby leagues in the UK created a newsgroup for this, which eventually evolved into UKRDA, but things have moved on since then.) Additionally, there's a big problem with link-rot and social media decay in modern resources, which can easily lead to a given source of information vanishing, becoming stale, or otherwise more useless over time. (We wrote a little about this issue &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;earlier this year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26888 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/derbydirectory.jpg" alt="DerbyDirectory" width="426" height="426"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://derbydirectory.info/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby Directory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aims to solve all of this, at least in the UK; although its resources are mostly useful regardless of where your league is based. The brainchild of two of Border City Roller Derby, Carlisle's members - coach, referee, and founder Schrödinger's Phat #1691, and coach and skater Hoolia #2122 - this website aims to collect together, and organise, all the information you need to start up a league, or start off as a newbie skater. As Border City has only very recently transitioned to the state of being a "bouting" league, the issues of beginning skaters, and beginning leagues, are very fresh in the minds of all involved.&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps as a result, the site's organisation is really very good, with categories from the Rookie Corner (a step-by-step guide to the frequently asked questions of people new to derby), and Kit (including an itemised list of the mandatory kit items, with suggested products, ordered by price), through a comprehensive guide to Skate Care, links to Bootcamps and Coaches who are available to run sessions, and even a guide on Starting a New League.
In all cases, the clean, simple style, and clearly defined categories help to get to the information you need, quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with all projects like this, the proof of the pudding will be in the longer term - but both of the founders seem committed to maintaining and updating the site - both expanding it, and fighting the entropic forces of link rot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They're also still collecting offers of additional information - and especially Coaches available to run sessions for their mini-classified section there. If you're a Coach whose time is available for other teams, do let the Derby Directory team know!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coaching</category><category>communication</category><category>derby directory</category><category>in the news</category><category>reviews</category><category>training</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/21/derby-directory-a-new-uk-focused-resource-for-growing-the-sport/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 10:15:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie's 10th Anniversary Rebrand - with your help!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/25/auld-reekies-10-anniversary-rebrand-with-your-help/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has been part of Roller Derby for a moderate time will have noticed the increasing trend for rebrands amongst the older leagues. When the Roller Derby revival was in its initial phase, many of the first leagues named themselves "Roller Girls" - almost certainly resonating with the post-90s echoes of "girl power" (and the RiotGirl punk movement, which played into initial conceptions of how Roller Derby culture would work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-26653 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/peoplesprojectweb.png" alt="PeoplesProjectweb" width="607" height="431"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a more modern era, as Roller Derby becomes ever more inclusive; both naturally (accepting more people means accepting more viewpoints), and intentionally (WFTDA's gender policy explicitly spelling out the inclusion of all kinds of women, as well as gender-expansive and non-binary people), that phrasing becomes increasingly uncomfortable for many leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; were the second ever league to exist in Scotland, founded 10 years ago, back in 2008. After a long process of discussion, the league made the (near-unanimous) decision to move to the gender-neutral formulation in 2017... but were immediately hit by the disruption of their main venue for their entire existence, &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/memories-of-meadowbank/"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, preparing to close at the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Auld Reekie Roller Derby rebrand is still moving ahead, in their symbolically significant decennial year; but, as with Central City Roller Derby [who were Rollergirls only a month ago], the rate at which a complete rebrand can happen is limited by realities of funding.
Changing a name - and informing WFTDA and UKRDA that you're doing so - is fairly easy. Changing your logo, and extending that to your website, uniforms, banners, merchandise and so forth, is much harder, and costs significantly to complete. Without their main venue, and with no really equivalent alternatives available in the medium term, Auld Reekie's revenue streams are lower than they otherwise would have been, and so they've had to seek additional sources of funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one reason why Auld Reekie are applying for funding from "The People's Projects". This website is one of the ways in which the public can influence the distribution of National Lottery funds, in order to support locally deserving projects. Auld Reekie are asking for £21.7k - some of which will go towards the rebranding costs above. (This is actually the smallest requested amount of funding out of all the projects in their region.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As importantly, however, the rest of the money will go towards improving accessibility and inclusion in Auld Reekie in other ways. As much as "Auld Reekie Roller Derby" is a statement of inclusion, acts are as important as words. Whilst Auld Reekie already work hard to provide an inclusive culture in terms of gender, there are other barriers in the sport that can be addressed.
Anyone starting out in Roller Derby will know just how very expensive it is to acquire even the minimum set of kit, and these costs act as a different kind of exclusionary filter for the sport. So, the league also plan to spend funds on doubling their provision for loaner kits for potential new skaters, lowering the financial barriers to becoming involved in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie have already passed the shortlisting phase for People's Project funding for their region, and simply need enough votes relative to the 4 other shortlisted projects in order to achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voting is open on The People's Project Funding for Auld Reekie's project until the 30th (next Monday). You can vote by simply following this link: &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.thepeoplesprojects.org.uk/projects/view/rebrand-recruitment-and-celebration"&gt;https://www.thepeoplesprojects.org.uk/projects/view/rebrand-recruitment-and-celebration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[We hope to also bring you a follow-up article on the new Auld Reekie Roller Derby brand, later in the year!]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller derby</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>in the news</category><category>lottery funding</category><category>rebranding</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/25/auld-reekies-10-anniversary-rebrand-with-your-help/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 15:36:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Vanishing History of Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Whilst we've been concerned by archiving the history of roller derby for several years, this particular article was inspired by the following threads on twitter: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thederbyapex/status/971562257518821376"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://twitter.com/thederbyapex/status/971562257518821376&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Nicktroptopolis/status/971840386011410432"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://twitter.com/Nicktroptopolis/status/971840386011410432&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern Roller Derby is a product of, and inescapably shaped by, the Internet, as is much of culture produced since the mid-1990s. Whilst this has positive effects, it also can have profoundly negative ones, especially regarding the transient and ephemeral nature of our cultural records and history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of time, records have been made with physical marks (scratches in clay, ink on paper, papyrus or animal skin, and so on; or even the physical structure of vinyl records or CDs), and mostly permanently. Secret physical records are kept secret by locking them in a safe, rarely by encrypting or enciphering them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As information technology became more prevalent, over the 20th century, and predominant over the early 21st, more and more of our records - which are our history for future generations (or even ourselves a few years later) - have no physical, human-readable representation. Documents, and photos, and forum posts, are patterns of bytes on a server which we often don't even own, or have direct access to. &lt;em&gt;Secret&lt;/em&gt; documents are encrypted patterns of bytes on a server we don't own, and are completely unreadable if the key to decrypt them is lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, it is now much harder to maintain a historical record of the recent past - the recent culture - than it was even two decades ago. This worrying phenomenon is sometimes referred to as a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_dark_age"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Dark Age&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; , and we should be more concerned about it than we are. In previous periods, some level of archiving and historical preservation happened "for free" - if you don't deliberately destroy a piece of paper, it will last a fairly long time. In the modern period, records from that old forum your league had before you updated are &lt;em&gt;gone forever&lt;/em&gt; unless you deliberately copied them and saved them elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby's entire modern culture is stored mostly on electronic documents - there are very few physical artefacts, outside of bout programmes, to cover the history of the sport. (It's also important to preserve those physical artefacts - and projects like the UK-based &lt;a href="http://nmrd.org.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Museum of Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are working on that.)
We currently have volunteer-run operations preserving some statistical records, for example, &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an open repository of all the bout scores, and bout stats, uploaded to it, and this is a &lt;em&gt;more important&lt;/em&gt; social and cultural role than the ratings and rankings it produces for subsets of those stats. However, these are both volunteer-run, and patchy in their coverage: for various reasons&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/#footnotes"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, much of Latin America ignores FTS and does not upload their records there, so we don't even have a good historical record for &lt;em&gt;games&lt;/em&gt; in Latin America (Mexico maintains its own website for game results, which does not sync with FTS, for some reason).
Similarly, &lt;a href="http://derbylisting.com/word/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derbylisting.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; attempts to record the status of leagues across the world, but is also very much dependant on engagement by leagues and the community itself. (And it's not clear to us how well it records historical changes.) There are also several other sites which have tried/are trying to do a similar thing - &lt;a href="https://derbyposition.com/en/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;derbyposition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, for example, and fragmentation of effort here makes things much harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/2/"&gt;In the next page, we'll talk about the harder problem of recording our shared cultural heritage - the stories of Roller Derby.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="footnotes"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;*The most important reasons being lack of volunteer effort in some regions, because:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;FTS still talks about, and displays, mostly WFTDA branding on itself, even though it takes records from all flat-track derby, not just WFTDA-member, or even WFTDA-rules, leagues (the MRDA branding, which it also has, is not visible on the front page - and &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; WFTDA is actually mentioned in the site's description of itself). Several leagues we've talked to in the past were under the impression that they simply couldn't use FTS if they weren't WFTDA members, or if they were, they couldn't use it for anything but their A teams.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;FTS doesn't have a rating or ranking scheme for Latin America. FTS's popularity in Europe is driven by (ironically, in contrast to the above) the fact that it provides a ranking and rating for all European teams, regardless of their WFTDA membership or if they're an A or B (or even C) team. This is the carrot part of the FTS system, and it simply doesn't exist (officially) for Latin America.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
 Strictly, it does, as &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SRDRank&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a rating and ranking system for the entire world, using FTS's records; but we're not anywhere near as visible as FTS, and we are acutely aware that the SRDRank site needs updates after resources devoted to it were diverted to the Roller Derby World Cup for several months. Lack of resources is a problem everywhere, sadly.
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Recording Culture and Stories&lt;/h3&gt;
Statistics are easy to record.The situation for more complex cultural records - forum posts, discussion threads, the entire contents of online magazines or journals - is both more subtle, and also more difficult to resolve. Members of the Roller Derby community who joined post-2014 may not even recognise the name "DNN" -&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.derbynews.net/"&gt;Derby News Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, but that titan of Roller Derby reporting and bout streaming was a central part of the Roller Derby community for the seven whole years - almost two fifths of the entire time Roller Derby has existed - before it died. We're extremely &lt;em&gt;lucky&lt;/em&gt; that the owners, and community, came together to keep the servers holding the site running - albeit with reduced resources - and to archive its valuable historical records. Because of this effort, we can still, for example, look back at &lt;a href="http://www.derbynews.net/2008/09/09/5_texas_stops_9_detroit_83_46/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;how Texas fared against Detroit back in 2008&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (and their rosters at the time!).
&lt;p&gt;For public sites, there is at least the hope that you can pretend it's someone else's problem - the &lt;a href="https://archive.org/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; exists explicitly to combat the loss of history due to the ephemeral nature of websites by trawling the web and taking archival, historical snapshots of sites it can access. This isn't perfect: the Archive can't check every site every day - or even every site every year; and it tries to focus on the websites with the most interest and links, as they're likely to be the most important. But it does give a certain minimum insurance against total loss - something, albeit possibly a tiny fragment, will possibly survive, even if you don't care to take precautions yourself.
When the next site with a huge chunk of Roller Derby culture dies - and &lt;a href="https://indieweb.org/site-deaths"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sites die all the time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - we may not be so lucky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're taking some steps to combat this, starting with a small thing today: we're working on an archive, to be public, of Roller Derby collective culture - the stories that make up the history of the sport from 2001 onwards - collected from the community itself. You can submit your stories to our Google forms - we have &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeFg0uCe1GrSUdv-2VrRU4Sczv_NhIygRZg3UwjjM-AxvIJKQ/viewform?usp=sf_link"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;one version in English&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeRppNu4hkwlRzofmcD_stFmuYzgM9-ZNW1jK_GWulDzPgagA/viewform?usp=sf_link"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;one in Spanish&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for more accessibility - in any language you want, and about any event in roller derby you can relate. (We're especially interested in making sure we get stories from the early days of the sport before they are lost, and from regions and leagues who aren't often covered... but all stories are welcome.)
In the near future, we'll be talking about how we'll make this archive available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/3/"&gt;In the next page, we'll talk about the issues recording the history of Roller Derby's governance.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Recording Our Sport's Governance &amp;amp; Transparency&lt;/h3&gt;
Much of the existing Roller Derby cultural history isn't even public - it's in private silos across the internet. The majority of governing bodies in Roller Derby maintain almost entirely private spaces, as do the majority of leagues. (Even when those spaces are not private, the use of restrictive copyright may also inhibit preservation - as several digital archiving projects have discovered; this is another reason why using better, more open licenses - &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or otherwise - enriches the community.)
We can trust that WFTDA, or MRDA, say, keeps a full and complete backup of all of their forum discussions. But we &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to trust, because we have no way to have an independent record of any of that contents - both because of technological walls (the forums are private, password-protected spaces), and legal ones (the WFTDA, etc, NDAs prevent public disclosure of those contents by anyone who does have access to them).
This is not to pick on WFTDA alone, as we're hopeful is clear - all Roller Derby governing bodies have this problem to various extents, even when they've committed to more open and transparent communication. For example, UKRDA has made some positive steps towards this - making minutes of Board Meetings &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1387CqPTaHx_dp1JAgoxSrHlnrbC45aBj"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;public&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - and have shown interest in working towards further transparency, but they're still working &lt;em&gt;towards&lt;/em&gt; them.
&lt;p&gt;We should note that problems of transparency have dogged many Sports Governing Bodies in the last few years - and &lt;a href="http://www.playthegame.org/news/comments/2016/034_the-rules-of-the-game-the-need-for-transparency-in-sports-governance/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;there are calls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a href="http://www.playthegame.org/knowledge-bank/downloads/sports-governance-observer-2015/c14e0343-6716-42b5-9aa0-a6c700daeb48"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reports&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) from those in the wider sports governance community for all SGBs to become as transparent as other democracies already are. WFTDA&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/#footnotes2"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; does do better than a great many SGBs; but some SGBs are particularly opaque (FIFA comes to mind).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transparency is sometimes hard, but it doesn't have to be this way. The British Government, which has not been an exemplar for good transparency over most of its existence, still manages to publish and archive a &lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;completely public record&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of all debates in Parliament&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/#footnotes3"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, since around 1800. This &lt;em&gt;Hansard&lt;/em&gt; system is also used by many other democracies across the World - New Zealand, Canada, Australia, South Africa, Singapore - and other similar systems are used by, for example, the &lt;a href="https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;United States of America &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;(in fact, the Constitution of the USA &lt;em&gt;requires&lt;/em&gt; that Congress keep such public records), and the &lt;a href="http://www.europarl.europa.eu/plenary/en/home.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;European Parliament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
In all of these cases, these records required a lot of effort to generate - they're hand-stenotyped transcriptions of verbal debates, with post-editing for readability and references - but because they exist, we know much more about the history of those institutions, their culture, and how this changed over time. (And because they're almost all public, copyright-free records, other copies can be made of them, so the risk of them being lost to the world is negligible.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, almost all of the debate in Roller Derby happens online, in text conversations on forums and chat rooms. Making available an "MRDA Hansard", or a "WFTDA Congressional Record" is almost trivial - the data already exists in written form, it just needs to be published somewhere, and with the correct level of access for the community. (We'd argue that if national governments can manage to make their debates Public to the World, it shouldn't be a big deal for any Governing Body of a sport whose founding ethic is "For The Skater, By The Skater").&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is obviously a trade-off here between transparency and the right to privacy. All organisations need private spaces - for grievance committees, embargoed information from other sources, and so on - but they need much fewer private spaces than they often create for themselves. Organisations also need to protect the rights of individuals to privacy of personal information - for example, any organisation in Europe needs to comply with the &lt;a href="https://www.eugdpr.org/gdpr-faqs.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GDPR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on this topic - and this will require some secrecy in some areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also important to note that just because a space is publicly accessible does not mean that it has to be open to public's input - only Members of Parliament may speak in the British House of Commons, but the entire world can see (and hear, nowadays) what they say. In the case of roller derby, Derbylisting.com records around &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1800&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; leagues playing under WFTDA/MRDA rules - even though the majority are not members of either organisation, they do have some moral rights to know what the community has coming for it, in return for the legitimacy they lend the organisations merely by adopting those rules. (Transparency can also be a good way to engage your community in the present, as well as allowing your record to be preserved in the past!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With more of our history and community in the public domain (both visible, and licensed to distribute more rights), maintaining our history becomes a shared possibility for the entire roller derby community.
We at the Scottish Roller Derby blog are also looking a hosting some smaller-scale public resources to help encourage transparency and community - we'll be writing more about the technology side of this in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="footnotes3"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;*The British Government also, since 2000/2002 commits to making a lot more of its internal documents and records available to the public of the world, via the Freedom of Information Acts (&lt;a href="https://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/2000/36/contents"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2000&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - England &amp;amp; Wales, &lt;a href="http://www.legislation.gov.uk/asp/2002/13/contents"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - Scotland), after consultation started in 1997 ("&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/your-right-to-know-the-governments-proposals-for-a-freedom-of-information-act"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Right To Know&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;"). Many other governments have committed to similar levels of free access to the public - not just their own citizens, but the world; Sweden may hold the record for first raising this issue in 1766!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="footnotes2"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;**WFTDA deserves credit, for example, for the amount of material it does publish, when out of NDA, on officiating the rules; for making its rating calculations completely public (something MRDA does not do, by contrast); for (albeit without a good interface other than sending an email) making bout stats for all Sanctioned Games available to anyone who asks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dnn</category><category>in the news</category><category>international</category><category>international derby</category><category>open</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 11:59:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rule 56 now coming Online on Monday 6th.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/01/rule-56-now-coming-online-on-monday-6th/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You might remember that last year, we brought you news of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/536421803211316/"&gt;Derby Stance Coaching Summit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - the UK's first Coaching-focussed conference designed to bring together coaches across the UK to share their experiences in workshops lead by some of the greatest coaches in Roller Derby - including Texas Rollergirls' Smarty Pants (Nadia Kean), who we &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/03/uks-first-coaching-summit-derby-stance/"&gt;interviewed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Derby Stance was a huge success - we've not met any of the 80 attendees who had a bad thing to say, and many who talked about the connections, lessons and ideas that they'd collected over the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby Stance was organised by &lt;strong&gt;Rule 56&lt;/strong&gt;, the coaching enterprise founded by Rainy City Roller Derby's Hydra (Maha El Nasser) and Leeds Roller Derby's Ecky Thump (Ruth Saxton). Now, working again with Smarty Pants, they're back with another development for the UK Coaching community, and beyond - e-learning and conferencing in a series of targeted webinars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea, as Ecky Thump explained, is to provide a much more accessible set of coaching resources. “In between skating, coaching, training, watching and doing admin, skaters have very little time for extra derby learning. Add travel and cost into that and conferences are a bit of a luxury. We hope that these webinars will give more coaches, not just those who live near to Yorkshire or whose leagues are willing to subsidise, the opportunity to engage with some of the talented coaches we have lined up.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The targeted scope of each webinar is also designed to assist with this, as the focus means that they can fit into an evening's session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pilot webinar - entitled "Coaching 101", and based on the introductory coaching talk which Smarty Pants delivers with her own coaching company &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.getsmartycoaching.com/"&gt;Get Smarty Coaching&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - is available for sign-up now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session will begin at &lt;strong&gt;19:00 (GMT)&lt;/strong&gt; on Monday &lt;strong&gt;March 6th&lt;/strong&gt;, and will last for approximately 1 hour. Event details at: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1451911724851183/permalink/1463473710361651/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1451911724851183/permalink/1463473710361651/&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;where a registration link will become available "before the end of the week".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the time in your timezone, click here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?msg=Coaching+101%3A+Rule+56+and+Smarty+Pants&amp;amp;iso=20170306T19&amp;amp;p1=136&amp;amp;ah=1"&gt;https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?msg=Coaching+101%3A+Rule+56+and+Smarty+Pants&amp;amp;iso=20170306T19&amp;amp;p1=136&amp;amp;ah=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coaches</category><category>in the news</category><category>rule56</category><category>upcoming events</category><category>webinar</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/01/rule-56-now-coming-online-on-monday-6th/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 20:55:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Are you ready for a skating spooktacular?</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/19/are-you-ready-for-a-skating-spooktacular/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9817" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/fb-hallowmean-a.jpg" alt="fb-hallowmean-a" width="3545" height="1305"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tricks or treats? Why choose when you can have both – and a whole lot more – at Mean City’s closing home game of the year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow’s only coed league will be hosting a devilish double dunt of derby delights on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 29 October&lt;/strong&gt; at the Dear Mean Place – aka the &lt;strong&gt;ARC Sportscentre in Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hallowe'en is when things go bump in the night - &lt;strong&gt;HallowMean&lt;/strong&gt; is when things go bump on the track and there are trick and treats for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, the &lt;strong&gt;Mean City ladies&lt;/strong&gt; – fresh from a gallus bout against Granite’s Fight Hawks and looking to maintain their forward momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Meanies have been reaping the benefits of a greater emphasis on tactics, fitness and skills – with fresh recruits bolstering the settled squad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their opponents on 29 October will be the out-of-this-world &lt;strong&gt;ASTROs (Auld Reekie All Star Rookies)&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s going to be a stern test of the Mean City ladies’ resolve, as well as a showcase for some of Scotland’s finest up and coming skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second game will see &lt;strong&gt;Mean City's coed team&lt;/strong&gt; ghosting to the track to take on &lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers' Belter Skelpers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tis the season to be fearful and while there’s no fear among the Mean City ranks, there will be some trepidation given the excellent form the Belter Skelpers have been in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bairn City Rollers’ coed team recently played a mix of Aberdeen and Dundee skaters – the Brawler Buddies – and really brought their A game, winning with a well-oiled performance combining offence, defence and excellent tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City’s coed team may lack the experience of their opponents, but they have spirit, guts and tenacity in abundance and will match them skate for skate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City President Elaine Hunter – aka Roller Dobby - said: “We can’t wait to round off our home season in style with a spook-tacular thriller for all the family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Trick or treat – why choose when you can have both? There will be skating, fun, cakes and cracking tunes – what else are Saturdays made for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Tickets are just &lt;b&gt;£4&lt;/b&gt; in advance – that’s just £2 per game – or &lt;b&gt;£5&lt;/b&gt; on the door. It’s a bargain and you’ll be supporting grassroots sport at the same time. Under-14s get in free.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean City presents HallowMean - Saturday 29 October 2016 - doors open at the ARC Sportscentre at noon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;For more information on the event – &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/312912055752880/"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;For tickets – &lt;a href="http://www.meancityrollerderby.com/tickets.php"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>coed</category><category>in the news</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/19/are-you-ready-for-a-skating-spooktacular/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 15:36:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Japan Open - the Other WFTDA First This Year</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While there has been plenty of deserved excitement over the recent European Smackdown, hosted by Crime City Rollers in Malmö, it is not the only groundbreaking tournament happening this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If European Smackdown showed that Europe is now ready to compete in the highest levels of &lt;a href="https://wftda.com"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt; play, then Kokeshi Roller Dolls' &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/JapanOpenRollerDerby"&gt;Japan Open Tournament&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;March 25 and 26&lt;/strong&gt; shows that Asia is now firmly emerging onto the International Derby stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6660" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/mega-image-jo-1024x267.png" alt="mega-image-jo-1024x267" width="1024" height="267"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Japan Open Tournament is the first ever Asia-Pacific Roller Derby tournament.  Played under WFTDA rules, the tournament will involve teams from Japan, USA (Alaska), Australia, New Zealand and, in a late change, Denmark (teams from China and Hawaii had to pull out during the tournament's organisation). Comprehensive Park Arena in Okinawa will be the host venue, with &lt;em&gt;free&lt;/em&gt; admission to all spectators, as this is also something of an outreach opportunity for the sport.
There's actually two tiers to the tournament - an 'A' tier, featuring WFTDA Member Leagues and WFTDA Sanctioned bouts;and a 'B' tier, which features mostly non-WFTDA members, or B-teams, and is not Sanctioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby actually has quite a long history in Japan; American influence seeded previous incarnations of the game in the 20th Century, and a Japan-native version ("RollerGame" or "RollerGame Japan") was popular in the country in the early 1990s, and then again in the early 2000s. (In fact, this weekend - March 19th and 20th - sees RollerGame Japan come to the USA in an &lt;a href="http://www.santamonica.com/event/roller-expo-2016/"&gt;expo event&lt;/a&gt; hosted in Santa Monica).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WFTDA Japanese Roller Derby community dates back to &lt;strong&gt;2010/11&lt;/strong&gt;, when both Kokeshi Roller Dolls and Tokyo Roller Girls were founded around the American military bases in Japan. Since then, each of the leagues or teams which has emerged has also been nucleated around American military presence: there is now derby in Tokyo (including at least one team, Kamikaze Badass, which is not associated with Tokyo Roller Girls), Yokosuka, Zama, Yokota, Misawa and two leagues in Okinawa. The community is actively attempting to recruit Japanese skaters, especially in Tokyo, which has had a Japanese team since 2012; it was skaters from Tokyo Roller Girls who also managed the creation of the Team Japan which competed in the 2014 Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Japan Open Tournament has been planned for some time; it has been the goal of Kokeshi Roller Dolls to hold such a tournament from early in their WFTDA certification process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read about the teams attending the Japan Open in the next pages in this guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're planning on viewing the Japan Open, our handy viewing guide (with a different page for every timezone with a team) may be in useful. Click here to access it: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/11/the-japan-open-schedule-timezones/"&gt;VIEWING GUIDE.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Profiles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;JRDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6674" style="border-style:solid;border-width:1px;" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/bigmap3.png" alt="bigmap3" width="800" height="421"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRDA&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-6520 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/logo_of_the_adelaide_roller_derby_league.jpg" alt="Logo_of_the_Adelaide_Roller_Derby_league" width="405" height="400"&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://adelaiderollerderby.com.au/"&gt;Adelaide Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are one of Australia's long-established roller derby leagues, dating from &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;. Their A-Team, the &lt;em&gt;Adeladies&lt;/em&gt;, have played basically every other league in Australasia, although the Japan Open is their first venture outside of that arena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/14248"&gt;FTS ranking&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;650.1&lt;/strong&gt; (WFTDA), the Adeladies are possibly the strongest league attending the tournament, and are the favourites to win the Championship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adelaides' Captain Elle Catraz had this to say to us: "Adelaide Roller Derby are thrilled to be sending their WFDTA representative skaters to participate in the Japan Open Tournament in Okinawa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Japan will be the farthest that Adelaide Roller Derby has travelled to bout and we are extremely excited and grateful for the opportunity to play against and watch teams from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our season doesn't officially kick off until early April so this will be our first bout of the season. Our skaters chose not to have much of an off season in preparation for this tournament, but it will be all worth it when they hit the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training wise, we had skaters travel to Queensland to participate in the Derby Fest training camp during January along with the whole league having the pleasure of being trained by Scald Eagle and Stefanie Mainey in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be the first time many of our skaters have travelled to Japan so our team have enjoyed team bonding sessions over Japanese food, while learning important Japanese phrases we can use both on and off the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also extremely proud and grateful to bring the tournament two of our extremely committed referees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Adeladies take great pride in representing their entire league when they travel and the Japan Open will be no exception. "&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="ardroster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
The Philistine &lt;strong&gt;#88 (Captain)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elle Catraz &lt;strong&gt;#46 (Captain)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed Bandit &lt;strong&gt;#777&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blue Wrenegade &lt;strong&gt;#2880&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ankle Grinder &lt;strong&gt;#91&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fury of Fenrir &lt;strong&gt;#24&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frill Seeker &lt;strong&gt;#32&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KillaKaze &lt;strong&gt;#11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaos! &lt;strong&gt;#601&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bam Bam Belial &lt;strong&gt;#29&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anne T Social &lt;strong&gt;#886&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maiden Hell &lt;strong&gt;#206&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry Smyles &lt;strong&gt;#2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Referees Chris Durant and Slaíne are also attending the tournament, as part of the officiating teams.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRDA&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-6523 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/brawlers.jpg?w=480" alt="brawlers" width="240" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/12/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://piratecityrollers.com/"&gt;Pirate City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/#pcrroster"&gt;(roster)&lt;/a&gt; are the strongest of Auckland, New Zealand's leagues, founded way back in &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, as the first league in the Southern Hemisphere. They have continued to establish firsts in roller derby since then.
Full WFTDA members since 2013, Pirate City have mostly played in games in the Australasian region, although they attended the 2015 Beach Brawl, where they did better than expected (as is usual for a non-US team!), despite only winning against hosts Gold Coast. Their B team, the &lt;em&gt;Broadside Brawlers&lt;/em&gt;, is the team competing at the Japan Open, however, and there's much less known about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With no &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/55620"&gt;FTS rating&lt;/a&gt; (the A team resides at 587.1(WFTDA)), it is hard to predict how the Brawlers will do against their competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pirate City B are scheduled to play Killa Geishas of Misawa and the JRDA Expo team, Nippon Senbatsu, in the B tier of the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brawlers Captains Drop the Pom! and RumpleStinson told us "The Broadside Brawlers are extremely excited to be attending their first tournament. We have been training hard and are looking forward to making the Pirate City Rollers proud.
We are looking forward to meeting some great new people and playing new teams, picking up some new tricks along the way and getting experience of international Derby."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="pcrroster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Drop the Pom! &lt;strong&gt;#999 (Captain)&lt;/strong&gt; [Suzie Harris]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RumbleStinson &lt;strong&gt;#33 (Captain)&lt;/strong&gt; [Shirley Stinson]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kid Vicious &lt;strong&gt;#711 (Bench)&lt;/strong&gt; [Devan Jackson De Toit]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manic Street Creature &lt;strong&gt;(Lineup)&lt;/strong&gt; [Mars Coombes]
Block Ness Monster &lt;strong&gt;#23&lt;/strong&gt; [Vanessa Rancour]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crash Test Honey &lt;strong&gt;#100&lt;/strong&gt; [Celia Langabeer]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holly Golightly &lt;strong&gt;#10&lt;/strong&gt; [Holly Brady]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linda ShoveLACE &lt;strong&gt;#76&lt;/strong&gt; [Sal St Clair Brown]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mad Kao &lt;strong&gt;#92&lt;/strong&gt; [Grace Kao]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nikalicious Vicious &lt;strong&gt;#11&lt;/strong&gt; [Nikki Henderson]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pnut Butt Her and Jam &lt;strong&gt;#247&lt;/strong&gt; [Andrea Kelly]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poppy Kneecaps &lt;strong&gt;#0&lt;/strong&gt; [Kirstie Kawana-Waugh]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shepard &lt;strong&gt;#345&lt;/strong&gt; [Abbie Jay]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sledge Hannah &lt;strong&gt;#42c&lt;/strong&gt; [Hannah Creek]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SufferKater [Katie Miles]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRDA&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-6527 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/dddd.png?w=600" alt="DDDD" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.devildogderbydames.com/"&gt;Devil Dog Derby Dames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/#ddddroster"&gt;(roster)&lt;/a&gt; are the second of Okinawa's Roller Derby leagues, founded by the personnel and spouses around the Marine Corps bases on the island. They have been WFTDA members since &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;. They attended the Wild West Showdown in 2015, where they lost narrowly to fellow Open attendees Juneau Rollergirls; a rematch between the two is on the cards here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/16732"&gt;FTS rating&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;506.8&lt;/strong&gt;, DDDD are one of the lower rated teams in the 'A' tier of the competition, although all of the Japanese A-tier leagues have close ratings so contests are hard to predict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Devil Dog Derby Dames' Home team is also competing in the tournament, in the 'B' tier. Lacking a rating, it is hard to predict their performance. They will be taking on similarly unrated Killa Geishas of Misawa, and the JRDA exhibition team "Nippon Senbatsu".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Devil Dogs told us: "This tournament is something that the Devil Dog Derby Dames past and present have been looking forward to for the past 5 years. Okinawa has Derby, we're here to stay and kick some ass!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="ddddroster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;(Mixed roster)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke Garcia&lt;strong&gt; (All-Stars Head Coach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Sapion&lt;strong&gt; (All-Stars Coach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zack Helms&lt;strong&gt; (Home? Head Coach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Purdy&lt;strong&gt; (Home? Coach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MsMURDR &lt;strong&gt;#88&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ohio Skate &lt;strong&gt;#7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Milla Dropabich &lt;strong&gt;#55&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Little Bo Reap &lt;strong&gt;#85&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DodgeHer Dollie &lt;strong&gt;#mc49&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grimm the Reaper &lt;strong&gt;#626&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brutally Scrumptious &lt;strong&gt;#850&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mexicutioner &lt;strong&gt;#9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nucleah Bombshell&lt;strong&gt; #1759&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gnarly Quinn&lt;strong&gt; #13&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honey Badger &lt;strong&gt;#67&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malicious Mare &lt;strong&gt;#509&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dorothy Wail &lt;strong&gt;#205&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kit Killher &lt;strong&gt;#15&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iron Maiden &lt;strong&gt;#323&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sailor Juke'N'er &lt;strong&gt;#777&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rollin' Purdy &lt;strong&gt;#713&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ball Buster &lt;strong&gt;#27&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knuckles Tesla &lt;strong&gt;#1856&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hannabelle Deck'd-her &lt;strong&gt;#33&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rosie the Ripper&lt;strong&gt; #402&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ankle Biter &lt;strong&gt;#256&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flex Luthor &lt;strong&gt;#314&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Referee Craig Nakagawa and Announcer Pete Daigle are also being contributed by DDDD.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRDA&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-6531 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/998254_462707763823646_1955140903_n.jpg" alt="998254_462707763823646_1955140903_n" width="500" height="481"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.copenhagenrollerderby.com/"&gt;Copenhagen Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/#crdroster"&gt;(roster)&lt;/a&gt; are part of the long established and active northern European Roller Derby community, founded in &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;. WFTDA full members since &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, Copenhagen are probably one of the most experienced teams in the competition in terms of "bouts played", thanks to the sheer density of nearby leagues. However, the team has not played outside of Europe, and the long travel may be a test for them. In the last year, CRD have been ramping up their experience, notably defeating Edinburgh's Auld Reekie B by a significant ratio late last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7768"&gt;FTS rating&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;536.5&lt;/strong&gt;, Copenhagen are mid-placed in the A tier of the tournament, but will only face the Japanese leagues in that tier, all of whom have lower ratings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copenhagen's Durakill Bunny had this to say on the team's feelings about their first International engagement. "We are extremely excited to travel to Japan and take part of this tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Japan trip was a Unique opportunity for the CRD A-team to have a very special goal to work towards. Not only in terms of derby skills and preparing for the games, but also in terms of working really hard and closely together on raising funds and organizing the trip. Everyone on the team have contributed to this the way they best could and we really feel that this have made us stronger together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of or skills on the track, we have definately upped our game. In December we had a bootcamp with Juke Boxx from London rollergirls and in February we had a bootcamp with Scald Eagle from Rose City Rollers. Both bootcamps helped us to identify important ares to work with and implement new derby techniques. In February we arranged a scrimmage with a Division 1, team Crime City Rollers which gave us a lot of learnings that we could bring into our training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are all extremely excited to get the chance to travel to Japan as a team and even before we have left Denmark, we feel that this has made us a better and closer team than we have ever been before. Travelling to Japan is without doubt a very exotic experience for all of us and we will all spend time before and after the tournament to explore the country."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="crdroster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Frix Rode &lt;strong&gt;#12 (Captain)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wicked Wawwa &lt;strong&gt;#70  (Co-Captain)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chuckles &lt;strong&gt;(Bench) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dubbi &lt;strong&gt;(Line-Up)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AC Dizzy &lt;strong&gt;#10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saboteur &lt;strong&gt;#119&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yaya Woosh &lt;strong&gt;#19&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mikamikaze &lt;strong&gt;#21&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ragna Rockette &lt;strong&gt;#321&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miss Vojens &lt;strong&gt;#34&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Durakill Bunny &lt;strong&gt;#42&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aevle &lt;strong&gt;#44&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guillotinker &lt;strong&gt;#440&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Juggernaut Jelly &lt;strong&gt;#510&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sofie Bay &lt;strong&gt;#55&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laughing Out Lizzie &lt;strong&gt;#707&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T-Sex &lt;strong&gt;#815&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRDA&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-6534 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/boot-noinc.jpg" alt="boot-noINC" width="270" height="146"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://juneaurollergirls.com/"&gt;Juneau Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/#jrgroster"&gt;(roster)&lt;/a&gt; are the only league in Alaska's capital city. Founded in &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, they joined WFTDA as an Apprentice league in 2013, graduating to full members in &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;. They are one of only two WFTDA ranked teams in Alaska.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's difficult to develop a firm ranking for them, as they are part of the "Alaskan island" of Roller Derby leagues in the state, playing each other far more than they play the rest of the continent. However, their A team did attend Wild West Showdown in February 2015, where they played fellow Japan Open attendees Devil Dog Derby Dames to a close win, despite having only 5 skaters on their roster! (This connection was also the seed for their attendance at the Open, which also serves to provide the team with more games while their home venue is out of commission.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/25021"&gt;FTS rating&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;542.7&lt;/strong&gt;, Juneau are mid-placed in the tournament. They will be playing all three big Japanese leagues - hosts Kokeshi, Tokyo Roller Girls, and Devil Dog Derby Dames - in A-tier bouts that we expect to be pretty close, but which should result in success for the Alaskans according to the stats. Juneau are bringing along only a tiny roster of 6 skaters, however, so their games will be more of an endurance contest than normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Juneau's Captain Just Julie told us: "Preparing to compete in the Japan Open feels like a fairy tale in the making for Juneau Rollergirls... the opportunity to play in this tournament is such an honor for our All-Stars. This is the kind of experience that our derby dreams are made of.
We were so impressed with how the Devil Dog Derby Dames rolled at the Wild West Showdown last year and I can't wait to meet more of Japan's roller derby community. One of the most satisfying aspects of traveling with my team is that in some small way we are coming together to support all the awesome athletes, outstanding officials and visionary volunteers out there who are dedicated to the growth and development of our sport. Seeing how we contribute to something so much bigger than ourselves was an empowering realization for geographically isolated teams like ours. I feel so fortunate to be sharing this experience with my teammates and it will be an honor and a privilege to serve my team as Captain. While some of our league-mates aren't able to make this trip, I know that all the hard work and derby love the league has invested in each other this season will be out there every time the Juneau Rollergirls hit the track. All in! All season!"
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id="jrgroster"&gt;Just Julie &lt;strong&gt;#11 (Captain)&lt;/strong&gt; [Julie Sanbei]&lt;/p&gt;
Shane Kruse &lt;strong&gt;(Bench)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shredlock Holmes &lt;strong&gt;(Bench)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fatty Dook &lt;strong&gt;#2&lt;/strong&gt; [Alicia Gillis]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catapult Kim &lt;strong&gt;#3&lt;/strong&gt; [Kim Glasow]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skatie Brite &lt;strong&gt;#22&lt;/strong&gt; [Katie White]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titan Young &lt;strong&gt;#25&lt;/strong&gt; [Stephanie Kruse]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hevee Mettle &lt;strong&gt;#71&lt;/strong&gt; [Evelyn Widmyer]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;JRDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6537" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/11112871_1077336432280149_1749476875903629144_n.jpg?w=600" alt="11112871_1077336432280149_1749476875903629144_n" width="300" height="300"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TokyoRollerGirls/"&gt;Tokyo Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/#trgroster"&gt;(roster)&lt;/a&gt; are mainland Japan's first Roller Derby league, dating from &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;. The league now incorporates the teams in Yokota and Zama, as well as its founding location in Yokosuka. Although founded by American services personnel and spouses, TRG have actively promoted and recruited in the Japanese population as well, and nowadays have good recruitment outside Americans - and two additional teams in Tokyo and Yokohama which are primarily Japanese nationals, one of which is Co-ed. TRG members were also instrumental in the creation and selection, under the "Women's Roller Derby Japan" and "Men's Roller Derby Japan" organisations, Team Japan and Ninjapan Rollers which attended the 2014 B&amp;amp;T Roller Derby World Cup and Men's Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/20991"&gt;FTS rating&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;503.4&lt;/strong&gt;, TRG are fairly low-ranked in the A tier of the tournament. They lost to hosts Kokeshi Roller Dolls the last time they encountered one another, as well as to other Okinawan league Devil Dog Derby Dames. In this tournament, TRG will be looking to show that they can succeed in their scheduled bouts, playing Copenhagen, Juneau and Adelaide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tokyo's Captain, Nactmerrie, explained their feelings about the Open. "In order for us to continue being a part of WFTDA, there is a requirement to play other WFTDA teams yearly, which can be difficult. We were so excited when we were invited to the tournament, since we will get to play different teams from all over the world! Most of our girls are from America and are either in the military or a military spouse, but we would love more Japanese skaters! For the upcoming tournament, we have been practicing often and scrimmaging against our men's team; which has been a huge help. We are mostly excited to play teams we have never played before and are hoping to raise our rank as well."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="trgroster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Nachtmerrie&lt;strong&gt; #86 (Captain)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Postlewaight&lt;strong&gt; #783 (Alternate)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Femmebot&lt;strong&gt; (Head Coach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pork Chop&lt;strong&gt; (Bench)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hung Low&lt;strong&gt; (Bench)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SorryNotSorry&lt;strong&gt; #110&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scary Thunderwood&lt;strong&gt; #1107&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bash &lt;strong&gt;#242&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low Down Derby Shame &lt;strong&gt;#4864&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomahawk Pixie &lt;strong&gt;#5280&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bean Town Beat Down &lt;strong&gt;#66&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terrin Skirtz &lt;strong&gt;#75&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ShortStack O'Paincakes &lt;strong&gt;#777&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laced Revenge &lt;strong&gt;#84&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USS DestroyHer &lt;strong&gt;#89&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thunder BELL &lt;strong&gt;#950&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRDA&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-6540 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/misawa.png" alt="misawa" width="200" height="201"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/12/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/killarollerderby"&gt;Killa Geishas of Misawa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/#mkgroster"&gt;(roster)&lt;/a&gt; are one of the smaller Japanese Roller Derby leagues based around US military bases (in this case, Misawa, at the very north end of Honshu). Founded in &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, the league has survived multiple venue issues over its 4 year life, and also spawned a men's team, the Misawa Rollin' Tanukis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With no WFTDA &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/52313"&gt;FTS rating&lt;/a&gt; (and a high uncertainty surrounding their evaluation in the Pacific region (there's only a single bout in the FlatTrackStats database for them, from 2014!)), it's very difficult to say how RGM will do in the tournament. As a smaller league, KGM are competing in the B tier of the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KGM's SINnamon Challenge told us: 'The Misawa Killa Geishas have had to fight tooth and nail to keep derby alive in the remote North. Our team has fought nonstop for 4 years practicing in changing venues and hospitable weather conditions, which has made us stronger as a team. The chance to play teams from New Zealand and throughout Japan is a chance for us to show others just how much fight we have in us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Blood, sweat, and tears,” only begins to describe the training the Misawa Killa Geishas have gone through in the many months leading up to Japan’s first big tournament. We’ve included personal goals, team goals, and one of the most important training aspects, team bonding. When we arrive to the Japan Open Roller Derby Tournament, we will show up prepared mentally, physically, and with a strong sisterhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We upped our scrimmages in preparation for the tournament. Every week we did our best to go up against our own teammates at their best. We learned, struggled, and conquered. After months of preparation we are heading to Japan Open Roller Derby Tournament tested, vetted, bruised, healed, and READY!!!'
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id="mkgroster"&gt;Pinche Loca&lt;strong&gt; #DD5 (Bench)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Nique Havoc &lt;strong&gt;#4&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Bench)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yellow Slamarine &lt;strong&gt;#4077 (Bench)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cimo D. Stroyin &lt;strong&gt;#11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SINnamon Challenge &lt;strong&gt;#38&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peach Bomb &lt;strong&gt;#800&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lola Bunny &lt;strong&gt;#15&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godjilla &lt;strong&gt;#325&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fenix Fire &lt;strong&gt;#602&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honey Basher&lt;strong&gt; #5309&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campbell Swoop &lt;strong&gt;#23&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ice Bloxx &lt;strong&gt;#906&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fay Tall O'Traction &lt;strong&gt;#1102&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweet D'Seat &lt;strong&gt;#h8r&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRDA&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-6543 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/kokeshi_rollers_300.png" alt="kokeshi_rollers_300" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kokeshirollerdolls.com/"&gt;Kokeshi Roller Dolls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/#krdroster"&gt;(roster)&lt;/a&gt; were the first roller derby league to be founded in Okinawa, dating from 2010. As with other Japanese leagues, they were created by American nationals in the military bases there. They are the hosts of the Japan Open, having previously played in 2014's Big O tournament&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/8126"&gt;FTS rating&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;518.2&lt;/strong&gt;, KRD are slightly stronger than the other Japanese leagues attending. We can expect close bouts against their select opponents across the tournament; as hosts, Kokeshi will want to put on a showing for the visitors to Okinawa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to Kokeshi's Cherry about the league, and the tournament. "After only 6 months of becoming a league, we were on the fast track to applying for a WFTDA Apprenticeship, with support from Rat City Rollergirls. Kokeshi leadership had big goals, and hosting a Far East Roller Derby Tournament was one of the future league goals in the application. We became a full WFTDA Member League in 2013, and [The Japanese Roller Derby Association] JRDA approached us in the fall of 2014.
We had a local, large venue and experience in bout production and outreach among local and international leagues. Having a primary Japanese sponsor support the tournament definitely helped get us moving. KRD is hosting and managing the tournament for skaters, officials and fans in cooperation with JRDA who work directly with Okinawa’s public organizations, media, and sponsors in Japanese.
JRDA's agenda is to find Japanese nationals to be a part of their organization and play in the 2017 Roller Games. Our [KRD] mission is to host an international tournament, bringing together leagues in the Pacific to play WFTDA sanctioned bouts and build camaraderie and partnerships among leagues and support officials, while promoting roller derby in the community.
We definitely have plans for future international tournaments, however, when the next one will be set and who the primary sponsor will be is yet to be determined. We have learned a lot about steps we need for success and what has held us back during the planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are planning for dual announcing, but a Japanese roller derby announcer is a hard billet to fill."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="krdroster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Shisa Beast &lt;strong&gt;#241 (Co-Captain)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sprocket2ya &lt;strong&gt;#77 (Co-Captain)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cherry&lt;strong&gt; (Coach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sir G. O.&lt;strong&gt; (Bench)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puncher &lt;strong&gt;(Asst. Coach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Courtney Loveless &lt;strong&gt;#O0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R.I.P..TIDE&lt;strong&gt; #O4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whipping Willow&lt;strong&gt; #1013&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moxxi&lt;strong&gt; #12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warden O'Neill &lt;strong&gt;#182&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rogue Wave &lt;strong&gt;#2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunny Daze&lt;strong&gt; #297&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beat Her Up Scotty &lt;strong&gt;#394&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psycho Anna Lies &lt;strong&gt;#5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamo-Cidal Mel &lt;strong&gt;#50&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lil N. Gin &lt;strong&gt;#9&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRDA&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-6677 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/japanrda.jpg" alt="JapanRDA" width="225" height="225"&gt;
The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.jrda.jp/"&gt;Japan Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/#jrdaroster"&gt;(roster)&lt;/a&gt; is a sponsor of the Japan Open.
It's unclear what the JRDA's involvement in Japanese Roller Derby as a whole is - none of the WFTDA-rules leagues in Japan are affiliates, and it was also not involved in the creation of the Japanese National Teams - although the JRDA website does announce that they are intending to attend the FIRS/USARS 2017 RollerGames festival, and they are raising funds for a "Roller Derby School". The JRDA is an affiliate of the Japan Roller Sports Federation and, through that, of FIRS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as providing  Japanese language support, interfacing with the Japanese companies and entities involved in the hosting and sponsorship of the tournament and organising the livestreams, JRDA are submitting a team ("Nippon Senbatsu" - roughly, "Japan's Selection" - the natural way to describe a national team in Japanese) to the event. We know essentially nothing about this team at all, as they are apparently debuting at the Open. Nippon Senbatsu will be competing in the B tier of the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="jrdaroster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Zu-Ca &lt;strong&gt;#8 (Captain) (Coach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YONE &lt;strong&gt;#0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chocolat &lt;strong&gt;#3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nico&lt;strong&gt; #6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HoneyBee&lt;strong&gt; #7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HALCA&lt;strong&gt; #9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;strong&gt;#11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ChicoRock&lt;strong&gt; #15&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MASA&lt;strong&gt; #29&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ZOOMIN &lt;strong&gt;#69&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BISHAMONTEN MIHO &lt;strong&gt;#555&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoomBoom!! &lt;strong&gt;#88 (Manager)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Min &lt;strong&gt;(Alternate)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>adelaide roller derby</category><category>articles</category><category>copenhagen roller derby</category><category>devil dog derby dames</category><category>in the news</category><category>interviews</category><category>japan</category><category>jrda</category><category>killa geishas of misawa</category><category>kokeshi roller dolls</category><category>pirate city rollers</category><category>tokyo roller girls</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 11:15:20 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>