<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about international)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/international.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 08:59:24 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Derby Stance 2018: Rule56's Coaching Summit returns, now International!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/31/derby-stance-2018-rule56s-coaching-summit-returns-now-international/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, we &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/03/uks-first-coaching-summit-derby-stance/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reported&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the first Derby Stance event: the UK's first ever "Coaching Summit", organised by North of England based coaching team Rule 56. Over a weekend of sessions from speakers across the UK (and one from the USA), the Roller Derby coaching community didn't just learn from each other, but also built some strong bridges and enthusiasm for pushing Coaching further in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the year and a bit since that big launch, Rule 56 have been continuing to &lt;a href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/happenings/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;develop coaching resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. With the aid of teleconferencing technology, they successfully provided a very effective short series of coaching webinars with Strong Athletic's Smarty Pants (as we &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/01/rule-56-now-coming-online-on-monday-6th/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reported&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/16/uk-coaching-rule-56-webinars-and-more/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;on&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; too), with attendees from across Europe and the Americas. They've also been running physical bootcamp sessions for skaters, like the upcoming "bite-sized" bootcamp on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1751163414965701/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working in Walls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on August 11th...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, whilst there was a second &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1979086938976164/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby Stance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; summit in February (taking advantage of the Roller Derby World Cup the weekend before to bring all those international skaters to one place), organising truly large-scale international coaching events has always been difficult, especially with our grass-roots amateur sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now! This winter, Rule56 are bringing together all the things they've learnt to make the &lt;em&gt;third&lt;/em&gt; Derby Stance a simultaneously larger, more international... and more &lt;em&gt;accessible&lt;/em&gt; event - by moving it entirely online!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-27125 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/derbystance2018.png" alt="derbystance2018" width="828" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby Stance Online&lt;/strong&gt; will be a 4 day virtual event, running from &lt;strong&gt;29 November&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;2 December&lt;/strong&gt; this year. Just like a physical event, there will be many different sessions to sign up with, grouped into 5 themes:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Just Start Coaching [5 sessions]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Strategic Coaching [4 sessions]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Mental Performance [5 sessions]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Game Day [3 sessions]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Juniors [3 sessions]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
as well as introductory and closing sessions, and a special session led by WFTDA's Beat-her Bones, representing WFTDA Education.
&lt;p&gt;Each of the 23 sessions will be available as a separate webinar, and can be signed up for (and paid for) independently of any others; of course, you can also sign up for the entire summit, as if it were a "physical" meeting as well, if you want. The flexibility of being able to pick and choose just the sessions you want, however, is a big advantage of the online-only format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with other webinars, the entire session will also be available to rewatch after the fact - so, even if your timezone makes it hard to attend the session live (or if you want to review a session later), you can still access all that coaching expertise, at your own convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other advantage of the online-only format is that it's immensely easier to pull together expert speakers and session leaders from across the entire globe. Rule 56 has managed to collect 14 of the best coaches in Roller Derby, and beyond, to contribute sessions to this event:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-27123 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/rule56__map-e1532701421288.png" alt="RULE56__map" width="1920" height="850"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smarty Pants&lt;/strong&gt; (Strong Athletic), &lt;strong&gt;Vivien Leigh-thal&lt;/strong&gt; (Rainy City Roller Derby), &lt;strong&gt;Booty Quake&lt;/strong&gt; (Roller Derby Athletics), &lt;strong&gt;Maurine Filip&lt;/strong&gt; (Stockholm Roller Derby), &lt;strong&gt;Rosie Peacock&lt;/strong&gt; (Glasgow Men's Roller Derby, Team Scotland Coach 2018), &lt;strong&gt;Devoida Mercy&lt;/strong&gt; (Philly Roller Derby), &lt;strong&gt;Maha El Nasser&lt;/strong&gt; (Rule 56), &lt;strong&gt;Papa Whisky&lt;/strong&gt; (Boulder County Bombers), &lt;strong&gt;Jess Paternostro&lt;/strong&gt; (Team Canada Roller Derby), &lt;strong&gt;Furrrocious&lt;/strong&gt; (Amsterdam Roller Derby)
&lt;strong&gt;Ballistic Whistle&lt;/strong&gt; (Southern Discomfort), &lt;strong&gt;Louise Capicotto&lt;/strong&gt; (Sport Psychology Consultant), &lt;strong&gt;Luludemon&lt;/strong&gt; (Terminal City Rollergirls), and &lt;strong&gt;Treblemaker 909&lt;/strong&gt; (Central City Roller Derby) are each contributing at least one session to the schedule (and some up to three).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can reserve tickets - for individual webinars, or the whole event - (and learn more about the summit) at the official website here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/derby-stance-online"&gt;http://www.rulefiftysix.com/derby-stance-online &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;from&lt;strong&gt; August 1st.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coaching</category><category>derby stance</category><category>international</category><category>rule56</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/31/derby-stance-2018-rule56s-coaching-summit-returns-now-international/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 08:32:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chilean National Championships 2018 - Torneo X returns!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/26/chilean-national-championships-2018-torneo-x-returns/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chile's National Tournament, the mysteriously named &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TorneoX/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Torneo X&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, has been running for as long, or longer, than many of the better-known European tournaments, having begun in 2015. (The Men's Derby equivalent in Chile, Torneo X-MEN, started 2 years later.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the 4th event coming up at the start of next month, we're giving you a quick overview of the tournament and the players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Chile is a long, thin, country, as the tournament has expanded, it has done so mostly north/south, following the areas of highest population density. A bit like Scotland, Chile has a band of high population (in this case, roughly in the middle of the country), surrounded by low density rural areas to the north and south. Torneo X 2018 fills this entire high density area, for the first time in its history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26980 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/torneox_map.gif" alt="TorneoX_map" width="600" height="568"&gt; Torneo X's growth over time since inception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, Chillán's Chillanrolleras retained the title from the previous year, maintaining an unbroken streak since they joined the tournament. However, Viña del Mar's Tacones Bandidos pushed them until the very last bouts for that title, so a repeat performance in 2018 is definitely not assured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is especially true as, with 2018's tournament growing to become the biggest yet, there are even more challengers for the cup. Especially likely to want to make a big splash are Santiago's Metropolitan Roller Derby, the only WFTDA-member league in the tournament, although it's their B-team, the Bayonetas, who are competing here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Torneo X 2018 will consist of 4 fixtures across the coming months, spread across the competing regions:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1st&lt;/strong&gt; Fixture: Osorno (Deskarriadas) &lt;strong&gt;4-5 August [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/212354766088268/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2nd&lt;/strong&gt; Fixture: Santiago (Adrenaline) &lt;strong&gt;8-9 September&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd&lt;/strong&gt; Fixture: Viña del Mar (Tacones Bandidos) &lt;strong&gt;6-7 October&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final&lt;/strong&gt; Puerto Montt (Diosas Volcanicas) &lt;strong&gt;9-10 November&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-26981" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/torneox_map.png?w=602" alt="TorneoX_map" width="602" height="1024"&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The historical rankings for the previous editions of the tournament are: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rank&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2015&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nativas RD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chillanrolleras&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chillanrolleras&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deskarriadas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deskarriadas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tacones Bandidos&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Diosas Volcanicas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nativas RD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Diosas Volcanicas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Diosas Volcanicas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deskarriadas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A Sangre Fría RD (Osorno)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adrenaline&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;RD Valdivia / Cuello Negro [as "Indomitas" 2018]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chillanrolleras Derby Club&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chíllan's premier team, and twice winners of the Torneo X, Chillanrolleras were bouting as early as 2013, although we have a gap in our records in 2015. From 2016, they've hosted multiple tournaments - including fixtures for the 2017 Torneo X itself - and have rarely lost a bout. SRDRank's current (unpublished) rating places them as the favourites to win the Torneo X title, and maintain their streak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chillanrolleras, as with many teams in Chile, have a brother league - Chillanrolleros - who share resources with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tacones Bandidos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tacones Bandidos are based in the coastal region of Vińa del Mar, Valparaíso. In their current form, they date from 2014, as a partnership with men's team, Bototos Bandidos.
The Tacones have had a pretty busy year to date - playing not just Chilean teams, but also Buenos Aires' Sailor City Rollers B, who they fought to a near-draw within the last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd rate the Tacones as likely to strongly contest the second place with the tournament newcomers from Santiago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diosas Volcánicas Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puerto Montt &amp;amp; Puerto Varas's Diosas Volcánicas are one of the older teams in Chile, dating back to 2012, founded by Dahmenatrix from San Diego Derby Dolls. They're one of the most southerly teams in Roller Derby (and certainly in Latin America), with only a few teams in southern Argentina and New Zealand much more to the south.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They've had a difficult time finding practice space, and have had periods where most training was outside (in one of the wetter regions of Chile!). This year, they've finally achieved stable training space - in a local prison gym! - and have been working on recruitment and training more intensively since then.
Their aim for 2018 is to qualify for the finals (in the top 4 of the table)... and then who knows how high in 2019?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deskarriadas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deskarriadas are the largest team in Osorno, founded in May 2014. They're the hosts of the first fixture of this year's Torneo X, in the first weekend in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Deskarriadas have been working towards the Torneo X all year, aiming to improve on their performance last year (where they placed 4th). In the first two years, they managed 2nd place, which is, we assume, their target for 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adrenaline Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adrenaline Roller Derby, one of two Santiago-based teams in the tournament, are the youngest contestants, founded in 2016. This relative youth has counted against them in ratings, and we'd consider them likely to be contesting in the same position as last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As hosts of the second fixtures in the tournament, home team advantage may well help them to beat expectations, in a fairly close lower half of the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indomitas RD Valdivia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby Valdivia consists of two member teams - the men's team, Indomitos, and the women's team, which used to be called Cuello Negro ("Black Swans"), but rebranded to Indomitas this year, whilst keeping the same logo. This rebrand was triggered by a complete rebuilding of the team, with the new "Indomitas" very different to the old 2015-2017 Cuello Negro in terms of skaters.
The Indomitas told us that they have spent the past year in intensive drilling, so that all their tactics are instinctive. They are prepared to demonstrate the heart, tenacity and perseverance that they can bring to the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nativas Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Temuco's first team, the Nativas date back to 2013. As with many of the teams here, they have "womens" and "mens" teams - although we can't find a name for the women's team except "Nativas Roller Derby". As one of the oldest teams in Chile, the Nativas competed in the first ever Torneo X, although they skipped the 2017 edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to a sparsity of bout data for the Nativas in FTS, we consider the returning team to be something of a wild card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metropolitan Roller Derby B, Bayonetas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santiago's Metropolitan Roller Derby are the only Chilean members of the WFTDA, with their travel team currently ranked at 122 (May 31 ranking release) by WFTDA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their B-team, the Bayonetas, have existed since 2014, and are one of the few teams in this tournament to have played extensively internationally - at least within South America. Out of the Chilean leagues, they've played nearby Valparaíso's Tacones Bandidos most often, with wildly different results - beating them 2 to 1 early in 2017, and losing by a similar ratio by the end of that year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>chile</category><category>international</category><category>international derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>torneo x</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments2018</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/26/chilean-national-championships-2018-torneo-x-returns/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 12:07:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Roller Derby comes to Kyoto! ローラーダービーが京都に来る。</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/12/roller-derby-comes-to-kyoto-roradabigajing-du-nilai-ru/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here at SRD, we always like to see Roller Derby expanding into new places; especially places where there's been no roller derby before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst Roller Derby has been in Japan (in Okinawa and Tokyo, and, until this year, Misawa), there's been little growth outside of those regions. (Tokyo Roller Derby have expanded to contain teams based in the surrounding cities, such as Yokohama, but not outside the Kantō region; the most recent independent team, Kamikaze Badass, is also based in Tokyo.) So, it was particularly exciting to see the announcement this year of a new league, based in Kyōto, in the Kansai region!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught up with Kyoto Roller Derby's founders, Kat and Josie, to find out a bit more about them, and what inspired them to seed more roller derby in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26824 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/kyotord.jpg" alt="KyotoRD" width="621" height="480"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's been a while since the last Roller Derby league was founded in Japan. Can you tell us a bit about yourselves as founders? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Kat: I skated with Bath Roller Derby Girls in the U.K. and I absolutely loved it! The team was in its early stages back then and it was so nice to be a part of something at the ground level. After moving to Japan and being really far away from any teams here, I kept writing messages of desperation on Facebook forums hoping to pique some interest. Eventually someone replied! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Josie: That would be me! I had been living in Japan for two years, teaching English and loving life up in the mountains, but every day I was still pining for the outlet that is derby. I messaged Kat having seen a plea of hers, and was thrilled to meet another skater out here. At the time we lived a few hours apart, so it wasn’t easy to meet up. But quickly we realised that a derby team was needed in the Kansai area. I began skating first at drop-in sessions with Bristol back in 2012, then for Severn Roller Torrent in Gloucester. I skated with SRT for two years, before moving to Japan in 2015. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The moment we met we couldn’t help reminiscing about all the things that derby meant to us. It’s such an important space and community that we felt could really bring a lot to Kyoto. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All but two Roller Derby leagues in Japan were founded by non-Japanese skaters; how are you reaching out to the people of Kyoto to grow the league? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Josie: We’ve been fortunate enough to work with and become friends with some amazing people out here, and we are really keen for all of our practices, future events and bouts to be a community thing. We are committed to using Japanese and English in all of our communications on social media and really strive to be as inclusive as possible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Kat: This is definitely really important to both of us, and we want to encourage as many new Japanese members to join us as possible. I recently watched the animation Aggretsuko, and couldn’t ignore the parallels between that and derby as a form of stress release. The show is about an awesome red panda who works in a sh&lt;em&gt;tty office, full of sh&lt;/em&gt;tty male bosses who talk down to her all day, and although she is sweet during working hours, at night she blasts out thrash metal karaoke to release her stress. I basically feel like derby could be this for so many of my friends! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kamikaze Badass Roller Derby Tokyo found that one issue they've had is with the conflation of Roller Game and Roller Derby in the minds of potential recruits. In the short time you've been in existence, have you identified any specific issues to deal with?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Often staff at venues have a negative view of it and think it’s going to be too dangerous, because of the associations with Roller Game.  Also a lot of younger people see roller skating as very dated, and don’t consider it as a sport for the modern age. We’ve reached out to a lot of leagues for help and guidance on this type of thing, as we are aiming to be as transparent and respectful as possible, whilst also smashing any preconceptions, as respectfully as possible of course.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting a league off the ground also needs resources as well as people power. How can the Community help Kyoto Roller Derby - and how are you planning to grow your resources? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We’ve actually just announced our first fundraiser at our local Japanese-run burrito joint, where we’ll be selling baked goods and our first official merch &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;[&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/162229187965089/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;see here for this event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;. Ideally we hope to hold a number of fundraisers throughout the year in order to spread the word and purchase essential kit for our fresh meat team. We’ve also been in touch with the wonderful Derby Without Borders &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;[&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/05/derby-without-borders-an-interview-with-founder-mae-dae/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;see our interview here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; who provide second hand kits for up and coming leagues across the globe, and that was after a tip from you, and from another within the Tokyo derby community. Worldwide derby spirit is definitely already pushing us in the right direction and we are so grateful, so we hope that as many people as possible will want to help us get going. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where do you see Kyoto Roller Derby in the future? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We want to see Kyoto Roller Derby as an active league in Japan, visiting teams around the country as well as worldwide! We want to have a really positive influence within the local community, with as many people as possible coming to watch our games, and feeling encouraged and empowered to get involved. Roller derby has had such an incredible impact on both of our lives and we can’t wait to watch it grow in Kyoto.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about Kyoto Roller Derby, and support them, on their social media platforms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/kyotorollerderbyjapan"&gt;www.facebook.com/kyotorollerderbyjapan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Instagram: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.instagram.com/kyotorollerderbyjapan"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;www.instagram.com/kyotorollerderby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;You can also email them at:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; &lt;a href="mailto:kyotorollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;kyotorollerderby@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;And support them via GoFundMe here:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.gofundme.com/kyotorollerderby"&gt;www.gofundme.com/kyotorollerderby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>international</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>japan</category><category>kyoto roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/12/roller-derby-comes-to-kyoto-roradabigajing-du-nilai-ru/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 18:39:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Vanishing History of Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Whilst we've been concerned by archiving the history of roller derby for several years, this particular article was inspired by the following threads on twitter: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thederbyapex/status/971562257518821376"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://twitter.com/thederbyapex/status/971562257518821376&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Nicktroptopolis/status/971840386011410432"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://twitter.com/Nicktroptopolis/status/971840386011410432&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern Roller Derby is a product of, and inescapably shaped by, the Internet, as is much of culture produced since the mid-1990s. Whilst this has positive effects, it also can have profoundly negative ones, especially regarding the transient and ephemeral nature of our cultural records and history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of time, records have been made with physical marks (scratches in clay, ink on paper, papyrus or animal skin, and so on; or even the physical structure of vinyl records or CDs), and mostly permanently. Secret physical records are kept secret by locking them in a safe, rarely by encrypting or enciphering them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As information technology became more prevalent, over the 20th century, and predominant over the early 21st, more and more of our records - which are our history for future generations (or even ourselves a few years later) - have no physical, human-readable representation. Documents, and photos, and forum posts, are patterns of bytes on a server which we often don't even own, or have direct access to. &lt;em&gt;Secret&lt;/em&gt; documents are encrypted patterns of bytes on a server we don't own, and are completely unreadable if the key to decrypt them is lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, it is now much harder to maintain a historical record of the recent past - the recent culture - than it was even two decades ago. This worrying phenomenon is sometimes referred to as a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_dark_age"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Dark Age&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; , and we should be more concerned about it than we are. In previous periods, some level of archiving and historical preservation happened "for free" - if you don't deliberately destroy a piece of paper, it will last a fairly long time. In the modern period, records from that old forum your league had before you updated are &lt;em&gt;gone forever&lt;/em&gt; unless you deliberately copied them and saved them elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby's entire modern culture is stored mostly on electronic documents - there are very few physical artefacts, outside of bout programmes, to cover the history of the sport. (It's also important to preserve those physical artefacts - and projects like the UK-based &lt;a href="http://nmrd.org.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Museum of Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are working on that.)
We currently have volunteer-run operations preserving some statistical records, for example, &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an open repository of all the bout scores, and bout stats, uploaded to it, and this is a &lt;em&gt;more important&lt;/em&gt; social and cultural role than the ratings and rankings it produces for subsets of those stats. However, these are both volunteer-run, and patchy in their coverage: for various reasons&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/#footnotes"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, much of Latin America ignores FTS and does not upload their records there, so we don't even have a good historical record for &lt;em&gt;games&lt;/em&gt; in Latin America (Mexico maintains its own website for game results, which does not sync with FTS, for some reason).
Similarly, &lt;a href="http://derbylisting.com/word/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derbylisting.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; attempts to record the status of leagues across the world, but is also very much dependant on engagement by leagues and the community itself. (And it's not clear to us how well it records historical changes.) There are also several other sites which have tried/are trying to do a similar thing - &lt;a href="https://derbyposition.com/en/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;derbyposition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, for example, and fragmentation of effort here makes things much harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/2/"&gt;In the next page, we'll talk about the harder problem of recording our shared cultural heritage - the stories of Roller Derby.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="footnotes"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;*The most important reasons being lack of volunteer effort in some regions, because:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;FTS still talks about, and displays, mostly WFTDA branding on itself, even though it takes records from all flat-track derby, not just WFTDA-member, or even WFTDA-rules, leagues (the MRDA branding, which it also has, is not visible on the front page - and &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; WFTDA is actually mentioned in the site's description of itself). Several leagues we've talked to in the past were under the impression that they simply couldn't use FTS if they weren't WFTDA members, or if they were, they couldn't use it for anything but their A teams.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;FTS doesn't have a rating or ranking scheme for Latin America. FTS's popularity in Europe is driven by (ironically, in contrast to the above) the fact that it provides a ranking and rating for all European teams, regardless of their WFTDA membership or if they're an A or B (or even C) team. This is the carrot part of the FTS system, and it simply doesn't exist (officially) for Latin America.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
 Strictly, it does, as &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SRDRank&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a rating and ranking system for the entire world, using FTS's records; but we're not anywhere near as visible as FTS, and we are acutely aware that the SRDRank site needs updates after resources devoted to it were diverted to the Roller Derby World Cup for several months. Lack of resources is a problem everywhere, sadly.
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Recording Culture and Stories&lt;/h3&gt;
Statistics are easy to record.The situation for more complex cultural records - forum posts, discussion threads, the entire contents of online magazines or journals - is both more subtle, and also more difficult to resolve. Members of the Roller Derby community who joined post-2014 may not even recognise the name "DNN" -&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.derbynews.net/"&gt;Derby News Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, but that titan of Roller Derby reporting and bout streaming was a central part of the Roller Derby community for the seven whole years - almost two fifths of the entire time Roller Derby has existed - before it died. We're extremely &lt;em&gt;lucky&lt;/em&gt; that the owners, and community, came together to keep the servers holding the site running - albeit with reduced resources - and to archive its valuable historical records. Because of this effort, we can still, for example, look back at &lt;a href="http://www.derbynews.net/2008/09/09/5_texas_stops_9_detroit_83_46/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;how Texas fared against Detroit back in 2008&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (and their rosters at the time!).
&lt;p&gt;For public sites, there is at least the hope that you can pretend it's someone else's problem - the &lt;a href="https://archive.org/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; exists explicitly to combat the loss of history due to the ephemeral nature of websites by trawling the web and taking archival, historical snapshots of sites it can access. This isn't perfect: the Archive can't check every site every day - or even every site every year; and it tries to focus on the websites with the most interest and links, as they're likely to be the most important. But it does give a certain minimum insurance against total loss - something, albeit possibly a tiny fragment, will possibly survive, even if you don't care to take precautions yourself.
When the next site with a huge chunk of Roller Derby culture dies - and &lt;a href="https://indieweb.org/site-deaths"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sites die all the time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - we may not be so lucky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're taking some steps to combat this, starting with a small thing today: we're working on an archive, to be public, of Roller Derby collective culture - the stories that make up the history of the sport from 2001 onwards - collected from the community itself. You can submit your stories to our Google forms - we have &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeFg0uCe1GrSUdv-2VrRU4Sczv_NhIygRZg3UwjjM-AxvIJKQ/viewform?usp=sf_link"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;one version in English&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeRppNu4hkwlRzofmcD_stFmuYzgM9-ZNW1jK_GWulDzPgagA/viewform?usp=sf_link"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;one in Spanish&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for more accessibility - in any language you want, and about any event in roller derby you can relate. (We're especially interested in making sure we get stories from the early days of the sport before they are lost, and from regions and leagues who aren't often covered... but all stories are welcome.)
In the near future, we'll be talking about how we'll make this archive available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/3/"&gt;In the next page, we'll talk about the issues recording the history of Roller Derby's governance.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Recording Our Sport's Governance &amp;amp; Transparency&lt;/h3&gt;
Much of the existing Roller Derby cultural history isn't even public - it's in private silos across the internet. The majority of governing bodies in Roller Derby maintain almost entirely private spaces, as do the majority of leagues. (Even when those spaces are not private, the use of restrictive copyright may also inhibit preservation - as several digital archiving projects have discovered; this is another reason why using better, more open licenses - &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or otherwise - enriches the community.)
We can trust that WFTDA, or MRDA, say, keeps a full and complete backup of all of their forum discussions. But we &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to trust, because we have no way to have an independent record of any of that contents - both because of technological walls (the forums are private, password-protected spaces), and legal ones (the WFTDA, etc, NDAs prevent public disclosure of those contents by anyone who does have access to them).
This is not to pick on WFTDA alone, as we're hopeful is clear - all Roller Derby governing bodies have this problem to various extents, even when they've committed to more open and transparent communication. For example, UKRDA has made some positive steps towards this - making minutes of Board Meetings &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1387CqPTaHx_dp1JAgoxSrHlnrbC45aBj"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;public&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - and have shown interest in working towards further transparency, but they're still working &lt;em&gt;towards&lt;/em&gt; them.
&lt;p&gt;We should note that problems of transparency have dogged many Sports Governing Bodies in the last few years - and &lt;a href="http://www.playthegame.org/news/comments/2016/034_the-rules-of-the-game-the-need-for-transparency-in-sports-governance/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;there are calls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a href="http://www.playthegame.org/knowledge-bank/downloads/sports-governance-observer-2015/c14e0343-6716-42b5-9aa0-a6c700daeb48"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reports&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) from those in the wider sports governance community for all SGBs to become as transparent as other democracies already are. WFTDA&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/#footnotes2"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; does do better than a great many SGBs; but some SGBs are particularly opaque (FIFA comes to mind).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transparency is sometimes hard, but it doesn't have to be this way. The British Government, which has not been an exemplar for good transparency over most of its existence, still manages to publish and archive a &lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;completely public record&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of all debates in Parliament&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/#footnotes3"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, since around 1800. This &lt;em&gt;Hansard&lt;/em&gt; system is also used by many other democracies across the World - New Zealand, Canada, Australia, South Africa, Singapore - and other similar systems are used by, for example, the &lt;a href="https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;United States of America &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;(in fact, the Constitution of the USA &lt;em&gt;requires&lt;/em&gt; that Congress keep such public records), and the &lt;a href="http://www.europarl.europa.eu/plenary/en/home.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;European Parliament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
In all of these cases, these records required a lot of effort to generate - they're hand-stenotyped transcriptions of verbal debates, with post-editing for readability and references - but because they exist, we know much more about the history of those institutions, their culture, and how this changed over time. (And because they're almost all public, copyright-free records, other copies can be made of them, so the risk of them being lost to the world is negligible.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, almost all of the debate in Roller Derby happens online, in text conversations on forums and chat rooms. Making available an "MRDA Hansard", or a "WFTDA Congressional Record" is almost trivial - the data already exists in written form, it just needs to be published somewhere, and with the correct level of access for the community. (We'd argue that if national governments can manage to make their debates Public to the World, it shouldn't be a big deal for any Governing Body of a sport whose founding ethic is "For The Skater, By The Skater").&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is obviously a trade-off here between transparency and the right to privacy. All organisations need private spaces - for grievance committees, embargoed information from other sources, and so on - but they need much fewer private spaces than they often create for themselves. Organisations also need to protect the rights of individuals to privacy of personal information - for example, any organisation in Europe needs to comply with the &lt;a href="https://www.eugdpr.org/gdpr-faqs.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GDPR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on this topic - and this will require some secrecy in some areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also important to note that just because a space is publicly accessible does not mean that it has to be open to public's input - only Members of Parliament may speak in the British House of Commons, but the entire world can see (and hear, nowadays) what they say. In the case of roller derby, Derbylisting.com records around &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1800&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; leagues playing under WFTDA/MRDA rules - even though the majority are not members of either organisation, they do have some moral rights to know what the community has coming for it, in return for the legitimacy they lend the organisations merely by adopting those rules. (Transparency can also be a good way to engage your community in the present, as well as allowing your record to be preserved in the past!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With more of our history and community in the public domain (both visible, and licensed to distribute more rights), maintaining our history becomes a shared possibility for the entire roller derby community.
We at the Scottish Roller Derby blog are also looking a hosting some smaller-scale public resources to help encourage transparency and community - we'll be writing more about the technology side of this in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="footnotes3"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;*The British Government also, since 2000/2002 commits to making a lot more of its internal documents and records available to the public of the world, via the Freedom of Information Acts (&lt;a href="https://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/2000/36/contents"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2000&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - England &amp;amp; Wales, &lt;a href="http://www.legislation.gov.uk/asp/2002/13/contents"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - Scotland), after consultation started in 1997 ("&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/your-right-to-know-the-governments-proposals-for-a-freedom-of-information-act"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Right To Know&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;"). Many other governments have committed to similar levels of free access to the public - not just their own citizens, but the world; Sweden may hold the record for first raising this issue in 1766!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="footnotes2"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;**WFTDA deserves credit, for example, for the amount of material it does publish, when out of NDA, on officiating the rules; for making its rating calculations completely public (something MRDA does not do, by contrast); for (albeit without a good interface other than sending an email) making bout stats for all Sanctioned Games available to anyone who asks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dnn</category><category>in the news</category><category>international</category><category>international derby</category><category>open</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 11:59:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Romania: new to the World Cup</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/10/team-romania-new-to-the-world-cup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Next in our series of articles covering new teams in the 2018 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the smallest attendees. Representing Eastern Europe along with Team Russia, it's Team Romania!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20282" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/romania.jpg" alt="Romania" width="800" height="800"&gt; Team Romania Logo: by Libby Odai and &lt;span class=""&gt;Alina Usurelu&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;As with much of Eastern Europe, the spread of Roller Derby in Romania has been very slow: in fact, there are currently no leagues in the country, even in the capital Bucharest. Team Romania, then, is necessarily formed from expats and descendants of citizens - with the intent to promote the sport in the country itself as a result.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Exe QT, one of Team Romania's founders, is perhaps typical. "I've lived in Sweden since I was 4, so I'm pretty much Swedish," she told us, "even though I go back to Romania once every couple of years and obviously still speak Romanian with my mum, relatives etc..."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;A skater for Gothenburg Roller Derby, Exe QT first thought of the possibility of Romanian entry for the World Cup because of a chance meeting at a London Rollergirls bootcamp. London Brawling's AnDrac is herself of Romanian ancestry, and meeting someone so well known in the sport set a "seed" in her brain. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;All it took for it to sprout was hearing that there were other eligible skaters... and it started to look very possible indeed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Despite there not being any skaters in Romania itself, the team takes the representation of their country seriously. "I believe it's a huge thing to get to represent your nation, in any situation," says Exe QT. "I am proud of my heritage, even though in my daily life, no-one would think about that I'm basically a first generation 'immigrant'." &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;And this patriotism is something echoed by fellow Team Romania member Tenacious (of Kent Roller Girls), for whom representation is really important: “to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; represent Romania, myself, a woman, to the world it's fantastic! We have always had great females taking part in many different sports, females that I have always looked up to with a lot of respect and admiration. I would like to show that Team Romania can be diverse and supportive of all genders of people!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;AnDrac, who has joined the Team Romania roster herself, told us, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"I am finally starting to feel quite excited about a potential Team Romania in the next World Cup as there is no roller derby in Romania yet. Hopefully we will be able to find a few more players to field a team.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;It will be an experience for all of us as we won't really have the time to train together like the more established teams but we would have paved the path for the future Romanians that play or will play Roller Derby around the world. Exciting times ahead!"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;As with many of the newer teams, the aim for Team Romania this time around is simply to represent. Exe QT notes, "For the Cup, I'm hoping that we could all go there and have fun! No-one should be upset if we lose games, and we could all celebrate being able to skate for our birth nation, enjoying the ambience, meeting new friends.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;If we would win a few games that would be awesome.  But I don't want to put too much pressure on everyone, because we will be a team that barely would have practiced together, and that is a big disadvantage!"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;And in the future, maybe Roller Derby will come to Bucharest itself! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Exe QT: "It would be great if we could find some people in Romania who'd be interested in starting up a team, but as we both know, it requires not only a lot of time and energy, but also money. Where should they practice, how do they get equipment etc etc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;I'd love to go there for a week and coach derby, like a full week's program on and off skates, so that they could start up (I coach my league, and I really love it)"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Even for the National Team itself, experienced skaters from Romania are welcome, as Tenacious notes, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;“I know Romanians are big on skating, inline especially. We can find a way of getting a team together, coaching them, even from the distance, if there's anyone interested in putting themselves forward!”&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Team Romania are still recruiting for players, and looking for coaches and support staff of all kinds, so if you would like to skate with them, apply at their Facebook page here: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/RollerDerbyTeamRomania/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;https://www.facebook.com/RollerDerbyTeamRomania/&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="_4tdt _ua1"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international</category><category>international derby</category><category>new national teams</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2018</category><category>team romania</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/10/team-romania-new-to-the-world-cup/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 10:20:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Crime City (B) gear up for Tenerife.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/04/crime-city-b-gear-up-for-tenerife/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst now most of the big events are finally dying down as leagues head into their winter off-season (sometimes reluctantly), there's still some sunny climes where tournaments are yet to come.
In particular, Tenerife Roller Derby have been on a bit of a tournament kick recently, and are topping their previous three-team international tournament (against Paris and Royal Windsor) with a possibly even more international one, by distance, as Dundee Roller Girls and Malmö's Crime City (B) both fly down to the Canaries to take in a bit of sun, and a lot of Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this interview, we caught up with Darling Ripper, of Crime City B, to see how the Swedish team are feeling about skating in 20º Celcius heat in December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11938" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/darling-ripper1.jpg" alt="darling-ripper1" width="2048" height="1366"&gt; Crime City B, Darling Ripper middle (visible 6 on arm) Photo: Helena Mettävainio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crime City B have had a very good year to date - you have won all 5 of your games, mostly by quite big margins.In particular, you seem to have made a big jump in performance, to judge from your rematch against Copenhagen and Berlin! In 2015, you lost in quite a close game to Copenhagen, in 2016, you won extremely convincingly; and while you've won against the Inglorious Bombshells twice, you increased your lead this year. Can you say how the year has been from your perspective, and if the team has been doing particular thing to improve this strongly?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DR: It has been a really great year for us and we are very proud of our own development! It's always hard to know exactly why we have improved this much, but I think it's due to the fact that our charter has been rather stable for the last year so we've become a really close-knit team and we have so much fun playing together as well! It also helps having such great coaches from our A and B team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In fact, Swedish (and Finnish, so maybe "Scandinavian" &lt;img class="_1ift _2560 img" src="https://www.facebook.com/images/emoji.php/v6/z4c/1/16/1f642.png" alt="🙂"&gt; ) Roller Derby has been doing exceptionally well in recent years. Do you have any thoughts about what Sweden is doing well, in general?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DR: Haha, I don't know what Sweden is doing in general, maybe wrestling polar bears? But I think the Scandinavian teams are quite good at helping each other out and we play and practice together in different ways so maybe that's why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tenerife will be the furthest Crime City B have travelled for a bout since you've existed. Do long trips feel different than short ones - and how are you expecting to deal with the much warmer climate? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DR: Traveling is always exhausting, but we are really excited to go to Tenerife and look forward to get away from the cold here in Crime City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flat Track Stats puts you as the favourite to win this tournament too, with Dundee Roller Girls and Tenerife both roughly equally rated. What's the teams' goal for this final tournament of the year? (Are you aiming to win, or do you have personal goals, or other goals here?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DR: Our aim for the tournament is to have fun and play our best game. We expect a hard competition from both teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, with this year going so well, what's next for Crime City B next year? Will you be aiming at higher level opponents - Flat Track Stats thinks that you're on a level with, say Nantes or Auld Reekie - and our own ratings put you a little higher, and in contention with the next tier of French teams, maybe Newcastle Roller Girls…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DR: We will have to wait and see what next year will bring us! But it would be fun to play those higher-ranked teams you mention. As a B team, it can sometimes be a bit hard to find competition at your level, seeing how we are not a WFTDA team and therefore can't play Sanctioned bouts. I hope more higher-ranked teams will be interested in playing us now that we have shown that we can put up a good fight!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tenerife Triple Header will be on &lt;strong&gt;December 17th&lt;/strong&gt;, from 14:00 (WET, which is the same as GMT) in Pancho Camurria Sports Centre, Santa Cruz, Tenerife. There's no event page at present, but we will add more information as we have it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girls are raising money to fund their attendance here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gofundme.com/drg-tenerife-tour"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/drg-tenerife-tour&lt;/a&gt; . &lt;/strong&gt;We will add funding links for other teams if we are made aware of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>international</category><category>malmo crime city rollers</category><category>roller derby tenerife</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/04/crime-city-b-gear-up-for-tenerife/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 10:50:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>International Roller Derby Survey 2016</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/19/international-roller-derby-survey-2016/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regular readers will know that the Blog has something of an interest in the growth of Roller Derby in newer regions. As Roller Derby spreads out of the "cultural West", the new areas it encounters have potential to enrich the sport, as well as bringing the usual benefits of enthusiastic new areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, what do newer skaters in those regions think about Roller Derby right now? How do they feel about the sport - and what do they want from it?
To start off an irregular series on this topic, we performed a small survey with several Roller Derby teams and leagues in Asia and the Middle and Near East, targeting specifically skaters who were local to those areas. Future articles in this series will talk to some of the respondents to the survey, and others, in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The responding skaters were members of: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Roller-Derby-Beirut-763063127094159/"&gt;Roller Derby Beirut&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Beirut), &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TLVDerbyGirls/?fref=ts"&gt;Tel Aviv Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Israel), &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/NRMonsters/?fref=ts"&gt;Tokyo Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Neon Roller Monsters, Japan), &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/kamikazebadassrollerderbyjapan/?fref=ts"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kamikaze Badass Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;(Japan),  &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BangkokRollerDerby/?fref=ts"&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Thailand), and the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/CaiRollergirls/?fref=ts"&gt;CaiRollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Egypt). Other leagues were asked, but were unable to respond due to issues outside their control. In total, there were &lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt; respondents. We should emphasise that, with such a small survey, proportions are subject to significant statistical uncertainty - differences of less than 20% in response are not statistically significant here. Whilst all of the respondents waived their right to anonymity in this survey, we will not be identifying them at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The median experience of the skaters was &lt;strong&gt;3 years&lt;/strong&gt;, with only one having less than a years' declared experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started off the survey by investigating how they got involved with their current league. 7, &lt;strong&gt;47%&lt;/strong&gt;, of respondents referred to finding out through friends, either online (Facebook or otherwise) or in person. One was led to join after reading an article about the league, and one via advertising in public spaces. The remainder were founding members of their league, or otherwise did not answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9602" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/screen-shot-2016-10-17-at-21-23-02.png?w=273" alt="screen-shot-2016-10-17-at-21-23-02" width="273" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, a little over half had heard of Roller Derby before joining their league. Of the &lt;strong&gt;60%&lt;/strong&gt; who had heard of Roller Derby from other venues, there were precisely two touchstones, each with &lt;strong&gt;43%&lt;/strong&gt; of the eligible cohort: the movie "Whip It", and experiences of the sport in other countries - the UK or USA; one did not give a detailed response. Most did not find their experience of roller derby to differ from their expectations, although one explicitly noted that the experience was better than the film made out (less "sexy" and more "down to earth").&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-9813" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/screen-shot-2016-10-19-at-13-23-13.png" alt="screen-shot-2016-10-19-at-13-23-13" width="826" height="395"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most respondents feel more of a part of a "&lt;em&gt;worldwide community&lt;/em&gt;" and "&lt;em&gt;aware of Roller Derby outside their country&lt;/em&gt;" than not. However, the positivity is more muted on the latter point, with the most common response being around the middle of the scale; contrastingly, 40% feel "completely" part of a worldwide community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also asked respondents two questions to see how they did interact with the worldwide community: "&lt;em&gt;How do you feel about Roller Derby worldwide?&lt;/em&gt;" and "&lt;em&gt;What do the letters WFTDA mean to you?&lt;/em&gt;"
On the former question, 4 did not respond in any way. The statistically significant majority of responses (53%, &lt;strong&gt;72%&lt;/strong&gt; of those who answered at all) were both positive and reflected ideals of community - common words were "one family", "sisterhood", "inspirational" and "capable". Only one respondent expressed a complete lack of knowledge about the wider community.
On the latter question, two respondents (&lt;strong&gt;13%&lt;/strong&gt;) did not know what WFTDA was. Of the remainder, 4 (&lt;strong&gt;26%&lt;/strong&gt;) focussed on the standards setting aspects of the Association, while another 5 (&lt;strong&gt;33%&lt;/strong&gt;) expressed mainly aspirational or community related feeling towards it. (The rest simply repeated the exact meaning).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-large wp-image-9582 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/screen-shot-2016-10-17-at-19-59-15-2.png?w=1024" alt="screen-shot-2016-10-17-at-19-59-15-2" width="1024" height="540"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were also interested as to how the respondents viewed Roller Derby - is it "&lt;em&gt;American&lt;/em&gt;" or "&lt;em&gt;Western&lt;/em&gt;" or both? Responses to both questions were mixed, and not well correlated, suggesting that images of "America" and "The West" are not close synonyms. However, there is a definite trend towards believing that Roller Derby is more Western than not, whilst the feelings about "Americanness" are more mixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To judge influence of wider and popular Roller Derby images, we asked the respondents if they had any Roller Derby heroes.
4 (&lt;strong&gt;27%&lt;/strong&gt;) said that they had no heroes, or raised philosophical objections to the concept. Several mentioned more than one choice, so percentages here do not add up to 100%: the most popular choices were Quadzilla (3, &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;), Bonnie Thunders (2, &lt;strong&gt;13%&lt;/strong&gt;) and "our league/our coaches" (3, &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;). Highly visible WFTDA Top 40 skaters are represented in 7 (&lt;strong&gt;47%&lt;/strong&gt;) of responses overall, a majority of responses for those who had any heroes at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also asked if respondents thought that &lt;em&gt;the kind of Roller Derby they did was different in any way to "Western" Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt; (if this existed as a thing).
&lt;strong&gt;33%&lt;/strong&gt; of respondents answered with a simple "&lt;em&gt;No&lt;/em&gt;". Of the rest, three (&lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;) essentially abstained, and the remainder were divided into &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; "&lt;em&gt;Yes&lt;/em&gt;", and the remainder mostly concerned with the relative skill gap they perceived. (Two (&lt;strong&gt;13%&lt;/strong&gt;) did consider the difference to be in relation to the perspective of society towards their sport).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-9814 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/screen-shot-2016-10-19-at-13-23-32.png" alt="screen-shot-2016-10-19-at-13-23-32" width="486" height="393"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concerning local derby, we were interested as to &lt;em&gt;how their peers and family reacted&lt;/em&gt; to the sport. The majority of respondents considered their family to be &lt;em&gt;more supportive&lt;/em&gt; than not (&lt;strong&gt;80%&lt;/strong&gt;), with &lt;strong&gt;47%&lt;/strong&gt; selecting the most positive option ("&lt;em&gt;totally supportive&lt;/em&gt;"). Of those with less supportive family and friends, all of them cited concerns about physical safety as the principal sources of worry, although one of the positive respondents noted that their family's similar fears been totally reversed once they had actually seen the sport in action. (Positive respondents generally used word like "&lt;em&gt;cool&lt;/em&gt;" or "&lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt;" to describe their peers/family's feelings.)
With particular reference to Japan, respondents noted the confusion specific to that country between "Roller Derby" and the Japanese entertainment variant "Roller Game" in the popular consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To close off the survey, we also asked respondents about &lt;em&gt;their hopes&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;fears&lt;/em&gt; for Roller Derby in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overwhelmingly, the &lt;em&gt;hopes&lt;/em&gt; consisted of desires for more popular recognition or mainstream tokens of acceptance(&lt;strong&gt;100%&lt;/strong&gt;). Breaking this down, &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; of responses specifically mentioned the Olympics as an aspirational target; &lt;strong&gt;33%&lt;/strong&gt; focussed more on increasing popularity and acceptance in their region, while another &lt;strong&gt;33%&lt;/strong&gt; had specific interest in the spread of Roller Derby to more countries worldwide. In particular, one respondent was specifically interested in having more roller derby outside of the USA, with tournaments in every region.
With respect to &lt;em&gt;fears&lt;/em&gt;, responses were far more varied. Two (&lt;strong&gt;13%&lt;/strong&gt;) had "no worries". Two were concerned about the sport's community spirit being harmed by increased professionalisation. &lt;strong&gt;33%&lt;/strong&gt; were concerned that the sport might die out - from lack of support either globally or regionally. &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; (overlapping with some of the above) were specifically concerned by costs. 1 (&lt;strong&gt;7%&lt;/strong&gt;) expressed concern at the increased influence of men in the sport.
In both cases, we believe that these are the same kinds of hopes and fears found across the Roller Derby community, even in the most established nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, then, we are encouraged by the response to our survey, especially concerning support from local and global communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, we hope to come back to you will follow-ups on this article, interviewing specific respondents (and others from leagues who were not surveyed).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international</category><category>international derby</category><category>statistics</category><category>surveys</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/19/international-roller-derby-survey-2016/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 11:22:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>From Lucerne with Shoves: Voodoo's international tournament plans!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/12/from-lucerne-with-shoves-voodoos-international-tournament-plans/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While this weekend continues the tradition of being rather busy in roller derby, in Glasgow, something a little epic is being planned. Fresh from the end of the British Championships Tier 4 competition, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Voodoo-Roller-Dollies-571771319549241/"&gt;Voodoo Roller Dollies&lt;/a&gt; are hosting a mini-tournament, with an international bent. Returning from Voodoo's last tournament (only this February!) are Glasgow C, the &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/content/cannie-gingers"&gt;Cannie Gingers&lt;/a&gt;; however, flying in all the way from Lucerne (Luzern), Switzerland, the third team are &lt;a href="http://www.thehellveticats.ch/"&gt;The Hellveticats&lt;/a&gt;, part of the new wave of Swiss and Central European roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/12/from-lucerne-with-shoves-voodoos-international-tournament-plans/12006363_963059253753777_8455008463369869288_n/" rel="attachment wp-att-4938"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4938" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/12006363_963059253753777_8455008463369869288_n.jpg" alt="12006363_963059253753777_8455008463369869288_n" width="614" height="231"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2012, the Hellveticats started with the usual enthusiasm of new leagues, despite, as Referee Lucy Cat Rolls told us "that most of the girls on the team haven't even watched a roller derby game, we did our best to train and build up our league". They've been bouting since late 2013, according to Flat Track Stats, mostly playing the rest of the Swiss and Central European derby community. In fact, the tournament will not just be a new experience for the Scottish teams, as it's the furthest trip that the Hellveticats have made in their history."As we have many members with family or other responsibilities we try to get bouts which are possible to travel within a day trip. But, every now and then, we make a journey with the team - we went to [Prague] in the Czech Republic and to Nice in France. Scotland is within a very good distance by plane so we decided to travel there together, we are thrilled to be invited to this awesome event."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it happens, the fact that the tournament exists at all is actually down to the Hellveticats' enthusiasm for a long distance trip. As Voodoo's Roll-N-Pin told us: "[The Hellveticats] actually contacted us, believe it or not. They got in contact with our very own Titan and from there it progressed. We wanted to make sure that they got as much of a Scottish derby experience as possible, [so we organised the tournament around them]." Not that Voodoo have ever been shy of a tournament, as Pin admitted, "tournaments are always a great way to involve so many people at the same time. To come up against new teams and get to spend even more time in a weekend or day playing against them. I mean, who doesn't love more derby time? It's double, and even triple, the fun at times with tournaments."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Hellveticats are travelling the furthest, it's Glasgow's &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/45330"&gt;Cannie Gingers&lt;/a&gt; who are the most dangerous competitors in the tournament, sitting almost 200 places above &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/38908"&gt;Voodoo&lt;/a&gt;, and 130 above the &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/20691"&gt;Lucerne&lt;/a&gt; team, in Flat Track Stats' European ranking scheme (although our own prediction scheme places the latter somewhat closer in ability to the Glasgow team). Despite the huge challenge they represent, Voodoo are relishing the rematch. "The Canny Gingers are always a fierce opponent and are really the definition of a true challenge, " said Roll N Pin, "but with each bout we play against superior teams, we gain more knowledge , discover more tactics  and get to try out more strategies. It would take a phenomenal achievement on our part to win against them, but for us it's not all about the win. At the end of the day if the other team are walking away with bump and bruises, sore spots and dead arms or legs then we know we have put up a great fight and have made them work for it. It gives us a goal to work towards as well, a comparison to ourselves to see how much we have improved and how we can improve more." And the Cannie Gingers aren't willing to rule out the possibility of a Voodoo win, saying "there are no guarantees in Derby; just look at the Rose/Victorian/Gotham games in the WFTDA Championships. We just want to play our games and take each jam as they come!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow C are also keen to see what Swiss derby has to offer, noting that "one of the great things about roller derby is the opportunities it brings, and it's an honour to play every team we face, for the things we are taught in each game. It will be interesting to see how our styles play against each other; we hope it will also be a fun experience and that [the Hellveticats] have a good Scottish welcome".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of who actually wins, all the teams have the same goals at heart. Roll N Pin "First and foremost, and it may seem cheesy, [our goal] is to have FUN! We want to present an environment to welcome all and make sure that the players and the crowd are having fun. But hey that's not too hard to do when you've got derby, tunes and CAKE!", and Lucy Cat Roll agrees, "I guess the biggest challenge will be understanding the Scottisch dialect and resisting to the urge of drinking whisky before the first whistle ;-) We hope to have fun and to meet many nice derby people and we hope to have you over in Switzerland one day and invite you for a nice tournament, some cheese and a ton of chocolate." The Gingers also, "above all, [] just want to have a nice time! We have some established skaters, and some who will be playing their first game, so it's a nice mix. We work hard at training, and in running our league, so we just want to represent GRD in the best way we can."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voodoo Roller Dollies have a new intake planned for the end of November, and extensive plans for the future. As Pin puts it: "Voodoo's future is looking bright. We have a new intake at the end of this month (as always we are looking to expand) and we have many a teams to play again for return games. We are hoping to get more involved in the derby community and attend more scrims. Maybe even host a few ourselves. One thing is for sure we will always come back hitting harder and pushing ourselves further."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tournament starts from &lt;strong&gt;Midday&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8666126,-4.2505074,17z/data=!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7"&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt; in Glasgow Caledonian University on Saturday &lt;strong&gt;14th November&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event page can be found on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/908423505918913/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, and tickets will be £5 on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as we are aware, the planned schedule of play is:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Doors 12:00&lt;br&gt;
Skate outs 12:20&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
1st game - VRD v GRD - 12:30&lt;br&gt;
2nd game - GRD v Hell - 13:55&lt;br&gt;
3rd game - Hell v VRD - 15:20&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>cannie gingers</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>hellveticats</category><category>international</category><category>interviews</category><category>tournament</category><category>voodoo roller dollies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/12/from-lucerne-with-shoves-voodoos-international-tournament-plans/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 20:42:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Visualising the Internationalisation of Roller Derby (part 1 of 2)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/07/visualising-the-internationalisation-of-roller-derby-part-1-of-2/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, we've been including some more analytics content on the blog, with included content here and some links from articles to more detailed discussions on the author's personal wordpress. In order to improve our analytics, it's important to have a big set of real world measurements to compare to - you can use these to train your model, and then also to test the new model's predictive power (obviously you use different subsets of your data for training and testing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;FlatTrackStats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; has a very large and complete set of bout records for flat track roller derby, dating back to the very first bouts in 2003. Even more luckily, the FlatTrackStats guys are committed to openness of data, so their records are licensed Creative Commons: Non-Commercial (this means that anyone can use their data for free, as long as they credit FTS, and don't try to profit from whatever they're doing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the interests of paying this forward (and because the author also personally believes that it's in the best interests of roller derby to not restrict information unless absolutely necessary), this article and all images therein is licensed &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;Creative Commons: Non-Commercial-ShareAlike&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (you can reuse this article, and the images therein for anything, as long as you credit me as the source, don't profit from your actions, and share your resulting things under exactly the same license).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have the FlatTrackStats team and bout databases, up to the last week, we need to process the data in order to make it useful for our model. Part of this processing involves dividing up all of the teams (for any given period of dates) into subsets, such that everyone in a subset has played at least one person in that subset. And if you're doing that kind of processing anyway, you end up writing some tools to visualise the resulting subsets just to check on them... and it turns out that this kind of visualisation is historically interesting in itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article presents the result of some visualisations of the partitions of Flat Track Roller Derby for each year, starting from 2005 (which is really when the first teams solidified from the experimentation in 2003-4). As this data is taken from the FTS bout database, it only includes bouts which teams submitted to FTS (or which were in the DNN derbymatic database, which was also rolled into FTS when DNN closed). We also exclude Exhibition and Home teams from our plots, which mostly has effects for Men's and Coed derby post 2010. Teams are represented by circles, with lines connecting them representing a bout between those teams in the time period covered. The plotting algorithm treats connections like elastic bands, so groups of teams who all played each other are drawn into dense central regions of the plot by the forces between them, while less connected groups are pushed out to the edges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, Women's Flat Track Roller Derby was in its infancy. In fact, there are only 9 travel teams known to FlatTrackStats for the period 1 Jan 2005 to 1 Jan 2006, and of course all of them are in the USA. If we partition them into the groups which played each other, we find that there's one "big" group, with 5 members, and 2 small groups with a pair of teams a piece. (It turns out that most of the "isolated" groups we find in any year are 2 or 3 member groups, with teams who are just starting out and only really played one game that year.) The members of the big group are quite familiar today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-1.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-4654 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-1.png?w=300" alt="Graph of dominant group of Women's Derby Teams, 2005" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(that's Gotham just sliding off the left edge of the graph).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no Men's, Junior or Coed teams at this early stage of Flat Track Derby, of course.
But Women's Derby is growing rapidly. Moving on to 1 Jan &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt; to 1 Jan 2007, many new teams have started up, mostly in the USA, but with one in Canada. And almost all of them (except one pair of teams) have played at least one other team in the biggest group:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-11.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4655" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-11-e1433665617798.png?w=300" alt="Women's FT 2006 Biggest Group" width="300" height="287"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
(here we start to see our colour scheme - &lt;span style="color:#ff0000;"&gt;Red is USA&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;Blue is Canada&lt;/span&gt;, and later on &lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;Green will be Europe&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="color:#33cccc;"&gt;Cyan: Australia&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="color:#993366;"&gt;Purple: New Zealand&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="color:#ffcc00;"&gt;Yellow the Asia-Pacific&lt;/span&gt;, and White: South America - drawn from FTS' internal categorisations). This group is really the founding set of the competitive Division 1, and most of them are still there today.
&lt;p&gt;But, in &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, something new happens. There's the continuing explosion of USA derby (the biggest group by far):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-12.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4656" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-12-e1433665562310.png?w=660" alt="Women's Largest Group, 2007" width="660" height="635"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
But the second biggest group, albeit only three teams, is the beginning of European derby: London Rockin' Rollers, Birmingham Blitz Dames and Stuttgart Valley Rollergirls taking their first steps onto the track:
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-2.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4657" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-2.png?w=300" alt="Women's Second Largest Group, 2007" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
(2007 is also the start of Men's Flat Track Roller Derby, with Harm City playing The Dirty Dozen for the first ever official bout.)
&lt;p&gt;By the end of 2008, the European Derby seed is beginning to grow, but they're still entirely separate from the big connected group in the USA. As well as a smattering of teams in the USA and Canada who only played one bout in 2008, there's also the beginning of Cyan on our graphs, with Adelaide Roller Derby playing Victorian Roller Derby League for the first Australian derby on the Flat Track. These are both trends that continue into the end of &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, with three entirely disconnected centres of Derby developing:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;The big USA/Canada (where you can see the tightly linked central bunch of "Division 1" teams continuing to dominate derby):
&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-13.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4658" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-13-e1433665656698.png?w=660" alt="W Group 1 - 2009" width="660" height="652"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The growing Europe (Names from FTS database, so Glasgow appear under their modern name of Glasgow Roller &lt;em&gt;Derby&lt;/em&gt;):
&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-21.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-large wp-image-4659 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-21-e1433665701389.png?w=660" alt="Group 2" width="660" height="570"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nascent Australia (so early that we have 6 teams, each of which played only one bout):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-10.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-4660 size-thumbnail aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-10.png?w=150" alt="Group 10" width="150" height="150"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-131.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone wp-image-4661 size-thumbnail aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-131.png?w=150" alt="Group 13" width="150" height="150"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-17.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-thumbnail wp-image-4662 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-17.png?w=150" alt="Group 17" width="150" height="150"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
Men's Derby has finally begun to reach a respectable size at this point, but still entirely USA based:
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-14.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4665" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-14-e1433665767740.png?w=300" alt="M Group 1 2009" width="300" height="251"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
In &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, however, two things happen of importance to the future of Roller Derby.
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, Europe finally contacts the USA, with London Rollergirls playing their first bouts across the Atlantic. Given the isolation of USA derby from the emerging European and Australasian areas, the ability of London surprises a lot of their opponents (setting a trend for both reactions to London, and reactions to non-US teams in general when visiting the USA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-110.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-large wp-image-4679 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-110.png?w=660" alt="W Group 1 2010" width="660" height="627"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
(the Green dot in the middle of the Red central dots is London, while the rest of Europe is relegated to the edge, due to lack of connections to the dense nexus of Important USA Teams). &lt;em&gt;Edit: interestingly, London A is already isolated from Europe by this point - they only played US teams in 2010. It is Rainy City who connect Europe with the USA, having played Oly Rollers B.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the very first Junior derby starts up (this is &lt;em&gt;Cleveland Firestarters&lt;/em&gt; (who were later replaced by Cleveland Junior Roller Derby) v &lt;em&gt;Indianapolis Junior Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-16.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4670" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-16.png?w=300" alt="J Group 1 2010" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Meanwhile, Australasian Derby is still developing apart from the rest of the world. Pirate City Rollers represent the first New Zealand travel team to play others, shown in purple:
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-22.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4667" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-22-e1433665837223.png?w=300" alt="W Group 2 2010" width="300" height="244"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
and a second wave of European derby is beginning, with Gent, Stockholm, Helsinki and others forming a new group of emerging teams, many of which will accelerate into importance both politically and competitively in the next few years:
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-3.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4668" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/group-3-e1433665858342.png?w=300" alt="W Group 3 2010" width="300" height="251"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We'll look at the trends in International Derby since the end of 2010 in our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/07/visualising-the-internationalisation-of-roller-derby-part-2-of-2-2011-to-present/"&gt;second post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in this series, where we'll also publish some links to the code used for these plots.&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>analysis</category><category>articles</category><category>flattrackstats</category><category>international</category><category>statistics</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/07/visualising-the-internationalisation-of-roller-derby-part-1-of-2/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 09:22:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Second Wave: Auld Reekie and Kokeshi Rollers make The Big O.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/04/29/the-second-wave-auld-reekie-and-kokeshi-rollers-make-the-big-o/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2013 was a big year for Scottish Roller Derby on the international scene, as Glasgow Roller Derby's Irn Bruisers and &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' Twisted Thistles both made the trip across the Atlantic to play in ECDX, the first UK teams other than London Roller Girls to start competing seriously against US teams on their home ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with London's initial experiences, ARRG and GRD made a splash, both doing much better than many of the US natives had expected. This year, both leagues are sending their A teams to different events - GRD is targetting &lt;em&gt;Spring Roll&lt;/em&gt; in Fort Wayne, and Auld Reekie are off to &lt;em&gt;The Big O&lt;/em&gt; in Oregon this coming weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thebigotournament.com/"&gt;The Big O&lt;/a&gt; is a yearly tournament hosted by Emerald City Roller Girls (based in Eugene, Oregon) since 2012. It's no stranger to international visitors: in 2013, Australia's Victorian Roller Derby flew across the Pacific to compete there, and the UK's own Southern Discomfort participated in the first ever international men's derby bout at the same event. As that implies, The Big O is not just a WFTDA or women's derby tournament: there is also a significant Men's Derby bracket and Junior Derby tournament as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie will be joined as International contenders amongst the US teams by Japan's &lt;a href="http://www.kokeshirollerdolls.com/"&gt;Kokeshi Roller Dolls&lt;/a&gt;. Okinawa-based Kokeshi are one of the oldest Japanese derby leagues, naming themselves after the distinctive round-headed Japanese wooden dolls (&lt;span style="color:#252525;"&gt;こけし) which also appear on their logo. Like many of the Japanese derby leagues, KRD are mostly composed of American nationals, drawn from the ranks of &lt;em&gt;United States Forces in Japan &lt;/em&gt;and their partners. The Big O will be Kokeshi's first international bouting experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both ARRG and KRD will be competing in the "lower Division 2" tournament bracket, out of the three WFTDA brackets available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Glasgow Roller Derby's Spring Roll planning to be covered in a later article, we caught up with Auld Reekie's Ciderella and Kokeshi's Riot Earp and Dark Passenger to get their thoughts on planning for, experiencing, and learning from, international tournaments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/04/logobpt.gif"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-3396" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/04/logobpt.gif?w=614" alt="The Big O Logo" width="614" height="363"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ARRG) The Thistles’ first trip across the Atlantic made something of a splash as both ARRG and Glasgow Roller Derby outperformed expectations at ECDX. Now that the USA is adjusting to the quality of top European teams, are you expecting your experience of the Big O to be different?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cider) In some ways yes. This is going to be a much tougher tournament as the teams we are playing are mostly ranked a lot higher than we've played before and the ranking system is a lot more settled than it was last year. However last year I'm sure we felt the same; we were travelling overseas to play teams ranked higher than us then as well. it is only looking back at that experience that this time around seems more challenging. We still just want to go out and play the best that we can and show the rest of the derby community what we can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(KRD) According to Flat Track Stats, KRD have relatively few interleague bouts under their belt, thanks to the relatively recent growth of derby in Japan. How are you preparing for your first really big derby tournament challenge?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PRACTICE! We practice as much as we can first. Only a handful of us have been to a tournament so we are heeding the words of those experienced skaters to mentally and physically prep ourselves. We also have been working together as a team to coordinate travel and fundraising plans, as this is such a long trip. (Riot Earp)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRD is preparing for our very first tournament in several ways. We have weekly scrimmages, we are practicing 3 days a week and participate in off skates workouts with groups or on our own. (Dark Passenger)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ARRG) Over the past year, the Thistles’ Ranking has pretty much continuously increased, according to Flat Track Stats metrics. In addition, you’re ranked as the best (non-London) team in the UK by UKRDA’s subset of FTS’s rankings, and have a comfortable spot in Division 2 of WFTDA’s rankings, heading up the European contingent. How important was the experience of ECDX to your improvement as a team? Is there a point where every league has to start looking across the Atlantic for more challenges?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cider) In terms of improvement as a team, ECDX was certainly a focus for us in our training but I don't necessarily think that a tournament itself improves a team, I believe it is the work behind the scenes that does that. Travelling overseas and knowing that this was our one (very expensive) opportunity to get into Division 2 that year was certainly a good motivation! That being said, tournaments are so different to single games that any experience a team can get attending them is vital if you are serious about progressing up the rankings. They take a lot more out of you and as a unit you need to be smart about how you play the long game. It can also be a bit overwhelming the first time you travel anywhere with your league, so the more experience you can get the better. That way you can focus on the game when you are there and not everything else happening around that.
As for going across the Atlantic to get those chances, well I really hope it does not get to the point where all leagues have to do this. Obviously if leagues want to do it, well that's great, it is a wonderful experience to see derby around the world and have that challenge against long-running leagues. The more a team climbs in the WFTDA rankings at the moment, the more likely they will need to go overseas to get the match ups they need, however, as there are now more European leagues doing this, hopefully it should have a knock on effect for the rest of Europe. In my opinion, the main reason top European leagues are forced to look elsewhere for games is due to their initial entry point into the WFTDA ranking system. Most start near the bottom, which means a fair sized rankings gap between themselves and perhaps other European leagues who have climbed the rankings but are actually similar in skill level. The team ranked higher then struggles, as they know they wont be able to get the point differential they need in that game to maintain their position. If there were a lot of teams ranked at their level that they could easily travel to, this would not be an issue as they could help that team out and then average out their ranking elsewhere, however, at the moment in Europe there are not enough near-by teams who have similar ranking levels for this to work.
Hopefully with the amount of European teams crossing the Atlantic this year, the gaps will close and we can spread these rankings around. Although then I am sure other parts of the world will have the same challenges as derby progresses elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ARRG) Compared to the lineup at ECDX, the Thistles are facing twice as many bouts, against higher ranked opponents (including the intimidating Arizona, ranked #29 by FlatTrackStats at the time of writing). How do you prepare to face these really tough opponents?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cider) Last year when we went to ECDX we arranged a couple of extra games around the area to get the most out of the trip over there; whilst we only played two games at the tournament, we actually played 4 in a short amount of time; so we do have the experience of playing a good amount of teams over a short space of time. However, the toughness of these teams is not something we have had much experience in. We've prepared the only way we know how; by training as hard as possible on and off skates to make sure we are physically and mentally up to scratch. We are approaching this tournament with our usual positive attitude and a set of goals we wish to achieve as a team one of which is to get another good climb up the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ARRG) This year, a few more UK teams are heading across the water to ECDX, including Tiger Bay Brawlers, who you narrowly defeated just a few weeks ago. How do you rate their chances in the tournament, given your experience?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cider) I think all the teams will do well at ECDX. As I said before tournaments are a great experience and perhaps a league with no experience of overseas travel and tournament weekends might find it a bit overwhelming, however, one of the benefits of being a derby league in Europe is that over seas travel and tournaments are hard to avoid. I'm very excited to see how these teams progress and hopefully I will be able to catch a few of the games on the live stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ARRG) Also joining you as the only other non-US team at The Big O are Okinawa’s Kokeshi Roller Dolls. What advice would you give them in approaching the tournament, especially facing a really tough team like Arizona (as you both will be)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cider) It is really important as a team to have clear goals going into a tournament and that everybody is on the same page. No matter what gets thrown at you in a game, focus on the bigger picture and remember it is a team effort. When you know you are going up against a tough team with a much higher ranking I think you should always aim high but be realistic about the situation; you're probably not going to get a 2:1 win ratio against them, but what can you get? Do you just want to get through the match alive? (There have been games where this is all I've wanted!) Get lead a certain percentage of the game? Shut down their point accumulation? Have a goal (or goals) and see them through. If you don't achieve them all, that's okay, just reassess afterwards, pick yourself up and have another look at them; maybe there is something you can learn from not having reached them that will help your team progress further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(KRD) The Big O is not just a chance to play challenging teams, it’s also a chance to meet other skaters. With some very impressive Division 1 teams in attendance, who are you most looking forward to meeting? Are you looking forward to meeting your fellow non-US team, Auld Reekie Roller Girls?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Riot Earp) There are a few big names thrown around the team as far as whom they HAVE to watch and want to meet, but personally, I’m excited to meet anyone and everyone! In my eyes, every skater there is an unbelievable athlete and work hard to be there. Each skater is special and amazing in their own way and I absolutely cannot wait to take it all in. We are extremely excited to meet ARRG. Being a non US localized team it’ll be great to make connections and learn and brainstorm on how they operate overseas and how it could help us improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Dark Passenger) We are extremely excited to meet Auld Reekie as well as all the other teams there competing. We are all so excited to be a part of The Big O, I don’t think there’s really any team we’re really looking forward to meeting. We can’t wait to meet all the teams!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As well as a WFTDA Division 1 bracket, The Big O also features a significant Men’s Derby schedule, and a (West-coast) oriented Junior Derby schedule as well. What bouts are you looking forward to trying to catch, schedule permitting?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cider) I really am looking forward to seeing Kokeshi play, that will be good. I would also like to see Texas - Rose, however, the timing overlaps with one of our games so I am not sure if I will get to see any of it. As for the Men's and Junior's, I would like to see what I can as it is always exciting and there is always something to learn!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Riot Earp) Being able to see Live Derby at this scale not on a computer monitor is more then we can ask for in the first place I know just being there to watch is going to be more then we could have asked for. We also just found out team USA will be there bouting the MVP mash up… this is one no one will miss!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Dark Passenger) There are so many bouts we’d like to catch. The big one would have to be Texas Roller Girls vs Rose City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going to the USA is expensive.  How do you decide how to raise funds for this kind of outlay, and how are you spreading the word about your events?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cider) Well we have some fantastic committees, especially marketing and sponsorship. They look at the figures and come up with some inventive fundraising ideas. We have an awards ball on June 21st which will be a lot of fun; Crazylegs is threatening to turn up in a wedding dress (the theme is dress fancy) so it is really not to be missed. Obviously after the success of our limited edition t-shirts last year, we've rolled out a new design which is friggin awesome and &lt;a href="http://auldreekierollergirls.bigcartel.com/"&gt;you can get right here.&lt;/a&gt; I really love a well designed t-shirt as a fundraising aid as everybody wins; the league gets some help and the buyer gets a great tee.
We also have another boot-camp coming up on the 19th July, so save the date, it's going to be a good one! &lt;em&gt;[Auld Reekie have held a range of fundraising events, including a Comedy Night at The Stand last week.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Riot Earp) FUNDRAISING FUNDRAISING FUNDRAISING! But yes in all seriousness along with mentally and physically prepping for this tournament we also had to financially prepare. The dollstars created a t-shirt line and have been selling them as well as setting up a &lt;a href="http://www.gofundme.com/5oqiug"&gt;GO FUND ME&lt;/a&gt; account. We also have been smaller fundraisers such as bake sales and babysitting for donations. Every penny has helped and we appreciate all those that have donated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Dark Passenger) The league has been fundraising since about October using GoFundMe and by having bake sales and by creating a unique &lt;a href="http://www.kokeshirollerdolls.com/images/ringer.jpg"&gt;Okinawa Roller Derby shirt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, what are your aims for the team with regards to the Big O as a competition and an experience? (For KRD, are you hoping this will raise awareness of Japanese derby, internationally? )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cider) Come back alive haha. We really want to climb further up the rankings, we are aiming high, Division 1 in fact, though we know this is a hell of a challenge. I think we really just want to see how we sit against teams ranked in the Division 1 area. No matter what happens this week, we will come back with a much clearer picture of what we need to do to progress further up the rankings and hopefully we can pass on this knowledge to other European leagues too, so that we can all benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Riot Earp) I think above all here in Okinawa we work hard to spread the word of derby. Most on island have not heard of it or have an ill-conceived notion of derby and assume we play 1970’s punch in the face derby. KRD works hard to help the sport of derby grow here in Okinawa and in mainland Japan. We hope that KRD being at the BIG O will not only help get our names out there but also the other leagues such as Tokyo Roller Girls and Devil Dog Derby Dames known. This is just the first step in what will be a long, fruitful adventure in derby for Kokeshi Roller Dolls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Dark Passenger) We are hopeful that KRD’s appearance at the Big O will bring an interest to other leagues to come out to Asia and skate against us and the other leagues on Mainland Japan and Okinawa. We are definitely planning on more international travel and participation in tournaments in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article would not have been possible without the assistance of ARRG's Double D-struction and KRD member "ghostopolis" on Reddit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>international</category><category>interviews</category><category>kokeshi roller dolls</category><category>krd</category><category>the big o</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/04/29/the-second-wave-auld-reekie-and-kokeshi-rollers-make-the-big-o/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 09:17:06 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>