<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about italian roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/italian-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:41:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 26 October 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-26102019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is another exceptionally busy weekend, so again we're moving Sunday-only events into a separate update later in the week.
Even doing that, it's a packed schedule, including: Bologna's Hyenas hosting two days of roller derby at the Ferrara Tattoo Convention, a double header of derby up in Aberdeen, Nantes and Gdańsk both hosting events to celebrate their leagues' respective anniversaries,  a whole sur5al tournament in New Zealand, and a &lt;em&gt;two-track&lt;/em&gt; international tournament in Hull! (And more - the first MRDA-sanctioned triple header in Spain, a weekend of derby in Querétaro... !)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're trying to stick to our rules below, so a lot of events - especially in Australia, which is currently at the height of its Spring events schedule - are having to be missed off the list. (We're open to considering treating very large countries in terms of their constituent States, for the purpose of allowing events, but we'd like the community to let us know how they feel about that.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've bent the rules a bit this time, because it's important to highlight derby in regions which need more attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/26Oct-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-26102019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>australian roller derby</category><category>belgian roller derby</category><category>bootcamps</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>italian roller derby</category><category>mexican roller derby</category><category>new zealand roller derby</category><category>polish roller derby</category><category>short track roller derby</category><category>south african roller derby</category><category>spanish roller derby</category><category>swiss roller derby</category><category>thai roller derby</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-26102019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 05 October 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-05102019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an exciting week for Scottish Roller Derby, with both Edinburgh's Auld Reekie, and Glasgow Roller Derby competing in international tournaments (ARRD in the Continental Cup in Helsinki, and GRD in the Kick Ass Cup in Hamburg). And, to add to that, this is the weekend of the annual Big Blether Scottish Roller Derby Conference, so all the leagues will be coming together there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also two-day international tournaments in Sweden, the Mexican National Division 2 Championships in Léon, Sudestada Roller Derby's debut bout in Necochea, and more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've bent the rules a bit this time, because it's important to highlight derby in regions which need more attention, and because it's quiet enough that we have the space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/05Oct-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-05102019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentine roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>big blether</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>continental cup</category><category>finnish roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>indonesian roller derby</category><category>italian roller derby</category><category>mexican roller derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>new zealand roller derby</category><category>swedish roller derby</category><category>swiss roller derby</category><category>uruguayan roller derby</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-05102019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Udine's Banshees show their love for derby in three languages!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/09/Banshees-multilingual/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are happy to host this guest post from the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/bansheesrollerderby/"&gt;Banshees of Roller Derby Udine&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;. In the spirit of their project, this post is available in English, Italian and Friulan [click the language button at the left to pick a language]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Flyer for #whyIchooserollerderby project, image of Banshees on track, overlaid with hashtag and instagram icons." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/09/Banshees-Copertina.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi everybody!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm Sugar Molotov from Banshees - Roller Derby Udine. We are a very small team in the rearmost region in north-east Italy and we are struggling to form a complete roster as many of us did or are still doing right now all around the world. We have all experienced the "roller what...?" reaction from people, and one day I thought: why is it so difficult to explain what's so exciting in this sport? How can I let them see and feel what I saw in Roller Derby and I'm feeling to this day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we decided to create a personal space on our social accounts (Facebook and Instagram) for every skater, ref, nso, or supporter to tell what they love about Derby and why they choose to play this amazing, thrilling and yet expensive and possibly dangerous sport, every day. We are all kind of very different people and still this brings us together in an unprecedented way, at least in my experience. This is how the &lt;em&gt;#whyIchooserollerderby&lt;/em&gt; campaign was born - of course we do not have as many followers as other, bigger teams would have, but we wanted to try it anyway!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, space is a very important concept in Roller Derby so we put no limit: I asked my teammates to join this project, choosing a photo and writing whatever they wanted about it. I wanted them to feel at ease to share what they felt comfortable to. On the way I thought that it would be nice to have other people joining it as well, and here I am asking if you'd feel like joining us. We don't have much to offer in return, except that we'll treasure every single contribution as if it was our own. Every text is translated in three languages, Italian as it's our nationality, English because we want as many people as possible to read it and Friulano, which is the language spoken in this specific, small region of Italy and  we want to take part in the effort to preserve it. It's part of our identity as well. Also, one of our teammate translated hers in spanish since it's her legacy, and we loved that immensely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So! I hope I've given you a reason to join our small project in the hope to make it count in spreading the news there's a new world here, and it's like anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the addresses of our pages, the campaign has just started of course, but you can see how it looks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/bansheesrollerderby/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/bansheesrollerderby/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/bansheesrollerderby/"&gt;https://www.instagram.com/bansheesrollerderby/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for sparing some time for us,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sugar Molotov&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banshees Roller Derby Udine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Mosaic image showing all of the profile pictures of contributors to the project, in grayscale, with central hue-based tone mapping from the Banshees logo." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/09/Banshees-mosaic.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: I wrote this letter when the campaign had barely started. It grew slowly but steadily and I really want to thank all the people who made an effort to keep it going: Enrico Comar and Mara Devincenti translated in friulano a few texts, but the majority were made by Enrico Gigante, whom we can’t thank enough. He’s always on the spot and faster than light! Thanks to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://arlef.it"&gt;ARLeF&lt;/a&gt;, the regional agency for friulano language and Francesca Battistutta from the regional counter for friulano language for the revisions. She also helped us a lot with this article and she’s invaluable to me for her cheerful self and  fierce friulano soul. All the graphics are made by Giulia Malaridotti (Woozy McWolf), our insomniac doggo-lover who send me edited pics at 3am in the morning so that I can publish them in time. English texts were reviewed by Chealsey Lynch (Marma Juke), our US blocker who’ll always be a Banshees in our hearts - we’ll miss you dearly. Special mention to my crazy fellow SMMs: Alessandra Menardi (Jackass Menny), Sveva Angelini (Freaky Pinball) and Alessandra Piermattei (Alycat), who believed in this project even when I didn’t and always had my back when I couldn’t keep up with the virtual world. Grrlz, you are simply the best. I could have never made this come true without you. Last but not least, the whole Banshees team who indulged in my whim and all the other fellow skaters and officials who took part in the project, sending us the most emotional, personal bits of their derby story. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#rollerderby #whyIchooserollerderby #quadskates #derbylife #rollerskating #rollerskate #roller #skate #derby #rollerskates #skating #flattrackrollerderby #derbylove #derbygirls #derbyguys #derbyfamily #supportyourlocalteam #bansheesudine #bansheetudine #friuliveneziagiulia #fvg #jointhebanshees #friulano #lenghefurlane #ARLeF #scottishrollerderby&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>campaign</category><category>friulano</category><category>furlan</category><category>italian</category><category>italian roller derby</category><category>italiano</category><category>multilingual</category><category>roller derby udine</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/09/Banshees-multilingual/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 13 July 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-13072019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend's highlights are back to our 1 update format as this is a little quieter. There's a bunch of exciting "summer" events on, though, which we should highlight up here: in the UK, Eastbourne Extreme takes derby outside and to the coast for a 2 day mixed tournament; in France, Saint-Gratien once again hosts the pan-France Tournament of 6 Regions; and in Bundaberg, Australia, the 2019 SKATE of Emergency continues to raise funds for emergency services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(We'd also like to highlight the next "Un sol para lxs oficialxs", raising travel funds for Argentinian officials to support Roller Derby across the country; and on a different note ALL-IN's Short Track Experiment event in Leeds, exploring the new ruleset and how it might help to sustain &amp;amp; develop the sport.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article amended on Tuesday for two late announced fixtures in Spain and Mexico.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/07/13Jul-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-13072019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>australian roller derby</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>italian roller derby</category><category>mexican roller derby</category><category>national tournaments</category><category>new zealand roller derby</category><category>short track roller derby</category><category>spanish roller derby</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-13072019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 18:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Guest Post: SKIR Golden Edition</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/skir2019-hazzard/</link><dc:creator>hazzard</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last month, Italy's largest Roller Derby tournament, Skate Im Ring (SKIR) held its Golden Edition, as always in Bolzano. Luckily for us, New Town Roller Derby's Hazzard
was attending, and has been good enough to provide us with this guest article!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 22nd and 23rd of June, 8 Italian roller derby teams and a swathe of officials had arrived at Arena Ritten, just outside of Bolzano in the North of Italy. They were to participate in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/423438998225036/"&gt;Skate Im Ring (SKIR) Golden Edition&lt;/a&gt; [link to Facebook] hosted by the Alp’n Rockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Image of the venue (Arena Ritten)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/07/ArenaRitten.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The fantastic Arena Ritten, host venue for SKIR 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weekend was the 4th edition of the SKIR and was its biggest edition so far.
The tournament consisted of a day of single-period ranking games and a day of full games. The teams were split into two groups and then seeded to go head to head with their counterparts in the other group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meeting with two of the organisers of SKIR, Betty Burp and Billi, we chatted about the previous editions of SKIR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/skir2019-hazzard/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>guest posts</category><category>italian roller derby</category><category>national tournaments</category><category>skate im ring</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/skir2019-hazzard/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 06 July 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-06072019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend's highlights are back to our two update format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's not one, but two national championships decided this weekend, as the finals of the Finnish National Championships and the first ever ARDE Spanish National Championships both fall here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/07/06Jul-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-06072019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentine roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>bootcamp</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>ecuadorian roller derby</category><category>finnish roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>irish roller derby</category><category>italian roller derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>mexican roller derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>new zealand roller derby</category><category>roller derby sevens</category><category>spanish roller derby</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-06072019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 29 June 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-29062019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend's highlights are back to our two update format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've broken our rule slightly for Germany this weekend, as it's important not to miss the Mine Monsters' birthday game, but also it's a good weekend for the German Bundesliga in Erfurt. And as usual there's so much stuff in France, we're giving them two entries for two two-day events...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also two firsts this weekend; the first ever Tasmanian Tournament kicks off in Australia, and the first ever Norwegian National Tournament (and Championship) is this weekend in Sadnes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/29Jun-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-29062019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentine roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>austrian roller derby</category><category>belgian roller derby</category><category>brazilian roller derby</category><category>british championships</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>costa rican roller derby</category><category>czech roller derby</category><category>estonian roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>irish roller derby</category><category>italian roller derby</category><category>mexican roller derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>new zealand roller derby</category><category>norwegian roller derby</category><category>south african roller derby</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-29062019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 19:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 22 June 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-22062019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend's highlights are back to our two update format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a good weekend for tournaments - with two tournaments of interest to us in the USA (ECDX, where a lot of European, as well as US, teams try to get last-minute games for WFTDA eligibility requirements; and Hawai'i's Big Island Brawl, as Okinawa are there); but also two National or quasi-National tournaments in Europe (Spain's first ever Division 2 playoffs, and the sort-of-Italian-national-tournament Skake Im Ring).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/22Jun-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-22062019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (8 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>australian roller derby</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>chilean roller derby</category><category>dutch roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>irish roller derby</category><category>italian roller derby</category><category>mexican roller derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>new zealand roller derby</category><category>norwegian roller derby</category><category>okinawan roller derby</category><category>rollerderbyhawaii</category><category>russian roller derby</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>spanish roller derby</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-22062019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 15:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>