<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about jakey bites)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/jakey-bites.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Jakey Bites vs Barrow Infernos</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/10/27/the-jakey-bites-vs-barrow-infernos/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 2 November, &lt;a title="The Jakey Bites Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/TheJakeyBites?fref=ts" target="_blank"&gt;The Jakey Bites &lt;/a&gt;will take on &lt;a title="Barrow Infernos Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/BarrowInfernos?filter=3" target="_blank"&gt;Barrow Infernos&lt;/a&gt; in Grangemouth Sports Complex, at 4pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both teams are keen to hold onto their recent winning streaks, with Barrow beating &lt;a title="Wirral Men's Roller Derby Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/ThePackAnimals" target="_blank"&gt;Wirral Men's Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="Bairn City Rollers Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers" target="_blank"&gt;Bairn City Rollers' &lt;/a&gt;Skelpies, where as The Jakey's have beaten &lt;a title="Team Steve Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Team-Steve/261667917252555?fref=ts" target="_blank"&gt;Team Steve &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a title="Super Smash Broller Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/supersmashbrollers" target="_blank"&gt;Super Smash Brollers&lt;/a&gt;. If you are yet to see any Men's Roller Derby, this will be a great first experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The November bout will be The Jakey's first outing since July, when &lt;a title="The Jakey Bites Take on Europe!" href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/10/the-jakey-bites-take-on-europe/" target="_blank"&gt;they played in the Men's European Roller Derby Championships&lt;/a&gt;. The team played excellently in the tournament, and learnt a lot from the experience that they have taken back to the training room. Their hard work will hopefully pay off when they come face-to-face with the team from Barrow-In-Furness next weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are now available online through &lt;a title="Buy tickets online" href="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=6E973R82UPT76" target="_blank"&gt;PayPal&lt;/a&gt;. Join the &lt;a title="Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/577858578940889/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt; to keep up-to-date with the latest news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/10/jakey-bites-poster1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2995" alt="Image courtesy of The Jakey Bites" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/10/jakey-bites-poster1.jpg" width="614" height="867"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of The Jakey Bites&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>barrow infernos</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>jakey bites</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>the jakey bites</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/10/27/the-jakey-bites-vs-barrow-infernos/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 18:10:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Jakey Bites Take on Europe!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/07/10/the-jakey-bites-take-on-europe/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/merdc-logo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2762" alt="MERDC Logo" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/merdc-logo.jpg" width="250" height="250"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of MERDC
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="The Jakey Bites Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/TheJakeyBites" target="_blank"&gt;The Jakey Bites&lt;/a&gt; are gearing up for their debut appearance in the upcoming &lt;a title="MERDC Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/MensEuropeanRollerDerbyChampionships" target="_blank"&gt;Men's European Roller Derby Championships&lt;/a&gt;! The tournament will be spread over the weekend of Saturday 20th July and Sunday 21st July, hosted in Birmingham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only the second MERDC tournament, so the organisers are keen to pull out all the stops to make their mark. The number of teams participating between last year and this year has increased from 7 to 16, and from the discussions on Facebook, it looks like the venue will be jam-packed with team merchandise and stock from the tournament sponsors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2012 winners, &lt;a title="Southern Discomfort Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/southerndiscomfortrd" target="_blank"&gt;Southern Discomfort&lt;/a&gt;, will be back to guard their title from teams from France, Wales, England, and Scotland. &lt;a title="The Inhuman League Facebook Page" href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/inhumanleague" target="_blank"&gt;The Inhuman League&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="South Wales Silures Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/SiluresRollerDerby" target="_blank"&gt;South Wales Silures&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a title="Quad Guards Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/QuadGuards" target="_blank"&gt;Quad Guards&lt;/a&gt; from Toulouse, will be joining The Jakeys in putting up a strong fight to take home the Cup. As well as getting the chance to watch all of these fantastic teams in action, The Jakeys are hoping to come up against &lt;a title="Super Smash Brollers Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/supersmashbrollers" target="_blank"&gt;Super Smash Brollers&lt;/a&gt;, as former Jakey - Danimal - has recently joined their team after moving to England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday will set the tournament off to a flying start, with 20 bouts played over 2 tracks. From the line-up issued by the MERDC, The Jakeys will take on Manchester's &lt;a title="New Wheeled Order Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/NewWheeledOrder" target="_blank"&gt;New Wheeled Order &lt;/a&gt;in the third bout of the tournament. By the end of the day, only 8 teams will remain to fight it out for a place on the leaderbord. On Sunday, spectators can settle down to watch all the action from 1 track. They will be treated to the Semi-Finals, Third Place Play-offs, and then THREE Finals!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When asking The Jakeys how they are preparing for the tournament, team skater WK Deid told us, "At Jakey HQ we have been taking preparation for the Euros very seriously, which isn’t like us at all. In addition to our normal Jakey training sessions and our other leagues training (Capital City, Mean City &amp;amp; Bairn City Rollers) we are scrimming almost every week or bouting. We have recently played Team Steve (and celebrated our first win!) and will play &lt;a title="GCRG's Facebook Event" href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/232381250219767/" target="_blank"&gt;Granite City’s co-ed bout&lt;/a&gt; in the two weeks before the tournament".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/jakey-bites.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2792" alt="Jakey Bites vs Team Steve" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/jakey-bites.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Jakey Bites vs Team Steve - Image courtesy of Dave McAleavy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cult Friction from Dundee Roller Girls will be on the road with The Jakeys as their Line Up Manager. She has built a strong relationship with the men's team after training and skating with them since September 2012. Cult was Bench Manager for The Jakeys in their bout against the Crash Test Brummies in 2012, and her involvement has escalated from there. She told us that, "Skating with the guys every week has resulted in fantastic relationships and friendships with them, as a team and individually. I know how they all skate like the back of my hand so I guess becoming the Line Up Manager was a natural progression. They have taught me a lot in the last 10 months and always push me to up my game so it is an absolute pleasure to be their Line Up at MERDC. I think they will make us all proud at the MERDC tournament and will give a great representation of Men's Roller Derby in Scotland". We couldn't agree more, Cult!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/cult-friction.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2805" alt="Cult Friction at The Jakeys v South Wales Silures - Image courtesy of Claire Brunton" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/cult-friction.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Cult Friction at The Jakeys v South Wales Silures - Image courtesy of Claire Brunton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Buy MERDC on EventBrite" href="https://merdc2013.eventbrite.co.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;Tickets are available online&lt;/a&gt; until 17th July, priced at £20 for a day pass, or £30 for a weekend pass. Keep up to date with the latest tournament news by joining the &lt;a title="MERDC Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/MensEuropeanRollerDerbyChampionships#!/events/661336940559208/" target="_blank"&gt;MERDC Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>jakey bites</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>merdc</category><category>the jakey bites</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/07/10/the-jakey-bites-take-on-europe/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 11:24:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Double Header: GCRG Presents Cherry Poppers and Co-ed</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/05/31/double-header-gcrg-presents-cherry-poppers-and-co-ed/</link><dc:creator>zenrhe</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Girls are proud to announce an exciting day of Roller Derby to take place at the home of our sisters - Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We will be supplying you derby fans with two exciting bouts!
&lt;p&gt;Granite City’s co-ed team ‘&lt;strong&gt;Of Fights and Men&lt;/strong&gt;’ skate together for the first time against the much respected and fantastic ‘&lt;strong&gt;Jakey Tayzers&lt;/strong&gt;’.
So come along and watch the mixed teams of men and women battle it out on track!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s not all...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are so excited to also announce that the first bout of the day will be&lt;strong&gt; an all female ‘Cherry Popper’&lt;/strong&gt; to get you warmed up! Two teams made up from 7 different Scottish leagues, with some skaters making their debut. Ladies from Nasty Nessies Roller Girls, Dundee Roller Girls, Bairn City Rollers, Fierce Valley Roller Girls, Auld Reekie Roller Girls, Glasgow Roller Derby and of course Granite City. Watch, support and take note -
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; You will be witnessing some of Scotland’s best new talent on track.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="ngg-singlepic ngg-center" alt="Double Header 130713" src="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/wp-content/gallery/events/double_header_130713.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So get this date in to your diaries, it's not to be missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets on Sale soon! Online Advance: £5, Door: £6 Under 14s Free with paying adult
Doors open: 11.30am. First bout 12pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cakes, Merchandise and Local Vendors will also be there.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;Join our &lt;span class="fblink"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/232381250219767/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disc&lt;/strong&gt;
Dundee International Sports Centre, Mains Loan - Dundee
&lt;a href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/locations/disc-2/"&gt;Details&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date/Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date(s) - 13/07/2013
&lt;i&gt;11:30 am - 5:00 pm&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Disc" href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/locations/disc-2/"&gt;Disc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[googlemaps https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=s_q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=Disc+Dundee+International+Sports+Centre,+Mains+Loan,+Dundee&amp;amp;aq=3&amp;amp;oq=dundee+in&amp;amp;sll=53.800651,-4.064941&amp;amp;sspn=10.717687,28.54248&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hq=Disc+Dundee+International+Sports+Centre,&amp;amp;hnear=Mains+Loan,+Dundee,+Dundee+City,+United+Kingdom&amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;ll=56.476266,-2.958927&amp;amp;spn=0.008882,0.006295&amp;amp;output=embed&amp;amp;w=425&amp;amp;h=350]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>aberdeen</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>double header</category><category>dundee</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>jakey bites</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/05/31/double-header-gcrg-presents-cherry-poppers-and-co-ed/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 10:44:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Jakey Bites Vs The Crash Team Brummies</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/09/23/the-jakey-bites-vs-the-crash-team-brummies/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/09/hotwheel.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/09/hotwheel.jpg" alt="" title="hotwheel" width="509" height="720" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1747"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of How Wheel Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/The-Jakey-Bites-Scottish-Mens-Roller-Derby/190825187685857?ref=ts"&gt;Jakey Bites&lt;/a&gt; travel down south to take on the mighty &lt;a href="http://www.crashtestbrummies.co.uk/"&gt;Crash Test Brummies&lt;/a&gt;.Its part of a double-header,the main event being a clash between Hot Wheel Roller Derby and Lincolnshire Bombers Roller Girls.
For those that wish to make the trip,you can buy tickets in advance &lt;a href="https://www.paypal.com/uk/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_flow&amp;amp;SESSION=L7g3Gtt5RFKi2i4yTcVcYfiRubC1V7Pl_rjw32Ol21eZY8rsfUeaQ5fI03q&amp;amp;dispatch=50a222a57771920b6a3d7b606239e4d529b525e0b7e69bf0224adecfb0124e9b61f737ba21b08198c76d66ace6699a60677529753b095fab"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and find more details at the Facebook &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/281884055211964/"&gt;event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other recent Scottish Mens Roller Derby news,we welcome not one,but two new leagues recently set up.To find out more,register your interest,or simply say hello,have a look at the Facebook pages for Glasgow's &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby?ref=stream"&gt;Mean City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and Falkirk's &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>jakey bites</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/09/23/the-jakey-bites-vs-the-crash-team-brummies/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 12:15:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Co-ed derby...it's not just for the girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/07/07/co-ed-derby-its-not-just-for-the-girls/</link><dc:creator>pandacatkaty</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/07/co-ed-derby.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/07/co-ed-derby.jpg?w=487" alt="Image"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The creation of the Jakey Bites, Scotland's first men's roller derby team, has created an interesting aspect of roller derby, bringing the boys off the sidelines and onto the track.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to attend the first Dundee Roller Girls scrim session that included members of the Jakey Bites, who were preparing for their first bout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beforehand, some of the girls I had spoken to were a bit apprehensive about it; others were really up for it. Some thought that the boys would cause more damage on track, others thought it would be great fun. And besides, the boys weren't as experienced as a lot of the girls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everyone who was there seemed to have a great time, and as a spectator, it was interesting to see the difference between guys and girls on track, what the physical differences between men and women brought to, and took away from, the performances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An interesting observance made to me by a Jakey not that long ago emphasises this point. He told me that men don't do as much hip checking as women. The fact is, that men don't have "hips" per se, their waists are narrow while their shoulders are wide, so they will go for a shoulder/side hit. But this may be where co-ed derby can help shape merby strategy: men skating with women can see how moves like hip checks can be effective and start incorporating that into training sessions. And with most male skaters not using hip checks, it could become an interesting tactic that can give a men's team an edge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I asked for the thoughts of some fellow skaters (male and female) and although it was mostly positive, there were some concerns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley's Frocky Horror said: " Being a Jakey wife I have seen first hand the damage that boys can do to each other, so I wouldn't be happy bouting or scrimming with boys. Having said that at FVRG we trained with our refs and learned to hit with them too. We don't do that now, just right at the start."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During my time at the Fair City Rollers, this was our situation too. Danimal, our league's guy ref, often trained with us, to the point where no one really batted an eyelid when we saw him lacing up his skates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girl Gadget said: "I understand the reservations that some female skaters have about skating with boys. I have done it at DRG before and found it be just as much fun as skating with girls. As it stands now, games are more about tactics than just going out and hitting each other. There is much less hitting than there was when I first started. Legal target zones are always an issue, regardless of sex. If you take Psychomilly for example, she's our tallest skater and struggles with legal target zones, yet is an amazing blocker and hits harder than anyone I know. I think both sides have much to gain from playing co-ed."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nasty Nessie Cherry Bow added: "I feel that women have reached a point now where we can comfortably compete and play alongside with our male counterparts on the track. Women can hit hard and are fast just as there are women who are slower and more tactical. We come in all shapes and sizes and so do the men! There are female skaters out there who weigh more than a male skater (myself included) who can take a hit and stay put regardless if that hit is from a man or a woman. Equally we can give as well as receive and I know there's a few men out there who have been sent flying by a well placed hit from a female skater. Additionally I think this will bring more men into the sport and we need all the fresh blood we can get to make sure this fantastic sport keeps going and evolving."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She even added that she felt there should be co-ed bouts, which would allow for a "new dimension of play".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, a lot of the men don't take for granted that their presence at scrims will be welcomed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Former Jakey Bite and long-time GCRG ref Buffy Boiler explained: "In my opinion co-ed is fine on the proviso that everyone, boys and girls, knows what they're getting into and that there is absolutely no stigma attached to people saying they're not comfortable with doing it. I would never expect to just rock up to a girls league scrim session and be welcomed to play - it would have to be something agreed in advance."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Whether or not there will be co-ed derby bouts remains to be seen, but one thing is for sure...men will be welcomed by many at scrims in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>jakey bites</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/07/07/co-ed-derby-its-not-just-for-the-girls/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 12:09:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow Roller Derby Announce 2012 Home Season</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/06/20/glasgow-roller-derby-announce-2012-home-season/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/06/hometeams-2goodeditweb.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/06/hometeams-2goodeditweb.jpg" alt="" title="HOMETEAMS 2goodeditweb" width="614" height="868" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1396"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby kick off their 2012 Home Season on Saturday the 30th of June with a bout between last years winners,the Death Stars, up against the Bad Omens.
All four Home Season bouts will take place at The Arc and are priced at £5 each,with a &lt;a href="http://regonline.activeeurope.com/Register/Checkin.aspx?EventID=1048961"&gt;season ticket&lt;/a&gt; costing a mere £15.Especially good value ,as not only do you get a bout free,but this first bout will also be a double-header,featuring a Mens Roller Derby clash between Sheffield's mighty Inhuman League and Scotland's very own &lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/06/18/the-jakey-bites-vs-the-inhuman-league/"&gt;Jakey Bites&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bad omens</category><category>death stars</category><category>grd</category><category>hell's belles</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>jakey bites</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/06/20/glasgow-roller-derby-announce-2012-home-season/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 15:07:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tyne and Fear Vs The Jakey Bites-Mens Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/16/tyne-and-fear-vs-the-jakey-bites-mens-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/tyne-jakey.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/tyne-jakey.jpg" alt="" title="tyne jakey" width="614" height="868" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1098"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of Tyne And Fear&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 21st of April 2012,a little bit of Derby history will be made,Scotland's first Mens Roller Derby league,the &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/The-Jakey-Bites-Scottish-Mens-Roller-Derby/190825187685857?ref=ts"&gt;Jakey Bites&lt;/a&gt; will play in their first public bout against Tyne And Fear,brother league to &lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;
The bout is part of a double header,with the first bout of the day between,NRG's Whippin' Hinnies and Hull's &lt;a href="http://hullsangels.wordpress.com/"&gt;Angels Roller Dames&lt;/a&gt;.The action takes place at the Walker Activity Dome,Wharrier Street,Newcastle Upon Tyne,doors open at 12:30pm and entry is £4.50.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>jakey bites</category><category>merby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/16/tyne-and-fear-vs-the-jakey-bites-mens-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 03:08:39 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>