<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about jewish roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/jewish-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Rollercon Nations Tournament 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/08/RNT-2019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the last few years, the National teams bouts have become a fixture of Rollercon.
Founded in 2017, before the last Roller Derby World Cup, they've been a great way for newer, or less visible National teams to be seen; and for raising awareness of the globally diverse nature of Roller Derby in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year was a particularly important point in the tournament's history, as two borderless nations - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/teamindigenousrollerderby/"&gt;Team Indigenous Rising&lt;/a&gt; (link to Facebook), and the new &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/jewishrollerderby/"&gt;Jewish Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; - competed in the tournament, and even played each other. (In fact, even the styling of the series of games as a true, all-day, tournament was a change this year, as previously there had not been enough competitors to realise this.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking for Team Indigenous, Jumpy McGee explained the importance of this to both teams:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Team Indigenous is extremely grateful to have this platform to bring our teams together and highlight that not all humans are defined by borders or citizenship.  There are centuries of displacement, violence, and oppression that have occurred causing people indigenous to their homeland to create home elsewhere.  We believe it was critical then to create a space where players identifying as a member of a nation had a place to belong.  And when WE talk about nation, we're talking about nation in the sense of a collection of humans who have the same cultures, beliefs, languages and traditions who cannot be contained or defined by borders.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2019 Nations tournament was run as an efficient double-elimination bracket, with seedings voted on by the competing teams. This means that each team could lose once in the tournament - that loss knocking them out of the "winners" bracket, and into a sudden-death bracket against other teams with a single loss. The eventual survivor of that sudden death bracket, having proven themselves the best of the teams, other than sole unbeaten team, gets to play in the final against that undefeated remainder. In this case, for time, all games were single period WFTDA-rules bouts, except for the final, run as a full-length WFTDA-rules game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as the two borderless nations, there were also three Asian nations represented: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/teamphilippines_rollerderby/"&gt;Team Philippines&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/teamkorearollerderby/"&gt;Team Korea&lt;/a&gt;, and Team "Japan-fam" (so named because they did not have a tryout and offered this opportunity to all skaters of Japanese heritage). This is also an important aspect of the event, and has been since it began, with Philippines and Korea founding members in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Action from the Korea / Philippines game, Philippines jammer on inside line passing blocked Korea jammer in pack." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/09/TristanKing-KoreaPhilippines.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Action from Korea versus Philippines (Photo: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/TKvisualarts"&gt;Tristan King&lt;/a&gt; [see link for license])&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As ShortStop noted for Korea, in particular:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
As a small nation, with relatively low representation in Roller Derby, [we] submitted an initial roster that included 8 Koreans, two skaters from OH Roller Derby Team (the only roller derby league in South Korea), and skaters from China, Vietnam, Thailand and Hong Kong. All of our non-Korean Asians are currently involved in building their own nations teams, and we thought it was a wonderful way to include them as start to gather their own teams.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Philippines' Electric PIRANHA, it's an equally strong, and personally important opportunity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
I have played sports throughout my whole life and have been playing roller derby now for four years. I never once in my life thought I would be able to represent a national team, a team that represents my heritage and culture. I had the opportunity to represent Team Philippines at the World Cup in Manchester and just recently in the Nations Tournament at RollerCon. Words cannot describe the feeling I get skating for Team Philippines. I am surrounded by smart, beautiful, athletic Filipinas. When we are together, there is an extraordinary and undeniable bond we have, like we've been skating together as a team for years when we only have had the chance to skate together a handful of times. We represent a country that has gone through colonization, war, and the fight for independence. I skate for my cultural heritage and I skate for my family. #pamilypirst #poweredbylumpia #poweredbyrice&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even for Japan, where there has been derby in some form for more than a decade, visibility is low, as we've discussed before on this blog.
Kris Rago, for Japan-fam noted to us that this was a factor in their participation here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Japan Fam was unique in the sense that roller derby is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/rdjapan/photos/a.316960268326566/2053816941307548/?type=3&amp;amp;permPage=1"&gt;present in Japan&lt;/a&gt; and that some of our skaters from both Japan and Hawaii were able to fly over and join our U.S. Japanese skaters. It was really wonderful to be able to come together and work together to represent our heritage and do amazing things on the track. My hope is more opportunities like this will help to strengthen the relationship between our U.S. Japanese skaters and skaters and leagues in Japan.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/08/RNT-2019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>international roller derby</category><category>jewish roller derby</category><category>team canada roller derby</category><category>team indigenous rising</category><category>team indigenous roller derby</category><category>team korea roller derby</category><category>team philippines roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/08/RNT-2019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 20:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Jewish Roller Derby: shining a light.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/29/jewish-roller-derby-shining-a-light/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;From almost its inception, Roller Derby has been a fertile ground for "exhibition" teams built around a common experience, from the light-hearted ("Tall and gangly skaters") through the more heartfelt ("surviving a serious injury", "possessing a hidden or invisible illness"). National Teams are themselves built on the same concept: an expression of a common aspect of identity, drawn from a sense of belonging to or of a particular geographical region, culture or ethnicity.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;A positive effect of all such teams is that they can give visibility to the concerns and experiences of the community they represent; this can be, and commonly is, the founding aim of such a team. This is certainly the case for the newest such project: the Jewish Roller Derby team, which launched only a few weeks ago.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We talked to Jewish Roller Derby's founders, Tiggz and Jodi Bon Jodi, both from Rose City Rollers, about their aims for the team, and how you can be involved.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Tiggz was drawn to form the team partly from her experience within another team drawn from shared history: the 2018 Team Russia Roller Derby. Whilst she enjoyed her time in a National Team and at the World Cup, she was conscious that she didn’t experience the same level of shared-history as the rest of the team did with each other. As the only team member qualifying via a relative with Russian-Jewish heritage, Tiggz was drawn to think about the importance of that other aspect of her culture.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;This experience was, perhaps, emphasised by living and working in Portland, itself a city with a very small Jewish population (as Jodi noted to us, “if I played for Gotham, maybe I’d not have felt the same need to make a team to represent Jewish people”, given New York’s ownership of the largest Jewish community outside Israel).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;But, more than that, it was also the feeling that this was a time when Jewishness needed more voices to counter rising bigotry which drove the pairs’ final decision to make the team.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;It would take considerable ignorance of history to not be aware of the long-standing spectre of anti-Semitism across the world. Whilst many vocal proponents of this insidious bigotry became quieter in the later half of the 20th century, over the last few decades (and especially the last few years), anti-Semitic speech and conspiracy theories have once again become a dangerous thread in politics, on both sides of the Atlantic Ocean, and elsewhere. Only a few days ago, for example, a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://edition.cnn.com/interactive/2018/11/europe/antisemitism-poll-2018-intl/"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;CNN International poll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; reported that around a quarter of Europeans polled believed that "Jews have too much influence in business and finance" and "have too much influence in conflict and wars worldwide", and similar figures are reported from the USA. Coupled with dog-whistle attacks from powerful world leaders, and an alarming increase in anti-Semitism motivated murders and assaults worldwide, it's an increasingly dangerous and difficult time to be Jewish.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;One way in which we can counter bigotry is to educate and shine a light on those groups discriminated against; bigotry stems from ignorance, and merely being more visible can help to fight fear and intolerance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The word and concept of "Jewishness" incorporates, inherently, a number of interrelated-yet-distinct qualities - belief in (and or practice of) a particular religion, participation in a particular culture, possession of a particular ethnicity or lineage - which any particular Jewish person may participate in all aspects of, or only some or one. (Indeed, there are multiple ethnic divisions within the overall “Jewish ethnicity”, with distinct traditions and languages.) As such, Tiggz and JBJ consider the question of "eligibility" of applicants to be one that should be settled by the applicant themselves, not imposed by a strict definition.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"I'd say to someone wanting to know if they can apply: ask yourself, 'what would it mean to you to be part of a Jewish Roller Derby team?', and decide based on that", says Tiggz.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;In fact, the founders are excited to see what a spectrum of Jewishness sign up for the project: from people of the Ashkenazi heritage who form the basis for much of Europe’s idea of “Jewish”, through Sephardim, Mizrahim, Maghrebhim and others; and to take opportunities to educate both each other and the Roller Derby community about their diversity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The first "competitive aim" for the Jewish Roller Derby project is to field a WFTDA-gender-policy team at the next Rollercon, against an opponent to be decided. After that, the founders have no concrete plans, although there's always more teams that can be challenged; from National teams to others attached to important campaigns.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;More importantly, of course, the Jewish Roller Derby project aims to, whatever bouts it participates in, provide both a space in which Jewish skaters can find community with one-another, and a space and platform for educating and advocating for the Jewish community, at a time when it is needed once again. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The Jewish Roller Derby project can be contacted via Facebook on their page: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/jewishrollerderby/"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/jewishrollerderby/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; and by email at:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:jewishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; jewishrollerderby@gmail.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;If you want to apply to be in the team for the exhibition bout at Rollercon 2019, you can do so via this form: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfEUYxozZdqzMXfPFQsJe2K4I3ZaD411U0NZSVApkWHMMv5Cg/viewform"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfEUYxozZdqzMXfPFQsJe2K4I3ZaD411U0NZSVApkWHMMv5Cg/viewform&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>in the news</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>jewish roller derby</category><category>rollercon</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/29/jewish-roller-derby-shining-a-light/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 11:48:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>