<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about junior derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/junior-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:41:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Future of Derby: Junior Roller Derby, Part One</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/09/the-future-of-derby-junior-roller-derby-part-one/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing on the theme of the future of roller derby, we turn our attention to the rapidly expanding world of junior derby. As the junior expo game at the World Cup showed, there is a wealth of talent coming through, ready to make the transition to the adult leagues. Closer to home, more leagues throughout the UK are setting up their own juniors sessions. Tiger Bay Cubs have been skating since January 2012 and hosted the landmark first public junior derby bout in the UK. We spoke to coach Pretty Grimm about the trials of setting up and developing a junior league, and their future vision for the Cubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was behind your decision to set up a junior league?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our junior league was founded by two skaters in the adults league that had a real passion and drive for making roller derby available to juniors. One skater is a high school teacher and really believes in what roller derby can do for young adults' confidence and development. We felt as a group of individuals that roller derby helps you grow on and off the track, not only do you get to learn an awesome sport and all the physical skills within that but it also gives the opportunity for young people to develop really essential life skills such as communication, working as a team and being comfortable discussing ideas and giving feedback to peers and authority figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is your league aimed at? Gender, age group etc?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our league is aimed at any young adult between the age of 11-17. We want to be as inclusive as possible and are happy to teach people to skate safely and pass their skating minimum skills whether they progress to blocking minimum skills and eventually playing roller derby. If they decide that roller derby is not for them and they just want to skate we encourage them to still come to skate to work on their skills and have fun skating and maybe try out reffing or NSOing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What obstacles did you face in setting up your league?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of things to consider when setting up a junior league. Firstly we needed to make sure that we were following government guidelines and our coaches all have the required safety checks to work with children and young adults. We are very fortunate that we have support from our local government which includes us in a programme for young adults to try out different sports. This programme helped us ensure that we adhered to all the guidelines set out for us and gave us a regular training spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensuring that the Tiger Bay Cubs was an affordable, approachable and available league was also a struggle at first. We wanted to make sure that people could join no matter what their circumstances. We therefore offer kit hire for free and the skating sessions for free however fundraising and helping the league financially is often difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recruiting new members and having people be aware of us is and has always been a struggle. Coaches who have full time jobs as well as adult league training on top of being a junior league coach can struggle to make time in the day to get out to schools to promote the junior league. However we have goals set in place for a recruitment drive in early 2015 which will hopefully battle some of these issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you received much support from your local community and the derby community?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our junior derby community although very small is very supportive. Parents of the junior league members have always been very supportive. Some of the parents of our members have actually started playing roller derby themselves as a result. Other parents travel over an hour to get their kids to practice and we have a committee which is partly made up of parents too.
The roller derby community is always supportive of other roller derby leagues (big or small quite literally) without the support of adult roller derby players we wouldn't have such a strong league now. We have been going almost 3 years now which is incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you do any research into interest in junior derby?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something we are currently trying to work on with our local government support officer. We want to get out and see how many local schools know about us and if we can offer taster sessions during school hours to get us to increase interest and skater numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a wider scale we have a great relationship with our UKRDA reps especially Judge Redd who is the Junior Derby Director on the board of directors for the UKRDA. We work to get our juniors bouting and playing other leagues around the UK. We are currently discussing more bouting opportunities around the country so stay tuned for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you affiliated to any groups/organisations, either derby related or otherwise?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above we have a great amount of support from our local government. They are a pivotal part in the running on the junior league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What have biggest challenges been in becoming a bouting team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numbers, money and finding teams to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skater numbers can always be an issue especially when you have young adults reaching adulthood and have other commitments such as school work, part time jobs and socialising outside of school. We are very fortunate to have some very dedicated skaters in our league both old and new who have stuck with us and have helped us reach a point where we are able to start bouting publically again.
We also recently had a group of players who turned 18 which meant that they were unable to skate for the junior league any longer which left a big gap in our team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we are a community supported league we struggle with being able to fund a lot of things that we need in order to run as a league and thing such as hall hire for a bout is just too far out of our reach at the moment. We are however working very hard with our government support officer to increase numbers, training time, awareness of the sport and hopefully that will mean that our numbers will grow and we will be able to organise another home game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also try to apply for a lot of community grants to help support the league however these are in high demand from sports clubs all over South Wales. We have previously had grant funding and put that into kit to enable skaters to come to try out the sport without the financial burden of buying equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently in discussions with the UKRDA and other junior leagues about more regular junior games and hopefully working towards a junior weekend tournament which would be super exciting. So watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much difficulty have you faced in finding opponents?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding a full team of 14 to play at the moment is extremely difficult however we do not have a full team of 14 ourselves! Bouting with a full roster of a junior league is just not feasible at the moment. However as we mentioned above we are looking into how we can play other leagues with reduced numbers, logistics of travel etc and how we can bring help advance the current state of junior roller derby at this time.
Hopefully early 2015 will bring some exciting new things for junior roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is your overall aim for your league?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to be inclusive to all those who want to skate. We are happy to develop all female, all male and co-ed teams to have a strong bouting junior roller derby league. Our juniors currently train as a co-ed team and we hope with more members we can build a strong team for all three types of bouting derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to be able to play across the UK and Europe and maybe even one day play internationally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where would you like to be in a year, and in 5 years?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a league in a year's time we would like to have more bouting experience under our belt and of course work towards getting a full roster of skaters to bouting level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 5 year's time we would like to be bouting regularly and have a few tournaments under our belt maybe even one in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; What do you see as being important in the future of junior derby in the UK?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support and nourishment of junior teams. Junior roller derby helps pave the future for our adult leagues in years to come. We need support from our adult leagues, the community, parents and our local authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also important to give young adults the opportunity to learn and grow at an early age. It's very exciting to think what that could mean for not only junior derby in itself but also adult derby when junior skaters turn 18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching our junior skaters over the past three years has been awesome. Not just for their ability to skate but also to see what type of people they are becoming. Roller derby doesn't just become exercise for these skaters, similarly to the adults league it becomes part of who you are. Many of our skaters who have been with us for the three years have become amazing individuals and we need more of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you think it's important to have a junior Derby infrastructure in the UK, i.e. for setting up tournaments etc.?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion yes. Everyone involved in roller derby can agree that it is a sport that takes up a lot of time and when you are a volunteer to your adult league, junior league, your job and your family as well as trying to raise funds, awareness and find time to skate it can be very difficult to work towards the bigger picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having an infrastructure and support on a wider scale would help advance junior derby further than where we are at, at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also from a skater's perspective it is that driving force of something to work towards. If we were able to have tournaments or even more regular games it would help grow the sport and keep the current skaters we have.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>future derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/09/the-future-of-derby-junior-roller-derby-part-one/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 09:29:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs : One Year On</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/31/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-one-year-on/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, 1st September 2013, a little bit of Scottish roller derby history was made, when the first Fierce Valley Roller Cubs, and first junior derby, training session took place. A year has passed, and many more firsts have been achieved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/cubstaster.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3650" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/cubstaster.jpg?w=300" alt="cubstaster" width="300" height="199"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the official start date was September 2013, the history of the Cubs actually stretches back much further, to around November 2011. A number of obstacles, not least funding, had to be overcome before getting our first intake of kids on skates, but when it finally happened, we were overwhelmed by the level of interest and support that we attracted. Our first two taster sessions were very well attended and a large number of those first Cubs are still with us today. It was as steep a learning curve for the coaches as for the Cubs themselves, working towards JRDA skills and assessments and figuring out how to adapt training plans to suit juniors. As word spread and interest grew, and many of our first batch of recruits passed their level one assessments, we were able to hold another taste session before Christmas and start a new intake in January.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the Cubs kept progressing, passing their level two assessments, it became clear that the four training sessions every Sunday wouldn’t be enough for our growing numbers and increasing skill levels, so a third session, on Friday evenings, was introduced for level three skaters. This session focuses on learning derby as opposed to skating skills, and has proven very popular. More recently, we've stopped splitting level one and two into juniors and seniors so all of our skaters, regardless of age, train together from the beginning.&lt;br&gt; As well as increasing numbers of kids taking part - we had further intakes at Easter and in the summer, we also have a dedicated parents' committee who organise fundraising and social events for the Cubs, the first of which was a successful Easter family fun day. It's great to know that we have a reliable group of supportive parents who are willing to help out in lots of different ways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the highlights of the first year was being asked to take part in a demonstration scrimmage at half time at an ARRG bout in May. It was a fantastic experience for those who took part to skate at Meadowbank in front of a crowd, and also to meet the skaters afterwards. We're grateful to everyone involved for letting the Cubs be part of the day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The biggest event in the past year has been, without a doubt, their first public game, which was also the first ever public junior roller derby game played in Scotland. We held a four day summer school in the run up to the game, to finalise those skills and tactics, with guest coaches from FVRG and PoS. We had a great turnout for the day itself and the kids thoroughly enjoyed themselves, showing what they can do. It was fantastic to see the support from the wider derby community and a proud moment for the coaches to see everything coming together on track.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/cubsbout.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3651" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/cubsbout.jpg?w=300" alt="cubsbout" width="300" height="126"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking back, it's hard to believe that a year has passed since the first Cubs session, but at the same time, it's difficult to remember a time that the Cubs didn't exist! The past year hasn't been without its challenges but the overwhelming success of the Cubs makes it worthwhile. As coaches, we have learned so much, and we are very lucky to have such a fantastic group of kids to work with. We currently have over forty skaters over three different levels , and each one of them impresses us with their hard work, determination and enthusiasm every time they put on their skaters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what's next for Fierce Valley Roller Cubs? We're planning another intake before the end of the year, and - exclusive - their second game. We can't wait to see where the next year will take us!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Photos courtesy of Claire Brunton of Zenspirations Photography.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/31/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-one-year-on/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 18:09:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs make Derby History!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/15/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-make-derby-history/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of first last weekend, from Gotham coming to the UK, through Dundee's debut of their B-team... but perhaps the most important event for the future of Scottish Derby occurred at Grangemouth Sports Centre on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After considerable hard work, from both the coaches and organisers, the skaters themselves (and encouragement from parents), Scotland's only Junior Roller Derby league, &lt;a href="http://www.fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs&lt;/a&gt;, held their first ever public bout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/10491187_665792883505850_5377019356439535080_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3540" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/10491187_665792883505850_5377019356439535080_n.jpg?w=660" alt="The Cubs, and Friends (Photo: Laura MacDonald)" width="660" height="440"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Cubs, and Friends (Photo: Laura MacDonald)&lt;p&gt;After a hard-fought game, with Team White taking and holding an early lead through to the end, despite continual resistance from Team Black, the bout ended &lt;strong&gt;White 219:168 Black&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We asked the Captains of both teams (Bon Jodie for Team White, and Purple Punisher for Team Black) to give us their own words about the bout experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bon Jodie&lt;/strong&gt;: I'm 'Bon Jodie' and I had the honour of captaining one team in Fierce Valley Roller Cubs' first public intraleague bout. To captain was an exhilarating experience and to bout for the first time was phenomenal. I was more nervous about bouting for the first time than captaining my team, but I did feel a responsibility from the start to make sure that everyone's spirits were high and they weren't too nervous and were enjoying themselves. Even though in the upcoming days I was extremely conflicted about my feelings towards my bout the second the first whistle blew the nerves were replaced by what I can only describe as determination and adrenaline rush combined. I was very proud of my team, and the other team as we all did so well, afterwards I won MVP during the awards and I was completely overjoyed, overall it was an amazing day I hope to experience again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purple Punisher&lt;/strong&gt;: The bout was meant to be fun and it was just that! Being involved and being captain for the first junior roller derby bout in Scotland was extremely nerve wracking because there was nothing to live up to, we were setting the example. We learnt so much from the bout and the crowd really helped settle the nerves. We made history and being captain was amazing!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bout awards were:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Jammer&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Arch Enemy&lt;/em&gt; (Team White), &lt;em&gt;Haylstone&lt;/em&gt; (Team Black)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Blocker&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Teeny Bash&lt;/em&gt; (Team White), &lt;em&gt;Crimson Crusader&lt;/em&gt; (Team Black)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MVP&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Bon Jodie&lt;/em&gt; (Team White), &lt;em&gt;Stunaimi&lt;/em&gt; (Team Black)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>interviews</category><category>intraleague</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/15/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-make-derby-history/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 19:44:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs Summer School</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/06/17/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-summer-school/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs have enjoyed a very busy and successful time since their launch in September, and are marking this by holding their first ever Summer School.  Running from the 7th to 11th July in the Mariner Centre, Falkirk, each day will focus on a different level, for both new and current skaters, with the option to attend one or more session.  Skaters can look forward to learning lots of new skills, some special guest coaches, and a trip to Blair Drummond Safari Park to finish off the week.  More exciting than that, Saturday the 12th will see the Cubs' first ever public game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/06/summer-school.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/06/summer-school.jpg?w=614" alt="summer school" width="614" height="868" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-3499"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email cubs@fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk to book or for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/06/17/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-summer-school/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 08:36:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs are recruiting!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/06/17/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-are-recruiting/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs are excited to announce their fourth intake of new skaters!  Open to girls and boys aged between 5 and 17, the taster session will take place on Sunday 29th June in the Mariner Centre, Falkirk.  Email freshmeat@fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk for more details.
&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/06/fresh-meat-june-2014-page-001.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/06/fresh-meat-june-2014-page-001.jpg?w=614" alt="fresh meat June 2014-page-001" width="614" height="868" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-3493"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/06/17/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-are-recruiting/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 08:25:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Review 2014: Fierce Valley Roller Cubs</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/20/derby-review-2014-fierce-valley-roller-cubs/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Latest in a series of year review interviews, we catch up with Crash Overload, Vice Chair and Head Coach of the Fierce Valley Roller Cubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/trial3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/trial3.jpg" alt="Photography by Zenspirations Photography" width="614" height="409" class="size-full wp-image-2932"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photography by Zenspirations Photography&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's been a busy year for the Fierce Valley Roller Cubs,from raising awareness and funds with events to running your first trial sessions. What have been the highs, and lows, of the past year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These last six months have definitely been a rollercoaster.  The highs include seeing the interest in roller derby from local children and watching them progress from their fresh meat taster session in September to taking on their Level 1 training and for many of them passing this assessment and progressing on to the next level of training.  The cubs are so enthusiastic and its fantastic to see them coming along to bouts to support their local roller derby teams as well as fully taking on the challenges that roller derby brings. 
We have since taken in another new batch of skaters in January and we are all enjoying watching our league expand and grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, we haven't seen many lows this year and the cubs committee and coaches all work hard to communicate and take the league forward with the interests of the skaters in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The idea to run a Junior League goes back a little further than the past year, first considered in 2011, it's fair to say it's taken longer than you might have liked to get to where you are now. What does it mean to to have The Cubs up and running for those who have been part of that long process?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's true that it's taken a long time to get the Cubs off the ground, the idea was first born in 2011 as a committee of FVRG, but due to a number of factors - mainly money - we couldn't get past the idea stage for a while.   When things really started to happen, around summer 2013, everything happened really quickly and it's not an exaggeration to say that we haven't stopped since then.  For those that have been involved from the start, it's still hard to believe how far we've come in a short period of time.  Looking at our current groups of skaters and seeing the interest in the Cubs continue to grow, it's more than we ever hoped for.  Delighted is probably the word to use, not to mention proud!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fierce Valley Roller Cubs are currently the only Junior league in Scotland, and one of a handful in the UK, have you had any help and advice from the other Junior Leagues in the country?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have taken advice from the JRDA website on training and assessments and are part of a page on Facebook for junior derby coaches to chat and swap advice and ideas.  Our coaches all have differing levels of experience of coaching adults and children and with the combined experience we have, we are moving steadily forward.  We have been making contact with other junior leagues in the hope that when our league are ready - we will have teams to play against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are some differences between the Junior Roller Derby ruleset and it's WFTDA parent, which must influence training and teaching methods. What challenges did you face in adapting an adult Fresh Meat session to work with younger skaters?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, in building the teaching plans, we looked at the skillset required and started creating plans designed for children of varying ages - our league starts at age 5 - and abilities.  The skillset required is almost the same as the WFTDA skillset so the basics are the same, its just the methods of teaching that differ.  We spend time talking through things with the cubs, explaining in language they will understand and try to make each drill fun but at the same time encourage practise and repetition in order to get better at the skill in order to move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We play games and run team building events to allow the cubs to talk and get to know each other, as there is not much time for that during a training session.  We also encourage the cubs to attend roller derby bouts run by local adult leagues to allow their understanding of the game and the rules to develop.  We have run a demo scrim for the Level 1 skaters using local adult skaters and refs to show penalties, walls, blocking and jamming skills which all helps to develop the cubs enthusiasm and confidence in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first sessions were held at the beginning of September 2013 and proved very successful, were you surprised at how readily the Cubs soaked up information and skills?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think all of the coaches have been amazed at how quickly the cubs pick up skills and how determined they are - when they fall they just bounce back up and get on with it!  They ask great questions and the rapport between the cubs themselves and between the cubs and the coaches is building and we can see the start of a strong league developing.  The cubs are already talking about being jammers and pivots, getting excited at the prospect of one day starting to bout as a team and its very encouraging for us to see and hear this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We're all familiar with the Roller Derby saved my soul story and how the sport has positively affected many of it's participants. How do you think Derby will impact on these young skaters?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have already seen the impact on some of the cubs, going from being shy and quiet to more confident young individuals.  They are increasing their strength and stamina and are overall positive in their outlook and in their perception of the sport.  They are all developing strong friendships with each other and have found role models in some of the adult skaters and coaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the cubs come along to a bout, we encourage them to come and speak to the skaters and you can see the excitement and awe in their faces.  Some of our older cubs come along to the junior sessions and take the role of mentors for the younger cubs and we encourage them to develop their coaching and mentoring skills which in turn helps with their confidence and increases their commitment to the league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And its not just the children who are impacted by roller derby, many of the adults who have not been involved in the sport before are now attending bouts, not to mention the parents who have signed up for taster sessions themselves as they are keen to try it.  We also have family groups who are now buying skates and spending time as a family skating outdoors or at roller discos so its fantastic to see how the sport can have an effect on an entire family!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lastly,can you tell us what your plans are for The Cubs in the coming year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well right now we are about to move in to another round of assessments and judging by recent training sessions, many of the cubs are looking good to get through this challenge.  JRDA have three skill levels for juniors and by the summer we are hoping to have skaters who will have passed all three levels and can move into advanced training and start working seriously on drills and look towards creating a bouting team.  We have another fresh meat session planned for a new intake of skaters at Easter too.
We are increasing the number of training sessions to accommodate the number of skaters at the different levels and because we also have an age split - 5 to 10 and 11 to 17 - this means double the amount of sessions required at each level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also looking to run another fundraising event in the very near future and hope to host a junior roller derby summer school for skaters of all levels.  So all in all, its been a busy but awesome year so far and all I can say is - onwards and upwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luv n shoves
Crash Overload&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fvrc</category><category>fvrg</category><category>interviews</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/20/derby-review-2014-fierce-valley-roller-cubs/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 22:09:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs Fresh Meat!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/12/04/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-fresh-meat/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/12/cubsfm1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/12/cubsfm1.jpg?w=210" alt="cubsfm" width="210" height="300" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3076"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a hugely successful first intake, Fierce Valley Roller Cubs is looking for new recruits!  Open to girls and boys between the ages of 5 and 17, FVRC is the only junior derby league in Scotland, so why not come along and see what it’s all about?  The session will be held on Sunday 22nd December, 1.30pm-3pm, in the Mariner Centre, Falkirk.  Email cubs@fvrg.co.uk for more details!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/12/04/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-fresh-meat/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 14:24:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Scottish Roller Derby T-Shirts</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/06/scottish-roller-derby-t-shirts/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scottish Roller Derby are rather excited to announce that a limited number of T-shirts are now available. As the blog is run on a not for profit basis, all profits from the sale of this run of t-shirts will go to support the next generation of skaters at the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/fiercevalleyrollercubs"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/imag0130.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/imag0130.jpg" alt="Photography-SandySRDBlog" width="614" height="921" class="size-full wp-image-3018"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photography-SandySRDBlog&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are Gildan Softstyle shirts in white, printed with the Scottish Roller Derby 'Lion Rampant Jammer' design in black. Available in small/med/large/xl and also as a ladies fitted medium. This is a limited run of shirts with a never to be repeated design/colour combination, priced at £10.
You can find them for sale at the upcoming Fierce Valley Roller Girls bouts, or contact the Cubs or Scottish Roller Derby directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reader can win one of these t-shirts, just find &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/scottish.rollerderby"&gt;Scottish Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook, like and share the competition post. A winner will be chosen at random and announced on Saturday the 9th of November.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>competition</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>merchandise</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/06/scottish-roller-derby-t-shirts/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 10:21:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs are go!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/09/12/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-are-go/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time coming, but Fierce Valley Roller Cubs is finally up and rolling!  The idea of forming Scotland’s first junior roller derby league was born in November 2011 with the intention of starting by summer 2012 at the latest.  It’s no secret that we’ve encountered several obstacles along the way, chief among them funding.  Every league will have encountered this at some point, but none of us were quite prepared for how much it would cost for insurance to cover a hall full of little people on skates.  Another issue was venues, with lots of discussion on where we could hold our sessions.  We were worried about finding a venue that would allow us to skate, but the recent increase in popularity of roller derby has helped us out here, and we’re lucky enough to have a venue which is also used by Fierce Valley Roller Girls and Bairn City Rollers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/trial1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/trial1.jpg?w=300" alt="trial1" width="300" height="199" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2930"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While trying to work out the funding problem we raised our profile by attending FVRG bouts and events, selling merchandise, spreading the word and signing up potential Cubs.  A major factor in pushing us towards our goal was introducing a more formal board structure and the addition of several new committee members with valuable experience of youth work and teaching children.  By summer 2013 we decided it was time to stop talking and start doing so we booked our trial dates - there’s nothing like pressure to spur you on!  Our big fundraising event was a roller disco, with assistance from Dai Ola Roller Discos, which not only gave us an opportunity to raise money but also to see what a hall full of kids on skates would be like.  The disco was a success and finally we were able to pay for our insurance, just in time for our first trial session on the 1st of September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/trial2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/trial2.jpg?w=300" alt="trial2" width="300" height="199" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2931"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once our trial sessions were booked, we had lots of work to do to organise them: how many kids would we allow in each session?  How would we split them up?  Who would run training?  What ratio of children to adults would we need?  Would it run like Fresh Meat?  How would we adapt it for kids? We had always intended the age range to be five to seventeen, but this presents its own problems.  We decided to run two trial sessions, the first for five to ten year olds and the second for the older group, eleven to seventeen.  The training plan is based on the Junior Roller Derby Association skillset along with some information from the FVRG Fresh Meat training plan. The kids on our mailing list were given first chance to book their places, which we decided to limit to fifteen, and spaces filled up very quickly.  It was reassuring to know that people were still interested after all that time.  A large number of the Cubs are the children or siblings of skaters (from FVRG, BCR. ARRG and the Jakey Bites, as far as we know!) so come armed with lots of derby knowledge already, but for others, their experience is limited to skating in the street or at roller discos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/trial4.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/trial4.jpg?w=300" alt="trial4" width="300" height="199" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2935"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all of our planning, we had no real idea of how the first session would go, so, after roping in some helpers from FVRG and BCR, it was time to go.  The first session went better than any of us could have hoped: the new Cubs were fearless and enthusiastic, not to mention well-behaved and quick to pick up skills.  By the end of the session, many of them were confidently doing stops, falls and crossovers and we were beyond impressed.  We approached the second trial session with more confidence after the success of the first, and our older Cubs did not disappoint.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/trial3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/trial3.jpg?w=300" alt="trial3" width="300" height="199" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2932"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has taken a lot of hard work to get to this point, but I’m sure everyone would agree that seeing the kids on skates made it worthwhile.  There’s still a long way to go and we know there will be challenges, but we can’t wait to train the next generation of Scotland’s derby skaters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographs courtesy of Claire Brunton of Zenspirations Photography&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/09/12/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-are-go/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 20:29:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs: still rolling</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/28/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-still-rolling/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It may appear to have gone quiet on the FVRC front recently, but behind the scenes, it's been a busy time.  It has been a bit of a slog, but the good news is that the end, or rather, the start, is now in sight.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've had an ongoing "wheel amnesty", looking for old, unloved indoor wheels that you no longer use, which we can use on kids' skates.  In addition, we're now appealing for donations of any old kit that you no longer have any use for, which is doing nothing but clutter up your house.  Any pads or even skates which you or your kids have outgrown would be gratefully recieved.  They don't have to be perfect, merely functional (and safe, obviously!).  We won't be able to have full spare kit for everyone, but we would like to have at least bits and pieces that we can lend.  If you have any wheels or kit that you would like to donate, please contact us either on Facebook or by emailing cubs@fvrg.co.uk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similary, we're also looking for people to help out in various ways - no derby experience neccessary!  Being involved with the Cubs doesn't have to mean being a coach, there's lots to do so it's all hands on deck.  Contact us if you'd like to be a part of the fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, with a view to raising some much-needed funds, we now have a PayPal account so we can accept donations.  I, along with a group of skaters from Fierce Valley Roller Girls, am climbing Ben Nevis next month and have decided to try to raise some money for the Cubs at the same time.  Any donations would be much appreciated, and would make the blisters worth it!  Our PayPal account can be found&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.paypal.com/uk/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_flow&amp;amp;SESSION=NVUfRa1f3v4rSdWQYoxudu1ibf1FYEa0ZzrxQ58D9e_5tjHYIHSa06fKQvK&amp;amp;dispatch=5885d80a13c0db1f8e263663d3faee8d96fc0752e9614158f04872d2f2ae25dc"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; 
Remember to look out for further information, hopefully coming soon.  If you're not already on our mailing list, drop us an email and we'll add you, to make sure you don't miss any important annoucements.
 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fvrc</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/28/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-still-rolling/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 20:31:39 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>