<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about kaiserslautern roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/kaiserslautern-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 09:17:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Guest Post: Saving RGA by Becoming KRD</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/savingrga_krd2019/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recently, Kaiserslautern's Roller Girls of the Apocalypse underwent an extensive rebrand - not just the kind where you change a single noun, but a complete alteration of their league to "Kaiserslautern Roller Derby", along with a complete replacement of their league logo and colours!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have been lucky enough to persuade KRD's Public Relations Chair, Felicity Fleet, to write up their thoughts on the rebranding process - and what it means to the league for us.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has also been hand translated by KRD's Lena Albert into German [available by clicking the Deutsch link in the left pane under "Scottish Roller Derby Blog"]!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first roller derby boot camp as an assessed skater provided me with an understanding of the Roller Girls of the Apocalypse (RGA) brand in the wider European roller derby community. “Some years RGA is really good, and some years we wonder ‘what happened’?” a veteran German skater commented to me. This would become a familiar refrain as I began to travel and play with or against other teams. As a skater developed in RGA’s Fresh Meat program, I could easily answer “what happened”: A new skater with little experience, like me, replaced a veteran skater. And it’s no one’s fault. That’s what RGA is as a league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RGA is a German league in Kaiserslautern with membership primarily from the surrounding American military community. If you don’t know much about the U.S. military, here’s a quick debrief: U.S. military members generally stay in one place for 2-4 years before they are required to move for their job. In 2018, RGA lost 13 skaters or officials to military moves. By the end of 2019, 12 more players will have left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The consequence is that RGA serves as a great feeder league. We have sent well-trained skaters to top leagues in the USA, and we have trained a number of promising new skaters in our 6-month Fresh Meat program who are forced to take their potential elsewhere shortly after they pass assessments. During the years we see a large exodus of members, the role of our veteran players in the league changes from “valued player” to “valued trainer”. Our vets will spend most of their own training time helping newer members learn the game and gain skills, while losing their own ability to train at a higher level. Consequently, our veteran skaters play the next year or two at a lower competitive level than they are capable, since most of their teammates are new. Surrounding teams meet us on the track and ask “what happened?” to our level of play. Then the newer players become good players, the exodus begins, and the cycle continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we had to question if this is a sustainable model for our league. We had to have some hard conversations and genuine self-reflection as we considered our brand in the community and what it means to be competitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/savingrga_krd2019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (5 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>german roller derby</category><category>guest posts</category><category>kaiserslautern roller derby</category><category>rebranding</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/savingrga_krd2019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>