<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about kallio rolling rainbow)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/kallio-rolling-rainbow.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 09:36:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Europe's First Continental Cup: the UK's next International Derby fixture in 2018</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/04/europes-first-continental-cup-the-uks-next-international-derby-fixture-in-2018/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By any account, 2018 has been a very good year for Roller Derby's international profile, in both Europe and the UK. From the third Roller Derby World Cup in Manchester this February, and the third Men's Roller Derby World Cup in Barcelona a few months later, we've gone on to host an MRDA Playoffs, in Halifax/hosted by Manchester Roller Derby, and a WFTDA Playoffs, in A Coruña.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pendulum is, inevitably, swinging back again from Spain to the UK, with the last event in this sequence: the first ever &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wftdaecc2018.com/"&gt;European WFTDA Continental Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, bringing up the rear in this inaugural year for the new format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the MRDA Playoffs (hosted by Manchester, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; Halifax), this is hosted by Birmingham Blitz Dames, but physically &lt;i&gt;located&lt;/i&gt; in Telford... but the hosts have done a lot to make the brand of the tournament their own. The distinctive diamond logo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-27531 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/blitzdamesdiamon.png" alt="BlitzDamesDiamon" width="245" height="240"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;has both a general connection to Birmingham's jewellery industry, and to the Blitz Dames themselves - and even references their ex-skater, goldsmith Isabella Day, who made the trophy for the tournament!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27532" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/continental_map_logos.png" alt="Continental_map_logos" width="1562" height="1070"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Continental Cups framework is a response to the increasing spread of Roller Derby, and particularly the increasingly global membership of WFTDA. With more than 400 member leagues, an ever decreasing fraction of travel teams can hope to compete in a WFTDA Playoffs (and travel costs become increasingly prohibitive if you just extend the cut-off for Playoffs, or extend the old Division 2). &lt;i&gt;Regional&lt;/i&gt; "Continental Cups" provide a WFTDA-certified tournament, for every region with enough teams, at a level just below that of Playoffs - but with much less travel costs. (Next year, there will also be a set of regional "Development Cups", providing a WFTDA-certified tournament option for regions who aren't competitive at the old "D2" level, with guest "seed" teams from more "connected" regions to help improve ranking accuracy.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe's Continental Cup, then, has a familiar set of teams (and countries) represented (order from WFTDA announcement):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Kallio Rolling Rainbow (Finland)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dublin Roller Derby (Ireland)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dock City Rollers (Sweden)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers (Wales)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Central City Roller Derby (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby (England)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
The current FTS Europe rankings (which include a different subset of games to WFTDA rankings; excluding games against teams outside Europe, but including unsanctioned games) disagree somewhat with this ordering - FTS thinks that some of these teams were strong enough to make Playoffs ahead of some of the European representation there! - but predict a rather close set of games, regardless. In fact, FTS currently rates the two "local" teams - hosts Birmingham Blitz Dames, and Central City Roller Derby - as being exceptionally close in strength - sadly, the bracket prevents them from meeting unless they both lose their first games, or meet in the final.
Similarly, FTS expects some surprisingly close matches in the first round of the elimination bracket, despite WFTDA's usual slaughter pairing setup: Kallio versus Middlesbrough should be a near-draw by European data; although WFTDA sanctioned ratings place Kallio much higher than the UK team. If you're playing the Bracket Challenge for this contest, that's your best chance for an early upset...
&lt;p&gt;Despite, or perhaps causing, of the possibility of so many upsets and ranking disparities, the European Continental Cup should continue the example of the two North American CCs, in having a higher than "usual" number of close bouts, despite the tendency of elimination tournaments to start with a round of blowouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bracket is available here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.wixstatic.com/ugd/590519_be81975ec1304fcf96b32590ddbe2d8a.pdf"&gt;BRACKET PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (note for those not in the UK - this event is on the weekend that the UK changes over from Daylight Savings Time, so be careful checking timings for the Sunday, in particular).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-27324" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/officials_eur_map.png?w=2048" alt="Officials_EUR_map" width="1024" height="768"&gt; Geographical distribution of European Officials at the ECC! Stars may represent more than one official from a given location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as for the competition, the Continental Cup is also a great chance for more representation for our highly skilled European Officiating community. Just at the Tournament and Crew Head levels, we have officials from Karlsruhe, Newcastle, Dublin, Nottingham, Paris/Lutece, London/Southern Discomfort, (and Michigan...) - including all of the other crew positions adds (deep breath) Amsterdam, Antwerp, Bath, Belfast, Birmingham, Brussels, Cambridge, Cardiff, Chelmsford, Copenhagen, Darmstadt, Devon, Dresden, Dundee, Essex, Falkirk, Frankfurt, Gothenburg, Kallio/Helsinki, Manchester, Metz, Mons, Nantes, Northampton, Oxford, Riems, Ruhrpott, Southend, Southampton, Vicenza, Vienna, Wiltshire, Wuppertal,  (and Rochester, NY; Monterrey County, CA; St Louis, MO; Boston, MA; USA... and Adelaide, SA, Australia)! Just as with the other international events in Europe this year, this kind of exposure, and opportunity to both officiate at a high level, and meet up with a wider-flung segment of the Derby Community is fantastic for Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not all, as there's also fantastic line-up of (mostly...) European announcers, from Head Announcer Biertrix (Rainy City Roller Derby), through a host of UK announcers from London through Manchester to Durham and Newcastle; and from Germany, Denmark, as well as the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, as with all WFTDA post-season events this year, there will be a genuine chance for all members of the community (WFTDA-members or no) to connect with WFTDA Membership via the co-hosted "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/772801099579539/"&gt;WFTDA World Summit Satellite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" event. We're very impressed by WFTDA's increased commitment to listening to the voices of the whole community, and would encourage the community to also make use of these opportunities in return: listening should be rewarded with dialogue. (On that note, WFTDA are also surveying every league which does derby and are not WFTDA-members - regardless of their gender policy etc - and we'd encourage everyone eligible to respond to this too, here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.org/surveys"&gt;WFTDA.org/surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The European Continental Cup will run from &lt;strong&gt;October 27th to October 28th&lt;/strong&gt; at The International Centre, Telford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WFTDA Continental Cup page: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/events/wftda-continental-cups/"&gt;https://wftda.com/events/wftda-continental-cups/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Facebook Event for European Continental Cup: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>birmingham blitz dames</category><category>central city roller derby</category><category>continental cup</category><category>dock city rollers</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>kallio rolling rainbow</category><category>middlesbrough roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments2018</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/04/europes-first-continental-cup-the-uks-next-international-derby-fixture-in-2018/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 15:54:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>June 11th's Packed Scottish Derby Schedule...</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The weekend of the 11th is another extravaganza for high level Scottish Roller Derby, with both Auld Reekie Roller Girls and Glasgow Roller Derby engaged in multiple bouts across the weekend, and Fierce Valley playing away in the continuing British Champs Tier 3 North fixtures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Glasgow and Fierce Valley playing away, the Scottish home games are happening at Auld Reekie's traditional venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Meadowbank+Sports+Centre/@55.956622,-3.1585026,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4887b86eb150070f:0x6955a8c9b9a10cc5!8m2!3d55.956619!4d-3.1563086"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, doors open at &lt;strong&gt;2:20pm Saturday 11th&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-7441" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13235130_10156950736565224_2994993262049877442_o.jpg?w=1024" alt="13235130_10156950736565224_2994993262049877442_o" width="1024" height="385"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heading up &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/350352705088707/"&gt;the double-header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Auld Reekie's All-Stars are taking on Kallio Rolling Rainbow, one of Finland's finest teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After their usual impressive performance at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-big-o-2016-schedule-timezones/"&gt;The Big O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Oregon, Auld Reekie are riding high, ready for another challenge - Kallio are slightly higher ranked than they are (FlatTrackStats &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/79684/rankings"&gt;predicts a win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the Finns, albeit with some uncertainty). This will be a WFTDA Sanctioned bout and contribute to both teams' rankings, so it will be an especially hard-fought contest, as both teams will want to reach Division 1 (or remain in Division 2) of the WFTDA Rankings in order to qualify for Playoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other bout is no less exciting in its own way, marking the debut of ARRG's new 'C'-team, the 'All-Star Rookies'&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/#sup"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as they take on Granite City Roller Girls B, the Fight Hawks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, with a team debut, it's hard to make predictions as to the result of the bout; this will be a contest between Auld Reekie's new skater training and the experience gained by the Fight Hawks over the last year. (Having seen some of ARRG's rookies in "rising stars" bouts in the last few months, however, there's some very impressive performers there...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets on the door will be £8 (just £4 per bout), or £5 online via &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2553305"&gt;BrownPaperTickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Concessions tickets will be just £6 on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Glasgow Roller Derby are apparently the stars of the show down in Oldham, as Rainy City Roller Derby are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://rainycityrollerderby.com/event/euro-weekender/"&gt;hosting a weekend of derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, in which Glasgow feature in 3 out of 4 bouts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a Scotland versus Wales playoff, Glasgow's A team, the Irn Bruisers, will be taking on Tiger Bay Brawlers' A; and their B team, the Maiden Grrders will also be facing off against TBB's B-Bombs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FlatTrackStats predicts an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/7953/7929"&gt;incredibly closely-matched bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; between the A-teams (the result depends on which team you give "home-team advantage" to). The B-teams are almost as close in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/10262/11067"&gt;FTS's predictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, although it looks like their stats very narrowly favour the Welsh team (albeit by only a few percent). With only one exception, match-ups between GRD and TBB have been hard-fought, high-level affairs, so we do anticipate some great derby here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Rainy City Roller Derby are scheduled against simply "Glasgow Roller Derby", which we might guess is the A team... Last time they faced each other, Glasgow came out with a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/59869"&gt;convincing win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;; but Glasgow's significant team changes this year have FTS &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/10262/11067"&gt;predicting a win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the home team this time around. Glasgow will have to pull out something special to keep the win record on their side...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the rankings of Tiger Bay Brawlers A, and Rainy City Roller Derby, these bouts also fill in a chunk of the higher-level UK matchups missing from British Champs this year. With the results from these games, we'll be publishing an "extended" BC Tier 1 ranking, extrapolating where some of the teams not competing in T1 might have ended up, this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[On the Sunday, Kallio Roller Derby are also featuring in this derby weekend, so presumably there's some exciting train travel in Kallio's Sunday morning schedule...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://britishchamps.com"&gt;British Champs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, after an extended period &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/17/british-champs-at-dundee/"&gt;hosted in Scotland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the Tier 3 North fixtures continue in the North of England, with Hallam Hellcats hosting a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/587023974805101/"&gt;double-header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of bouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7445" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13267947_1010255862421996_6895825634478283487_n.jpg" alt="13267947_1010255862421996_6895825634478283487_n" width="530" height="750"&gt; Hallam's bout poster was also available as a limited edition physical print! (Design by Ed Syder) &lt;a href="http://edsyder.tumblr.com/"&gt;http://edsyder.tumblr.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hosts will be taking on Preston Roller Girls, while Scotland will be represented by Fierce Valley Roller Girls taking on Manchester Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FVRG will be hard pressed to defeat currently unbeaten Manchester, but a loss will keep them at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/womens-tables-2016/"&gt;bottom of the table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and in danger of relegation. Meanwhile, Hallam and Preston will be fighting it out to avoid the second-from-bottom spot in the table - there's not much to call between them, but FTS believes that home-team advantage gives the hosts &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/25963/8972"&gt;a slight edge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="sup"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;the Auld Reekie current team naming scheme is a bit confusing - the A team are simply "All-Stars", whilst the B team append "Reserves" and the C team "Rookies". This makes it a bit hard to unambiguously form acronyms for the two, but we're working on this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>auldreekierollergirls</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>fvrg</category><category>gcrd</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>hallam hellcats roller derby</category><category>kallio rolling rainbow</category><category>manchester roller derby</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 11:04:44 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>