<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about kokeshi roller dolls)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/kokeshi-roller-dolls.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:21 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Tomodachi Cup: Kokeshi Roller Dolls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/01/the-tomodachi-cup-kokeshi-roller-dolls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the second ever international tournament in Okinawa, Japan grows ever closer, we're bringing you another interview with a team attending the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;March 24&lt;/strong&gt;th to &lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt;th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last of our interviewees in the WFTDA Sanctioned tier of the tournament, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.okinawarollerderby.com/"&gt;Kokeshi Roller Dolls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are one of the two "local" leagues, based in Okinawa itself. KRD can contest with Tokyo Roller Girls for the title of "oldest league in Japan", both being founded around the same date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Japan Open, Kokeshi were the only Japanese team to defeat the might Juneau Roller Derby. Previously to that, the team has also played international roller derby away, at The Big O in 2014. KRD skaters also contributed to the teams competing at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/"&gt;first ever public&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; roller derby bout in China!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14036 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/kokeshi.png" alt="kokeshi" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRD were happy to answer some questions for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As the host league, and member of the organising Japan Derby Tournament Committee, what are you most proud of about the Tomodachi Tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRD: We’re technically not the host league; we’ll be hosting a revamped tournament next year called the Far East Face Off, but this year our role on the JDTC was solely to cover the marketing aspect of tournament preparation. One of our league members is a graphic designer, and was able to design the logo, banners, tees, and tournament program, which was a massive bonus for the JDTC. We're impressed that the committee, which first formed in September, was able to overcome a language barrier and pull off the planning of a tournament in under six months. Many of us worked overwhelmingly hard to make that happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the last tournament, Kokeshi played the three visiting A teams from outside Japan, pulling off a win against Juneau in their last bout of the tournament. What lessons are you taking into the Tomodachi, when facing Fairbanks and Pacific in particular?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRD: We’ve been practicing specific defensive strategies and better communication, and even increasing our endurance and strength training off skates. I think last year, our energy was focused on running the tournament, rather than practicing effective strategies. This year, our athletic staff isn’t involved in the tournament operations, and can focus on leading the team. Additionally, we were caught off guard by the slippery floor surface; the arena floors had recently been resealed and polished, and many of us did not have grippy wheels that first day. Lesson learned! We’ll be prepared for any surface this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You've played both Tokyo and D4 [Devil Dog Derby Dames] fairly regularly, of course (and D4 are particularly close by…). How are you feeling about your rematches against them this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRD: We didn’t bout either of these leagues last season, and with the high turnover rate due to military relocation, many of our skaters have never played against these leagues. We have had opportunities within the past season to play fun informal mixed scrimmages with members of TRG and D4, so keeping a competitive mental focus might be challenging since we’re used to having fun on the track. Both leagues have some very skilled skaters that we’re excited to go up against. Our goal is to practice effective communication and teamwork now that our skaters have had a whole season to train together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outside of your division, what teams and bouts are you most looking forward to at the Tomodachi?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRD: We're interested to see the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers play together. KRD was given the opportunity to skate with many of them in Beijing last summer at the HeForShe roller derby expo, which was a phenomenal experience. It sounds challenging to have a team comprised of women from different leagues all skating together for the first time, and we’re excited to see how they adapt to working together on the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's next for Kokeshi, after the Tomodachi?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRD: KRD is undergoing an exciting rebranding campaign! We are renaming the league “Okinawa Roller Derby” to better represent our location when we venture off island to play in tournaments. We are heading to Kaiserslautern, Germany for a tournament this June. We want to expand our horizons, challenge ourselves, and see what we can accomplish as a travel team. Then we’ll take the summer off to refocus on recruitment and, of course, put in some hours at the beach!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>kokeshi roller dolls</category><category>okinawa roller derby</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/01/the-tomodachi-cup-kokeshi-roller-dolls/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 10:15:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tomodachi Derby Tournament - The Teams</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, the Asia-Pacific Region saw its first ever Roller Derby Tournament, hosted in Okinawa. Whilst the Japan Open was a huge success, the host leagues were keen to hold another one, with even more direct control from the leagues and skaters themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14076 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tomodachi.png" alt="tomodachi" width="400" height="400"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is the result - another two day tournament, now hosted by the new Japan Derby Tournament Committee, a collective of the involved Japanese leagues. As with the previous Tournament, the Tomodachi also serves a practical benefit to all the teams involved, giving somewhat geographically isolated teams a chance to play those from other areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be bringing you more info with interviews with the attending leagues in the run up to the event on the &lt;strong&gt;24th&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt;, (at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/%E6%B2%96%E7%B8%84%E7%9C%8C%E7%B7%8F%E5%90%88%E9%81%8B%E5%8B%95%E5%85%AC%E5%9C%92/@26.3099785,127.8141462,15.5z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x76c4ab9c228dd0cb!8m2!3d26.3107468!4d127.8213143"&gt;Okinawa Comprehensive Sport Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), but we're starting (as with EuroClash) with an overview of the competitors... (a timetable is available on our technical annex, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/tomodachi2017.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;WFTDA-Sanctioned Division&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14022" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/pacificrollerderby.png" alt="pacificrollerderby" width="200" height="200"&gt;Pacific Roller Derby&lt;/h3&gt;
Pacific Roller Derby are one of the oldest of the cluster of Hawaiian teams, dating from 2008, and a member of WFTDA since 2009! Due to the geographical factor, they mostly play the other Islands teams, especially at the yearly "Battle of the Islands" tournament. Based in the Islands' Capital, Honolulu, Pacific are currently 305th in the WFTDA Rankings (344th by FTS), partly, we suspect, simply due to not having had much opportunity to play non-Hawaiian teams. The Tomodachi will be their first fixtures against non-HI leagues since 2014!
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14024" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/fairbanks_rollergirls.png" alt="fairbanks_rollergirls" width="200" height="240"&gt;Fairbanks Rollergirls&lt;/h3&gt;
Hailing from their namesake in Alaska, Fairbanks Rollergirls are another member of the "Alaskan Derby" set alongside last year's Japan Open competitors, Juneau (who memorably attended with only 6 skaters!). A WFTDA member since 2011, the league has hosted the Alaskan "United We Roll" tournament for the last two years. We rate them at 1137th out of all teams (male and female, A and B) in the World which can be rated, whilst FTS places them 331st out of all WFTDA teams (a much smaller set).
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14034" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/devil_dog_300.png" alt="devil_dog_300" width="200" height="199"&gt;Devil Dog Derby Dames&lt;/h3&gt;
Local Okinawan Derby league, Devil Dog Derby Dames, (868th SRDRank), were a competitor at the Japan Open last year, although failed to defeat the non-Japanese teams in the WFTDA Division. (Their Home Team, competing in the Unsanctioned Division, defeated exhibition team Nippon Senbatsu.) The year before that, DDDD managed a win over fellow Okinawa league Kokeshi, which they'll be looking to repeat this time.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14036" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/kokeshi.png" alt="kokeshi" width="200" height="200"&gt;Kokeshi Roller Dolls&lt;/h3&gt;
The first league in Okinawa, Kokeshi Roller Dolls, (700th SRD Rank) were hosts of the Japan Open last year, as well as organising hosting for the Tomodachi Tournament as part of the Japan Roller Derby Tournament Committee. At the Japan Open, they took a win over Alaska's Juneau Roller Derby; we will see if they managed to repeat the feat against Fairbanks this time around.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14028" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tokyo.jpg" alt="tokyo" width="200" height="200"&gt;Tokyo Roller Girls&lt;/h3&gt;
The first league in "mainland" Japan, Tokyo Roller Girls, (745th SRD Rank) faired as well as the Devil Dog Derby Dames at the last tournament. However, they've had a busy home season since then, with all three of their home teams bouting each other, and recruitment has been strong. (TRG skaters have also been behind much of the activity of Women's Roller Derby Japan, the governing body for the Japanese Women's National Team, including their impressively active outreach in the last year.)
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Men's Division&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14032" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/grd_logo_cmyk.png" alt="grd_logo_cmyk" width="200" height="102"&gt;Glenmore Reservoir Dogs&lt;/h3&gt;
Hailing from Calgary, Canada, Glenmore Reservoir Dogs (Chinook City Men's Roller Derby) are the 17th ranked MRDA team in the world (65th SRD Rank), and are the men's component of Chinook City Roller Derby. Perhaps most recently known on the international stage as hosts of the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup, the league as a whole also regularly host the annual "Flat Track Fever" (women's derby) tournament. Last year, the Reservoir Dogs themselves competed at the Mayday Mayhem (Colorado) and the O-Town Throwdown (Ontario), taking second place at the former.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14038" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/japan-logo-232x300.jpg" alt="japan-logo-232x300" width="193" height="250"&gt;NinJapan Rollers&lt;/h3&gt;
The Japanese Men's National Team, and still the only Men's league in Japan, NinJapan Rollers have fairly frequently competed against the other Japanese teams (especially Tokyo), but have rarely had the chance to play non-National teams from other locations. In the 2016 MRDWC, NinJapan placed 17th, although their performance was very close to that of Puerto Rico, one place above them. The NinJapan Rollers have also (partly due to necessity) actively promoted Roller Derby throughout Japan, and have a comprehensive "off-season" training and recruitment system to build up their pool of skaters.
&lt;h2&gt;Unsanctioned Division&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14026" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/yokosuka.png" alt="yokosuka" width="200" height="189"&gt;Yokosuka Sushi Rollers&lt;/h3&gt;
A Tokyo Roller Girls "Home Team", this is the Sushi Rollers' first appearance as a travel team, let alone their first tournament. Based in and around United States Fleet Activities Yokosuka naval base, the Sushi Rollers were the founding team of Tokyo Roller Girls, and remain one of the strongest in intraleague contests. It remains to be seen how they will fare in their first bouts away from Honshu.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14040" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/pan-asian.jpg" alt="pan-asian" width="223" height="200"&gt;Pan-Asian Spring Rollers&lt;/h3&gt;
The Pan-Asian Spring Rollers are a collaboration between the other (non-Japanese) East Asian Roller Derby leagues, with members from Beijing Roller Derby, Shanghai Roller Girls, Hong Kong Roller Derby and Bangkok Roller Derby. Several of these leagues participated in the first ever Roller Derby bout in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; last year (hosted by Beijing), and so collaboration to attend the Tomodachi seems natural.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14030" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/teamwrdj-sm.jpg" alt="teamwrdj-sm" width="250" height="154"&gt;Team WRDJ&lt;/h3&gt;
Team "Women's Roller Derby Japan" is a the open-subscription exhibition team, run by the committee for . It comprises skaters from the Neon Roller Monsters (Tokyo Roller Girls' Japanese-nationals-team), Tokyo Three Rollers (Tokyo's Open-To-All/Coed Team), Kokeshi Roller Dolls, Devil Dog Derby Dames, and a single skater from Hawaii's Echo City Knockouts (of Kailua-Kona).&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>beijing roller derby</category><category>devil dog derby dames</category><category>fairbanks rollergirls</category><category>glenmore reservoir dogs</category><category>hong kong roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>kokeshi roller dolls</category><category>ninjapan rollers</category><category>pacific roller derby</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><category>shang-hai rollers</category><category>tokyo roller girls</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>women's roller derby japan</category><category>yokosuka sushi rollers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 08:05:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Japan Open - the Other WFTDA First This Year</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While there has been plenty of deserved excitement over the recent European Smackdown, hosted by Crime City Rollers in Malmö, it is not the only groundbreaking tournament happening this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If European Smackdown showed that Europe is now ready to compete in the highest levels of &lt;a href="https://wftda.com"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt; play, then Kokeshi Roller Dolls' &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/JapanOpenRollerDerby"&gt;Japan Open Tournament&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;March 25 and 26&lt;/strong&gt; shows that Asia is now firmly emerging onto the International Derby stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6660" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/mega-image-jo-1024x267.png" alt="mega-image-jo-1024x267" width="1024" height="267"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Japan Open Tournament is the first ever Asia-Pacific Roller Derby tournament.  Played under WFTDA rules, the tournament will involve teams from Japan, USA (Alaska), Australia, New Zealand and, in a late change, Denmark (teams from China and Hawaii had to pull out during the tournament's organisation). Comprehensive Park Arena in Okinawa will be the host venue, with &lt;em&gt;free&lt;/em&gt; admission to all spectators, as this is also something of an outreach opportunity for the sport.
There's actually two tiers to the tournament - an 'A' tier, featuring WFTDA Member Leagues and WFTDA Sanctioned bouts;and a 'B' tier, which features mostly non-WFTDA members, or B-teams, and is not Sanctioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby actually has quite a long history in Japan; American influence seeded previous incarnations of the game in the 20th Century, and a Japan-native version ("RollerGame" or "RollerGame Japan") was popular in the country in the early 1990s, and then again in the early 2000s. (In fact, this weekend - March 19th and 20th - sees RollerGame Japan come to the USA in an &lt;a href="http://www.santamonica.com/event/roller-expo-2016/"&gt;expo event&lt;/a&gt; hosted in Santa Monica).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WFTDA Japanese Roller Derby community dates back to &lt;strong&gt;2010/11&lt;/strong&gt;, when both Kokeshi Roller Dolls and Tokyo Roller Girls were founded around the American military bases in Japan. Since then, each of the leagues or teams which has emerged has also been nucleated around American military presence: there is now derby in Tokyo (including at least one team, Kamikaze Badass, which is not associated with Tokyo Roller Girls), Yokosuka, Zama, Yokota, Misawa and two leagues in Okinawa. The community is actively attempting to recruit Japanese skaters, especially in Tokyo, which has had a Japanese team since 2012; it was skaters from Tokyo Roller Girls who also managed the creation of the Team Japan which competed in the 2014 Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Japan Open Tournament has been planned for some time; it has been the goal of Kokeshi Roller Dolls to hold such a tournament from early in their WFTDA certification process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read about the teams attending the Japan Open in the next pages in this guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're planning on viewing the Japan Open, our handy viewing guide (with a different page for every timezone with a team) may be in useful. Click here to access it: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/11/the-japan-open-schedule-timezones/"&gt;VIEWING GUIDE.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Profiles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;JRDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6674" style="border-style:solid;border-width:1px;" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/bigmap3.png" alt="bigmap3" width="800" height="421"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRDA&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-6520 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/logo_of_the_adelaide_roller_derby_league.jpg" alt="Logo_of_the_Adelaide_Roller_Derby_league" width="405" height="400"&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://adelaiderollerderby.com.au/"&gt;Adelaide Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are one of Australia's long-established roller derby leagues, dating from &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;. Their A-Team, the &lt;em&gt;Adeladies&lt;/em&gt;, have played basically every other league in Australasia, although the Japan Open is their first venture outside of that arena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/14248"&gt;FTS ranking&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;650.1&lt;/strong&gt; (WFTDA), the Adeladies are possibly the strongest league attending the tournament, and are the favourites to win the Championship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adelaides' Captain Elle Catraz had this to say to us: "Adelaide Roller Derby are thrilled to be sending their WFDTA representative skaters to participate in the Japan Open Tournament in Okinawa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Japan will be the farthest that Adelaide Roller Derby has travelled to bout and we are extremely excited and grateful for the opportunity to play against and watch teams from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our season doesn't officially kick off until early April so this will be our first bout of the season. Our skaters chose not to have much of an off season in preparation for this tournament, but it will be all worth it when they hit the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training wise, we had skaters travel to Queensland to participate in the Derby Fest training camp during January along with the whole league having the pleasure of being trained by Scald Eagle and Stefanie Mainey in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be the first time many of our skaters have travelled to Japan so our team have enjoyed team bonding sessions over Japanese food, while learning important Japanese phrases we can use both on and off the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also extremely proud and grateful to bring the tournament two of our extremely committed referees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Adeladies take great pride in representing their entire league when they travel and the Japan Open will be no exception. "&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="ardroster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
The Philistine &lt;strong&gt;#88 (Captain)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elle Catraz &lt;strong&gt;#46 (Captain)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed Bandit &lt;strong&gt;#777&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blue Wrenegade &lt;strong&gt;#2880&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ankle Grinder &lt;strong&gt;#91&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fury of Fenrir &lt;strong&gt;#24&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frill Seeker &lt;strong&gt;#32&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KillaKaze &lt;strong&gt;#11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaos! &lt;strong&gt;#601&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bam Bam Belial &lt;strong&gt;#29&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anne T Social &lt;strong&gt;#886&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maiden Hell &lt;strong&gt;#206&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry Smyles &lt;strong&gt;#2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Referees Chris Durant and Slaíne are also attending the tournament, as part of the officiating teams.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRDA&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-6523 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/brawlers.jpg?w=480" alt="brawlers" width="240" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/12/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://piratecityrollers.com/"&gt;Pirate City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/#pcrroster"&gt;(roster)&lt;/a&gt; are the strongest of Auckland, New Zealand's leagues, founded way back in &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, as the first league in the Southern Hemisphere. They have continued to establish firsts in roller derby since then.
Full WFTDA members since 2013, Pirate City have mostly played in games in the Australasian region, although they attended the 2015 Beach Brawl, where they did better than expected (as is usual for a non-US team!), despite only winning against hosts Gold Coast. Their B team, the &lt;em&gt;Broadside Brawlers&lt;/em&gt;, is the team competing at the Japan Open, however, and there's much less known about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With no &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/55620"&gt;FTS rating&lt;/a&gt; (the A team resides at 587.1(WFTDA)), it is hard to predict how the Brawlers will do against their competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pirate City B are scheduled to play Killa Geishas of Misawa and the JRDA Expo team, Nippon Senbatsu, in the B tier of the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brawlers Captains Drop the Pom! and RumpleStinson told us "The Broadside Brawlers are extremely excited to be attending their first tournament. We have been training hard and are looking forward to making the Pirate City Rollers proud.
We are looking forward to meeting some great new people and playing new teams, picking up some new tricks along the way and getting experience of international Derby."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="pcrroster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Drop the Pom! &lt;strong&gt;#999 (Captain)&lt;/strong&gt; [Suzie Harris]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RumbleStinson &lt;strong&gt;#33 (Captain)&lt;/strong&gt; [Shirley Stinson]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kid Vicious &lt;strong&gt;#711 (Bench)&lt;/strong&gt; [Devan Jackson De Toit]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manic Street Creature &lt;strong&gt;(Lineup)&lt;/strong&gt; [Mars Coombes]
Block Ness Monster &lt;strong&gt;#23&lt;/strong&gt; [Vanessa Rancour]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crash Test Honey &lt;strong&gt;#100&lt;/strong&gt; [Celia Langabeer]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holly Golightly &lt;strong&gt;#10&lt;/strong&gt; [Holly Brady]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linda ShoveLACE &lt;strong&gt;#76&lt;/strong&gt; [Sal St Clair Brown]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mad Kao &lt;strong&gt;#92&lt;/strong&gt; [Grace Kao]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nikalicious Vicious &lt;strong&gt;#11&lt;/strong&gt; [Nikki Henderson]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pnut Butt Her and Jam &lt;strong&gt;#247&lt;/strong&gt; [Andrea Kelly]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poppy Kneecaps &lt;strong&gt;#0&lt;/strong&gt; [Kirstie Kawana-Waugh]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shepard &lt;strong&gt;#345&lt;/strong&gt; [Abbie Jay]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sledge Hannah &lt;strong&gt;#42c&lt;/strong&gt; [Hannah Creek]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SufferKater [Katie Miles]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRDA&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-6527 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/dddd.png?w=600" alt="DDDD" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.devildogderbydames.com/"&gt;Devil Dog Derby Dames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/#ddddroster"&gt;(roster)&lt;/a&gt; are the second of Okinawa's Roller Derby leagues, founded by the personnel and spouses around the Marine Corps bases on the island. They have been WFTDA members since &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;. They attended the Wild West Showdown in 2015, where they lost narrowly to fellow Open attendees Juneau Rollergirls; a rematch between the two is on the cards here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/16732"&gt;FTS rating&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;506.8&lt;/strong&gt;, DDDD are one of the lower rated teams in the 'A' tier of the competition, although all of the Japanese A-tier leagues have close ratings so contests are hard to predict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Devil Dog Derby Dames' Home team is also competing in the tournament, in the 'B' tier. Lacking a rating, it is hard to predict their performance. They will be taking on similarly unrated Killa Geishas of Misawa, and the JRDA exhibition team "Nippon Senbatsu".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Devil Dogs told us: "This tournament is something that the Devil Dog Derby Dames past and present have been looking forward to for the past 5 years. Okinawa has Derby, we're here to stay and kick some ass!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="ddddroster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;(Mixed roster)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke Garcia&lt;strong&gt; (All-Stars Head Coach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Sapion&lt;strong&gt; (All-Stars Coach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zack Helms&lt;strong&gt; (Home? Head Coach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Purdy&lt;strong&gt; (Home? Coach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MsMURDR &lt;strong&gt;#88&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ohio Skate &lt;strong&gt;#7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Milla Dropabich &lt;strong&gt;#55&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Little Bo Reap &lt;strong&gt;#85&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DodgeHer Dollie &lt;strong&gt;#mc49&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grimm the Reaper &lt;strong&gt;#626&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brutally Scrumptious &lt;strong&gt;#850&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mexicutioner &lt;strong&gt;#9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nucleah Bombshell&lt;strong&gt; #1759&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gnarly Quinn&lt;strong&gt; #13&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honey Badger &lt;strong&gt;#67&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malicious Mare &lt;strong&gt;#509&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dorothy Wail &lt;strong&gt;#205&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kit Killher &lt;strong&gt;#15&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iron Maiden &lt;strong&gt;#323&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sailor Juke'N'er &lt;strong&gt;#777&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rollin' Purdy &lt;strong&gt;#713&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ball Buster &lt;strong&gt;#27&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knuckles Tesla &lt;strong&gt;#1856&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hannabelle Deck'd-her &lt;strong&gt;#33&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rosie the Ripper&lt;strong&gt; #402&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ankle Biter &lt;strong&gt;#256&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flex Luthor &lt;strong&gt;#314&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Referee Craig Nakagawa and Announcer Pete Daigle are also being contributed by DDDD.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRDA&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-6531 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/998254_462707763823646_1955140903_n.jpg" alt="998254_462707763823646_1955140903_n" width="500" height="481"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.copenhagenrollerderby.com/"&gt;Copenhagen Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/#crdroster"&gt;(roster)&lt;/a&gt; are part of the long established and active northern European Roller Derby community, founded in &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;. WFTDA full members since &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;, Copenhagen are probably one of the most experienced teams in the competition in terms of "bouts played", thanks to the sheer density of nearby leagues. However, the team has not played outside of Europe, and the long travel may be a test for them. In the last year, CRD have been ramping up their experience, notably defeating Edinburgh's Auld Reekie B by a significant ratio late last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7768"&gt;FTS rating&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;536.5&lt;/strong&gt;, Copenhagen are mid-placed in the A tier of the tournament, but will only face the Japanese leagues in that tier, all of whom have lower ratings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copenhagen's Durakill Bunny had this to say on the team's feelings about their first International engagement. "We are extremely excited to travel to Japan and take part of this tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Japan trip was a Unique opportunity for the CRD A-team to have a very special goal to work towards. Not only in terms of derby skills and preparing for the games, but also in terms of working really hard and closely together on raising funds and organizing the trip. Everyone on the team have contributed to this the way they best could and we really feel that this have made us stronger together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of or skills on the track, we have definately upped our game. In December we had a bootcamp with Juke Boxx from London rollergirls and in February we had a bootcamp with Scald Eagle from Rose City Rollers. Both bootcamps helped us to identify important ares to work with and implement new derby techniques. In February we arranged a scrimmage with a Division 1, team Crime City Rollers which gave us a lot of learnings that we could bring into our training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are all extremely excited to get the chance to travel to Japan as a team and even before we have left Denmark, we feel that this has made us a better and closer team than we have ever been before. Travelling to Japan is without doubt a very exotic experience for all of us and we will all spend time before and after the tournament to explore the country."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="crdroster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Frix Rode &lt;strong&gt;#12 (Captain)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wicked Wawwa &lt;strong&gt;#70  (Co-Captain)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chuckles &lt;strong&gt;(Bench) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dubbi &lt;strong&gt;(Line-Up)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AC Dizzy &lt;strong&gt;#10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saboteur &lt;strong&gt;#119&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yaya Woosh &lt;strong&gt;#19&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mikamikaze &lt;strong&gt;#21&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ragna Rockette &lt;strong&gt;#321&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miss Vojens &lt;strong&gt;#34&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Durakill Bunny &lt;strong&gt;#42&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aevle &lt;strong&gt;#44&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guillotinker &lt;strong&gt;#440&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Juggernaut Jelly &lt;strong&gt;#510&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sofie Bay &lt;strong&gt;#55&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laughing Out Lizzie &lt;strong&gt;#707&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T-Sex &lt;strong&gt;#815&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRDA&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-6534 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/boot-noinc.jpg" alt="boot-noINC" width="270" height="146"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://juneaurollergirls.com/"&gt;Juneau Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/#jrgroster"&gt;(roster)&lt;/a&gt; are the only league in Alaska's capital city. Founded in &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, they joined WFTDA as an Apprentice league in 2013, graduating to full members in &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;. They are one of only two WFTDA ranked teams in Alaska.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's difficult to develop a firm ranking for them, as they are part of the "Alaskan island" of Roller Derby leagues in the state, playing each other far more than they play the rest of the continent. However, their A team did attend Wild West Showdown in February 2015, where they played fellow Japan Open attendees Devil Dog Derby Dames to a close win, despite having only 5 skaters on their roster! (This connection was also the seed for their attendance at the Open, which also serves to provide the team with more games while their home venue is out of commission.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/25021"&gt;FTS rating&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;542.7&lt;/strong&gt;, Juneau are mid-placed in the tournament. They will be playing all three big Japanese leagues - hosts Kokeshi, Tokyo Roller Girls, and Devil Dog Derby Dames - in A-tier bouts that we expect to be pretty close, but which should result in success for the Alaskans according to the stats. Juneau are bringing along only a tiny roster of 6 skaters, however, so their games will be more of an endurance contest than normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Juneau's Captain Just Julie told us: "Preparing to compete in the Japan Open feels like a fairy tale in the making for Juneau Rollergirls... the opportunity to play in this tournament is such an honor for our All-Stars. This is the kind of experience that our derby dreams are made of.
We were so impressed with how the Devil Dog Derby Dames rolled at the Wild West Showdown last year and I can't wait to meet more of Japan's roller derby community. One of the most satisfying aspects of traveling with my team is that in some small way we are coming together to support all the awesome athletes, outstanding officials and visionary volunteers out there who are dedicated to the growth and development of our sport. Seeing how we contribute to something so much bigger than ourselves was an empowering realization for geographically isolated teams like ours. I feel so fortunate to be sharing this experience with my teammates and it will be an honor and a privilege to serve my team as Captain. While some of our league-mates aren't able to make this trip, I know that all the hard work and derby love the league has invested in each other this season will be out there every time the Juneau Rollergirls hit the track. All in! All season!"
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id="jrgroster"&gt;Just Julie &lt;strong&gt;#11 (Captain)&lt;/strong&gt; [Julie Sanbei]&lt;/p&gt;
Shane Kruse &lt;strong&gt;(Bench)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shredlock Holmes &lt;strong&gt;(Bench)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fatty Dook &lt;strong&gt;#2&lt;/strong&gt; [Alicia Gillis]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catapult Kim &lt;strong&gt;#3&lt;/strong&gt; [Kim Glasow]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skatie Brite &lt;strong&gt;#22&lt;/strong&gt; [Katie White]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titan Young &lt;strong&gt;#25&lt;/strong&gt; [Stephanie Kruse]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hevee Mettle &lt;strong&gt;#71&lt;/strong&gt; [Evelyn Widmyer]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;JRDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6537" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/11112871_1077336432280149_1749476875903629144_n.jpg?w=600" alt="11112871_1077336432280149_1749476875903629144_n" width="300" height="300"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TokyoRollerGirls/"&gt;Tokyo Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/#trgroster"&gt;(roster)&lt;/a&gt; are mainland Japan's first Roller Derby league, dating from &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;. The league now incorporates the teams in Yokota and Zama, as well as its founding location in Yokosuka. Although founded by American services personnel and spouses, TRG have actively promoted and recruited in the Japanese population as well, and nowadays have good recruitment outside Americans - and two additional teams in Tokyo and Yokohama which are primarily Japanese nationals, one of which is Co-ed. TRG members were also instrumental in the creation and selection, under the "Women's Roller Derby Japan" and "Men's Roller Derby Japan" organisations, Team Japan and Ninjapan Rollers which attended the 2014 B&amp;amp;T Roller Derby World Cup and Men's Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/20991"&gt;FTS rating&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;503.4&lt;/strong&gt;, TRG are fairly low-ranked in the A tier of the tournament. They lost to hosts Kokeshi Roller Dolls the last time they encountered one another, as well as to other Okinawan league Devil Dog Derby Dames. In this tournament, TRG will be looking to show that they can succeed in their scheduled bouts, playing Copenhagen, Juneau and Adelaide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tokyo's Captain, Nactmerrie, explained their feelings about the Open. "In order for us to continue being a part of WFTDA, there is a requirement to play other WFTDA teams yearly, which can be difficult. We were so excited when we were invited to the tournament, since we will get to play different teams from all over the world! Most of our girls are from America and are either in the military or a military spouse, but we would love more Japanese skaters! For the upcoming tournament, we have been practicing often and scrimmaging against our men's team; which has been a huge help. We are mostly excited to play teams we have never played before and are hoping to raise our rank as well."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="trgroster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Nachtmerrie&lt;strong&gt; #86 (Captain)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Postlewaight&lt;strong&gt; #783 (Alternate)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Femmebot&lt;strong&gt; (Head Coach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pork Chop&lt;strong&gt; (Bench)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hung Low&lt;strong&gt; (Bench)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SorryNotSorry&lt;strong&gt; #110&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scary Thunderwood&lt;strong&gt; #1107&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bash &lt;strong&gt;#242&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low Down Derby Shame &lt;strong&gt;#4864&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomahawk Pixie &lt;strong&gt;#5280&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bean Town Beat Down &lt;strong&gt;#66&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terrin Skirtz &lt;strong&gt;#75&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ShortStack O'Paincakes &lt;strong&gt;#777&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laced Revenge &lt;strong&gt;#84&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USS DestroyHer &lt;strong&gt;#89&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thunder BELL &lt;strong&gt;#950&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRDA&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-6540 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/misawa.png" alt="misawa" width="200" height="201"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/12/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/killarollerderby"&gt;Killa Geishas of Misawa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/#mkgroster"&gt;(roster)&lt;/a&gt; are one of the smaller Japanese Roller Derby leagues based around US military bases (in this case, Misawa, at the very north end of Honshu). Founded in &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, the league has survived multiple venue issues over its 4 year life, and also spawned a men's team, the Misawa Rollin' Tanukis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With no WFTDA &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/52313"&gt;FTS rating&lt;/a&gt; (and a high uncertainty surrounding their evaluation in the Pacific region (there's only a single bout in the FlatTrackStats database for them, from 2014!)), it's very difficult to say how RGM will do in the tournament. As a smaller league, KGM are competing in the B tier of the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KGM's SINnamon Challenge told us: 'The Misawa Killa Geishas have had to fight tooth and nail to keep derby alive in the remote North. Our team has fought nonstop for 4 years practicing in changing venues and hospitable weather conditions, which has made us stronger as a team. The chance to play teams from New Zealand and throughout Japan is a chance for us to show others just how much fight we have in us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Blood, sweat, and tears,” only begins to describe the training the Misawa Killa Geishas have gone through in the many months leading up to Japan’s first big tournament. We’ve included personal goals, team goals, and one of the most important training aspects, team bonding. When we arrive to the Japan Open Roller Derby Tournament, we will show up prepared mentally, physically, and with a strong sisterhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We upped our scrimmages in preparation for the tournament. Every week we did our best to go up against our own teammates at their best. We learned, struggled, and conquered. After months of preparation we are heading to Japan Open Roller Derby Tournament tested, vetted, bruised, healed, and READY!!!'
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id="mkgroster"&gt;Pinche Loca&lt;strong&gt; #DD5 (Bench)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Nique Havoc &lt;strong&gt;#4&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Bench)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yellow Slamarine &lt;strong&gt;#4077 (Bench)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cimo D. Stroyin &lt;strong&gt;#11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SINnamon Challenge &lt;strong&gt;#38&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peach Bomb &lt;strong&gt;#800&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lola Bunny &lt;strong&gt;#15&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godjilla &lt;strong&gt;#325&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fenix Fire &lt;strong&gt;#602&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honey Basher&lt;strong&gt; #5309&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campbell Swoop &lt;strong&gt;#23&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ice Bloxx &lt;strong&gt;#906&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fay Tall O'Traction &lt;strong&gt;#1102&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweet D'Seat &lt;strong&gt;#h8r&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRDA&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-6543 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/kokeshi_rollers_300.png" alt="kokeshi_rollers_300" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kokeshirollerdolls.com/"&gt;Kokeshi Roller Dolls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/#krdroster"&gt;(roster)&lt;/a&gt; were the first roller derby league to be founded in Okinawa, dating from 2010. As with other Japanese leagues, they were created by American nationals in the military bases there. They are the hosts of the Japan Open, having previously played in 2014's Big O tournament&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/8126"&gt;FTS rating&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;518.2&lt;/strong&gt;, KRD are slightly stronger than the other Japanese leagues attending. We can expect close bouts against their select opponents across the tournament; as hosts, Kokeshi will want to put on a showing for the visitors to Okinawa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to Kokeshi's Cherry about the league, and the tournament. "After only 6 months of becoming a league, we were on the fast track to applying for a WFTDA Apprenticeship, with support from Rat City Rollergirls. Kokeshi leadership had big goals, and hosting a Far East Roller Derby Tournament was one of the future league goals in the application. We became a full WFTDA Member League in 2013, and [The Japanese Roller Derby Association] JRDA approached us in the fall of 2014.
We had a local, large venue and experience in bout production and outreach among local and international leagues. Having a primary Japanese sponsor support the tournament definitely helped get us moving. KRD is hosting and managing the tournament for skaters, officials and fans in cooperation with JRDA who work directly with Okinawa’s public organizations, media, and sponsors in Japanese.
JRDA's agenda is to find Japanese nationals to be a part of their organization and play in the 2017 Roller Games. Our [KRD] mission is to host an international tournament, bringing together leagues in the Pacific to play WFTDA sanctioned bouts and build camaraderie and partnerships among leagues and support officials, while promoting roller derby in the community.
We definitely have plans for future international tournaments, however, when the next one will be set and who the primary sponsor will be is yet to be determined. We have learned a lot about steps we need for success and what has held us back during the planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are planning for dual announcing, but a Japanese roller derby announcer is a hard billet to fill."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="krdroster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Shisa Beast &lt;strong&gt;#241 (Co-Captain)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sprocket2ya &lt;strong&gt;#77 (Co-Captain)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cherry&lt;strong&gt; (Coach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sir G. O.&lt;strong&gt; (Bench)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puncher &lt;strong&gt;(Asst. Coach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Courtney Loveless &lt;strong&gt;#O0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R.I.P..TIDE&lt;strong&gt; #O4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whipping Willow&lt;strong&gt; #1013&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moxxi&lt;strong&gt; #12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warden O'Neill &lt;strong&gt;#182&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rogue Wave &lt;strong&gt;#2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunny Daze&lt;strong&gt; #297&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beat Her Up Scotty &lt;strong&gt;#394&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psycho Anna Lies &lt;strong&gt;#5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamo-Cidal Mel &lt;strong&gt;#50&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lil N. Gin &lt;strong&gt;#9&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/2/"&gt;Adelaide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/3/"&gt;Pirate_City&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/4/"&gt;Devil_Dog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/5/"&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/6/"&gt;Juneau&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/7/"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/8/"&gt;Misawa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/9/"&gt;Kokeshi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/10/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRDA&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-6677 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/japanrda.jpg" alt="JapanRDA" width="225" height="225"&gt;
The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.jrda.jp/"&gt;Japan Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/#jrdaroster"&gt;(roster)&lt;/a&gt; is a sponsor of the Japan Open.
It's unclear what the JRDA's involvement in Japanese Roller Derby as a whole is - none of the WFTDA-rules leagues in Japan are affiliates, and it was also not involved in the creation of the Japanese National Teams - although the JRDA website does announce that they are intending to attend the FIRS/USARS 2017 RollerGames festival, and they are raising funds for a "Roller Derby School". The JRDA is an affiliate of the Japan Roller Sports Federation and, through that, of FIRS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as providing  Japanese language support, interfacing with the Japanese companies and entities involved in the hosting and sponsorship of the tournament and organising the livestreams, JRDA are submitting a team ("Nippon Senbatsu" - roughly, "Japan's Selection" - the natural way to describe a national team in Japanese) to the event. We know essentially nothing about this team at all, as they are apparently debuting at the Open. Nippon Senbatsu will be competing in the B tier of the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="jrdaroster"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Zu-Ca &lt;strong&gt;#8 (Captain) (Coach)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YONE &lt;strong&gt;#0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chocolat &lt;strong&gt;#3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nico&lt;strong&gt; #6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HoneyBee&lt;strong&gt; #7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HALCA&lt;strong&gt; #9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;strong&gt;#11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ChicoRock&lt;strong&gt; #15&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MASA&lt;strong&gt; #29&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ZOOMIN &lt;strong&gt;#69&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BISHAMONTEN MIHO &lt;strong&gt;#555&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoomBoom!! &lt;strong&gt;#88 (Manager)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Min &lt;strong&gt;(Alternate)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>adelaide roller derby</category><category>articles</category><category>copenhagen roller derby</category><category>devil dog derby dames</category><category>in the news</category><category>interviews</category><category>japan</category><category>jrda</category><category>killa geishas of misawa</category><category>kokeshi roller dolls</category><category>pirate city rollers</category><category>tokyo roller girls</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 11:15:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Big O Tournament Timing and Links</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/05/01/big-o-tournament-timing-and-links/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As always when trying to watch international derby hosted in another country, time zone conversion gets in the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Scottish Roller Derby Blog is here to help you out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a table for the correct times (&lt;del datetime="2014-05-07T15:07:39+00:00"&gt;and links for WFTDA.tv streams and FlatTrackStats predictions&lt;/del&gt;links to Blaze Streaming Media's YouTube Archive) for all Auld Reekie and Kokeshi Roller Dolls bouts in both UK and Japanese time zones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also included a few of the interesting Division 1 bouts on each day as well (but for the full schedule, see the Big O website itself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried, for Kokeshi, to provide some Japanese transcriptions of team names in bad Katakana, just for accessibility's sake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-
General Info at&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thebigotournament.com/scores.html"&gt;The Big O Live Scores Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/41130"&gt;Flat Track Stats Tournament Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://wftda.tv"&gt;WFTDA.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls are also hosting Viewings of the ARRGvTuscon and ARRGvEmerald bouts on Saturday and Sunday, starting 90min before each bout begins, at the Safari Lounge (downstairs) in Edinburgh.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;Time (Host)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;Time (UK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;Time (Japan)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;Track&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;Event&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;Archive Link&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;FTS Prediction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="7"&gt;Day 1 ("Friday")&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background-color:tomato;"&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;2pm Fri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;10pm Fri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;6am Sat
6時 土曜日&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;Kokeshi v Humbolt
こけし 対 ヘムボルツ&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T7nbOnvA1Kg"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/47550/rankings"&gt;FTS Pred&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background-color:yellowgreen;"&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;4pm Fri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;12am Fri/Sat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;8am Sat
8時 土曜日&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;ARRG v Arizona&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eywHQFtXRPo"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/47073/rankings"&gt;FTS Pred&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background-color:white;"&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;8pm Fri&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;4am Sat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;12pm Sat
12時 土曜日&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;Texas v Oly&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ULXTGZYpvas"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/47082/rankings"&gt;FTS Pred&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="7"&gt;Day 2 ("Saturday")&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background-color:yellowgreen;"&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;9am Sat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;5pm Sat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;1am Sun
1時 日曜日&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;ARRG v Tucson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q8w6mkD9diA"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/47092/rankings"&gt;FTS Pred&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background-color:tomato;"&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;7pm Sat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;3am Sun&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;11am Sun
11時 日曜日&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;Kokeshi v Arizona
こけし 対 アリゾナ&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ul00p_Ac68"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/47107/rankings"&gt;FTS Pred&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background-color:yellowgreen;"&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;7.30pm Sat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;3.30am Sun&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;11.30am Sun
11時30分 日曜日&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;ARRG v Sac City&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QhkGqrRdnjU"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/47109/rankings"&gt;FTS Pred&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="7"&gt;Day 3 ("Sunday")&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background-color:white;"&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;11am Sun&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;7pm Sun&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;3am Mon
3時 月曜日&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;Texas v Philly&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=caZdnw6OH0c"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/47114/rankings"&gt;FTS Pred&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background-color:yellowgreen;"&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;1pm Sun&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;9pm Sun&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;5am Mon
5時 月曜日&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;ARRG v Emerald&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7MjBWhykwnw"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/47117/rankings"&gt;FTS Pred&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background-color:tomato;"&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;1pm Sun&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;9pm Sun&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;5am Mon
5時 月曜日&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;Kokeshi v Pikes Peak
こけし 対 ピケスピイク&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I419_bb957A"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/47116/rankings"&gt;FTS Pred&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background-color:white;"&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;5pm Sun&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;1am Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;9am Mon
9時 月曜日&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;Philly v Oly&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TCvIPo8q15g"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/47123/rankings"&gt;FTS Pred&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr style="background-color:white;"&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;7pm Sun&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;3am Mon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;11am Mon
11時 月曜日&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;"MVPs" v Team USA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Yo6Q-an7sE"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="border:1px solid black;"&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>kokeshi roller dolls</category><category>the big o</category><category>tournament</category><category>twisted thistles</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/05/01/big-o-tournament-timing-and-links/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 11:35:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Second Wave: Auld Reekie and Kokeshi Rollers make The Big O.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/04/29/the-second-wave-auld-reekie-and-kokeshi-rollers-make-the-big-o/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2013 was a big year for Scottish Roller Derby on the international scene, as Glasgow Roller Derby's Irn Bruisers and &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' Twisted Thistles both made the trip across the Atlantic to play in ECDX, the first UK teams other than London Roller Girls to start competing seriously against US teams on their home ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with London's initial experiences, ARRG and GRD made a splash, both doing much better than many of the US natives had expected. This year, both leagues are sending their A teams to different events - GRD is targetting &lt;em&gt;Spring Roll&lt;/em&gt; in Fort Wayne, and Auld Reekie are off to &lt;em&gt;The Big O&lt;/em&gt; in Oregon this coming weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thebigotournament.com/"&gt;The Big O&lt;/a&gt; is a yearly tournament hosted by Emerald City Roller Girls (based in Eugene, Oregon) since 2012. It's no stranger to international visitors: in 2013, Australia's Victorian Roller Derby flew across the Pacific to compete there, and the UK's own Southern Discomfort participated in the first ever international men's derby bout at the same event. As that implies, The Big O is not just a WFTDA or women's derby tournament: there is also a significant Men's Derby bracket and Junior Derby tournament as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie will be joined as International contenders amongst the US teams by Japan's &lt;a href="http://www.kokeshirollerdolls.com/"&gt;Kokeshi Roller Dolls&lt;/a&gt;. Okinawa-based Kokeshi are one of the oldest Japanese derby leagues, naming themselves after the distinctive round-headed Japanese wooden dolls (&lt;span style="color:#252525;"&gt;こけし) which also appear on their logo. Like many of the Japanese derby leagues, KRD are mostly composed of American nationals, drawn from the ranks of &lt;em&gt;United States Forces in Japan &lt;/em&gt;and their partners. The Big O will be Kokeshi's first international bouting experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both ARRG and KRD will be competing in the "lower Division 2" tournament bracket, out of the three WFTDA brackets available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Glasgow Roller Derby's Spring Roll planning to be covered in a later article, we caught up with Auld Reekie's Ciderella and Kokeshi's Riot Earp and Dark Passenger to get their thoughts on planning for, experiencing, and learning from, international tournaments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/04/logobpt.gif"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-3396" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/04/logobpt.gif?w=614" alt="The Big O Logo" width="614" height="363"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ARRG) The Thistles’ first trip across the Atlantic made something of a splash as both ARRG and Glasgow Roller Derby outperformed expectations at ECDX. Now that the USA is adjusting to the quality of top European teams, are you expecting your experience of the Big O to be different?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cider) In some ways yes. This is going to be a much tougher tournament as the teams we are playing are mostly ranked a lot higher than we've played before and the ranking system is a lot more settled than it was last year. However last year I'm sure we felt the same; we were travelling overseas to play teams ranked higher than us then as well. it is only looking back at that experience that this time around seems more challenging. We still just want to go out and play the best that we can and show the rest of the derby community what we can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(KRD) According to Flat Track Stats, KRD have relatively few interleague bouts under their belt, thanks to the relatively recent growth of derby in Japan. How are you preparing for your first really big derby tournament challenge?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PRACTICE! We practice as much as we can first. Only a handful of us have been to a tournament so we are heeding the words of those experienced skaters to mentally and physically prep ourselves. We also have been working together as a team to coordinate travel and fundraising plans, as this is such a long trip. (Riot Earp)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRD is preparing for our very first tournament in several ways. We have weekly scrimmages, we are practicing 3 days a week and participate in off skates workouts with groups or on our own. (Dark Passenger)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ARRG) Over the past year, the Thistles’ Ranking has pretty much continuously increased, according to Flat Track Stats metrics. In addition, you’re ranked as the best (non-London) team in the UK by UKRDA’s subset of FTS’s rankings, and have a comfortable spot in Division 2 of WFTDA’s rankings, heading up the European contingent. How important was the experience of ECDX to your improvement as a team? Is there a point where every league has to start looking across the Atlantic for more challenges?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cider) In terms of improvement as a team, ECDX was certainly a focus for us in our training but I don't necessarily think that a tournament itself improves a team, I believe it is the work behind the scenes that does that. Travelling overseas and knowing that this was our one (very expensive) opportunity to get into Division 2 that year was certainly a good motivation! That being said, tournaments are so different to single games that any experience a team can get attending them is vital if you are serious about progressing up the rankings. They take a lot more out of you and as a unit you need to be smart about how you play the long game. It can also be a bit overwhelming the first time you travel anywhere with your league, so the more experience you can get the better. That way you can focus on the game when you are there and not everything else happening around that.
As for going across the Atlantic to get those chances, well I really hope it does not get to the point where all leagues have to do this. Obviously if leagues want to do it, well that's great, it is a wonderful experience to see derby around the world and have that challenge against long-running leagues. The more a team climbs in the WFTDA rankings at the moment, the more likely they will need to go overseas to get the match ups they need, however, as there are now more European leagues doing this, hopefully it should have a knock on effect for the rest of Europe. In my opinion, the main reason top European leagues are forced to look elsewhere for games is due to their initial entry point into the WFTDA ranking system. Most start near the bottom, which means a fair sized rankings gap between themselves and perhaps other European leagues who have climbed the rankings but are actually similar in skill level. The team ranked higher then struggles, as they know they wont be able to get the point differential they need in that game to maintain their position. If there were a lot of teams ranked at their level that they could easily travel to, this would not be an issue as they could help that team out and then average out their ranking elsewhere, however, at the moment in Europe there are not enough near-by teams who have similar ranking levels for this to work.
Hopefully with the amount of European teams crossing the Atlantic this year, the gaps will close and we can spread these rankings around. Although then I am sure other parts of the world will have the same challenges as derby progresses elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ARRG) Compared to the lineup at ECDX, the Thistles are facing twice as many bouts, against higher ranked opponents (including the intimidating Arizona, ranked #29 by FlatTrackStats at the time of writing). How do you prepare to face these really tough opponents?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cider) Last year when we went to ECDX we arranged a couple of extra games around the area to get the most out of the trip over there; whilst we only played two games at the tournament, we actually played 4 in a short amount of time; so we do have the experience of playing a good amount of teams over a short space of time. However, the toughness of these teams is not something we have had much experience in. We've prepared the only way we know how; by training as hard as possible on and off skates to make sure we are physically and mentally up to scratch. We are approaching this tournament with our usual positive attitude and a set of goals we wish to achieve as a team one of which is to get another good climb up the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ARRG) This year, a few more UK teams are heading across the water to ECDX, including Tiger Bay Brawlers, who you narrowly defeated just a few weeks ago. How do you rate their chances in the tournament, given your experience?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cider) I think all the teams will do well at ECDX. As I said before tournaments are a great experience and perhaps a league with no experience of overseas travel and tournament weekends might find it a bit overwhelming, however, one of the benefits of being a derby league in Europe is that over seas travel and tournaments are hard to avoid. I'm very excited to see how these teams progress and hopefully I will be able to catch a few of the games on the live stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(ARRG) Also joining you as the only other non-US team at The Big O are Okinawa’s Kokeshi Roller Dolls. What advice would you give them in approaching the tournament, especially facing a really tough team like Arizona (as you both will be)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cider) It is really important as a team to have clear goals going into a tournament and that everybody is on the same page. No matter what gets thrown at you in a game, focus on the bigger picture and remember it is a team effort. When you know you are going up against a tough team with a much higher ranking I think you should always aim high but be realistic about the situation; you're probably not going to get a 2:1 win ratio against them, but what can you get? Do you just want to get through the match alive? (There have been games where this is all I've wanted!) Get lead a certain percentage of the game? Shut down their point accumulation? Have a goal (or goals) and see them through. If you don't achieve them all, that's okay, just reassess afterwards, pick yourself up and have another look at them; maybe there is something you can learn from not having reached them that will help your team progress further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(KRD) The Big O is not just a chance to play challenging teams, it’s also a chance to meet other skaters. With some very impressive Division 1 teams in attendance, who are you most looking forward to meeting? Are you looking forward to meeting your fellow non-US team, Auld Reekie Roller Girls?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Riot Earp) There are a few big names thrown around the team as far as whom they HAVE to watch and want to meet, but personally, I’m excited to meet anyone and everyone! In my eyes, every skater there is an unbelievable athlete and work hard to be there. Each skater is special and amazing in their own way and I absolutely cannot wait to take it all in. We are extremely excited to meet ARRG. Being a non US localized team it’ll be great to make connections and learn and brainstorm on how they operate overseas and how it could help us improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Dark Passenger) We are extremely excited to meet Auld Reekie as well as all the other teams there competing. We are all so excited to be a part of The Big O, I don’t think there’s really any team we’re really looking forward to meeting. We can’t wait to meet all the teams!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As well as a WFTDA Division 1 bracket, The Big O also features a significant Men’s Derby schedule, and a (West-coast) oriented Junior Derby schedule as well. What bouts are you looking forward to trying to catch, schedule permitting?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cider) I really am looking forward to seeing Kokeshi play, that will be good. I would also like to see Texas - Rose, however, the timing overlaps with one of our games so I am not sure if I will get to see any of it. As for the Men's and Junior's, I would like to see what I can as it is always exciting and there is always something to learn!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Riot Earp) Being able to see Live Derby at this scale not on a computer monitor is more then we can ask for in the first place I know just being there to watch is going to be more then we could have asked for. We also just found out team USA will be there bouting the MVP mash up… this is one no one will miss!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Dark Passenger) There are so many bouts we’d like to catch. The big one would have to be Texas Roller Girls vs Rose City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going to the USA is expensive.  How do you decide how to raise funds for this kind of outlay, and how are you spreading the word about your events?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cider) Well we have some fantastic committees, especially marketing and sponsorship. They look at the figures and come up with some inventive fundraising ideas. We have an awards ball on June 21st which will be a lot of fun; Crazylegs is threatening to turn up in a wedding dress (the theme is dress fancy) so it is really not to be missed. Obviously after the success of our limited edition t-shirts last year, we've rolled out a new design which is friggin awesome and &lt;a href="http://auldreekierollergirls.bigcartel.com/"&gt;you can get right here.&lt;/a&gt; I really love a well designed t-shirt as a fundraising aid as everybody wins; the league gets some help and the buyer gets a great tee.
We also have another boot-camp coming up on the 19th July, so save the date, it's going to be a good one! &lt;em&gt;[Auld Reekie have held a range of fundraising events, including a Comedy Night at The Stand last week.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Riot Earp) FUNDRAISING FUNDRAISING FUNDRAISING! But yes in all seriousness along with mentally and physically prepping for this tournament we also had to financially prepare. The dollstars created a t-shirt line and have been selling them as well as setting up a &lt;a href="http://www.gofundme.com/5oqiug"&gt;GO FUND ME&lt;/a&gt; account. We also have been smaller fundraisers such as bake sales and babysitting for donations. Every penny has helped and we appreciate all those that have donated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Dark Passenger) The league has been fundraising since about October using GoFundMe and by having bake sales and by creating a unique &lt;a href="http://www.kokeshirollerdolls.com/images/ringer.jpg"&gt;Okinawa Roller Derby shirt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, what are your aims for the team with regards to the Big O as a competition and an experience? (For KRD, are you hoping this will raise awareness of Japanese derby, internationally? )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cider) Come back alive haha. We really want to climb further up the rankings, we are aiming high, Division 1 in fact, though we know this is a hell of a challenge. I think we really just want to see how we sit against teams ranked in the Division 1 area. No matter what happens this week, we will come back with a much clearer picture of what we need to do to progress further up the rankings and hopefully we can pass on this knowledge to other European leagues too, so that we can all benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Riot Earp) I think above all here in Okinawa we work hard to spread the word of derby. Most on island have not heard of it or have an ill-conceived notion of derby and assume we play 1970’s punch in the face derby. KRD works hard to help the sport of derby grow here in Okinawa and in mainland Japan. We hope that KRD being at the BIG O will not only help get our names out there but also the other leagues such as Tokyo Roller Girls and Devil Dog Derby Dames known. This is just the first step in what will be a long, fruitful adventure in derby for Kokeshi Roller Dolls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Dark Passenger) We are hopeful that KRD’s appearance at the Big O will bring an interest to other leagues to come out to Asia and skate against us and the other leagues on Mainland Japan and Okinawa. We are definitely planning on more international travel and participation in tournaments in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article would not have been possible without the assistance of ARRG's Double D-struction and KRD member "ghostopolis" on Reddit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>international</category><category>interviews</category><category>kokeshi roller dolls</category><category>krd</category><category>the big o</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/04/29/the-second-wave-auld-reekie-and-kokeshi-rollers-make-the-big-o/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 09:17:06 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>