<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about leeds roller dolls)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/leeds-roller-dolls.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 11:56:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: Leeds Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/15/euroclash-interviews-leeds-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leeds Roller Derby is, technically, the youngest team attending Newcastle Roller Girls' &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;in March, having formed from the merger of Leeds Roller Dolls and Hot Wheel Roller Derby only &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/19/by-their-powers-combined-they-are-leeds-roller-derby/"&gt;scant months ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
Whilst Hot Wheel had a lower ranking than Leeds Roller Dolls, we're pretty sure that the new LeedsRD will gain from the breadth of skaters available to it, and would predict that their performance will be at least as good as Leeds Roller Dolls (currently ranked 22nd in Europe by Flat Track Stats).
There's certainly a wealth of experience in both teams, as LRD spent much of 2016 in the Tier 1 of British Champs (finishing in the middle of the table), and then in the Mayday Mayhem across in the USA; whilst Hot Wheel, who were just breaking into Europe, debuted at SKOD 2016 in Belgium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14923 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/02/lrdtrain.jpg" alt="lrdtrain" width="1600" height="922"&gt; Leeds Roller Derby don't have a logo, so we're showing you their first practice together instead!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LeedsRD Co-Captains Lana del Slay and Nina answered a few questions for us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We should start with the big news: Leeds Roller Derby didn't exist as a league until late last year, when Leeds Roller Dolls and Hot Wheel Roller Derby merged. You've published your first combined roster, and there's a good contribution from both leagues - what would you say each league brings to the new collaboration?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lana del Slay: I think each league brings similar things, that's part of the reason we merged. We have great people who bring a range of experience and knowledge but mainly passion and enthusiasm for the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 was a pretty good year for both of your source leagues: Leeds Roller Dolls and Hot Wheel both did exceptionally well in British Champs, but also the Dolls had their second successful trip to the USA in the Mayday Mayhem, and Hot Wheel their first "international" tournament at SKOD2016 [beating their seeding by 4 places!], following the Dolls (who attended in 2014). What were the high points for you over 2016, and will the new Leeds Roller Derby be picking up where Leeds Roller Dolls left off, in terms of International derby?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lana del Slay: Both those things were high points for sure, but I think we’re all in agreement that the decision to merge is the best thing either team has ever done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nina: And that’s our biggest priority right now - focusing on us, Leeds Roller Derby. Our number one goal for the season is becoming a &lt;em&gt;team&lt;/em&gt;, which may not sound very ambitious considering where both of us came from in 2016 but we feel it's the best thing for us. This isn’t just about 2017, it’s about the season after that, and the season after that. Once we know our teammates then we can focus on international derby. And there is so much talent in the UK and Europe we are happy to concentrate our efforts this side of the pond for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This interview is to help promote EuroClash, which is just one big tournament that LeedsRD is throwing itself into in its first year. How are you preparing for taking on some of the top European teams, and who are you most looking forward to playing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nina: Lots of training and getting to know each other! In terms of the teams, we are excited to play both ARRG and Dublin. Each team brings something different. ARRG we haven't played in quite some time so will be a bit of an unknown whereas both LRD and HWRD played DRD 2015/2016 [&lt;em&gt;ed: Leeds Roller Dolls took a win in late 2015, whilst Hot Wheel lost last October&lt;/em&gt;] so will be interesting to see how we perform against them as Leeds Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With the schedule as it is, LeedsRD will also have the chance to watch quite a few other games - are there any teams, or matchups between teams, which you're particularly looking forward to?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nina: Yes! Definitely Bear City and Paris. Newcastle and MMR are always good teams to watch too because their blockers are so physical and hard hitting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 is already a big year for Leeds Roller Derby, but is there anything else coming up in the future for the league? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lana del Slay: So much is happening in the Leeds Roller Derby camp. We are beavering away putting the final touches to our season outside of the British Champs. We plan to have a few home games over the year where we can hopefully showcase our full league and host games for the A and B team as well as our Junior league. October is going to be a very big month for us. We’re going to be celebrating 10 years of roller derby in Leeds with our rebrand which we’re going to be launching then, and let's not forget the return of the Great Yorkshire Showdown which is also going to be in October.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>euroclash</category><category>hot wheel roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>leeds roller dolls</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/15/euroclash-interviews-leeds-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 10:53:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>By their powers combined, they are... Leeds Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/19/by-their-powers-combined-they-are-leeds-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, it perhaps says something about Roller Derby as a culture that growth happens most publicly as a result of new leagues forming, rather than people banding together...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...but in Leeds, that trend is being bucked, as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://leedsrollerdolls.com/"&gt;Leeds Roller Dolls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [#65 WFTDA, #11 UKRDA, #150 SRD ] and Hot Wheel Roller Derby [#9 UKRDA, #179 SRD], Leed's two long-standing leagues, have announced today their merger into one single &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/WeAreLeedsRD/"&gt;Leeds Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-12931" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/screen-shot-2016-12-19-at-10-07-11.png" alt="screen-shot-2016-12-19-at-10-07-11" width="920" height="564"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rebrand and image of the resulting league is still in development, so the travel team will compete in black and white at British Champs Tier 1 this year, before unveiling new colours later in the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head coach and Men’s Team England skater Jerry Attric’, who founded LRD in 2007, and  HWRD in 2010 – said: “There has been some pretty fierce rivalry between us over the years but, as time has gone on, it has become obvious that we both want the same things – most importantly to be the best - and our members agreed that we could do this better together than apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We all want to create a team that will be a real challenge to the top teams going forwards, and will have room for the development of newer skaters too.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking about how the negotiation process worked, Livid Doll, long term LRD coach and skater said: “There aren’t many people with us who were here back then, but of course we had to be sure that the two teams’ histories weren’t going to get in the way. We had a meeting. We put the past behind us and we started afresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A lot of work has been going on behind the scenes and we trained together for a couple of weeks before the vote opened to give us all a sense of how we’d mesh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re extremely excited about what lies ahead for us as a united force.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One element which may have crystallised the need to cooperate for a greater result is the loss of Leeds Roller Doll's venue, the Leeds Futsal Area, earlier in 2016. Leeds Roller Derby will be using Hot Wheels' venue of Leed's University's The Edge sports centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the focus currently is on Leeds Roller Derby's A team, as they need to be ready for British Champs 2017, the league also plans a B team, recreational team and a juniors team!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>hot wheel roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>leeds roller dolls</category><category>merger</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/19/by-their-powers-combined-they-are-leeds-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 10:12:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Triple Champs at Glasgow!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/23/triple-champs-at-glasgow/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While this Friday and Saturday feature &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/"&gt;Asia's first ever WFTDA tournament&lt;/a&gt;, the time difference means that there's also plenty of time to experience the best that the United Kingdom also has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After opening the &lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/"&gt;British Championships&lt;/a&gt; Premier Tier with a double header only a few weeks ago, Glasgow Roller Derby are topping their own event with a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1682046455408262/"&gt;Triple Header of Premier Tier bouts&lt;/a&gt; this Saturday, &lt;strong&gt;26th March&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting at &lt;strong&gt;11:15&lt;/strong&gt;, in Glasgow Caledonian University's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8676586,-4.2505954,16.15z/data=!4m5!1m2!2m1!1sARC!3m1!1s0x0000000000000000:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7"&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Glasgow themselves will be taking on both Royal Windsor Roller Girls' "Who Dares Windsor" and Leeds Roller Dolls' "Leeds Rebel Roses", while Newcastle Rollergirls will be returning to the North to also take on Royal Windsor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-6749 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/12809518_984872564914955_8578538005295953183_n.jpg" alt="12809518_984872564914955_8578538005295953183_n" width="595" height="841"&gt;
On points difference, Newcastle are &lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/womens-tables-2016/"&gt;currently topping the table&lt;/a&gt;; although drawn with Leeds and London on actual wins. They'll be looking to take a second win, solidifying their position at the top; but of course Leeds themselves are in the same position to take the lead.
Meanwhile, both Royal Windsor and Glasgow themselves need to pick up wins to move up the table. With two games each, they'll be looking to pick up as many points as possible. (Winning both games would move either team to the top of the table in a single fixture!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Royal Windsor spoke to us about their feelings on the challenge. "We have been training super hard for this weekend. It is a momentous occasion for us as we want to make our mark on this year's premier tier. We are looking forward to putting all our hard work into practice and hopefully coming away with a result that the team can be proud of."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt; expects Glasgow to triumph over Royal Windsor with about a 3:1 score ratio, and over Leeds about 3:2; with Newcastle predicted a 5:3 win over Royal Windsor. Of course, the last fixture in Glasgow completely defied the statistics, so everything is definitely to play for!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hosts Glasgow Roller Derby's Sarah McMillan told us: "Glasgow is really excited to be hosting the British Championships Premier Tier games this weekend! 3 of thee highest level of UK roller derby games will be played in one day, here in Glasgow!! Our All-star team, the Irn Bruisers will be playing two games in one day - first up, we're playing Royal Windsor and the last game of the day will be us against our old friends Leeds!
The other game is Table toppers Newcastle playing Royal Windsor, so it promises to be a really exciting day! More information and advanced tickets are available on the GRD website - &lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com"&gt;www.glasgowrollerderby.com&lt;/a&gt; with a 10% discount on a ticket for blog readers using code SCOTBLOG"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>leeds roller dolls</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>royal windsor rollergirls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/23/triple-champs-at-glasgow/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 15:25:07 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>