<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about lincolnshire rolling thunder)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/lincolnshire-rolling-thunder.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Mean City take on two, too, on the 12th!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/07/mean-city-take-on-two-too-on-the-12th/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last article, we covered events planned for this weekend on one Coast of Scotland. But, the West Coast also has just as much derby planned for the &lt;strong&gt;12th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;March, &lt;/strong&gt;in Glasgow Caledonian University's&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/vtgcEHaTUys"&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;in an event known only as&lt;strong&gt; Purple Reign.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kicking off with doors open at &lt;strong&gt;11:30am&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby/"&gt;Mean City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s Mens and Women's teams will both face off against challengers in this exciting double header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Women will face off against Midlothian's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/lothianderby/"&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt;, hoping to continue their winning streak from 2015. For their part, LDD will be keen to pick up a win, after an opening season loss against Dundee's Bonnie Colliders at home. FlatTrackStats is unable to predict this game, so the only way to find out what will happen is to turn up on the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Men will be taking on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/LRTRollerDerby/timeline?ref=page_internal"&gt;Lincolnshire Rolling Thunder&lt;/a&gt;'s B-team (who may be called the Thugly Ducklings). Once again, FlatTrackStats is unable to predict this game, as Rolling Thunder's B-team is so new. Clearly, the Ducklings will be keen to break their duck in their first trip up to Scotland; but Mean City's Men will be equally enthusiastic to put a narrow loss against Teeside Skate Invaders (away) earlier this year behind them, and prove they can command on their home turf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MCRD President Elaine Hunter said, "Last year was a momentous 12 months in the history of Mean City, with both our women's and men's teams winning - not to mention our coed all-stars.
"I'm delighted that the 2016 home season is kicking off with a cracking double-header - featuring our friends at Lothian Derby Dolls and Lincolnshire Rolling Thunder.
"We've been training hard and can't wait to make our 2016 home debut at the ARC - offering thrills, skills and spills for all the family.
"As usual we'll sell you the full seat, but you'll only need the edge. Come and join us as the purple reign continues."
Join the Purple Reign on 12th March at Glasgow's ARC. Tickets are just £5 &lt;a href="http://www.meancityrollerderby.com/tickets.php"&gt;in advance&lt;/a&gt; - £6 on the door. Under-14s have free entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, Mean City will be hosting the after party upstairs at their sponsor, &lt;a href="http://theravenglasgow.com/"&gt;The Raven&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1555212058123782/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1555212058123782/&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>lincolnshire rolling thunder</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/07/mean-city-take-on-two-too-on-the-12th/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 22:43:59 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>