<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about lothian derby dolls)</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/lothian-derby-dolls.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:54:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Fair City Rollers: Rising</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/20/fair-city-rollers-rising/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Sunday is the only time you'll see Perth's local roller derby league, Fair City Rollers, on track at home this year, due to the popularity of their excellent local venue, Bell's Sport Centre. As a result, for those following the team, it's an opportunity not to be missed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-26879" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/fcr_map-layered.png?w=1024" alt="FCR_map-layered" width="1024" height="948"&gt; Fair City, and the leagues combining to face them as "Scotland's Rising Stars"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fear Maidens, Fair City's travel team, will be facing a mixed exhibition team drawing newer skaters from Ayrshire Roller Derby, Bairn City Rollers' Central Belters, Dundee Roller Derby, Granite City Roller Derby, Lothian Roller Derby and Mean City Roller Derby. Coming together as "Scotland's Rising Stars", these skaters represent some of the best new talent in Scottish roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fear Maidens have played one previous bout this year, losing away to Dundee's B team, the Bonnie Colliders, back in &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/8969"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Due to way Flat Track Stats' rating changes are applied (always equally, but oppositely, to both teams), this has almost certainly underrated the Perth team at present, due to both Dundee teams' considerable strength gains year on year. Whilst this game against an exhibition team will not compensate in the ratings, we're confident of a strong showing from Perth's only roller derby team at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City's Invader Zoom told us, "We are so excited to be playing at home again and can't wait for the people of Perth to see some of our new recruits in action. Our last home game was a nail biter that had the audience on the edge of their seats all game, and we are sure this game will be just as thrilling with a challenge team of skaters from 6 different Scottish leagues!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as Roller Derby action on track, there will be the usual collection of stalls, including an opportunity to support the charity &lt;a href="http://www.clicsargent.org.uk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CLIC Sargent in Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, raising money to help Young Lives versus Cancer. Fair City Rollers will be participating in CLIC Sargent's Rainbow Assault assault course event in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City Rollers' "&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1869400046436599/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pack to the Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;" is at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/Sty37VvYGx92"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bell's Sports Centre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Perth, on the &lt;strong&gt;24th June&lt;/strong&gt;, 2018. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>fear maidens</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/20/fair-city-rollers-rising/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 13:36:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An interview with Lothian Derby Dolls' Captain: Fully Harmed</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/18/an-interview-with-lothian-derby-dolls-captain-fully-harmed/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The third team we've covering in the run up to Auld Reekie Roller Girls' &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/535844416618826/"&gt;ARRGmageddon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Tournament is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/lothianderby/"&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. LDD are, perhaps, the underdogs coming into the tournament in some ways, having lost to Dundee's Bonnie Colliders early this year. However, their roster at that point was somewhat different to their current lineup, so it's really hard to call.
We talked to their Captain, Fully Harmed, to see how Lothian's year has been, and how they're thinking about the upcoming Tournament:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- So, I think it's fair to say that Lothian Derby Dolls have had a mixed year so far; early on you had a few losses against the Bonnie Colliders and Mean City, but more recently you pulled off a win against Ayrshire Roller Derby away... how would you say the league is steering itself?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I would say this year has been very mixed. We started off quite low; I think with LDD it's always very skater dependant, and we lost a few reliable, strong skaters. We've really spent the summer building up our core again. We've got a reliable lot of, I'd say, 15 skaters, but, because of the type of league we are...  you know, it could be chicken pox and, because we're mums, that could be (say) 5 skaters off for a couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We've also had some injuries with some of our players, Poca Loca [LDD ViceCaptain] came back quite strong from an ankle injury, but she's still not 100%, and Fury has a niggling knee injury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;However, I &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; say it's been a really really positive year, because while we've really stepped back from bouting, we've really worked on our skill, to get that more solid; our skills, our communication, our teamwork. Definitely, on taking over as Captain, that's been our focus as a team: it's not about winning or losing in my eyes, (I mean, a win's brilliant) it's about us all having our personal goals, and as a team having a goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We are a little league; we're the smallest of the leagues who will be playing [in ARRGmageddon], by miles. I mean, we've got 30 active skaters just now.  For us to be even putting ourselves forward for the tournament, we've come a long way, this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Ayrshire was a brilliant experience; lovely people, lovely skaters. We were really happy to win, but for us it was more about showing that working on our skills together as a team, and you know, it really proved to us that when you work on your skills and trust each other, it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;So, thats the change from the [bout against the] Bonnie Colliders... when we played them, we weren't really working well as a team, I would say we got downheartened very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;These days,  as a Captain, I'm pushing&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;- "Fine, if we're losing, we're working on Our Goals, all the time, keep strong, .. " So you know, I'm not expecting a win, in a week's time, but I'm expecting us to have our goals and win that way !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- Despite you saying that, LDD are the only team competing at ARRGmageddon who've actually had Tournament experience (from the Battle of Britain tournament in 2013). Quite a few of the skaters from 2013's roster are still around, has their experience helped in preparation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I think it does help. The skaters who were involved in that experience, you know, they've been very honest - that there's negative [factors] to being involved in a tournament - but, we've talked about that, and we're going to try to avoid those issues with people's stamina, and try to keep the positivity going all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I think, compared to [Battle of Britain], there's a lot more positivity, there's a lot more — happiness - I feel positive, regardless of the score, that LDD will&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;come out, and we'll play strongly, we'll work together well, but, you know, we're against big teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;But, I think that previous experience will help us - we've got a lot of players with [general] experience, though. We just keep everything calm, and…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- When the high of the tournament has passed, what's coming up next for LDD?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Well, other than the tournament, we're looking for return matches, with New Town and the Fight Hawks, we're looking at some more new bouts with new teams, which are about our levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The problem with [finding bouts in] Scotland, is you've got Glasgow, ARRG, Granite, Dundee, even the [Bairn City Rollers'] Central Belters are up there, and Fierce Valley,… and then there's us. [Our interest is] trying to play with more teams that are our level, so we can get better scrims, and bouting experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;But, also, we're really working on our Coed. Fear and Lothian were our big piece of work we did this year, with Capital City, and I think training with men has brought a different dynamic to the team. Definitely, it's speeded up our game: we've got less time to stop and think about things on track.
So, Fear and Lothian will be having a bout, we've got a couple of idea of teams, we're just negotiating that at the minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;That's definitely a focus for LDD as well, keeping the Coed going - and really working on our female game, consolidating all the skills we've been working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;So, we're feeling positive. And I think we're the kind of team that, you know, it doesn't matter if we win or lose, but … the thing about Ayrshire was, they're a great team, they think about this the same way as us: you go out and you do the best you can, and you enjoy it - I mean, that's why we all do it&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;- you enjoy yourself, that's sometimes forgot. And, we are a team that really do; we socialise together, we love each other, we support each other, if we're injured,&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;and we do have a lot of kids and they play together too. It sounds a bit mushy, but we're very much in and out of each others' lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;And, it sounds terrible, but if somebody hurts one of my Dolls, I'll do everything I can to support them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;So, very much, we've got a lot of camaraderie between us, and I think we've come along way together, through all the ups and downs for LDD; I'm sure there's more to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We are a wee league I mean, ARRG's got about 60 skaters and you can't… compare them.But actually,  I've skated with some of the girls from the C team, you know, at scrims and things, and they're a lovely bunch, so...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I think LDD's getting to know leagues a bit better, I mean, Dundee are very friendly with us, and Granite too… so it'll be an enjoyable day, we're really looking forward to it.

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The ARRGmageddon Tournament is running on the &lt;strong&gt;26 November&lt;/strong&gt;, at Auld Reekie's usual venue of &lt;strong&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/strong&gt;, as an all-day event starting at &lt;strong&gt;11am&lt;/strong&gt;.. Ticket prices are £8 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2714193"&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, £10 (£6 concessions) on the door, free entry for under 14's.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>arrgmageddon</category><category>articles</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/18/an-interview-with-lothian-derby-dolls-captain-fully-harmed/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 13:40:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ayshire Roller Derby hit the Track, Full Throttle</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/16/ayshire-roller-derby-hit-the-track/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Someone at Ayrshire Roller Derby is clearly a fan of old Lucasarts adventure games. The league's long-awaited debut bout, hosted at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Magnum+Leisure+Centre/@55.60667,-4.685244,15z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0xaa425516c021b7f4!8m2!3d55.60667!4d-4.685244"&gt;Magnum Leisure Centre, Irvine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, is titled simply "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/300853163602927/"&gt;Day of the Tentacle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;", not just a reference to ARD's Kraken/Octopus mascot, but also the name of Lucasarts' famous sequel to their original hit, Maniac Mansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/300853163602927/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8739" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/08/13901351_1024883397619520_1178475040826834661_n.jpg" alt="13901351_1024883397619520_1178475040826834661_n" width="768" height="318"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike the game, we expect that ARD have few plans for world domination or toilet-based timetravel, and instead will be concentrating on the challenge of taking on Lothian Derby Dolls for their first public bout as a team. It's something that Scotland's west-most league have been working on for months, with many of their skaters immediately signing up for multiple cherry poppers (or "rookie bouts" as the more serious in roller derby seem to be calling them) as soon as they've passed mins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it all builds to this, the &lt;strong&gt;10th September&lt;/strong&gt; in Irvine, when they come together as a team for the first time in public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most visible skaters the aforementioned games has been Poison Petal, who's probably bent the rules on how much experience you can gain and still count as a rookie over the last 9 months. She was also happy to talk to us (and take some comments from others on the team) on this occasion:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;"We have been on an awesome adventure since the team was first formed until now. There's been highs and lows and many hall changes, but we are finally just about there! Our first bout will take place on the 10th of September against Lothian Derby Dolls. Now the hard work begins all over again. We've navigated our way through mins and now we have even more skills, strategies and tactics to learn. There is a very excited buzz around the team at the moment with everyone pushing themselves in order to merit their green jersey and gain a place on that first team. I asked a few of the team about how they felt about the game coming up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Barty Ouch, one of our newest mins passed players, said  «[I'm] nervous, excited, slightly terrified; but can't wait to hopefully make the roster and get out there with my team, and show that all our hard work has paid off and what ARD is all about. It'll be a fantastic day for everyone playing or not and this is really just the beginning for us.»&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Super Sal agreed,  «I'm terrified, and excited all at the same time. I'm also proud of the team (and myself) for getting to this point! It's taken a while. For me anyway!»&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;R2 DeckYou «I'm looking forward to taking the first step with ARD into the derbyverse. This will be the first time that I can play with a full team of the girls I've laughed and cried with for the last 10 months.»"&lt;/p&gt;
Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;11:30&lt;/strong&gt;, for a probable start around midday. There's no online tickets available at the time of writing, so you'll have to get them on the door...&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/16/ayshire-roller-derby-hit-the-track/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 12:09:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Powers of Two at Mean City</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/24/powers-of-two-at-mean-city/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; obviously like the number two. That's the only explanation for the preponderance of twos in this weekend's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/487160101472894/"&gt;upcoming event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; they're hosting, at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662183,-4.2519236,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8662153!4d-4.2497349"&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Glasgow.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-7335" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/11707838_666231253513298_2828507735651128838_o.jpg?w=1024" alt="11707838_666231253513298_2828507735651128838_o" width="1024" height="384"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only is this a double header, with &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; exciting bouts to experience, but both bouts have their own multiplicative factors as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headlining, we have Scotland's National Men's Roller Derby team, Power of Scotland, facing off against "The Other Guys" - the "&lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt; best Scottish men's skaters" from four (&lt;em&gt;2&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;!) Scottish leagues: Mean City themselves, Capital City, Bairn City's Skelpies and Granite City's Brawlermen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;are less than two months away from the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;World Cup in Calgary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and this is an important fixture both for training and also fundraising. As well as donations direct to PoS, the Team Physio (Dundee Roller Girls' Goldginger) Claire will be offering physio for donations [she also has a separate fundraiser &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.justgiving.com/Claire-Semple2"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] - and official Team Photographer Laura MacDonald will also be in attendance [she's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gofundme.com/PoSLauraCalgary"&gt;raising money too&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;!].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second up, Mean City's own co-ed team (who I don't think actually have a name yet) are facing off against a &lt;em&gt;double&lt;/em&gt;-league mashup of Capital City Roller Derby and Lothian Derby Dolls: "Fear and Lothian". The two Edinburgh-based leagues have been working pretty closely in preparation for this game, and we believe that Fear and Lothian is going to become a longer standing collaboration - there will be new merch available at the bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With both bouts containing exhibition teams, there's no stats to predict the outcomes - so the only way to see what will happen is to come along!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://meancityrollerderby.com/tickets.php"&gt;£5 in advance&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;£6&lt;/strong&gt; on the door (under-14s free).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;11:30am&lt;/strong&gt; for an approximately midday start this &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 28th May&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/24/powers-of-two-at-mean-city/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 09:37:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dolls in Bowls at Transgression Park</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/06/dolls-in-bowls-at-transgression-park/</link><dc:creator>kj782</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;In addition to their passion for all things derby, a handful of LDD skaters have a new found lust for ramps and aggressive quad skating.  On &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 24&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; April&lt;/strong&gt;, Lothian Derby Dolls are excited to be hosting a Quad Skate Night at &lt;strong&gt;Transgression Park&lt;/strong&gt; in Midlothian.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=" wp-image-6950 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/12321707_525422107661960_6255470024138098836_n.jpg" alt="12321707_525422107661960_6255470024138098836_n.jpg" width="430" height="607"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="line-height:1.7;"&gt;A few members of Lothian Derby Dolls have been spending time at the local indoor skate park over the last few months, pushing themselves out of their comfort zones by getting to grips with skating on an uneven surface and learning new skills and tricks at the same time.  Some have mastered bowls and drop-ins already!  And it’s pretty impressive.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In collaboration with &lt;a href="http://www.transgressionpark.com"&gt;Transgression Park&lt;/a&gt;, LDD are hosting the very first Quad Skate Night at the venue.  It promises to be a fun and social event, bringing the roller derby community together for a bit of banter and an opportunity to have a go at something a bit different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6957" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/12565422_10153252438310025_8112855549625087405_n.jpg" alt="12565422_10153252438310025_8112855549625087405_n" width="960" height="960"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;LDD's Sam-Awry getting some air&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chicksinbowls.com"&gt;Chicks In Bowls&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;was the idea driven by Lady Trample of the Pirate City Rollers, Auckland, New Zealand.  The aim is simple; to inspire people to strap on a pair of skates and have a go at something new.  There are over 200 CIB chapters worldwide, CIB Scotland being a fledgling chapter.  With events such as this at Transgression, it is the hope that word can spread about this different way of skating and the benefits that learning skills in the skate park can have on the track.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See the event page on Facebook for details.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1160296620677643/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1160296620677643/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;To find out about Chicks in Bowls Scotland visit &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/chicksinbowlsscotland/?fref=ts"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/chicksinbowlsscotland/?fref=ts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cib</category><category>ldd</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>skate park event</category><category>transgression park</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/06/dolls-in-bowls-at-transgression-park/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 21:37:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Skaters on track for New Town Cherry Popper</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/09/new-skaters-on-track-for-new-town-cherry-popper/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;March 19th&lt;/strong&gt; sees the Livingston area's &lt;strong&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; host a one of roller derby's traditions - a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1048868645164481/"&gt;cherry popper bout&lt;/a&gt;, showcasing new skaters from a mix of leagues. The bout will be held in New Town's current bouting venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/DSZTrnU8cYo"&gt;Blackburn Community Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6395" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/412387_204493976333497_2093997456_o.jpg?w=600" alt="412387_204493976333497_2093997456_o" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skaters from Auld Reekie Roller Girls, Bairn City Rollers, Lothian Derby Dolls, Doonhame Derby Dolls, Ayrshire Roller Derby, Fair City Rollers and Preston Roller Girls will join host New Town's own new skaters on track in two exhibition teams: The Morello Mashers (skating in hot pink) and the Women of Mass Destruction (skating in sapphire).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an ideal opportunity to see the potential of new roller derby skaters as they play their first bout in public. It's particularly exciting to see skaters from some of Scotland's leagues who are not publicly bouting yet, as this is a preview of perhaps what we might expect from Ayrshire, Doonhame and Fair City when they enter public bouts as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a slightly later game than we normally have in Scotland, with doors opening at &lt;strong&gt;4:45pm&lt;/strong&gt;, for a 5:15pm start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are available online from &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2521813"&gt;brownpapertickets&lt;/a&gt; for just &lt;strong&gt;£4&lt;/strong&gt;. Under 14s are free. Tickets will also be available on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>cherry poppers</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/09/new-skaters-on-track-for-new-town-cherry-popper/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 21:19:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mean City take on two, too, on the 12th!</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/07/mean-city-take-on-two-too-on-the-12th/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last article, we covered events planned for this weekend on one Coast of Scotland. But, the West Coast also has just as much derby planned for the &lt;strong&gt;12th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;March, &lt;/strong&gt;in Glasgow Caledonian University's&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/vtgcEHaTUys"&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;in an event known only as&lt;strong&gt; Purple Reign.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kicking off with doors open at &lt;strong&gt;11:30am&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby/"&gt;Mean City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s Mens and Women's teams will both face off against challengers in this exciting double header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Women will face off against Midlothian's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/lothianderby/"&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt;, hoping to continue their winning streak from 2015. For their part, LDD will be keen to pick up a win, after an opening season loss against Dundee's Bonnie Colliders at home. FlatTrackStats is unable to predict this game, so the only way to find out what will happen is to turn up on the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Men will be taking on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/LRTRollerDerby/timeline?ref=page_internal"&gt;Lincolnshire Rolling Thunder&lt;/a&gt;'s B-team (who may be called the Thugly Ducklings). Once again, FlatTrackStats is unable to predict this game, as Rolling Thunder's B-team is so new. Clearly, the Ducklings will be keen to break their duck in their first trip up to Scotland; but Mean City's Men will be equally enthusiastic to put a narrow loss against Teeside Skate Invaders (away) earlier this year behind them, and prove they can command on their home turf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MCRD President Elaine Hunter said, "Last year was a momentous 12 months in the history of Mean City, with both our women's and men's teams winning - not to mention our coed all-stars.
"I'm delighted that the 2016 home season is kicking off with a cracking double-header - featuring our friends at Lothian Derby Dolls and Lincolnshire Rolling Thunder.
"We've been training hard and can't wait to make our 2016 home debut at the ARC - offering thrills, skills and spills for all the family.
"As usual we'll sell you the full seat, but you'll only need the edge. Come and join us as the purple reign continues."
Join the Purple Reign on 12th March at Glasgow's ARC. Tickets are just £5 &lt;a href="http://www.meancityrollerderby.com/tickets.php"&gt;in advance&lt;/a&gt; - £6 on the door. Under-14s have free entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, Mean City will be hosting the after party upstairs at their sponsor, &lt;a href="http://theravenglasgow.com/"&gt;The Raven&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1555212058123782/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1555212058123782/&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>lincolnshire rolling thunder</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/07/mean-city-take-on-two-too-on-the-12th/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 22:43:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lothian Derby Dolls Vs Dundee Roller Girls Bonnie Colliders 13 Feb 2016</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/02/19/lothian-derby-dolls-vs-dundee-roller-girls-bonnie-colliders-13-feb-2016/</link><dc:creator>kj782</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bout review by Fully Harmed &amp;amp; Killah Jules of Lothian Derby Dolls.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;57&lt;/strong&gt; v’s DRG &lt;em&gt;Bonnie Colliders&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;414&lt;/strong&gt;
13 Feb 2016, Jack Kane Sports Centre, Edinburgh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5808" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/12751972_10153290311725025_1687578989_o.jpg" alt="12751972_10153290311725025_1687578989_o" width="1080" height="720"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5807" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/12765729_10153290313055025_364153108_o.jpg" alt="12765729_10153290313055025_364153108_o" width="1080" height="720"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photographs by Laura MacDonald&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the first bout of the year for LDD and we fielded a team with mixed levels of experience, with a few skaters injured or away having babies. We felt this was a good opportunity to give our newer skaters some experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt; The Bonnie Colliders dominated the game with strong blockers making holes in the LDD walls for nippy jammers to take advantage of.  LDD had a hard time reforming their defensive walls and then lost three skaters from the game due to penalties. The second half was more positive for LDD with Fi-Nix taking an epic star pass from Jugz and Tea Wrecks hitting out her first jammer in competitive play.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;LDD's heads never went down despite getting beaten by such a wide margin. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5806" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/12755250_10153290315560025_1787426263_o.jpg" alt="12755250_10153290315560025_1787426263_o" width="1080" height="720"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photograph by Laura MacDonald&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;In roller derby things change quickly and we will be training hard until our next bout on the &lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt;th of &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt; against Mean City in Glasgow.  &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1555212058123782/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1555212058123782/ &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout reports</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>ldd</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/02/19/lothian-derby-dolls-vs-dundee-roller-girls-bonnie-colliders-13-feb-2016/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 17:43:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Upcoming Events Roundup!</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/13/upcoming-events-roundup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scottish Roller Derby is just starting to emerge from its traditional month of hibernation, and there's already a lot of derby events scheduled for the next few weeks. To get you started on your next year of Derby, we've collected them together in one place for you with handy links!
We’ve already covered most of the derby recruitment events &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/01/03/start-derby-in-the-new-year/"&gt;in a previous post&lt;/a&gt;, so here we present mostly bouts and fundraising. We should note, however, a few addenda to the fresh meat article:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Firstly, &lt;strong&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; have completely filled up their attendance list for their fresh meat, and are now closed for additional skaters until their next recruitment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Secondly, just missing out on our article, &lt;strong&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; also have a recruitment event scheduled for &lt;strong&gt;Tuesday 26th January&lt;/strong&gt;, starting at &lt;strong&gt;7pm&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;Magnum Leisure Centre, Irvine&lt;/strong&gt;. There is some kit available, but you are advised to contact ahead of time &lt;a href="mailto:ayshirerollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;ayshirerollerderby@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/strong&gt; also announced recruitment very recently, with a session planned for &lt;strong&gt;31st January&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Musselburgh Sport Centre&lt;/strong&gt;, starting at &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt;. You are advised to contact &lt;a href="mailto:newskaters@lothianderbydolls.com"&gt;newskaters@lothianderbydolls.com&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The Scottish Derby bout calendar starts on the &lt;strong&gt;30th of January&lt;/strong&gt;, with 3 bouts occurring:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; A and B are taking on Vagine Regime UK in a double-header hosted in the Lagoon Centre, Paisley. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/440385519419560/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/440385519419560/&lt;/a&gt; There's also the second annual GRD Drag Party planned after this event, for which details &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/156611594708195/"&gt;go here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Over in Edinburgh, &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; are also holding their first bout of the year, with the Reserves taking on Roller Derby Dresden. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/918798478210693/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/918798478210693/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Meanwhile, down in Newcastle, Men's National Team &lt;strong&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; are taking on Tyne and Fear B as part of a double header with Newcastle Roller Girls. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1829763710583763/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1829763710583763/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The action doesn't stop the week after, as the &lt;strong&gt;6th of February&lt;/strong&gt; sees:
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; host a 12-team Charity Sur5al tournament at The Peak, Stirling. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/908140529265523/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/908140529265523/&lt;/a&gt; There's also an &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1507929376179373/"&gt;afterparty event&lt;/a&gt; for the tournament, which is sure to be well attended!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Also on the 6th, Power of Scotland have a fundraiser up in Aberdeen, as &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Brawlermen&lt;/strong&gt; host a Quiz Night in Sinatra's Bar. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1711963732359161/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1711963732359161/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The &lt;strong&gt;13th of February&lt;/strong&gt; continues to be lucky for derby enthusiasts, as we have another two events to choose from:
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;In Edinburgh, &lt;strong&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/strong&gt; take on Dundee Roller Girls' Bonnie Colliders at the Jack Kane Centre, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1537726313212932/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1537726313212932/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Meanwhile, playing away at Eston Leisure Centre,Middlesborough, &lt;strong&gt;Mean City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; take on Teesside Skate Invaders in a double header hosted by Middlesborough Milk Rollers. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/370810093043423/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/370810093043423/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/13/upcoming-events-roundup/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 20:54:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lothian Derby Dolls round up of 2015</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/26/lothian-derby-dolls-round-up-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls have been kind enough to send us this update on their year&lt;/em&gt;:
&lt;p&gt;2015 has been a busy year on and off skates for &lt;a href="http://lothianderbydolls.com/"&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year the Dolls have been really focusing on progressing our new skaters into the team, building on the skills the experienced skaters already have and being involved in helping the wider roller derby community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dolls are very proud to have 6 skaters bouting in our team who have come through the LDD fresh meat programme this year and one referee passing his refereeing tests to be officiating regularly. With all the excitement and skills of the last fresh meat who graduated in December, we are going to have even more skaters hot on the Dolls’ heels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LDD skated in three public bouts against the Central Belters in May, GCRD ‘B’ team, the Fight Hawks in September and New Town Roller Girls in October. LDD put together the Dolly Mixtures to play against DRG ‘B’ team in September with skaters from the Central Belters, Doonhame Derby Dolls, Voodoo Dollies and Mean City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5314" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/fb_img_1450951138669.jpg" alt="FB_IMG_1450951138669" width="1080" height="720"&gt; LDD taking on Granite City B, the Fight Hawks (Photo: Laura MacDonald)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also had a wonderful year of being out in the derby community more, which has helped us build strong ties with teams such as BCR's Central Belters and Capital City Roller Derby. LDD have been happy to have some co-ed experience with CCRD and enjoy our new found partnership. The Dolls have also been busy this last year taking part individually, guest skating, refereeing, NSO-ing and helping out with other teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our events team have been busy organising all our fundraising events as well as bouts, scrims and meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LDD are always looking to skate on different floors and were delighted to be given the opportunity to skate at Transgression Park, our local skate park. LDD and TP are working on a partnership, so watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LDD were lucky enough to welcome [London Rollergirls + Team England coach and Southern Discomfort skater] Ballistic Whistle for a training session which all our Dolls got so much from, with some finding themselves a little star-struck.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A word from our 2015 Captain &lt;strong&gt;Psycho&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; In 2015, what was your LDD highlight?
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Being nominated as captain for the Doll Stars for 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
 How do you feel about how far LDD has come?
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;The team has improved massively over the years since the start but more so in the last year due to the commitment of the league members.&lt;/p&gt;
 Your personal proudest moment of 2015?
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Seeing 5 of the last fresh meat to go on and play their first game and receiving my award for the most inspirational Doll. I was totally gobsmacked.&lt;/p&gt;
 What are you hopes for 2016?
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;To see the creation of the 2nd LDD team, the Rising Stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
LDD has only been so successful due to the strength and commitment of all the Dolls who are involved in LDD. LDD has had some of our skaters get injured and we have missed them on the track, but because of their commitment we have not missed their presence, especially when they are shouting at us all while coaching or organising social events, so we can all laugh together.
&lt;p&gt;LDD are also excited to welcome two more LDD babies to our team in 2016 and can’t wait to meet them both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LDD have come so far in the last year and we have no plans to slow down in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love and Shoves, Lothian Derby Dolls!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/26/lothian-derby-dolls-round-up-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 10:15:54 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>