<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about malmo crime city rollers)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/malmo-crime-city-rollers.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 08:59:33 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Tenerife Roller Derby bringing the heat to Winter tournaments...</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/15/tenerife-roller-derby-bringing-the-heat-to-winter-tournaments/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teneriferollerderby/"&gt;Tenerife Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are hosting one of the last tournaments of the year, as they host Dundee Roller Girls and Malmö's Crime City for a sunny Winter's triple header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've already talked to Dundee (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/08/dundees-international-debut/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and Crime City (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/04/crime-city-b-gear-up-for-tenerife/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), so it's time to catch up with the hosts to talk about their year, and their preparations. Speaking to us was Mercromina Tenerife's Co-Captain and also Co-Captain of the current Team Spain (as Mercedes)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-12850 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/mercedes_look.jpg" alt="mercedes_look" width="2048" height="1367"&gt; Mercromina, centre, blocking against Las Palmas earlier this year (Photo: Javier Velasco)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tenerife have had a good year this year, with a good performance in the first Spanish National Tournament (second place to Madrid!), and only one loss outside that (to the very strong Paris B). Are you pleased with your team's performance, and what have you been taking from it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;This past year has been a very important year for us. It might sound strange, but we've lost some games and that has made us get out of our comfort zone and realize how hard one has to work to stay on top. We had never lost against a Spanish team before the final against Madrid this year (in which they played an amazing game and totally deserved the win), so we are convinced that a team needs to lose games sometimes to grow stronger. Of course, that kind of thought comes a bit later, in that moment you just want to win everything. So, in general, I am very pleased with our performance last year at the National Championship, especially if you take into account that we hadn't played any game for a complete year.&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tenerife Roller Derby is also a big part of Team Spain 2018, just as it was a big part of the 2014 team. (And you're co-Captain of Team Spain at the moment!) In 2014, that causes a lot of flights to be needed for practice! How does it feel to be back on Team Spain, and how are the team balancing membership of the National Team with Tenerife's own ambitions?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;I am honoured to have been co-captaining both teams, Tenerife Roller Derby and Team Spain, this year. It is a big responsibility but also a very challenging and exciting work to do, very rewarding.&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;They're both two teams that I love and in which I have enjoyed a great number of games. Living so far away makes it always difficult to attend all practices and participate in the tournaments so not everyone is able to do it and some of us have to do a big economic effort, but, at least in my case, I can say that it's worth it.&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;This year the World Cup will take place in Manchester, so it will be much cheaper than last time, that's great news.&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;Nevertheless, this tournament will be my last one, since I'm retiring from derby after 6 very intense and engaged years, so I'll follow the adventures of my beloved Team Spain mates from a bit further away and the ones from my home team a bit closer.&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recently, it seems that Tenerife have really been excited by international roller derby, inviting a lot of teams from outside Spain for mini-tournaments. What lead to this decision to have these mini-tournaments, and does it help to be a nice warm sunny country when Europe is in Winter when inviting teams?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;We have always been very interested in playing international games. In fact, we've done at home more international than national games (Finland, Scotland, Portugal, Germany, England, France, Sweden are some of the countries that have visited us). This season we are organizing the games in this mini-tournament form so we can offer the teams two games in a row. That's always a good point for visiting teams, having the chance to play two games in one trip.&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;It's not easy to bring teams to the island, because of the long distances and the cost of the trip, but, of course, being an incredibly beautiful and sunny island is always something that encourages them to come. Lots of teams use the chance to stay a few more days here and have some holidays together. I can't imagine a better team bonding acitivity. &lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your next tournament features two teams from much further North in Europe (everyone is further north than Tenerife, but …!) - Dundee and Malmö - but this isn't the first time you've played Scottish, or Swedish, teams. How are you preparing for the tournament - and do you have any advice for the visiting teams?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;We are training really hard for this and the other tournaments to come. We've had a lot of important members of the team leaving us recently but we are also lucky enough to always have new talented and motivated skaters with us, so we are currently focusing on maintaining the level that we've achieved in the last years and doing a good transition to our new skaters squad.&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With both National Championships, and these tournaments, Tenerife Roller Derby must have even more exciting things lined up for next year? What can you tell us of the future plans?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;Our future plans for this season include some more tournaments at home, but also travelling to play tournaments abroad. That is a really exciting thing for us, since we haven't been able to travel to play a tournament yet, except for the National Championships last summer. So we're really looking forward to it. Our plan is to keep growing and try to be the best team in Spain, although we're very pleased that derby is growing in our country and more and more teams are raising their level, we've always supported our other national teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tenerife's Torneo Triangular Roller Derby is on this 17th December, starting at 2pm , at the Pabellón de deportes Pancho Camurria. Event page is here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1790180551249253/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1790180551249253/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>malmo crime city rollers</category><category>roller derby tenerife</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/15/tenerife-roller-derby-bringing-the-heat-to-winter-tournaments/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 20:15:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Crime City (B) gear up for Tenerife.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/04/crime-city-b-gear-up-for-tenerife/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst now most of the big events are finally dying down as leagues head into their winter off-season (sometimes reluctantly), there's still some sunny climes where tournaments are yet to come.
In particular, Tenerife Roller Derby have been on a bit of a tournament kick recently, and are topping their previous three-team international tournament (against Paris and Royal Windsor) with a possibly even more international one, by distance, as Dundee Roller Girls and Malmö's Crime City (B) both fly down to the Canaries to take in a bit of sun, and a lot of Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this interview, we caught up with Darling Ripper, of Crime City B, to see how the Swedish team are feeling about skating in 20º Celcius heat in December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11938" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/darling-ripper1.jpg" alt="darling-ripper1" width="2048" height="1366"&gt; Crime City B, Darling Ripper middle (visible 6 on arm) Photo: Helena Mettävainio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crime City B have had a very good year to date - you have won all 5 of your games, mostly by quite big margins.In particular, you seem to have made a big jump in performance, to judge from your rematch against Copenhagen and Berlin! In 2015, you lost in quite a close game to Copenhagen, in 2016, you won extremely convincingly; and while you've won against the Inglorious Bombshells twice, you increased your lead this year. Can you say how the year has been from your perspective, and if the team has been doing particular thing to improve this strongly?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DR: It has been a really great year for us and we are very proud of our own development! It's always hard to know exactly why we have improved this much, but I think it's due to the fact that our charter has been rather stable for the last year so we've become a really close-knit team and we have so much fun playing together as well! It also helps having such great coaches from our A and B team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In fact, Swedish (and Finnish, so maybe "Scandinavian" &lt;img class="_1ift _2560 img" src="https://www.facebook.com/images/emoji.php/v6/z4c/1/16/1f642.png" alt="🙂"&gt; ) Roller Derby has been doing exceptionally well in recent years. Do you have any thoughts about what Sweden is doing well, in general?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DR: Haha, I don't know what Sweden is doing in general, maybe wrestling polar bears? But I think the Scandinavian teams are quite good at helping each other out and we play and practice together in different ways so maybe that's why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tenerife will be the furthest Crime City B have travelled for a bout since you've existed. Do long trips feel different than short ones - and how are you expecting to deal with the much warmer climate? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DR: Traveling is always exhausting, but we are really excited to go to Tenerife and look forward to get away from the cold here in Crime City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flat Track Stats puts you as the favourite to win this tournament too, with Dundee Roller Girls and Tenerife both roughly equally rated. What's the teams' goal for this final tournament of the year? (Are you aiming to win, or do you have personal goals, or other goals here?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DR: Our aim for the tournament is to have fun and play our best game. We expect a hard competition from both teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, with this year going so well, what's next for Crime City B next year? Will you be aiming at higher level opponents - Flat Track Stats thinks that you're on a level with, say Nantes or Auld Reekie - and our own ratings put you a little higher, and in contention with the next tier of French teams, maybe Newcastle Roller Girls…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DR: We will have to wait and see what next year will bring us! But it would be fun to play those higher-ranked teams you mention. As a B team, it can sometimes be a bit hard to find competition at your level, seeing how we are not a WFTDA team and therefore can't play Sanctioned bouts. I hope more higher-ranked teams will be interested in playing us now that we have shown that we can put up a good fight!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tenerife Triple Header will be on &lt;strong&gt;December 17th&lt;/strong&gt;, from 14:00 (WET, which is the same as GMT) in Pancho Camurria Sports Centre, Santa Cruz, Tenerife. There's no event page at present, but we will add more information as we have it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girls are raising money to fund their attendance here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gofundme.com/drg-tenerife-tour"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/drg-tenerife-tour&lt;/a&gt; . &lt;/strong&gt;We will add funding links for other teams if we are made aware of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>international</category><category>malmo crime city rollers</category><category>roller derby tenerife</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/04/crime-city-b-gear-up-for-tenerife/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 10:50:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>European Smackdown - the Statistics</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/08/european-smackdown-the-statistics/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Crime City Rollers' European Smackdown wasn't just a history-making event, bringing WFTDA-sanctioned Division 1 derby to mainland Europe, it was also our first chance to get a look at how those Division 1 teams have changed as the new season starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned in &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/18/gotham-rose-victorian-a-three-way-tie/"&gt;a previous article&lt;/a&gt;, despite the fact that Euro Smackdown wasn't a true tournament (it was more of an invitational, with teams playing different numbers of bouts, and no attempt at ranking them by performance), the fact that it produced a large number of match-ups means that we can use Bayesian inference techniques to infer what the actual relative power of the participating teams are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start off, lets look at the actual results (versus the predictions from &lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;FlatTrackStats&lt;/a&gt;). We don't consider WFTDA Rankings because the ranking scheme that WFTDA uses combines Team Strength with Strength of Schedule (how many "hard" opponents you played), and so does not purely reflect the actual relative strength of teams.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;colgroup&gt; &lt;col width="33%"&gt; &lt;col span="4" width="0*"&gt; &lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#eeeeff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bout&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Score(HT)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Score(FT)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Score Ratio
(HT) FT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FTS Predicted Score Ratio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#ffeeff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;London:Detroit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146:47&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;345:79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; (3.1) 4.3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 6.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#eeffff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Glasgow:Malmö&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;39:257&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;46:536&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; (0.15) 0.09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 0.65&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#ffeeff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;London:Stockholm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;133:31&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;295:49&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(4.2) 6.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 4.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#eeffff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Glasgow:Helsinki&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;43:212&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73:485&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(0.20) 0.31&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 0.85&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#ffeeff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Detroit:Malmö&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;37:130&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;75:233&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; (0.28) 0.32&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 0.875&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#eeeeff"&gt;
&lt;td colspan="5"&gt;DAY 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#eeffff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;London:Glasgow&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;322:3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;526:9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; (100) 58&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 7.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#ffeeff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Malmö:Helsinki&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;79:36&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;176:70&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; (2.2) 2.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 1.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#eeffff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Glasgow:Stockholm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;27:182&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;66:371&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; (0.15) 0.18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 0.59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#ffeeff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Detroit:Helsinki&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;94:73&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;162:216&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; (1.3) 0.75&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 1.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#eeffff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;London:Malmö
&lt;p&gt;(notsanctioned)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;194:33&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;311:98&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(5.9) 3.2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 5.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
What's quite interesting here is that, while FTS was very wrong as to the magnitude of most of the score ratios, it was actually only wrong once as to the result of a bout - calling Detroit/Helsinki for Detroit. This was also the closest bout of the entire tournament - and Detroit was winning, with a score-ratio close to what FTS predicted, at the end of the first period.
&lt;p&gt;Another thing we can see is which games were "games of two halves" - the Detroit/Helsinki, Glasgow/London and London/Malmö games all exhibit very strong shifts between the scores at half-time and full-time - in fact, by almost 50%!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, onto the actual strength calculations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ran 300000 steps of a Bayesian Monte-Carlo simulation on the Euro Smackdown data, with 600 "walkers" per step. This allows us to explore the space of "possible strengths" and determine what the most likely strengths are for each Team competing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As London Roller Girls were overwhelmingly likely to be the strongest team in the tournament, we calculate strengths for the remaining 5 teams relative to London. Strength here is "how many points London would score, in an average game, for every point the team scored". We use FTS ratings as a basis for our comparisons, as WFTDA rankings do not purely reflect the strength of teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6274" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/figure_1-es2.png" alt="figure_1-es2" width="1996" height="1050"&gt; Plot of predicted and inferred Team Strengths (relative to London Roller Girls). Strengths are "approximate number of points London would score, for every point the Team scores")&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This graph shows two sets of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vertical lines indicate how strong FlatTrackStats thought the teams should be, relative to London Roller Girls, before the tournament starts. As FlatTrackStats's ranking algorithm is relatively conservative, this approximates to the performance of the teams at the end of last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The histograms show the distribution of "consistent" team strengths, inferred from the results of European Smackdown. The peaks of the distributions correspond to the most likely strengths for each team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As can be seen, there's two pretty obvious outliers - Crime City Rollers (marked as "Malmo") are significantly stronger than FTS thought they should be; and Glasgow Roller Derby are significantly weaker. The other three teams, Detroit, Helsinki and Stockholm are bunched close enough together that it's hard to separate them in this scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can get a better look at the grouping for lower strength teams if we exclude the London bouts from consideration. One issue with London's strength is that its opponents score lower, meaning that each point is "worth" more in terms of altering their proportional strength. (The difference between a final score of 3 and 4 is a 33% change in your strength!) This makes predictions a bit more fuzzy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6353" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/figure_1-malmo.png" alt="figure_1-malmo" width="1726" height="831"&gt; Inferred strengths for Detroit, Stockholm, Helsinki, Glasgow with respect to Crime City (as Malmo).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above graph is calculated in the same way, but from only the bouts not involving London (and therefore shows strength relative to Crime City, as MALMO). It's a little clearer from this analysis that Detroit is measurably distinct in strength from Stockholm and Helsinki, and Stockholm and Helsinki are almost separable themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another interesting feature of the full analysis, is that, while the outliers are both "far" from their predictions, the set of all strengths is still relatively symmetrically distributed around FTS's predictions. This implies that London themselves haven't significantly altered in strength over the winter - any large shifts in the teams relative to them are due to those teams own strength changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of this analysis suggest that either Crime City Rollers had a significant home-teams advantage, or they're significantly improved (by about 50%) after taking a break over Winter. If the latter is the case, we expect them to be a significant force in Division 1 this year - this performance puts them closer to teams like Montreal or Atlanta!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Glasgow's performance this year seems to have been hit by the departure of several strong pivots from the A-Team Roster, with Mona Rampage, (The Very Hungry) Splat(erkiller), and Jen Sykes all missing from the roster. Conservatively, their performance here is roughly 1/6th as strong as they evidenced in Division 1 tournament in the USA last year. Hopefully, this is simply a consequence of the restructuring early in the season, and the new roster will continue to strengthen and gel over the coming year...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the other teams, Stockholm have slightly fallen back from their high-point last year, possibly following the departure of one of their star jammers, Mad Malooney. (It's tempting to suggest that the slight increase in performance by Helsinki is related, partly, to their gaining the same skater!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recap of the tournament is available from &lt;a href="http://www.derbycentral.net/2016/03/the-european-smackdown-recap/"&gt;Derby Central&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>detroit roller derby</category><category>european smackdown</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>helsinki roller derby</category><category>london rollergirls</category><category>malmo crime city rollers</category><category>statistics</category><category>stockholm roller derby</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/08/european-smackdown-the-statistics/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 17:06:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Malmo Crime City Rollers Vs Glasgow Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/05/28/malmo-crime-city-rollers-vs-glasgow-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/05/midsummer.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1278  " title="Midsummer Murders" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/05/midsummer.jpg" alt="Midsummer Murders" width="550" height="775"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Midsummer Murders - Image courtesy of Malmo Crime City Roller Girls
&lt;p&gt;On 9th June, &lt;a title="Glasgow Roller Derby Website" href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s Irn Bruisers take on Malmo's &lt;a title="Crime City Rollers Website" href="http://crimecityrollers.com/index.php" target="_blank"&gt;Crime City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; in a double header event. The Swedish hosts will then go on to play a re-match against Ireland's Cork City Firebirds in what promises to be an action-packed afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crime City are advertising tickets online on their &lt;a title="Midsummer Advert on Crime City Rollers Website" href="http://crimecityrollers.com/news_midsummer.php" target="_blank"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, but you'll need to go to lastminute.com* to book your flights first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Other online flight companies are available :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>irn bruisers</category><category>malmo crime city rollers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/05/28/malmo-crime-city-rollers-vs-glasgow-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 18:50:22 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>