<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about mcrd)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/mcrd.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Capital City Host the Final SMRDN game of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/27/capital-city-host-the-final-smrdn-game-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year we saw the launch of the Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals (SMRDN), which saw Bairn City Rollers, Mean City and Capital City all fight for the bragging rights of being the top Scottish Men's team. With two games played and two wins to BCR's Skelpies they have taken the title of champions for this year. There is however still one more game left to play which is sure to be an exciting clash for more than one reason, which is Capital City vs Mean City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone wp-image-4863 size-large" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ccrd-banner-smrdfin.jpg?w=614" alt="ccrd-banner-smrdfin" width="614" height="227"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two teams have yet to met on track in a public game, with this their first encounter deciding who will take second place in this years SMRDN and the looser picking up 3rd and last place for 2015. With so much to play for, both teams will be fighting for every point from the first whistle to the last. And if this wasn't enough to tempt you along, Capital City have turned the event into a double header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get everyone ready for the main event, they are putting on a coed game first at which we will get to see some of the the Granite City Brawlermen in action for the first time as they join forces with some of the girls from Granite City Roller Girls as well as other guys and girls from the likes of Capital City, Mean City and Bairn City to form both of the coed teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This double header will take place at Meddowbank on Saturday the 19th of September, for more information visit the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4864" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ccrd-tall-smrdfin.jpg" alt="ccrd-tall-smrdfin" width="513" height="720"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>ccrd</category><category>coed</category><category>double header</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>mcrd</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mens roller derby scotland</category><category>scottish men's roller derby nationals</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><category>smrdn</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/27/capital-city-host-the-final-smrdn-game-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 11:21:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Close Encounters of the Thrilled Kind - derby double header</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/26/close-encounters-of-the-thrilled-kind-derby-double-header/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/3xo4jhp-imgur.png"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-3550 aligncenter" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/3xo4jhp-imgur.png?w=300" alt="3xO4jHP - Imgur" width="422" height="163"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow is bracing itself for a close encounter of the ‘thrilled’ kind as some of the grooviest skaters in Scotland and England clash as part of a unique sporting double-header.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city’s first men’s roller derby team – Mean City – will host the special event on August 23 at the ARC sports centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City will be playing Teeside’s Skate Invaders – the first time the two teams have clashed – in an all-male, action-packed contest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space will be a premium as the Invaders beam into Glasgow – hoping they can blast their way to victory against the MCRD troopers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The double bill will also see Glasgow Roller Derby’s Cannie Gingers compete against Fierce Valley Roller Girls’ Parma Violents in an all-female thrill-fest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jim Whyte, Chairman of Mean City Roller Derby (MCRD), said: “We can’t wait for this very special double-header. The skating will be out of this world with four great roller derby leagues going toestop to toestop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Mean City is Glasgow’s first and only men’s roller derby league and has been going from strength to strength since it was formed in 2012. We’re genuinely thrilled to be welcoming three amazing squads to Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Skate Invaders are a great team and a terrific bunch of lads – we can’t wait to line up against them. Mean City features some of the best skaters in Scotland and we will be giving our all to ensure the super summer of sport continues in Glasgow.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby (GRD) – Mean City’s all-female sister league – is renowned throughout the roller derby world. Its A team – the Irn Bruisers – recently stormed America, while its B team – the Maiden Grrders – are also a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such is the strength in depth at GRD that a third travel team has been formed – the Cannie Gingers – who made their competitive debut against Fierce Valley in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jim added: “Fierce Valley had the edge in the first encounter, but Glasgow will be keen to win on home soil. It’s going to be another cracking encounter between two brilliant teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Get your tickets now – just £5 in advance for two amazing full games of roller derby starring four interstellar teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s going to be a great showcase of all that roller derby has to offer – an action-packed afternoon of skating, scoring, skills, thrills and spills.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby has been developing as a league since its formation in 2012. Men’s roller derby is a fledgling off-shoot of the modern day all-female sport of roller derby – with the game rising in popularity with people of all genders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City train regularly in the Glasgow area and new members are always welcome to give the sport a go in a supportive environment. Equipment can be provided – just get in touch in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby"&gt;www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby&lt;/a&gt; to buy tickets for the event and to find out more about joining the revolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cannie gingers</category><category>fvrg</category><category>grd</category><category>mcrd</category><category>parma violents</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/26/close-encounters-of-the-thrilled-kind-derby-double-header/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 22:59:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mean City Fresh Meat - Saturday 19th April</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/04/18/mean-city-fresh-meat-saturday-19th-april/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 19th April, Mean City Roller Derby will be hosting a Fresh Meat taster session to recruit new skaters into their Roller Derby league. The event will be held in The ARC in Glasgow Caledonian University from 1pm until 4pm. Both males and females aged  18 and over are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reserve your space and secure a loan of equipment, email &lt;span class="_c24"&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:meancityrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;meancityrollerderby@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;with your skate size and the equipment that you require.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see MCRD's &lt;a title="Mean City Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1437233266520284/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event &lt;/a&gt;for full details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/04/10151975_438763326260093_6305273651417002059_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3385" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/04/10151975_438763326260093_6305273651417002059_n.jpg" alt="Mean City Fresh Meat Poster" width="614" height="230"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Mean City Roller Derby&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fresh meat</category><category>glasgow</category><category>mcrd</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>the arc</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/04/18/mean-city-fresh-meat-saturday-19th-april/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2014 11:20:31 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>