<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about mean city roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/mean-city-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:41:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Big Blether 2: Mean City host the return of the Scottish Derby community meetup.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/06/big-blether-2-mean-city-host-the-return-of-the-scottish-derby-community-meetup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, the Scottish Roller Derby Community made a bit of history, by finally getting together in one place for a &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/18/the-big-blether-scotland-together/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big Blether&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This wasn't just a disorganised chat, of course: this was the first ever Roller Derby Conference for Scottish derby, on the model of the European "EROC". On the 7th of October 2017, the vast majority of active Scottish leagues were represented by pairs of delegates [and all but one of those who couldn't make it sent statements by proxy], actively engaged in process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-24409 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/screen-shot-2017-09-13-at-16-17-08.png" alt="Screen Shot 2017-09-13 at 16.17.08" width="335" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the first Big Blether was the brainchild of Auld Reekie Roller Girls' Crazylegs and Skinner, and Glasgow Roller Derby's Head Referee, Candy Moho, it was also agreed that future convocations would pass the torch onto other leagues around the country, spreading the democratic work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as it goes, the first volunteers to do the hard thing of repeating previous success were Glasgow's All-Gender league, Mean City Roller Derby. Very slightly more than a year later, their iteration of the conference, Big Blether 2, is coming to central Glasgow on the 20th October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principal task of a repeat convention is more nuanced than that of a first meeting. The first Big Blether did great things in generating conversation; in spreading knowledge [we personally enjoyed the group discussion elements, and how well they were orchestrated] and sharing problems. &lt;em&gt;More importantly&lt;/em&gt;, it generated actions - foci for future progress and development, mutually agreed by all those present. (It also gained Scottish derby a little bit of publicity, via an article in Five On Five magazine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second Big Blether will have the equally hard task of looking at those actions, a year later, and seeing what has been done, what has not; correcting course, potentially, or pushing forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it might do us well to look at what actions the first Big Blether produced, across the multiple sessions it held (these were scheduled as pairs of parallel sessions, run as facilitated group discussions):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby Oversight&lt;/strong&gt; spread some useful information (and quashed some misapprehensions) about the existing governance structures in Roller Derby. The action produced was to develop a "&lt;strong&gt;Scottish Derby Lobbying Group&lt;/strong&gt;" to provide a unified voice for the Scottish community in representing our needs and desires to larger entities.
We followed up on this, and believe that at least some work was done towards this aim, but as yet there is no formal group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Game Scheduling&lt;/strong&gt; produced some frank discussion between leagues about competition for resources; the low ratio of leagues to halls and fans (as well as to officials), the network effects which mean that smaller leagues can be accidentally outcompeted by older, more established clubs, and so on. The actions for this session were to more strongly adopt the shared &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby Schedule&lt;/strong&gt; for scheduling bouts and events (this common document is hosted on Google Docs, and made available via links in the Scottish Derby Facebook group) and to consider &lt;strong&gt;Sharing Fixtures with Other Leagues&lt;/strong&gt;.
We've seen use of the Schedule increase significantly since the first Big Blether, and there have been a number of "shared fixtures", so we think these actions have been broadly successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Officiating&lt;/strong&gt; involved some extensive discussions about the widespread issues of officials recruitment and training (and respect within leagues). The action for this session was to promote more central training and learning opportunities for Officials (on and off skates) - a &lt;strong&gt;Ref School&lt;/strong&gt; to be run by Glasgow Roller Derby - and for leagues to work towards giving their officials a more "cohesive identity" to form around and generally &lt;strong&gt;treat them as first class citizens&lt;/strong&gt; of the sport.
The Glasgow Roller Derby Ref School has run a few sessions (and Dundee have continued to run their own series of Officiating bootcamps, extant before Big Blether); and the branding of several league's officials as their own "teams" seems to represent a start of the second action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Access to Scottish Derby&lt;/strong&gt; revolved around the perennial issues of costs, access to halls and training certifications; as well as problems with providing kit, and burnout in "highly active" members of the community; and the less discussed issues with cultural homogeneity in derby. This session produced a lot of "personal actions" for leagues to &lt;strong&gt;Share More Resources&lt;/strong&gt;, and investigate community Volunteering Schemes.
It's difficult to measure how well this has been progressed without hearing from all the leagues - so this will be a point of discussion in October!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting as a whole also produced actions to produce and maintain a &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby Ranking&lt;/strong&gt;, which would enable a &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby National Tournament&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Scottish League or Championships&lt;/strong&gt;.
These have progressed very slightly (there's an initial Scottish Derby Ranking derived from Flat Track Stats Europe ratings), but on the meat of the matter - an organised competitive structure - there's a lot of work to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The second ever Big Blether will give those actioned a chance to report on their progress, as well as discussing any new topics which have developed in the past 12 months - since that year has seen three World Cups, a changing structure in other International Gameplay, and at least one new style of Roller Derby, we’re sure that there will be lots to talk about.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2nd Big Blether will be hosted on the 20th October 2018, in &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/bsRwxpsb6Do"&gt;Glasgow Quakers Meeting House, Elmbank Crescent, Glasgow. G2 4PS&lt;/a&gt;. Final timings to be decided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams can register representatives (as can independents) here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSf5LLsKjK3egYsLrcJNX8vWnnoRV5DRErii42kKAsANWbbP-w/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSf5LLsKjK3egYsLrcJNX8vWnnoRV5DRErii42kKAsANWbbP-w/viewform&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;REGISTRATION CLOSES 1 OCTOBER.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can contribute to the discussion topics on offer, and shape the schedule, via this form here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeiKb3UVcj1mKjVAeZmUVUY5krWkziPGH7HKCR4OQirmRKATQ/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeiKb3UVcj1mKjVAeZmUVUY5krWkziPGH7HKCR4OQirmRKATQ/viewform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>communication</category><category>in the news</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>officials</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>team scotland</category><category>the big blether</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/06/big-blether-2-mean-city-host-the-return-of-the-scottish-derby-community-meetup/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 10:00:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fair City Rollers: Rising</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/20/fair-city-rollers-rising/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Sunday is the only time you'll see Perth's local roller derby league, Fair City Rollers, on track at home this year, due to the popularity of their excellent local venue, Bell's Sport Centre. As a result, for those following the team, it's an opportunity not to be missed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-26879" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/fcr_map-layered.png?w=1024" alt="FCR_map-layered" width="1024" height="948"&gt; Fair City, and the leagues combining to face them as "Scotland's Rising Stars"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fear Maidens, Fair City's travel team, will be facing a mixed exhibition team drawing newer skaters from Ayrshire Roller Derby, Bairn City Rollers' Central Belters, Dundee Roller Derby, Granite City Roller Derby, Lothian Roller Derby and Mean City Roller Derby. Coming together as "Scotland's Rising Stars", these skaters represent some of the best new talent in Scottish roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fear Maidens have played one previous bout this year, losing away to Dundee's B team, the Bonnie Colliders, back in &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/8969"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Due to way Flat Track Stats' rating changes are applied (always equally, but oppositely, to both teams), this has almost certainly underrated the Perth team at present, due to both Dundee teams' considerable strength gains year on year. Whilst this game against an exhibition team will not compensate in the ratings, we're confident of a strong showing from Perth's only roller derby team at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City's Invader Zoom told us, "We are so excited to be playing at home again and can't wait for the people of Perth to see some of our new recruits in action. Our last home game was a nail biter that had the audience on the edge of their seats all game, and we are sure this game will be just as thrilling with a challenge team of skaters from 6 different Scottish leagues!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as Roller Derby action on track, there will be the usual collection of stalls, including an opportunity to support the charity &lt;a href="http://www.clicsargent.org.uk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CLIC Sargent in Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, raising money to help Young Lives versus Cancer. Fair City Rollers will be participating in CLIC Sargent's Rainbow Assault assault course event in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair City Rollers' "&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1869400046436599/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pack to the Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;" is at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/Sty37VvYGx92"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bell's Sports Centre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Perth, on the &lt;strong&gt;24th June&lt;/strong&gt;, 2018. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>fear maidens</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/20/fair-city-rollers-rising/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 13:36:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mean City face the Lothians, twice, 16th June.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/13/mean-city-face-the-lothians-twice-16th-june/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend, there's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/153012025545908/"&gt;yet more Roller Derby action&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Glasgow, as Mean City Roller Derby, the city's open gender league, takes on two opponents at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Livingston + West Lothian's New Town Roller Girls, who have been pretty busy this year already, travelling up to Inverness to play ICRD in April. NTRG have been building up to this next bout with an open scrimmage against The World last month, and with one of their skaters having visited Rimini, Italy's Stray Beez in the last month, we assume that New Town will be buzzing with confidence on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NTRG will be taking on Mean City's WFTDA-gender-policy team ("Mean City Women"). The Mean City team have had a quieter year, last facing Lothian Derby Dolls towards the end of 2017, so it will be interesting to see how things have changed on track in the past 6 months...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flat Track Stats &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/101836"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;predicts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a close game, with the median result being a 19:21 points ratio in favour of the home team; with scores that close, however, it could be just a single power jam which decides the result!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second game, Fear &amp;amp; Lothian, the Midlothian-based open gender team, will face Mean City's open gender team. Fear &amp;amp; Lothian have had a less busy year to date than NTRG, with their last game in November 2017. Since then, however, the team have been holding regular scrims with their WFTDA-gender colleagues in Lothian Derby Dolls, and have undergone a round of recruitment. We may even see some new faces on track this Saturday!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City's Open Gender team have regularly faced F&amp;amp;L - one of the limitations of open gender derby is still the paucity of opponents - and the two teams know each other well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City overall has also had a new intake at the start of the year - and there's some changes in both rosters, to judge from their series of roster photos being run over on their Facebook page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26849 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/mcrdvflvntrd.jpg" alt="MCRDvFLvNTRD" width="1080" height="1080"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City President, Gord'n'Thorg told us:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Glasgow's first - and meanest - Open To All Roller Derby league return to The Arc at Glasgow Caledonian University this Saturday 16th of June.  After a false start ("yielding!") earlier in the year; we're getting back to the track with a Double Header against two of our friendly, neighbouring leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We start with a WFTDA-flavoured face-off between the home side and Livingston's New Town Roller Girls.  Members of both teams have had a tasty sample of each other at a few recent scrims.  We're looking forward to getting a proper look at each other across league lines.  I don't think anyone would be adverse to the idea of another semi-local rivalry getting up and rolling...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the subject of rivalries; we're following this with open-gender action, as Fear and Lothian array themselves against us once again.  Our contests have been fierce in the past, and we'll be looking for more of the same as we field some new faces against familiar foes...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can't believe that all of this can be yours and only lighten your purse by £5.00, we'll also be giving you your first chance to lay hands on our latest batch of Mean City Merchandise.  You'll wonder how you've managed without it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to seeing everyone there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, weather permitting..."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see both games on the &lt;strong&gt;16th June&lt;/strong&gt;, from &lt;strong&gt;12:15&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/zaDvW85FqFF2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in Glasgow Caledonian University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;Tickets: &lt;strong&gt;£5.00&lt;/strong&gt;. Under-14s free when accompanied by a paying adult.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>articles</category><category>fear &amp; lothian</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/13/mean-city-face-the-lothians-twice-16th-june/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 15:00:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Are you ready for a skating spooktacular?</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/19/are-you-ready-for-a-skating-spooktacular/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9817" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/fb-hallowmean-a.jpg" alt="fb-hallowmean-a" width="3545" height="1305"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tricks or treats? Why choose when you can have both – and a whole lot more – at Mean City’s closing home game of the year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow’s only coed league will be hosting a devilish double dunt of derby delights on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 29 October&lt;/strong&gt; at the Dear Mean Place – aka the &lt;strong&gt;ARC Sportscentre in Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hallowe'en is when things go bump in the night - &lt;strong&gt;HallowMean&lt;/strong&gt; is when things go bump on the track and there are trick and treats for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, the &lt;strong&gt;Mean City ladies&lt;/strong&gt; – fresh from a gallus bout against Granite’s Fight Hawks and looking to maintain their forward momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Meanies have been reaping the benefits of a greater emphasis on tactics, fitness and skills – with fresh recruits bolstering the settled squad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their opponents on 29 October will be the out-of-this-world &lt;strong&gt;ASTROs (Auld Reekie All Star Rookies)&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s going to be a stern test of the Mean City ladies’ resolve, as well as a showcase for some of Scotland’s finest up and coming skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second game will see &lt;strong&gt;Mean City's coed team&lt;/strong&gt; ghosting to the track to take on &lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers' Belter Skelpers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tis the season to be fearful and while there’s no fear among the Mean City ranks, there will be some trepidation given the excellent form the Belter Skelpers have been in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bairn City Rollers’ coed team recently played a mix of Aberdeen and Dundee skaters – the Brawler Buddies – and really brought their A game, winning with a well-oiled performance combining offence, defence and excellent tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City’s coed team may lack the experience of their opponents, but they have spirit, guts and tenacity in abundance and will match them skate for skate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City President Elaine Hunter – aka Roller Dobby - said: “We can’t wait to round off our home season in style with a spook-tacular thriller for all the family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Trick or treat – why choose when you can have both? There will be skating, fun, cakes and cracking tunes – what else are Saturdays made for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Tickets are just &lt;b&gt;£4&lt;/b&gt; in advance – that’s just £2 per game – or &lt;b&gt;£5&lt;/b&gt; on the door. It’s a bargain and you’ll be supporting grassroots sport at the same time. Under-14s get in free.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean City presents HallowMean - Saturday 29 October 2016 - doors open at the ARC Sportscentre at noon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;For more information on the event – &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/312912055752880/"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;For tickets – &lt;a href="http://www.meancityrollerderby.com/tickets.php"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>coed</category><category>in the news</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/19/are-you-ready-for-a-skating-spooktacular/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 15:36:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City's Sparkling Year peaks with Glasgow rematch.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/23/granite-citys-sparkling-year-peaks-with-glasgow-rematch/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Granite City Roller Derby's rebranding (from Roller &lt;em&gt;Girls&lt;/em&gt;) at the end of last year obviously prefigured some kind of Pokémon style evolution to a new level of performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year has been an exceptional one for the league to date. A-team, the Northern Fights, absolutely demolished their Division in British Champs, taking the top spot after convincing wins against fellow Tier 4 North members Spa Town, Halifax Bruising Banditas and Blackpool Roller Derby League, and earning promotion into Tier 3 North next season. They've gotten 3 skaters into the Team Scotland 2016 Training Team. And their B-Team, the Fight Hawks, have embarked on a second successful year of bouts, working their way up the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Granite City are trying to top things off with a double header at home on &lt;strong&gt;27 August&lt;/strong&gt;, placing the Northern Fights against Glasgow Roller Derby's tough B-team, the Maiden Grrders; whilst the Fight Hawks take on a mixed team of great skaters from Doonhame Roller Derby, Ayrshire Roller Derby and Mean City Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught up with GCRD's &lt;strong&gt;Krusty&lt;/strong&gt;, the Northern Fights' Co-Captain (and Team Scotland Training team member) Udder Mayhem (&lt;strong&gt;Christine&lt;/strong&gt;), and Fight Hawks' Co-Captain and Northern Fights Bench Manager Pert Hits (&lt;strong&gt;Sam&lt;/strong&gt;) to see how the league feels about their year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8850" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/08/13925480_10155196192769012_6950054464319126321_o.jpg" alt="13925480_10155196192769012_6950054464319126321_o" width="1448" height="2048"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Obviously, 2015 was not a good year for Granite City at Champs, ending with your relegation to Tier 4 from Tier 3. This season, however, you've really stepped into gear, convincingly topping the table for promotion back up into T3! Did you make this a conscious aim for the year, and what changes did you make to help it happen?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christine:&lt;/strong&gt; 2015 was a challenge for us. We lost some experienced skaters, but we also gained new ones, however, we hadn’t quite gelled into the team we knew we could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disappointment at the beginning of 2015 forced us to refocus our tactics and to adopt the use of specific line-ups. To facilitate this, the Fights organized extra “team time” dedicated training sessions, which was funded through the skaters own fundraising efforts (e.g. boot sales, personal fundraising etc.). We were very determined to be the awesome team we knew we could be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn’t win all of our games, but we started to perform much better against higher ranked teams, and finished British Champs 2015 with a convincing win against Halifax Bruising Banditas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 2016, fortnightly team-focused sessions have continued as part of our structured training, and are now funded by the league for both the Fights and the Hawks. We recognised the importance of training as a team, especially as GCRD continues to grow. We’ve gelled really well this year as a result, and this is reflected in our performance in Tier 4. We hold regular team meetings to revisit our goals, and are planning for a more successful time in Tier 3 in 2017. Bring it on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam:&lt;/strong&gt; The regular team training has certainly helped the team bond and act as an effective unit. These sessions also allowed the 2016 Bench staff (myself and Krusty) to really focus on the team, feedback what was working and direct the team to further their game, the game they want to play. It has been really pleasing to see the team numbers grow, allowing them to move away from specific line-ups and into a direction where they know each other and their play and it doesn’t matter who they are lined up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GCRD have also had a good year in National terms, with 3 skaters (including two of your highest rated jammers in Champs) making it through to the Team Scotland Training Squad selection. I think last time you had 4, but it's also true that less GCRD skaters tried out this time. How do feel about your skaters making the training team (and the training team itself having skaters from so many leagues)?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christine:&lt;/strong&gt; As one of selected skaters, I am obviously delighted that I managed to make it through to the training squad, along with the brilliant Rock’N Riot and Jo Mamma. All three of us are also coaches, and we are keen to soak up as much as we can and bring it back to GCRD training sessions, so that the skills we learn can be passed on to benefit the rest of the league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer the other question, I am personally thrilled to see so many talented skaters from a variety of leagues! It will keep things interesting as every league is different, and we can all learn new and awesome things from each other. We had our first session a couple of days ago, and it was a fantastic and positive experience. I asked the question “how many hours did you drive to get here?” many times that day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam:&lt;/strong&gt; Echoing Christine, we are very proud of our skaters being selected for the Team Scotland training squad. Each year we have had good representation at Team Scotland try outs and then onto Team Scotland itself. Seeing such a variety of leagues represented on the training team is so reassuring that the sport in our wee country is really progressing and skaters really advancing. Some exceptional high-level derby being played across the country!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This upcoming bout against Glasgow's Maiden Grrders is your first non-Champs bout this year. This is something of a delayed rematch - the last time Granite City faced the Maidens was in 2013, where Glasgow took a convincing win. How are you feeling about this time around?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christine:&lt;/strong&gt; We look forward to welcoming the Maidens to Aberdeen, and are excited for the challenge! A lot has changed since 2013 and it will be a very different experience for both teams involved. For instance, when the Fights last played the Grrders, I was more focused on passing my minimum skills! We’ve been working very hard the past few months, and this will be a good test for us as we approach Tier 3 again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam:&lt;/strong&gt; The best test for us! The team are really looking forward to this challenge, aiming for all the hard work to pay off and give the Grrders a run for their money. I think the skaters involved, from both teams, have changed so much since 2013 it will be really fun game both to be part of, but to watch too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the Northern Fights busy with British Champs, GCRD B have had most of the flexibility in their fixtures. You’ve taken on both Dundee B (the Bonnie Colliders) at home, and more recently, Auld Reekies ASTROs away. Are the Fights jealous of your free schedule, and what’s next for the Hawks?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christine:&lt;/strong&gt; I guess I am a little bit jealous, but pinning down games has been somewhat of a challenge for both the Fights and the Hawks, especially in the first half of the year. A lot of work has been done behind the scenes to try and remedy it, however, there were home game slots for both May and July that I couldn’t find a team for the Fights to play against, and July’s date was completely cancelled in the end. Now we are approaching autumn, and Champs is finishing for most teams by this point, we are finding it much easier. We have one more home game against Sheffield Steel Roller Girls in October, and are playing ARRG’s All Star Reserves in November, which should keep the Fights busy! It should also challenge us, and help us to prepare for Tier 3 next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam:&lt;/strong&gt; If they are they’ve certainly not voiced it… but I guess travelling (half) the length of Britain once a month for 3 or 4 months keeps you busy and focused. They are certainly excited about the few home games we have planned for the later half of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hawks have a few games in the pipeline, a couple more double header home games and an away game too. As a team, we are still evolving and finding our game but as time is moving on we are gelling better as team too. As Co-Captain, I’m excited for the skaters to get more games under the belt and get the opportunities to play and show-case their hard work. I am also really looking forward to training with our freshly minimum passed skaters and helping build them up to game time! Some very exciting skaters are on the up through not only our minimum course, but our Intermediate training group too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first time for the Fight Hawks taking on a mixed team of skaters from across Scotland. How do you plan for that, and how are you feeling about taking on some of the rising stars from Ayrshire and Doonhame?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam:&lt;/strong&gt; Our plan is probably similar to if we were preparing for any other league team; play &lt;em&gt;OUR&lt;/em&gt; game. Training alongside the Northern Fights, and scrimming against them as teams, has really helped us focus on our weaknesses and up our skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are really looking forward to taking on Ayrshire and Doonhame! As noted previously, I am always super impressed and excited by the calibre of roller derby coming out of every league and I expect these two leagues to be no exception. I hope we are a suitable warm up for Ayrshire before their first home bout on September 10th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, personally, having spent the first few Hawks games as their Bench due to injury, I am so super excited! I was with the Hawks standing on the side-lines during their game with Mean City, and really look forward to playing against some of the Mean City ladies in this game too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We believe that this bout is also raising funds for some great charities, can you tell us a bit about this?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Krusty: &lt;/strong&gt;At every home game we host, we try to give some exposure to local charities within Aberdeen and surrounding areas. We have supported local charities at every home game and managed to raise substantial amounts of pennies on our cake stall, our home bakes are kindly donated by skaters, friends and family. We are overwhelmed by the donations we receive and the generosity of our supporters (and officials!) that purchase our fine home bakes. Sales from our cake stall on the 27&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; August will be donated to &lt;strong&gt;Befriend a Child&lt;/strong&gt;, they are Aberdeen's only 1:1 befriending service for vulnerable children and young people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also decided for this game that we would like to ‘borrow’ an idea we saw Sheffield Steel Rollergirls post up, holding a bra amnesty in support for &lt;strong&gt;‘Smalls for All’&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s something my work is doing too and it’s a fantastic idea! We are looking for brand new pants and new or worn bras that still have good wear in them. It’s an easy thing to organise but it will be greatly received by Smalls for All who is a charity which helps women and children in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone has any great suggestions for our next charity appeal, come speak to us at the game on Saturday!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City's Double Header is at their usual venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Beach+Leisure+Centre/@57.155602,-2.082094,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48840e4028217933:0x30c6b9176815da5b!8m2!3d57.155602!4d-2.0799"&gt;Aberdeen Beach Leisure Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;August 27th&lt;/strong&gt;. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;12:30pm&lt;/strong&gt;, for the first whistle at 1:10pm. Tickets are just &lt;strong&gt;£4&lt;/strong&gt; on the door. The Facebook event page is here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1717081471898842/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1717081471898842/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/23/granite-citys-sparkling-year-peaks-with-glasgow-rematch/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 18:31:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Science v Magic: Twice in one month!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/09/science-v-magic-twice-in-one-month/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've previously mentioned that Glasgow Roller Derby are hosting an exhibition double header on the 20th of the this month, featuring a Science v Fantasy themed B-feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if you like the idea of pitting SF against F, then you don't even have to wait that long, as Glasgow's only Coed league, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby/"&gt;Mean City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, are holding their own &lt;em&gt;coed&lt;/em&gt; extravaganza this weekend (&lt;strong&gt;13th August, 2pm&lt;/strong&gt;) as the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1807206382885256/"&gt;Wizards take on Gallifrey's finest Timelords.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;This is an opportunity to see both established MCRD skaters, as well as their newest up-and-coming skaters in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-8598" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/08/13653353_836734026463019_2149065422421141685_o.jpg?w=2048" alt="13653353_836734026463019_2149065422421141685_o" width="1024" height="724"&gt; Just one of four (4!) posters that Mean City produced for the event!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event will be at Mean City's usual venue, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662153,-4.2519236,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8662153!4d-4.2497349"&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Glasgow, with afterparty at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Rufus+T+Firefly/@55.8635334,-4.2600056,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48884420befd257d:0xff9a66f3090f61a0!8m2!3d55.8635594!4d-4.257813"&gt;Rufus T Firefly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. (Links above link to maps.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advance warning also: the following week (&lt;strong&gt;2oth August&lt;/strong&gt;) features a bit of a clash. As well as the aforementioned &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/550878811750965/"&gt;Soy Division v Vagine Regime/Science v Fantasy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; double header in &lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;, there will also be a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/972951379480637/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls / Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; joint double header in &lt;strong&gt;Grangemouth&lt;/strong&gt;! As the second bout in the schedule features the long anticipated rematch of Bairn City's Skelpies against Tyne and Fear B (the Inglorious B**stards), it seems that both events have unmissable second fixtures...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's &lt;em&gt;possible&lt;/em&gt;, based on the preliminary timings, to just about see the first bout in Glasgow, and then rush across Scotland by car to get to Grangemouth in time for both bouts, but we're not sure we'd risk it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The approximate timings are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First bout (&lt;strong&gt;Science v Fantasy&lt;/strong&gt;) at Glasgow, skateouts start &lt;strong&gt;13:05&lt;/strong&gt; (implies end around &lt;strong&gt;14:30&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second bout (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/SoyDivisionDerby/?fref=ts"&gt;Soy Division&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;/&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GayRobots/?fref=ts"&gt;Vagine Regime&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt; ends &lt;strong&gt;17:10?&lt;/strong&gt; (which implies a &lt;strong&gt;15:45&lt;/strong&gt; start, or earlier depending on slack?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First bout at Grangemouth (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://fvrg.co.uk"&gt;FVRG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; intraleague) starts &lt;strong&gt;15:30&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second bout (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers/?fref=ts"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;' Skelpies v &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/tyneandfear/?fref=ts"&gt;Tyne and Fear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; B) starts &lt;strong&gt;17:20&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes around 40 minutes to get from the centre of Glasgow to the centre of Grangemouth, so it should, hypothetically, be possible to see all of the mixed bout at Glasgow, jump in a car, and arrive &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; 20 minutes before the first game starts in Grangemouth. Assuming that derby runs to time, which is, of course, not something we can ever rely on, and that our guesses about the timings are correct... ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>annoucements</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>soy division</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>vagine regime uk</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/09/science-v-magic-twice-in-one-month/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 11:15:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Powers of Two at Mean City</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/24/powers-of-two-at-mean-city/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; obviously like the number two. That's the only explanation for the preponderance of twos in this weekend's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/487160101472894/"&gt;upcoming event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; they're hosting, at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662183,-4.2519236,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8662153!4d-4.2497349"&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Glasgow.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-7335" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/11707838_666231253513298_2828507735651128838_o.jpg?w=1024" alt="11707838_666231253513298_2828507735651128838_o" width="1024" height="384"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only is this a double header, with &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; exciting bouts to experience, but both bouts have their own multiplicative factors as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headlining, we have Scotland's National Men's Roller Derby team, Power of Scotland, facing off against "The Other Guys" - the "&lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt; best Scottish men's skaters" from four (&lt;em&gt;2&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;!) Scottish leagues: Mean City themselves, Capital City, Bairn City's Skelpies and Granite City's Brawlermen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;are less than two months away from the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;World Cup in Calgary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and this is an important fixture both for training and also fundraising. As well as donations direct to PoS, the Team Physio (Dundee Roller Girls' Goldginger) Claire will be offering physio for donations [she also has a separate fundraiser &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.justgiving.com/Claire-Semple2"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] - and official Team Photographer Laura MacDonald will also be in attendance [she's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gofundme.com/PoSLauraCalgary"&gt;raising money too&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;!].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second up, Mean City's own co-ed team (who I don't think actually have a name yet) are facing off against a &lt;em&gt;double&lt;/em&gt;-league mashup of Capital City Roller Derby and Lothian Derby Dolls: "Fear and Lothian". The two Edinburgh-based leagues have been working pretty closely in preparation for this game, and we believe that Fear and Lothian is going to become a longer standing collaboration - there will be new merch available at the bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With both bouts containing exhibition teams, there's no stats to predict the outcomes - so the only way to see what will happen is to come along!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://meancityrollerderby.com/tickets.php"&gt;£5 in advance&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;£6&lt;/strong&gt; on the door (under-14s free).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;11:30am&lt;/strong&gt; for an approximately midday start this &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 28th May&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/24/powers-of-two-at-mean-city/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 09:37:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mean City take on two, too, on the 12th!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/07/mean-city-take-on-two-too-on-the-12th/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last article, we covered events planned for this weekend on one Coast of Scotland. But, the West Coast also has just as much derby planned for the &lt;strong&gt;12th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;March, &lt;/strong&gt;in Glasgow Caledonian University's&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/vtgcEHaTUys"&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;in an event known only as&lt;strong&gt; Purple Reign.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kicking off with doors open at &lt;strong&gt;11:30am&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby/"&gt;Mean City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s Mens and Women's teams will both face off against challengers in this exciting double header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Women will face off against Midlothian's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/lothianderby/"&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt;, hoping to continue their winning streak from 2015. For their part, LDD will be keen to pick up a win, after an opening season loss against Dundee's Bonnie Colliders at home. FlatTrackStats is unable to predict this game, so the only way to find out what will happen is to turn up on the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Men will be taking on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/LRTRollerDerby/timeline?ref=page_internal"&gt;Lincolnshire Rolling Thunder&lt;/a&gt;'s B-team (who may be called the Thugly Ducklings). Once again, FlatTrackStats is unable to predict this game, as Rolling Thunder's B-team is so new. Clearly, the Ducklings will be keen to break their duck in their first trip up to Scotland; but Mean City's Men will be equally enthusiastic to put a narrow loss against Teeside Skate Invaders (away) earlier this year behind them, and prove they can command on their home turf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MCRD President Elaine Hunter said, "Last year was a momentous 12 months in the history of Mean City, with both our women's and men's teams winning - not to mention our coed all-stars.
"I'm delighted that the 2016 home season is kicking off with a cracking double-header - featuring our friends at Lothian Derby Dolls and Lincolnshire Rolling Thunder.
"We've been training hard and can't wait to make our 2016 home debut at the ARC - offering thrills, skills and spills for all the family.
"As usual we'll sell you the full seat, but you'll only need the edge. Come and join us as the purple reign continues."
Join the Purple Reign on 12th March at Glasgow's ARC. Tickets are just £5 &lt;a href="http://www.meancityrollerderby.com/tickets.php"&gt;in advance&lt;/a&gt; - £6 on the door. Under-14s have free entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, Mean City will be hosting the after party upstairs at their sponsor, &lt;a href="http://theravenglasgow.com/"&gt;The Raven&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1555212058123782/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1555212058123782/&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>lincolnshire rolling thunder</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/07/mean-city-take-on-two-too-on-the-12th/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 22:43:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Upcoming Events Roundup!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/13/upcoming-events-roundup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scottish Roller Derby is just starting to emerge from its traditional month of hibernation, and there's already a lot of derby events scheduled for the next few weeks. To get you started on your next year of Derby, we've collected them together in one place for you with handy links!
We’ve already covered most of the derby recruitment events &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/03/start-derby-in-the-new-year/"&gt;in a previous post&lt;/a&gt;, so here we present mostly bouts and fundraising. We should note, however, a few addenda to the fresh meat article:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Firstly, &lt;strong&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; have completely filled up their attendance list for their fresh meat, and are now closed for additional skaters until their next recruitment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Secondly, just missing out on our article, &lt;strong&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; also have a recruitment event scheduled for &lt;strong&gt;Tuesday 26th January&lt;/strong&gt;, starting at &lt;strong&gt;7pm&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;Magnum Leisure Centre, Irvine&lt;/strong&gt;. There is some kit available, but you are advised to contact ahead of time &lt;a href="mailto:ayshirerollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;ayshirerollerderby@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/strong&gt; also announced recruitment very recently, with a session planned for &lt;strong&gt;31st January&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Musselburgh Sport Centre&lt;/strong&gt;, starting at &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt;. You are advised to contact &lt;a href="mailto:newskaters@lothianderbydolls.com"&gt;newskaters@lothianderbydolls.com&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The Scottish Derby bout calendar starts on the &lt;strong&gt;30th of January&lt;/strong&gt;, with 3 bouts occurring:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; A and B are taking on Vagine Regime UK in a double-header hosted in the Lagoon Centre, Paisley. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/440385519419560/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/440385519419560/&lt;/a&gt; There's also the second annual GRD Drag Party planned after this event, for which details &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/156611594708195/"&gt;go here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Over in Edinburgh, &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; are also holding their first bout of the year, with the Reserves taking on Roller Derby Dresden. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/918798478210693/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/918798478210693/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Meanwhile, down in Newcastle, Men's National Team &lt;strong&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; are taking on Tyne and Fear B as part of a double header with Newcastle Roller Girls. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1829763710583763/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1829763710583763/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The action doesn't stop the week after, as the &lt;strong&gt;6th of February&lt;/strong&gt; sees:
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; host a 12-team Charity Sur5al tournament at The Peak, Stirling. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/908140529265523/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/908140529265523/&lt;/a&gt; There's also an &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1507929376179373/"&gt;afterparty event&lt;/a&gt; for the tournament, which is sure to be well attended!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Also on the 6th, Power of Scotland have a fundraiser up in Aberdeen, as &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Brawlermen&lt;/strong&gt; host a Quiz Night in Sinatra's Bar. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1711963732359161/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1711963732359161/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The &lt;strong&gt;13th of February&lt;/strong&gt; continues to be lucky for derby enthusiasts, as we have another two events to choose from:
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;In Edinburgh, &lt;strong&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/strong&gt; take on Dundee Roller Girls' Bonnie Colliders at the Jack Kane Centre, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1537726313212932/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1537726313212932/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Meanwhile, playing away at Eston Leisure Centre,Middlesborough, &lt;strong&gt;Mean City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; take on Teesside Skate Invaders in a double header hosted by Middlesborough Milk Rollers. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/370810093043423/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/370810093043423/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/13/upcoming-events-roundup/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 20:54:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Once Upon a Skate...</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/01/once-upon-a-skate/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join Fierce Valley Roller Girls as they end their year with an exciting double header! Up first will be Fierce Valley Roller Cubs, Scotland's only junior roller derby league, in a Goodies vs. Baddies intraleague. Fierce Valley Roller Girls will then be joined by skaters from Bairn City Rollers, Mean City Roller Derby and Lothian Derby Dolls to face off as Storybrooke vs. Enchanted Forest in a Once Upon A Time themed game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/once.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5172"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-5172 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/once.jpg?w=300" alt="once" width="563" height="212"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the venue is rather 'intimate', we recommend buying your tickets in advance to avoid disappointment. Tickets are priced at £5 in advance/£7 on the door, and kids under 14 go free with a paying adult.  Tickets are available in advance &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2469041"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors will open at 3pm for a 3.30pm start. As always, there will be a selection of handmade crafts, home-baking and team merchandise for sale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/01/once-upon-a-skate/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 09:47:21 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>