<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about men's roller derby world cup)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/mens-roller-derby-world-cup.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Bairn City Rollers: Central Scotland's International Derby League</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/27/bairn-city-rollers-central-scotlands-international-derby-league/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2018 it seems Derby World cups are like busses, you wait so long for one to arrive and another appears just after it. February saw the Womens Roller Derby World Cup blow everyone away and now, thankfully, we are past its comedown. But it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; time to get ready for the Men’s Roller Derby World Cup, which kicks off on the 5th of April in Barcelona. This is the third MRDWC; the first was held in England back in 2014, and the second was two years ago in Canada. Back at the first World Cup in 2014, 15 nations battled it out, that tally rose to 21 in Canada, and this year at Barcelona there will be 24 nations represented, with even more set to join in at the next MRDWC after this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland/"&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/a&gt; has featured at every MRDWC so far with its roster comprised of skaters from all over Scotland, as well as some from South of the border. From the first MRDWC to the current POS lineup going to Barcelona, &lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers/"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; has had its skaters featured in each of the squads. BCR's Gibb is one of only three skaters in the current PoS roster who have been present on all three of Power of Scotland’s final World Cup squads to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-26515 size-large" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/20180321_204818.jpg?w=700" alt="Power of Scotland and Bairn City Skater Gibb #5" width="700" height="351"&gt; Power of Scotland and Bairn City Skater Gibb #5 (Credit: Andy Mo Photography)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the first World Cup &lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers/"&gt;BCR&lt;/a&gt;’s current or past skaters accounted for over quarter of the POS squad. At the last MRDWC in 2016, six current or past BCR skaters made it onto the training squad, of which four made it into the final squad that traveled to Canada. This time around, partially thanks to injuries and retirements, they have two skaters who made the training squad and both will be at Barcelona with Power of Scotland. One will be skating (Gibb) and the other now as part of the staff (rEd Baron).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BCR are proud that they have skaters once again involved with of Power of Scotland at this World Cup. They are also very proud of their skaters' (past and present) achievements representing and playing for Power of Scotland since its inception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-26514 size-large" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/20180321_204752.jpg?w=700" alt="Power of Scotland and Bairn City skater Red Baron" width="700" height="352"&gt; Power of Scotland and Bairn City skater rEd Baron (Credit: Andy Mo Photography)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst we are used to seeing some faces from outside of Scotland in POS squads, we are not used to seeing our male skaters in Scotland appearing elsewhere on other National teams. That was until now! At this MRDWC there will be a couple of skaters that play and train in Scotland who will be representing nations other than Scotland, and both hail from Bairn City Rollers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers/"&gt;BCR&lt;/a&gt; are incredibly honoured and proud to say that in their ranks they have skaters who will be representing not one, not even two, but three different nations at Barcelona. On the track at the tournament along with Gibb representing Power of Scotland they will have Oliver lining up for &lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/WalesMensRollerDerby/"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt; and Vezzani for &lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/mensrollerderbyteamitaly/"&gt;Team Italy&lt;/a&gt;.
If you follow Men’s Derby in Scotland Oliver and Vezzani’s faces will be familiar but perhaps their names not-so-much: they have opted, like many, to play under their real surnames. Normally you would see Oliver playing under his derby name of Basha ROO, and Vezzani as Despicable V.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-26512 size-large" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/20180321_204624.jpg?w=700" alt="Team Italy and Bairn City skater Vezzani (Despicable V)" width="700" height="352"&gt; Team Italy and Bairn City skater Vezzani (Despicable V)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Oliver and Vezzani in their past have represented Power of Scotland (both made the 2016 training squad), with Vezzani representing POS at the first MRDWC. Both have now decided that, going forward, they wish to represent other nations instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-26513 size-large" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/20180321_204726.jpg?w=700" alt="Team Wales and Bairn City skater Oliver (Basha ROO)" width="700" height="352"&gt; Team Wales and Bairn City skater Oliver (Basha ROO)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking to Oliver about why he decided to try out for Wales he said:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;My mum's side of the family are all from Wales and are passionately Welsh, even my Gran who was originally from Birmingham, so it was a bit of a no brainer to play for Team Wales when I got the chance. The last World Cup, I couldn't commit to traveling down to Wales for training regularly and flying to Canada, financially and work wise. Thankfully this time round I was in a position to be able to.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Vezzani has a similar story for Italy:
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;At the first MRDWC there was no Team Italy, currently in Italy there are really no Men’s teams/leagues. They do have the Woodgang, which is a team made up of skaters from all over Italy and a few other places. A little like how we had the Jakey Bites here in Scotland. When I tried out for POS for the 2016 World Cup there was no Team Italy, they only appeared very late in the day after I had already made the POS training squad.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;When I didn’t make the final 20, quite a few people said to me about trying out for Italy instead. But because I had already made one countries training squad for that world cup I decided against it. Although when I watched and cheered on Italy at the World Cup I realised then, I really wished I had. At that point I decided that if I was going to try out for any Nation going forward it was going to be Italy.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
We also asked both how friends, family and team mates reacted when they found out that they would be representing Wales or Italy.
&lt;p&gt;Oliver:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;My Family have been really supportive about me playing in the World Cup for Wales, so much so that they are coming to Barcelona to come and watch. My mum's gone full Welsh fan-girl so expect lots of daffodils and dragons, lol. My team mates are pleased for me as well although a few wished I had picked Power of Scotland instead.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Vezzani:
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;When it came to trying out last year, I had told a couple of people that I had wanted to but never told anyone when I was actually going to do it. It was only when I played my first game for Italy in November last year (at the Road to Barcelona tournament in Holland) that everyone found out I had tried that also included 99% of BCR as I had managed to keep it a secret. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The response from friends and teammates has been fantastic and everyone has been really supportive. My dad is really proud and happy that I will be representing Italy and my sister seems to be the most excited by it all, even more than me. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
We all know that at the previous MRDWCs, Scotland’s fans have become well known for their support, sheer volume, and chanting for not only for Scotland but other Nations they take a liking to.
Seeing as both Oliver and Vezzani are Scotland-based skaters, they will be hoping that they will get some support from the Scottish fans when they take to the track in Barcelona. Here at SRD, we do hope that the Scottish fans at Barcelona and back home will be celebrating and cheering on both of these skaters, and the Welsh and Italian teams.. at least, when they are not playing against Power of Scotland!&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bcr</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc</category><category>mrdwc 2018</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>team italy mens</category><category>team wales mens</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/27/bairn-city-rollers-central-scotlands-international-derby-league/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 10:09:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A chat with: Team Middle East Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/08/14/a-chat-with-team-middle-east-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a break from podcast style interviews, Scottish Roller Derby podcasts are back with an interview with one of the co-chairs of new Men's Roller Derby National team, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TMErollerderby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Middle East Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Middle East are actively recruiting for any skaters with eligibility to represent any of the Middle Eastern countries, with an aim to compete in the 2020 Men's Roller Derby World Cup. This would make them the first men's team representing any nations in the middle east, and only the second team representing a Middle Eastern Nation at all (after &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamIranRollerDerby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Iran Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - also still open to applicants - who will represent at the Women's Roller Derby World Cup 2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[soundcloud url="https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/337873869" params="auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true" width="100%" height="450" iframe="true" /]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>team iran roller derby</category><category>team middle east roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/08/14/a-chat-with-team-middle-east-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 20:20:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Upcoming National Teams Bouts</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/12/upcoming-national-teams-bouts/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With both World Cups now less than a year away - the&lt;a href="http://www.rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;in February, and the &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in April, there's an increasing number of National Teams related fixtures being announced, as all the teams get in some practice, some visibility, and some fundraising opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's easy to miss what's happening, so maybe it helps to keep them all in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the events we're aware of (and do please let us know if we've missed anything!)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Women's National Teams&lt;/h3&gt;
15th July: Equipe de &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt; play an exhibition bout hosted by Les Passeuses Dâmes [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1394914887229155/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;p&gt;15th July: Team &lt;strong&gt;Portugal&lt;/strong&gt; have an open training session for Portuguese skaters [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1887307271583565/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16 July: at least some of Team &lt;strong&gt;Germany&lt;/strong&gt; are at Euro Derby Con participating in events [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/596116850567901/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22 July: Team &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; Roller Derby turn up to play London Rollergirls B, the Brawl Saints as part of a double header in London [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/431163560596192/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29 July: Team &lt;strong&gt;Korea&lt;/strong&gt; and Team &lt;strong&gt;Philippines&lt;/strong&gt; make their world debuts at Rollercon, playing against each other on Saturday! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/143735569514656/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29 July: Team &lt;strong&gt;South Africa&lt;/strong&gt; have their final round of tryouts! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1932492993665870/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5-6 August: Team &lt;strong&gt;England&lt;/strong&gt; host Team &lt;strong&gt;Sweden&lt;/strong&gt;, Team &lt;strong&gt;Finland&lt;/strong&gt; and Team &lt;strong&gt;Canada&lt;/strong&gt; for a weekend round-robin event, in Nottingham! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1883460565201595/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5-6 August: &lt;strong&gt;Aotearoa&lt;/strong&gt; Roller Derby (Team &lt;strong&gt;New Zealand&lt;/strong&gt;) play a black v white scrim, followed by a bootcamp run by their coach, Mick Swagger. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/147390622507530/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 August: Team &lt;strong&gt;England&lt;/strong&gt; will also be scrimming with an open subscription team after that round-robin [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/203298956860930/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 August, 20th August: Team&lt;strong&gt; West Indies&lt;/strong&gt; scrim against all comers in two open subscription bouts in Bedford (6th) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1962826457294629/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;] and Birmingham (20th) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/738090882982520/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 September: Team &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; will be taking on a scrimmage against an open subscription team [Applications open] [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1874512536208906/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23 September: Équipe de &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt; Feminine host a fixture against 2 undisclosed National Teams, in Tourcoing, France [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/276715376142982/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 October: Team &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt; host Team Italy and Team Netherlands for a triple header [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/298561590623060/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;Austria&lt;/strong&gt; are hosting Team Germany and Team Switzerland for a triple header [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/138743263531937/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; are playing an undisclosed team in Dublin [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/666484320215767/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; are again scrimmaging with an open subscription team (applications open) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/111479986185051/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;England&lt;/strong&gt; take on an undisclosed team in Peterborough. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/105377736693871/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2-3 December: Team &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt; welcomes undisclosed opponents to the Road to Manchester tournament! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/222986121542528/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Men's National Teams&lt;/h3&gt;
(Some time during this period, Team &lt;strong&gt;Finland&lt;/strong&gt; are planning... something.)
&lt;p&gt;15 July: Team &lt;strong&gt;New Zealand&lt;/strong&gt; have their tryouts in Kawerau [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/287594671647468/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23 July: Team &lt;strong&gt;England's&lt;/strong&gt; Stage 1 Tryouts (open submission) happen in Nottingham [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1409006599141670/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5-6 August: Team &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt; host the Torneo Barcelona City... but aren't playing in it? [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1906063339640738/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 October: Team &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt; have a mysterious event [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/246263629227122/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18-19 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;Netherlands&lt;/strong&gt; hosts &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Italy&lt;/strong&gt; in a "Road to Barcelona" event. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/259318537912275/?"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18-19 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;Germany&lt;/strong&gt; hosts undisclosed opponents in a... "Road to Barcelona" event [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/482556138758766/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;England&lt;/strong&gt; take on an undisclosed team in Peterborough (double header with Women's team above) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/105377736693871/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2018</category><category>team scotland</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/12/upcoming-national-teams-bouts/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 16:08:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Seeing in the New: National Teams in Dundee.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/10/seeing-in-the-new-national-teams-in-dundee/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend sees a double-dose of National Teams action for those in Scotland, as Dundee hosts a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1382676465099043/"&gt;combined event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with Team Scotland Roller Derby and Power of Scotland both on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14736 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/02/tspostb.jpg" alt="tspostb" width="1071" height="400"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, the Training Team for Team Scotland will be holding a Black v White bout, competing against themselves as part of the selection process for the new Team Scotland. After playing as two teams last weekend in Belgium (and winning both games), all of the skaters will be at their best, and bringing you (by definition), the highest level roller derby in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the Power of Scotland roster from the 2016 Men's World Cup will be playing their swansong bout, against Team Belgium Men's Roller Derby. Symbolically, this is their passing of the torch to the new Power of Scotland training team, who are currently undergoing the selection process after their tryouts in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the close connection between the National Teams, we were delighted to be able to talk with Rosie Peacock (PoS 2016 LUM/Assistant Coach, TS 2017/8 Head Coach) and Laura "Milky" Liston (PoS 2016 Coach, member of TS 2017/8 Training Team) about things. Between them, the two were selected to Captain the Team Scotland rosters in Belgium, so they have a great feel for the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First question, then: How did it feel to be selected as a Captain for the bouts last weekend?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rosie:&lt;/em&gt; So, Milky captained both in the end because I had too much caffeine and got super radge... Me and Milks were the only two who were nominated, but it was good the team trusted us to do the thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura&lt;/em&gt;: It was lovely knowing some of the team had nominated us, and it was such an amazing opportunity to Captain the squad, but yeah, we were the two nominated haha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, following up on that: Team Scotland won both their games, with both rosters against Belgium. How do you feel the games went - what are you happiest about, and is there anything you might work on?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rosie&lt;/em&gt;: I think outer defence side walls are really tight and fluid and adaptive; I'd love to work more on our offer credit and jammer pairings, but that's something we can't progress too much further until we have our final squad and definitely establish roles...
I need to keep my temper and not drink red bull when pmsing 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura&lt;/em&gt;: I really loved some of the bonds and partnerships we starting building on track, which I think were really apparent throughout the day. I'm looking forward to seeing how they develop in the final squad. Both of the games brought different challenges so it was great to see how we adapted to the change in gameplay style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And moving to this weekend: obviously we can't talk too much about selection itself, but clearly everyone there is hoping to make the final selection - do you see changes in both your own performance (and gelling) and your teammates already at this point?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura&lt;/em&gt;: Oh definitely. The opportunity to skate with so many high level skaters has really helped strengthen my skating on a personal level. We've been lucky enough to have Belgium and Cardiff to gel as a team in a competitive environment, and I think both have made a really noticeable improvement to our performances as a team together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Both of you have strong connections with Power of Scotland, especially the 2016 Squad who are playing as well - against Belgium! - we know the team are treating this as a "sending off" of the old team, but will a tiny tear be in your eyes to see them playing together for the last time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura&lt;/em&gt;: Hah! I think I got all my emotions out in Calgary when the whole squad was there. It'll be great to see the guys playing together again but I'm looking forward to seeing what our new squad will look like, and so excited about the future of PoS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rosie&lt;/em&gt;: I'm looking so forward to playing the best sport in the world, with the best group of humans I've had the pleasure to know x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The doors open for the double header at &lt;strong&gt;11:30, Saturday 11th&lt;/strong&gt; February, at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/DISC:+Dundee+International+Sports+Centre/@56.4762694,-2.9611212,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48865cfd69198245:0x74e93fd03837f5ac!8m2!3d56.4762665!4d-2.9589272"&gt;Dundee International Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are &lt;strong&gt;£6&lt;/strong&gt; in advance (from Brown Paper Tickets), &lt;strong&gt;£8&lt;/strong&gt; on the door. (Tickets at: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2794252"&gt;http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2794252&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/10/seeing-in-the-new-national-teams-in-dundee/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 11:19:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Seleccion Argentina de Roller Derby Masculino</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/16/mrdwc-2016-team-review-seleccion-argentina-de-roller-derby-masculino/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now heading into the last few teams for our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; profiles, we're in Latin America. Despite the popularity of co-ed roller derby in Latin America, only Argentina sent a team to the last Men's Roller Derby World Cup... and they're back this time, as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/seleccionargentinaRDM/"&gt;Seleccion Argentina de Roller Derby Masculino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time around, despite a very short roster, Argentina performed admirably, taking a 7th place draw with Power of Scotland in the final rankings. They handily defeated both Netherlands and Sweden, and only narrowly lost to Australia's Wizards of Aus in a close final bout. Only England and France defeated them, albeit by the same impressive margins they managed over most contenders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-8261 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/13029406_930304773750095_6815529119385752589_o.jpg" alt="13029406_930304773750095_6815529119385752589_o" width="1000" height="1000"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, Argentina have a larger roster, more experience, and less jet-lag to contend with. In Group Orange, they're a serious contender for the second "promotion spot" for a chance at the top placements - facing England and Sweden from last time, and new teams Italy and Chile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to Argentina to learn about their journey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Seleccion Argentina were the only Latin American team competing in the 2014 MRDWC. How does feel to be returning with so many other Latin teams this time around? [Since this interview started, Colombia dropped out of the WC, sadly]&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels just amazing. Not only because we get to reach a new goal with our new &amp;amp; full team, but also to see how much male derby has grown in Latin America!
&lt;b&gt;This time, your group places you against the mighty England, as well as Chile, Italy, Sweden. Last time around, you ranked much higher than Sweden, and most of the other teams are unknown. What are your aims for the group? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are expecting great difficult games with each team of our group. We know each other very well with our brothers from Chile, and we’re also aware how much they've grown this time to now, and the same for Sweden. We don`t know Italy, that's going to be a surprise of a game... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What teams are you most looking forward to playing (or seeing) at MRDWC this year?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, we are really excited to play against England, such a great and experienced team, it's gonna be a great experience for us. But what we're really looking forward is to see all teams, and every game. We don’t have many chances to play in Argentina, since there are no many leagues yet, and this is the chance to see lot of games, great teams, learn from it, and get to know skaters from all over the world. So the whole tournament is THE experience we´re looking forward to live, and see. 
&lt;b&gt; I know that both Women's and Men's (and Coed) roller derby is very popular in Latin America. Can you tell us how your recruitment worked for the team? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, most of the guys who get in to Roller Derby is because a girl who plays in a team brings him to see, and gets him in touch with the nearest male team. And so it was when the National team was founded. Always supported by our friends, women from Women's Team ARG, who encouraged us to aim higher in the begining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Are you mostly from Argentine teams?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly :P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Argentina has players from ThunderQuads RDM (Bs.As. city), Black Panthers RD (La Plata city, Bs.As.), Contragolpe RDM (Mendoza), Rayo Naranja RD (Tucuman), different Provinces of our country. AND one player from the Philadelphia Hooligans, Penn Jersey Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This year, MRDWC are promoting the lead up to the Cup with the "Road to Calgary" tag. In the spirit of this, what bouts and training have you been doing since the last selection? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, our "Road to Calgary" was full of hard work. Since last selection, we got to work in new try-outs as soon as possible. After that, we set a training schedule. Since most of the players were surrounding Buenos Aires area, we set 2 training day per week, despite the gym work needed. We get to play a few demos to test the improvements, a simple game White vs. Blue. It wasn't 'till our last "goodbye demo", 2 weeks ago, that we got to play against others who aren't of the team, a coed game with the bravest guys and women from the local teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Are you getting a lot of media support (and fans) for Seleccion Argentina in Argentina? How many fans can we expect in the stadium?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, if you take into account that derby is a really new sport around here, which isn&lt;code&gt;t popular at all (think that all media attention is always put on soccer), we could say we've had a lot of support. We&lt;/code&gt;ve worked a lot on public representation, and a few reporters got in touch, and invited us to radio inverviews, or local newspapers notes. That really moved our followers, that the other side, a lot of people, from friends, family, players from all over the country, showed us their support, on crowfunding campaigns, or or getting us in touch with media representatives, potential sponsors, or people they though might help us. Our biggest treasure is the people whom helped us to get here, and that love is the passion we're bringin to the MRDWC. It's a long and expensive ride from Argentina to Canada, even for us, the economy isn&lt;code&gt;t pretty well. But there&lt;/code&gt;s a few friends, crazy friends, traveling with us, so you'll see the light-blue and white among the crowd :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Argentina's first bout is against Chile on Track 2, 6pm UK time (11am Calgary)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Seleccion Argentina Roster is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="page" title="Page 24"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08&lt;/strong&gt; Pibe
&lt;strong&gt;087&lt;/strong&gt; Leandro, Oscares
&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; Sebastian, Castillo
&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; Mauro, Cruz
&lt;strong&gt;1618&lt;/strong&gt; Mingo
&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; Mr. Borderline
&lt;strong&gt;1753&lt;/strong&gt; Triske
&lt;strong&gt;1826&lt;/strong&gt; Itu Napolitanga
&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; Facundo Bentos
&lt;strong&gt;21&lt;/strong&gt;  Heavy Dolche
&lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt;  Pablo, Esquivel
&lt;strong&gt;235&lt;/strong&gt; Luke
&lt;span style="line-height:1.7;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28&lt;/strong&gt; Jose Augusto, Sanchez
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Victor, Diaz
&lt;strong&gt;314&lt;/strong&gt; The Crow
&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Nicolas, Bergallo
&lt;strong&gt;44&lt;/strong&gt; Hector, Porro
&lt;strong&gt;666&lt;/strong&gt; Luis, Llorente
&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; Black Shadow
&lt;strong&gt;930&lt;/strong&gt; Rafael, Guevara
&lt;strong&gt;99&lt;/strong&gt; Gregorio, Donnet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bench&lt;/strong&gt; Maisa, Barbosa
&lt;strong&gt;Coach&lt;/strong&gt; Daiana, Sismael
&lt;strong&gt;Jammer Assist.&lt;/strong&gt; Jillian, Vidal
&lt;strong&gt;Stuff Assist.&lt;/strong&gt; Ana, Sylvia Anabel Chasampi
&lt;strong&gt;Staff&lt;/strong&gt; Elena T.F.
&lt;strong&gt;Staff&lt;/strong&gt; INI
&lt;strong&gt;Staff&lt;/strong&gt; Turbonegra&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentina</category><category>articles</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/16/mrdwc-2016-team-review-seleccion-argentina-de-roller-derby-masculino/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC Team Review: Team Chile Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/12/mrdwc-team-review-team-chile-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Completing our set of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; team profiles, we're covering the newest team from Latin America, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamChileRDM/"&gt;Team Chile Roller Derby Masculino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chile are in group Orange, facing England, Italy, Sweden and fellow Latin Americans Argentina. With England almost certain to take the top spot in the group, Chile will be in a difficult spot to take the other promotion slot, as only Italy is as inexperienced as they are. The Latin America match up between Argentina and Chile should also be fascinating to watch...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-8244 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/11051780_1459842104328566_1210320533841469507_n.jpg" alt="11051780_1459842104328566_1210320533841469507_n" width="720" height="705"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to Team Chile's Marmota at the team warmup in Calgary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Firstly, how does it feel representing Chile, as they attend the Men's World Cup for the first time?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, as Chile, and speaking f0r my teammates, I want to say that this is really an honour. Because this sport, especially in my country, is really really new - most of us have been playing roller derby for 2, 3 years at most. So we're a new team, and we're not playing the modern, modern roller derby where graces and new formations are used. So, I don't know - we're used to playing the walls, like all roller derby used to be played. We're used to playing the defensive game, this is mostly our strategy. So, then, we're trying to play a it little faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's an honour, and it was really hard, because each and every one of us had to pay for their ticket, their accommodation. The only thing we got [in sponsorship] from a Chilean company was the uniform. And this is really bad. But I think it's a mixed work - if we don't move, then who is going to move? But, we don't get much attention - we hope that for the next World Cup we will be bigger! I hope!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So that happened to Women's Team Mexico in 2011:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happened to the Women's Chilean team in 2014 too! But women seem more persuasive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who are you most looking forward to playing here?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Argentina!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ah, yes, you're both in the same group. Are you confident?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not a confident player now - my team is really more confident than I, because I expect to pay more attention for the first jams, and then decide how I feel after that. &lt;em&gt;But&lt;/em&gt;, we know them - most of our team have played the Argentine team, which is basically the ThunderQuads. My team, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ComplotDerbyClub"&gt;Complot&lt;/a&gt;, was in the first &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/64046"&gt;Torneo HARD&lt;/a&gt; [hosted by ThunderQuads] Tournament, and we came in second. So, we know how they play - and I don't know if they know how we play. I don't know if they've done their homework! [Our relative obscurity] is our one advantage - Argentina are strong, and they're bigger than us, I don't know if you saw some of the players! And they're really really fast - we have to pay a lot of attention to their lines and their offense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that game, that game I want to play right now! The other teams, we don't know - we watched them in the last World Cup on the streams, but Argentina is our neighbouring country, so the rivalry is there! Like Scotland/Ireland or Canada/USA!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you hope to get out of the World Cup, what are you aiming for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, personally, first: I am aiming to get to know as many people as we can. I think the only way the sport is going to grow and become stronger is if we all team up, and all team up together with the other team, and we work together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I think we are wanting, as a team, to develop our play more together. Because, Chile is a long country - it was really hard for all of the guys to get together for even one training a month. We don't have the advantage of some teams which just get to play together all the time...
Team Chile's first bout is against Argentina on Track 2 at &lt;strong&gt;6pm&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;UK time&lt;/em&gt; (11am Calgary)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Team Chile Roster is:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;1080&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Hijoeperra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;111&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Waffen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Kiltro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Memeiro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;27&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Viruta Thunder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Vieja&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Petit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Mr. Sokram&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;416&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Capitán Basuritas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Aquilez&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;7018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Kamikaze&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;77&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Manquelipe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Cy8org (Cyborg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;8000&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Mecánico&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;88&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Toro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;95&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Zakumi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;969&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Rocka&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;99&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Marmota&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;m30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Picóta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;s66&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Insane&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Bench Coach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Pony Tolueno&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Bench Manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Loca Zeppelin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>chile</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/12/mrdwc-team-review-team-chile-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 07:22:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Power of Scotland</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/29/mrdwc-2016-team-review-power-of-scotland/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And now to Team Scotland, who made us cry with national pride in 2014...was it just me? In the 2014 Men's Roller Derby World Cup Scotland were in Group Orange with Belgium, Canada and Japan. They were knocked out by our friends in Wales and shared 7th place with Argentina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1448576822432.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1448576822432.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1448576822432.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Power of Scotland logo 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spoke with Optimus Grime about Team Scotland in the run up to the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How are preparations going for the world cup?      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are going very well. We have had a list of targets to reach, both on and off the track and are on  course to achieve them all. There have been a few bumps here and there, but they have just been flawless adjusted and things have seemlessly carried on. We are very pleased thus far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How often do you train?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since day 1 we have known our training schedule which has been great for attendance. Huge credit to our training and management for sorting that out so early. We are training every 2nd sunday in Grangemouth. Turnouts are great, especially since 1/3 of the team live in areas of England. Each session has been really tough, but we are growing all the time and it gets better each time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off skates training varies. There are no set team off skates training due to everyone living so far apart, but all skaters are pushing themselves more and more on and off the track. I know everyone is taking this very seriously and doing everything they can to be in the best condition they can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From which leagues have your players been selected?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a very big geographical distance in the roster. The entire list includes;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City Brawlers - Aberdeen
Bairn City Rollers - Falkirk
Mean City Roller Derby - Glasgow
Capital City Roller Derby - Edinburgh
New Wheeled Order - Manchester
Inhuman League - Sheffield
Super Smash Brollers - Nottingham
Southern Discomfort - London
Wirrel Pack Animals - Liverpool
Kings of Block &amp;amp; Roll - Exeter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Management &amp;amp; Coaches:
Dundee Roller Girls
Auld Reekie Roller Girls
Granite City Brawlers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are your team goals for the World Cup?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite simply but realistically.....make it out of the group stages. Anything after that is a bonus. We are both fortunate and unfortunate to have a 6 team group. Fortunate for the chance to play so many teams from all over the world, but with that comes a higher chance of fatigue. We are very excited though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the group there is really only 1 slot available as USA will no doubt advance from the groups. With 5 teams battling for that space this will be extremely competitive, but we have the talent and desire to be that team that gets to the quarter finals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell me about your fundraising and sponsorship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have recieved some great sponsorship for the run up to the World Cup.
Mostly with our uniforms, merch and safety gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our sponsors are;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Datum360
MP Locums
S1 Helmets
Witness the Fitness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would also like to offer a huge thank you to;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interplanetary Print Syndicate
Roller Derby City
Power of Greyskull
EDF Energy
The Whisky Wolf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our fundraising has been a variety of coaching and event organisation.
We have had a sponsored; Beard shaves, Pub quizzes and Bungee jumps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest source of fundraising have been bootcamps and guest coach sessions which have been as wide spread as our roster and even abroad.
Such as Belfast, Malaga and France. The biggest of which was our Big Bootcamp in Dundee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can we expect to see from team Scotland at the World Cup?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically a huge improvement from our last world cup involvement. Not any less passionate, but far more strategic, skilled and patient, from both a jammer and blocker point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also alot of new faces, but plenty of previous ones too. Our roster is far more extensive than the last World Cup, just from the leagues people have come from. This has brought a big variety of skills to Power of Scotland this time around and has made for a very balanced team.
Finally, we hope to display a better performance &amp;amp; therefore ranking this time around. Moreover, show the world that we can still give the big boys a hard time on the track and be considered one of the better teams in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Scotland are indeed in a six team group for the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup. They are in Team Red with Finland, Ireland, Japan, Mexico and the USA. Their first game will be on Track 1 against Team USA at 11am Calgary time, 4am UK time...make some coffee although I'm sure the excitement will wake you up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466932874572.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466932874572.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466932874572.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>team scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/29/mrdwc-2016-team-review-power-of-scotland/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 20:50:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: All-Ireland Men's Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/26/mrdwc-2016-team-review-all-ireland-mens-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2014, All-Ireland Men's Roller Derby were in Group Blue along with Australia, France and Germany. In their final game they played against Finland who took the bowl. Ireland ended the inaugural Men's Roller Derby at number 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466933364081.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466933364081.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466933364081.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Ireland's logo 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very lovely Eoin Flynn was kind enough to answer some questions about how the team have been getting ready for the world cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are preparations going for the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With only weeks to before Calgary, we're fired up and as prepared as we ever could be. The work for MRDWC 2016 began almost immediately after the last World Cup so we've had plenty of time to build on what we learned there, as a nation very new to men's roller derby, and we'll be very different from what you saw in Birmingham. That team was expanded into a training squad from which the final roster was picked so everyone's now been training and playing together for over a year, everybody knows their job and that they can rely on the others to do their's too. We're ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How often do you train?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With players located anywhere from LA to Limerick, it's quite a job to get everyone together at the same time. But we've all put in the effort to train regularly, and collected the air miles along the way!
Since January 2014 we've had full squad training at least every two months for an entire weekend. There have been several home and away games in between too. Of course we'd all do this all day every day if we could!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any off-skates training?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our coach - Jessica Rammit - wouldn't have it any other way! Everyone does their own gym work, of course, but we're lucky to have a derby-specific off-skates stuff to work on courtesy of her. None of us will forget bleep-test day! And our off-skates warm-ups are part of our team bonding now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From which leagues have your players been selected?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Ireland: Men Behaving Derby (All-Irl), Pig Town Boys (Limerick), Cork City Firebirds, and Harland Wolves (Belfast)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From UK: New Wheeled Order, Southern Discomfort, Crash Test Brummies, Kings of Block N' Roll, Borderland Brawlers, Quads of War, and Lincolnshire Rolling Thunder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And from USA: Los Angeles' Drive-By City Rollers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your team goals for the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a team, we want to play as we know we can; calmly and together.
The worst thing would be to come away knowing we could have done better, we're determined to give it all on track, right from the first whistle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More specific goals include putting some decent points up against Team USA, but hey, doesn't everyone wanna do that? We also want to keep a grip on the top-ten slot that we earned in 2014, with so many more nations competing this time around, the rankings places are going to be hard fought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about your fundraising and sponsorship.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paying for this crazy sport of ours has been a lot harder this time around, getting everyone to Canada is not going to be cheap. So we've been very lucky to have great support from companies like S1 and Non-Universal Nuts. We've also just done a great deal with TwoTonMurphy.com who are printing, selling, and shipping all of our online merchandise - and all the profits go to our travel fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've also got a gofundme page: &lt;strong&gt;gofundme.com/merbyireland&lt;/strong&gt; , where people have been very generous in supporting us, every little bit helps immensely so we're very thankful. Local leagues have been helping out too, The Cork City Firebirds we very kind to raise funds for us at their 'Love Roller Derby' event recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can we expect to see from Team Ireland at the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll understand if we don't share any tactics here! Expect to see a well-drilled team far different from the 2014 one, back then there was essentially NO men's derby on the island of Ireland, we've come a long way. Expect dogged determination and playing to the final whistle. You might also expect some strong representation at the after-party! But most of all expect us to be one unit, The team motto is 'Ní neart go cur le chéile.' which means 'There is no strength without unity', we will be strong and we will be united.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time around, Ireland are in Group Red with Finland, Japan, Mexico, Scotland and the USA. They will play their first game of the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup against Finland (on track 1) at 1pm Calgary time, 6am in the UK and Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466937146038.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466937146038.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466937146038.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all ireland men's roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>team ireland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/26/mrdwc-2016-team-review-all-ireland-mens-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 20:43:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Wales Men's National Roller Derby Squad</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/26/mrdwc-2016-team-review-wales-mens-national-roller-derby-squad/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2014, Wales were in Group Red with Finland and USA. Their final game was against Australia with the winner taking the shiny plate. Australia took that win and Team Wales took 6th place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466933587792.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466933587792.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466933587792.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Wales' logo, retained from the 2014 MRDWC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spoke to team Wales skater Ben Phillips who was lovely enough to answer some questions for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;BENPHILLIPS!!!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are preparations going for the world cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prep is going well, we've been training quite regularly since the start of this squad's tenure. Coming from the previous squad, which was consisted more of a ragtag group of skaters, into a more structured system with a HR and a proper Head Coach in Oceanne Esparcieux, the benefits have been felt greatly.
A large number of the previous squad tried out again and made it so it feels similar to the old squad but with a much needed injection of new blood in the shape of the coaching and new players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How often do you train?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twice a week with South Wales Silures and twice a week with Cardiff Bay Crossbones (Roller Hockey team), Refereeing local women's teams when I feel the itch for skating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International duties are once a month training then games on top of that. We had a pretty good showing in 4 Nations and a friendly against Ireland so we feel like we should be firing on all cylinders come July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any off skates training?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to cycle to work as much as I can (17miles each way) as a form of cardio and try to get the gym when I have time in the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From which leagues have your players been selected?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly South Wales Silures but not as much as the 2014 squad, returning from the previous squad is the Underrated and outstanding Berserker from Southern Discomfort and Swifty from Milton Keynes. We've had some great new blood in the form of U-go Boss from NWO, J-Wrecks from Sons of Icarus, Tom Thump from Wirral Pack Animals, to name a few. We have a resident canadian in the form of Hung Solo who is with River City Riot in Calgary so hopefully he can give us the skinny with the Canadians when we meet them in our group match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your team goals for the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To rise in the world rankings, 6th last time round so anything above that would be a success. We're pretty confident we can qualify through our group with our biggest game is against the hosts Canada. Having played them in MRDWC14 I cant wait to meet them on track again, great bunch of guys with some fancy footwork to boot! My personal goal is to have Tim Horton's (Timmy H) for breakfast the entire time in Canada... Dem DoubleDoubles...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally believe, depending on how we do in the group stages, we can reach the semis but it'll all depend how we react to the transatlantic flight and Calgary altitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about your fundraising and sponsorship.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So our facebook page, &lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/Wales-Mens-National-Roller-Derby-Squad-278766772249805/&lt;/strong&gt; has been running a gofundme at &lt;strong&gt;www.gofundme.com/teamwalescalgary&lt;/strong&gt; as well as a helmet competition with Swift Customs &lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/Swiftcyclesandskates/&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the hopes of raising donations we have pitted each player against another in a series of 'hilarious' challenges ranging from funny to just a bit weird, the internet seems to like stuff like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can we expect to see from team Wales at the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some heavy hitting as is standard in our derby heritage but with much more control and swish than people may expect. We've got what it takes to be part of the big dogs in this World Cup and hopefully we can prove it. Thanks for listening/reading to my rambling answers and hope you enjoy Wales' games at MRDWC16!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup Wales are in Group Green with Canada, Colombia,  Spain and Germany.  Their first game will be on track 1 against Colombia at 10am Calgary time...which is like 5pm UK time, from the looks of both of these teams, it's definitely going to be a fantastic game to watch! [Due to Colombia dropping out of the Cup, Mexico replaces them - so Wales' first game is at the same time, but against Mexico...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466938690275.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466938690275.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466938690275.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>team wales</category><category>wales men's national roller derby squad</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/26/mrdwc-2016-team-review-wales-mens-national-roller-derby-squad/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 20:36:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: England Men's Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/26/mrdwc-2016-team-review-england-mens-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our coverage of the Men's Roller Derby World Cup has returned slightly closer to home, as the time has come to speak to the UK and Ireland. First up is the English National Team - England Men's Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014, England were in Group Green with Argentina, the Netherlands and Sweden. They made it to the final game to play against Team USA for the shiny, shiny cup and whilst Team USA took the win, England took the silver medal finishing second. I, for one am rather excited to see these chaps play in July!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466933286146.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466933286146.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466933286146.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team England logo 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Manager Niks Kent was kind enough to answer some questions about how the team have been getting ready for the world cup.Please note that I spoke to Niks before England held their sevens tournament, did you see it? It was most excellent!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are preparations going for the world cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really well! We're in the refining stage. We have a couple of warm up games, and a highly competitive red v white game as part of our upcoming sevens tournament before we leave for Calgary though, so still plenty to do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How often do you train?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've been training once a month since July, plus a few training games.
We're delighted to have been supported at all our training by world cup level officials, so there's been no getting away with any sneaky forearms or cut tracks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any off skates training? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each skater has their own individual fitness regime, depending on their personal goals.
We have also been working on our mental game, and the lovely Katie from The Treasure Hunt Company took us out for a rather competitive treasure hunt round Nottingham as a team building adventure - not even the monsoons could stop us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From which leagues have your players been selected? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our squad consists of players from across England Wales. We have representatives from Southern Discomfort, South Wales Silures, Crash Test Brummies, Lincolnshire rolling thunder, Manchester Roller Derby, Barrow Infernos and Tyne and Fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your team goals for the World Cup? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to play really good roller derby. REALLY GOOD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about your fundraising and sponsorship.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundraising and sponsorship in roller derby is really difficult. Over the past two to three years, the market has been flooded with teams competing for fans funds, which are finite, so everyone has had to become more creative. We've hosted tournaments, crowd funders and sold merch, but we won't make anywhere near our costs. We don't qualify for any funding from national bodies or charities either, so it's been hard. We have however been supported by our fantastic sponsors, in no particular order: Double Threat Skates - keeping our hardware working Roller derby City - our official kit and merch supplier Hoodlum Fang - creator of helmet covers and flags Bont- making our feet and compression clad legs do their thing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can we expect to see from team England at the World Cup? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An innovative and creative display of roller derby, by a skilled team of gentleman skaters.
And bowler hats. Lots of bowler hats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time around, England are in Group Orange with old pals Sweden and Argentina as well as Chile and Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their first game of the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup will be against Sweden (tune to track 2 for this one) at 12pm which is 5am UK time. Make a nice cup of tea to wake you up for this one. In a nice cup with a saucer because it's the World Cup, you can be fancy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466935371393.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466935371393.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466935371393.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>england men's roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>team england</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/26/mrdwc-2016-team-review-england-mens-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 20:26:58 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>