<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about men's european cup)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/mens-european-cup.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>First time tournament announcing, or: How Chasing Katy survived MEC 2o16</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/17/first-time-tournament-announcing-or-how-chasing-katy-survived-mec-2o16/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Last weekend's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MensEuropeanCup/"&gt;Men's European Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (2016) in Newcastle was a great success, not least because of the high quality stream, and the commentary provided. One of the MEC2016 announcers was Chasing Katy, co-host of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://tdtmpodcast.wordpress.com"&gt;Talk Derby To Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; podcast, and independent announcer; she's graciously written up her experience for the blog here. (Comments in [ ] are editorial)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;To be honest, I hadn't initially applied to announce at this year's Men's European Cup. Not because I didn't want to do it, but because I hadn't thought I was ready for that big an event. But after some cajoling (thanks, Mags Payne!) and some reassurance (thanks [fellow Talk Derby To Me Podcast Hosts] sMACk and King), I submitted my application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Part of the application was an announcer CV, something I'd never done before. It was interesting to go back throughout my time in roller derby and try and remember all the games I'd announced (the first being waaaaay back in September 2011 when the Fair City Rollers took on the Wakey Wheeled Cats). Doing that slightly reassured me that I'd been doing it long enough that I should know what I'm doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;A couple of weeks later I got the news...I was on the crew and we were given access to the super-secret MEC 2016 Announcers' Facebook group, where I got to see who I would be announcing with. There were some familiar names and faces, but the great thing was I'd only announced with two people before (Archie [Bairn City Rollers' man of many names] and sMACk) so it was going to be a good way to meet other announcers and learn some new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I know that I'm portraying an image of me being cool, calm and collected about this whole process. That's intentional, because I can't spell the noise my brain was making the entire time. It was something between a whimper, a scream and a panic attack. It involves lots of vowels, that much&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Then, about a week before the tournament, we got the schedule for day 1 and I learned I would be doing feed announcing as well as in house. I'd never done feed prior to MEC, but made a point of listening to the WFTDA Champs announcers the weekend before. I was also down to do house announcing for Tyne and Fear (the hosts) against Panam Squad with Helliverance, who I'd known for years but never announced with. Then, for the final game of the day, I was back on feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;As MEC got closer, my nerve-citement increased and on Friday, myself, sMACk, [Granite City's] Krusty and [Auld Reekie's Terrifying] Tink headed to Newcastle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We had to be at the Walker Activity Dome for 7.30am on Saturday, so I was extremely bleary-eyed and in need of coffee when I met Sven and Malice, our THAs for the weekend. We were shown the workings of the feed, where everything was (loos, coffee, all the essentials) and given the chance to get sorted. I had prepped with some notes on the teams, so I read over the ones I needed for my first call, got a coffee and spoke to some other very tired people. Coffee, I soon realised, is the elixir of life for people involved in roller derby tournaments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Thankfully, my first time on the feed (10am on Saturday for De Ronnys vs the Mad Riders) was with sMACk. Given the many hours we have spent talking on microphones to each other, that definitely made it a bit less scary (I tried to ignore the fact that, unlike the Talk Derby To Me podcasts, this was live and we were actually sitting in the same place) and I&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;enjoyed it. Beforehand, a lot of seasoned announcers were telling me that they preferred feed to house and after doing that game, I can see why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;For me, the main difference was that I could say more. When you do in-house announcing, there's a risk that the teams will hear something that could give them an advantage in the game (for example, the cardinal rule, never announce a jammer getting released from the penalty box or approaching the back of the pack) but that risk is reduced on feed. I could happily chat about why a team was doing certain things tactically or how I feel they could make changes to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Another thing I also found fun was interacting with people watching the feed. There were tweets and YouTube comments coming in throughout and it was cool to get tidbits of information about the teams or just a “good job, guys”. I did not agree with King Crazy and StatMan that sMACk and I needed subtitles, however. (Haggis, haggis, Irn Bru to you too!!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The house game went well, but as it was the home team in action, the crowd got loud and I soon began to realise that I needed to take care of my voice. This wasn't like a single or double header, after which I could go home and rest. I had a whole other day to get through and I wanted to be able to speak by the end of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The rest of the day went well. I ate a Hippo burger and got to watch some fantastic roller derby, and speak to a whole bunch of people I hadn't met before or hadn't seen in ages. I even managed to squeeze in a bit of dancing! But it was about 10pm before we got back to the hotel and I was ready to just chill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The next morning we didn't need to be at the venue until 8.30 – a long lie going by the previous day! First up, I got to do house announcing with the fantastic Archie, whose enthusiasm and showmanship really got me in the mood for another day of announcing, then I was back on feed later with Roller Polar Bear and finally I closed out my day house announcing the third place game between Lincolnshire Rollin' Thunder and South Wales Silures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I've got to admit, by the end of my last call, I was ready to not speak again for a while and I really wanted to go home to my own bed. Six amazing games of roller derby, out of a total of 13 played over the weekend, that I got to blether on about. The Hall's Soothers and hot water with lemon have been flowing ever since (and I even managed to pick up a bit of lurgy at some point over the weekend).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;But all in all, it was a fantastic experience, during which I learned a lot, met some great people, saw the best of European Men's Roller Derby and got the chance to grow as an announcer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Hopefully, they will have me back next year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>men's european cup</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>talk derby to me</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/17/first-time-tournament-announcing-or-how-chasing-katy-survived-mec-2o16/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 10:27:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Interview with: Mags Payne</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/12/an-interview-with-mags-payne/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://champs.mrda.org/"&gt;Men's Roller Derby Association Champs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; this weekend, we thought we'd catch up with someone who's been a key part of Scotland's own National Men's Team, but perhaps got a little less attention: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland/?fref=ts"&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Head Official (2015/16), and ubiquitous referee (especially if you're in Newcastle or her home league &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), &lt;em&gt;Mags Payne&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-9430 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14380016_10100686642377194_6212990695481911800_o.jpg" alt="14380016_10100686642377194_6212990695481911800_o" width="1600" height="1600"&gt; Mags Payne (centre) Photograph by: Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, first, let's start with the introductions: Who are you, Mags Payne?&lt;/strong&gt;
Mags Payne is an NYPD cop, hell-bent on vengeance after the murder of his wife and child..wait. No. That's MAX Payne. I am Mags Payne, referee with ARRG, Power of Scotland's Head Official for 2015/2016, Agent of S.T.R.I.P.E, and MRDA Recognised Official. I've been refereeing for 4 years. I'm also a Crazy Cat Lady, follower of the Winnipeg Jets, and all-round nerd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, in your day job, you're a technical writer. Quite a few referees have day jobs in contexts which require attention to detail, and an ability to apply complex rules - do you think Refereeing appeals because the skills are already there, or is it the other way around (that you Referee for the same reason you have the jobs you have).&lt;/strong&gt;
I think in a lot of ways, competent refs are born rather than made! There's a lot of things that are incredibly important for refs, that you can't really learn - it's a character trait you just have to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like you've mentioned, attention to detail is important, but you have to be able to pay attention to a lot of detail at once. You have to focus without being &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; focused on one thing. You also have to be able to think on your feet - that doesn't mean you have to be super smart, but simply you can think fast with clarity. Every awesome ref I can think of has a lot of the same traits: fast thinking, calm under pressure, walks a fine line between eye on the minutiae and keeping the bigger picture in mind, and a fair lack of ego. I think certain kinds of people are drawn to reffing. And you'll see a lot of the attributes required to ref showing up in their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You were selected as Power of Scotland's Head Official for 2015/2016. What did that involve, how did it feel, would you do it again?&lt;/strong&gt;
I revolved between being chuffed and terrified when they chose me! I would go and ref their practices and feed back any sort of 'ref' thing I noticed. So; highlighting if someone was particularly getting clockwise blocks, and what they were doing that was causing it. The guys made me feel absolutely welcome, despite the fact that 90% of my interactions with them was blowing my whistle and yelling at them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have absolutely loved the experience though - it felt like a really collaborative relationship, and it gave me a lot of confidence that I hadn't had before. When you've head reffed a scrim between the best male skaters in Scotland and Mild Discomfort, it does kind of give you a little confidence boost! Honestly, I would do it again in a heartbeat - it really was one of the best things I've ever applied for!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You've also been raising your own crop of new refs, via the Ref School you ran with ARRG. Can we talk a bit about the importance of nurturing officials in the community like this?&lt;/strong&gt;
Honestly,I think sometimes leagues think refs grow on trees! And we've seen a swathe of referees retiring in the past couple of years, but not as many refs stepping up to fill their places. It also takes at least a year until people are about ready for some of the teams in Scotland! So really, I wanted to foster an environment where new referees could learn and grow, but also in a formalised way that meant there was a 'path' for them with a support network build in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes being an official can be a lonely endeavour - you're not really &lt;em&gt;part&lt;/em&gt; of a team as such. Although you're usually affiliated with a league, because you're always trying to remain professional and impartial, you can seem a little stand-offish. There's also the fact that when you're first starting out you're trying to build your confidence to make your calls, and be respected by the skaters as having the necessary authority. Having a weekly meeting (ours was in the backroom of a pub!), where you can chat and really go over the rules theory, in a friendly and supportive environment does wonders for new refs. I learned a lot from it too - cause sometimes they'd ask me things I'd never thought of! I'm only new to the head reffing thing, so I stole &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sleazethezebra.com/2015/06/26/allow-me-to-introduce-you-to-ref-school/"&gt;Von Sleaze's Ref School&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; wholesale. It was an absolute life line, and is set out in a great way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm quite protective of my new refs (I may have a few referees, and at least one PoS skater, who call me Mama Mags...) and I wanted them to have the confidence to ask questions. In fact, I laid down a rule of 'there are no such thing as stupid questions, just stupid people who think they know everything'. As a referee, you're always asking questions - did I see that? Did that have impact? Does this rule mean what I think it means? With the information I've just been given in this official review, was my call correct? It's something I really wanted to encourage people to do. Don't doubt yourself (you should only call what you're 100% about), but be open to being wrong, to asking questions, and always looking for the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that the guys found it useful, and I'd be looking to run it again in future. Dundee also does mini reffing bootcamps which new refs should definitely try and attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your next big Refereeing event is the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MensEuropeanCup/?fref=ts"&gt;Mens's European Cup&lt;/a&gt;, hosted by Newcastle's Tyne and Fear! It's the Nth time you've been in Newcastle this year, but probably the biggest event: how are you preparing, and what are you most looking forward to?&lt;/strong&gt;
Honestly, I'm nervous as anything. Have you &lt;em&gt;seen&lt;/em&gt; the crews?! Trying to get over the 'superstar refs...and Mags' feeling is tough. But I've been trying to get as many opportunities to get some practice as possible, seeking feedback wherever I can get it, and upping my strength program. I basically want to be in the best possible shape I can be for it, physically and mentally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm really looking forward to meeting some of the 'big names' of officiating. Skaters have their big name heroes - we have it too! I'm also looking forward to meeting people like Duncan Disorderly and Momo whom I've spoken to on messenger etc, but never actually chatted to in real life. Big name heroes who might actually know my name! And it's always great to hang out with the Newcastle crowd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to do my tiny part to keep Scotland's officiating reputation high!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As well as all of this Roller Derby Officiating, you're also a keen gamer; we know you're taking a break from Refereeing this weekend for a good cause - can we end this article with a little look at that?&lt;/strong&gt;
Yes please! I'm playing video games for 30 hours this weekend to raise money for Edinburgh's Sick Kids Hospital. It's part of an event known as Sick Kids' Save Point. If you could throw me a pound, that would be AMAZING! &lt;a href="https://sksp.everydayhero.com/uk/magsthepirate"&gt;https://sksp.everydayhero.com/uk/magsthepirate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's european cup</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>referees</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/12/an-interview-with-mags-payne/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 20:08:16 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>