<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about mens roller derby scotland)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/mens-roller-derby-scotland.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Roller Derby Is Back in Grangemouth in 2018</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/02/14/roller-derby-is-back-in-grangemouth-in-2018/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9205" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/bcr-banner.jpg" alt="bcr-banner" width="851" height="315"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby in 2018 has well and truly started after the Christmas break as we have just witnessed the Womens World cup in Manchester recently and still have the Men's world cup to look forward to in April. But this month sees the return of derby in Scotland, with the first games of 2018 taking place thanks to Bairn City Rollers. As they will be kicking of their 2018 by hosting a double header in Grangemouth Sports Complex on Saturday the 24th of February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a double header with a Geordie feel to is as BCR's Skelpies take on Tyne and Fears &lt;span class="_4n-j _fbReactionComponent__eventDetailsContentTags fsl"&gt;Inglorious B&lt;em&gt;Stars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for the first game of the day followed after there is an &lt;span class="_4n-j _fbReactionComponent__eventDetailsContentTags fsl"&gt;All Gender game made up of skaters from Newcastle.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="_4n-j _fbReactionComponent__eventDetailsContentTags fsl"&gt;The Skelpies and the BStars have faced off against each other three times to date, with the B*Stars taking the win each time, can the Skelpies take the win this time? Be sure to come along to find out.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="_4n-j _fbReactionComponent__eventDetailsContentTags fsl"&gt;Doors open 1.30pm and tickets are priced at £5 on the door. If you would like to know more &lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/587963344880848/"&gt;visit the facebook event page here&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bcr</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mens roller derby scotland</category><category>skelpies</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>tyne &amp; fear</category><category>tyne and fear</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/02/14/roller-derby-is-back-in-grangemouth-in-2018/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 11:15:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2015 A year in review for Capital City</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/22/2015-a-year-in-review-for-capital-city/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2014 was a year of firsts for  Capital City, which saw them have members take part in the first ever Men's Roller Derby World Cup with Power Of Scotland, play their first ever co-ed game under the name Capital Chums then round off their year off by hosting and playing in their first ever home game.  2015 started with their AGM and voting in a new captain (Despicable V) and vice (Dafty) who would guide them through the next 9 months of games they had booked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2015 was their first full bouting year and their bout management had been working hard to line up games. Unfortunately one of their games had to be cancelled when the opponents lost their training venue and another two games ended up being postponed until 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year saw the first ever Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals tournament being held over the course of the year. This saw all the bouting men's teams in Scotland (Bairn City Rollers, Capital City and Mean City) face off against each other during the year, to see who would be crowned the first Scottish Nationals Champion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/ccrd-bcr.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5260"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5260" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/ccrd-bcr.jpg?w=614" alt="ccrd-bcr" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital City's first game of the year and the first game of Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals was against Bairn City Rollers, which saw them travel to Grangemouth to play the Skelpies on their home turf. The final score was Skelpies 192 to CCRD 127 in what was a hard fought game from beginning to end that saw both teams only fielding 10 skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the cancelled  and postponed games It would be almost 5 months until Capital City took to the track again. In that time they took in a few new skaters (Darth Evader and Mad Science) and were working hard at getting them through their mins ready for the games later on in the year. They also had four skaters (Bounce, Dafty, Tequila Jammer and Despicable V) make it into the 30 training squad for Power of Scotland for the Men's Derby World Cup next year. Of those four two (Dafty and Tequila Jammer)  made it into the final selection of 20 skaters going to Calgary next year and also took part in the 4 nations tournament, which saw England, Scotland, Wales and France all play each other over the course of a weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/darth-evader-54.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4876 size-medium" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/darth-evader-54.jpg?w=240" alt="Darth Evader 54" width="240" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Darth Evader #54&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/mad-science-36.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4875 size-medium" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/mad-science-36.jpg?w=240" alt="Mad Science 36" width="240" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Mad Science #36&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
It want until the 11th of July that Capital City got back on track this time making their first ever trip south of the border heading down to Manchester to take on the Chaos Engine. Unfortunately due to injuries and holidays they were a little light on skaters so drafted in two guest skaters with Momo from The Brawlermen and Bish Bash Josh ex Capital City Skater who now lives down in Manchester  both being unicorns on the day. The final score was Chaos Engine 213 to Capital City 107.
&lt;p&gt;Their Third and final public game of the year was on the 19th of October when Mean City paid them a visit in the final game of the Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals for 2015. As Bairn City had won both of their games they had been crowned the 2015 Champions but this game would decide who got 2nd and 3rd place. At the final whistle the scores were Capital City 158 - Mean City  217, meaning Mean City took 2nd place and Capital City took 3rd in a very hard hitting and fought game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/mc-ccrd.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5259"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5259" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/mc-ccrd.jpg?w=614" alt="mc ccrd" width="614" height="271"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a sadder note, during 2015 Capital City and Scottish derby also said goodbye to a couple of faces. After all our public games were played Deathworm Jim decided to hang up his skates. Having been with Capital City from their inception his presence will definitely be missed on and off the track. At the beginning of the year, an old familiar face returned to Capital City, transferring from Mean City. Unfortunately not long after the Chaos engine game, Bounce also decided that the time was right for him to also hang up his skates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before the end of the year Capital City wanted to fit in one last thing. At the beginning of December they invited everyone's friends from the North, the Granite City Brawler Men down for a closed game, which both enjoyed so much that a return game has already been planned for next year. For that game they also voted in their new Captain (Hajuken) and Vice (Critical Hit) to get them ready for the year ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2015</category><category>articles</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>mens roller derby scotland</category><category>mighty unicorns</category><category>scottish men's roller derby nationals</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/22/2015-a-year-in-review-for-capital-city/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 15:37:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital City Host the Final SMRDN game of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/27/capital-city-host-the-final-smrdn-game-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year we saw the launch of the Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals (SMRDN), which saw Bairn City Rollers, Mean City and Capital City all fight for the bragging rights of being the top Scottish Men's team. With two games played and two wins to BCR's Skelpies they have taken the title of champions for this year. There is however still one more game left to play which is sure to be an exciting clash for more than one reason, which is Capital City vs Mean City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone wp-image-4863 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ccrd-banner-smrdfin.jpg?w=614" alt="ccrd-banner-smrdfin" width="614" height="227"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two teams have yet to met on track in a public game, with this their first encounter deciding who will take second place in this years SMRDN and the looser picking up 3rd and last place for 2015. With so much to play for, both teams will be fighting for every point from the first whistle to the last. And if this wasn't enough to tempt you along, Capital City have turned the event into a double header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get everyone ready for the main event, they are putting on a coed game first at which we will get to see some of the the Granite City Brawlermen in action for the first time as they join forces with some of the girls from Granite City Roller Girls as well as other guys and girls from the likes of Capital City, Mean City and Bairn City to form both of the coed teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This double header will take place at Meddowbank on Saturday the 19th of September, for more information visit the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4864" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ccrd-tall-smrdfin.jpg" alt="ccrd-tall-smrdfin" width="513" height="720"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>ccrd</category><category>coed</category><category>double header</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>mcrd</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mens roller derby scotland</category><category>scottish men's roller derby nationals</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><category>smrdn</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/27/capital-city-host-the-final-smrdn-game-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 11:21:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New faces at the Capital City Vice Quad Bout</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/07/new-faces-at-the-capital-city-vice-quad-bout/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few months back, Capital City introduced a few new faces into the world of Scottish roller derby when we took part in a &lt;a title="Capital City’s cherry popping bouters" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/30/capital-citys-cherry-popping-bouters/"&gt;co-ed bout with Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;. Forward on a few months and we are at it again. This time it's our very first home bout and our first bout as Capital City’s Mighty Unicorns. Our opponents were Bristol Roller Derby’s Vice Quads, a team which may have been around for a similar length of time as ourselves but had already bouted the likes of Quads of War, SWS b, The Crash Test Brummies and a few more to boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bout itself kept all who were watching on the edge of their seats from the first whistle to the last jam. Bristol may have took an early lead but we worked hard to pull the score line back into our favor during the first half. The scores remained close throughout the game right up to the final whistle, when it ended 173 - 164 in our favor (only a 9 point difference).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those of you who were there will have recognized a few familiar faces from the last couple of years in our ranks along with our newer bouters from our co-ed game along with some brand new faces. This time we had the pleasure of introducing you all to Bruise Campbell, JAKILL3, Sassenick and Wrighteous. I managed to catch up with three of our new faces after the bout for a quick interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/bruise-campbell-333.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4322" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/bruise-campbell-333.jpg?w=200" alt="Bruise Campbell" width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Bruise Campbell picture by Capital City&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/jakill3-317.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4318" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/jakill3-317.jpg?w=200" alt="JAKILL3 " width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; JAKILL3 picture by Capital City&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/sassenick-149.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4319" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/sassenick-149.jpg?w=200" alt="Sassenick" width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Sassenick picture by Capital City&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/wrighteous-626.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4320" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/wrighteous-626.jpg?w=200" alt="Wrighteous " width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Wrighteous picture by Capital City&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;b&gt;JAKILL3 #317 (JK)
Sassenick #149 (SN)
Wrighteous #626 ( W)&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How did you find out about Derby and CCRD?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W):&lt;/b&gt; Found out about derby through a friend, derby name Hazzard, who skates with NTRG. She took me to a few of the AARG bouts and i was hooked, and after I was given a link for mens derby bout i knew i had to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I missed the fresh meat intake, but luckily NTRG allowed myself to train with them where i passed my mins. luckily got to join CCRD at the next fresh meat where i was asked if i would like to join the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(SN):&lt;/b&gt; Originally found out about derby through a university friend (Jess E. Ska from GRD), but then my girlfriend got involved in ARRG and dragged me along to an open skating event. I loved it, and as soon as she told me about CCRD, I decided to give it a shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Having not skated previously how did you find working towards and passing your mins?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK):&lt;/b&gt; I found learning to skate with ccrd very easy and the guys at the club are great to get on with, teaching you with a lot of patience and good humor and breaking each lesson down into a skill block at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(SN):&lt;/b&gt; Because we're quite a small league, the first six months or so that I was skating I was thrown in the deep end. There were 4 of us who were new to Derby, but the rest of the regular attendees ended up representing Power of Scotland at the World Cup. It was hard not to compare myself to them at first, but as more new people arrived I realised just how much I'd come on, and that gave me a huge confidence boost and it became a lot easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/scott-carroll.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-4327" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/scott-carroll.jpg?w=300" alt="Picture courtesy of Scott Carroll Photography" width="520" height="346"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/ScottCarrollLivePhotography"&gt;Scott Carroll Photography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What would you say has been your biggest achievement so far in derby?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W):&lt;/b&gt; It would have to be receiving the award for best jammer at the CCRD bout against Bristol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I honestly thought HaJuken or Dafty would have won that award and was completely stunned when my name was called. Plus having my family and friends there to see it made it that much more memorable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK):&lt;/b&gt; Passing my mins and be able to play against bristol vice squad, where our team played well together and I got awarded best blocker from the bristol vice squad guys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(SN):&lt;/b&gt; In Derby generally, I was an NSO for the final of the 2014 Men's European Cup, which was an amazing experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a skater, it has to be the first time we played together as a team. We had a closed scrim against Mean City who are much more experienced at skating together, and I felt like I knew what was happening, and that I was being useful. It was a great feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Did you get any pre first bout nerves?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK):&lt;/b&gt; A little, didnt want to let the team down. But with great organisation and guidance from the more advanced players it made the day a lot more enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(SN):&lt;/b&gt; Oh yes. I was having a major panic, and I had to go and sit on my own in the changing room with my headphones in to calm down. As soon as the warm up started though, all that disappeared and I was fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W):&lt;/b&gt; I was nervous all the way until bout day arrived, where i found myself really relaxed and just pumped up. I could not wait to get on track and just have fun on the day. If you had asked me before bout day i honestly thought i would be so nervous i would have thrown up on the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/scott-carol.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-4326" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/scott-carol.jpg?w=300" alt="Picture courtesy of Scott Carroll Photography" width="520" height="346"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/ScottCarrollLivePhotography"&gt;Scott Carroll Photography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Playing in and winning your first ever bout must be a dream come true, how did you feel after the final whistle and the official score went up on the scoreboard?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK): &lt;/b&gt;Well it was touch and go at the end, but when the final decision came to our advantage I was over the moon a bit emotional. I feel I worked hard to get there and with the team it made it not only my proudest day but the happiest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W):&lt;/b&gt; Ecstatic, I had a great time, the team played amazingly and it was a great and very competitive bout. I was all over the place wondering if we had won or not, but when the score became official i was just ecstatic. My first ever bout with a team i had only just joined a few weeks ago and we won against Bristol Vice Quads, could not ask for anything better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What sticks in your memory most from your first bout?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(SN):&lt;/b&gt; At one point I managed to force a track cut. Not a huge thing in the scheme of things, but I did it without thinking, and it was the first time that I can point to that I was playing smart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W): &lt;/b&gt;There was a point when I was trying to get through the pack as a jammer, when I got hit back slightly. HaJuken was behind me and caught me just before I started to fall, pushed me back up and through the side of the pack to get lead jammer. It was just a fantastic bit of team work by HaJuken and watching it back on video and in pictures shows how good a player he is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK):&lt;/b&gt; Just how much work and time and effort goes into getting the bout ready for the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Did you get any good advice that helped you on track or prepare for the bout?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W):&lt;/b&gt; I think the best bit of advice was just what we had been given as a team which was to keep our heads, keep calm and have fun. Let them make mistakes, don't get riled up when hit just do what we do best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK):&lt;/b&gt; Ginge ..advised us to stay calm all the time which I need, I am easily distracted and get over competitive and can get stuck in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(SN):&lt;/b&gt; "Don't worry about it. You know what you're doing, so stop freaking out. Push yourself in your warm up, and you'll be fine."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Is there any advice you could give others who have their first bout still to come?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W):&lt;/b&gt; Keep calm and have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK): &lt;/b&gt; Stick in, train hard and If your not falling your not trying hard enough. As you have to push yourself to learn quicker. Also remember theres a team to support you. and as my second name sake bobby mcferrin sings "dont worry... be happy" and try and relax&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/chris-renton.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-4325" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/chris-renton.jpg?w=300" alt="Picture by Chris Renton" width="521" height="346"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture by Chris Renton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Are there any skaters (Male or Female) who inspire you?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(SN):&lt;/b&gt; Far too many. I'm still pretty much in awe of Rose City Wheels of Justice blockers after watching them in the WFTDA champs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK):&lt;/b&gt; Well the list is so long I’d love to be as fast as craig (Tequila) and as tough as gregg (Dafty) and but as calm as hannah (Ginge) and as calming as marco (Despicable V). I find that most of the team are great mix of all of the above. Also admiral attackbar from arrg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W):&lt;/b&gt; Hazzard from NTRG, she puts a lot of hard work into her team and is a fantastic skater. Can not wait till she is skating for team Scotland. Optimus Grime from Mean City and now part of Power of Scotland. He is just a great all round player and have been lucky enough to have trained with and scrimmed against him on a couple of occasions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Skaters generally set goals for themselves, now that you have played in your first bout what goal's are you now looking to achieve/work towards?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(S):&lt;/b&gt; The biggest thing I learned about my skating was that I really need to work on the basics - ploughing especially. In almost all the pictures of me, I'm t-stopping which is really ineffective in a game situation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK):&lt;/b&gt; Better bridging, walls, stopping faster also building my stamina and strength and not forgetting my dark side over competitiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W):&lt;/b&gt; To build on my skills and look to improve my all round game, and hopefully one day maybe even try out for Power of Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10830932_862436320444831_4570080339720243265_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-4324" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10830932_862436320444831_4570080339720243265_o.jpg?w=300" alt="Picture courtesy of Scott Carroll Photography" width="545" height="363"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/ScottCarrollLivePhotography"&gt;Scott Carroll Photography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mens roller derby scotland</category><category>new faces of derby</category><category>new skaters</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/07/new-faces-at-the-capital-city-vice-quad-bout/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 13:41:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital City get ready for their bout - interview with team captain Tequila Jammer</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/13/capital-city-get-ready-for-their-first-home-bout/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Capital City have been busy since the announcement of their first home bout/Edinburgh's first ever Men's derby headline bout and launch their crowd funder campaign to help raise funds to put on the event. I caught up with team Captain Tequila Jammer to find out about their crowd funder and how things are going, on the run up to the bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Since you announced your first home and mens game, everyone must be pretty excited, it has been a long time coming. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty excited?! We're positively fizzing with excitement! Seriously, it's been a long hard road to build the league, recruit members and train hard to a standard that we can play but we're finally there and ready to show everyone what we got.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Organising your first bout is time consuming and takes a lot of effort from everyone, how long have you all been planning this?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've got some of the most dedicated skaters, organisers and just generally awesome people you could possibly meet so organising hasn’t been too much of a stress with everyone chipping in but this has been in the works for a long time - it was one of our main goals this year from our AGM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/cg2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4048 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/cg2.jpg?w=614" alt="cg2" width="614" height="388"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture by Dave McAleavy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;It’s great to see you working with ARRG to make your bout a double header with their Cannon Belle’s taking on Malmö's Crime City Rollers B in the opening game. Had you always planned to make the game a double header&lt;/b&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not initially but we’re always happy to work with other leagues to put on the best possible show. Having, ARRG, Bristol and an international element will be sure to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;In a novel approach and a first for Scottish Roller Derby, you have decide to crowdfund to help raise money for the bout. What was the catalyst for you to try this way to raise funds?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funding your first game is ridiculously expensive… well in Edinburgh anyway. With hall costs being close to £1000 as well as added extras, we needed a cool way to generate cash to put on a great show. Crowdfunding has worked well in the past for some of our members so we thought why not try it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;On your crowdfund page you have a lot of options for people to purchase and in a bold move you even put up your skate out song as an option to purchase. Was it difficult to find a balance of the right amount of items and what items you have on offer?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahhhhh… the perks. Well, we tried to have something for everyone; for the person who couldn’t make it but wanted to support us to the fully fledged life long fan. We tried to make them fun or unique like a custom made uniform or blowing the first whistle… but, yeah you’re right the skate out was a gamble. It’s gone now too… hopefully it won’t be too embarrassing, whatever it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;You detail how much you want to raise on your page and how that breaks down for the bout. Of that the vast majority (around three quarters) is attributed to hall cost. Has this been a barrier to you putting on a bout previously?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One word. Yes. Edinburgh is ridiculously expensive for hall costs. That’s if you can find a proper venue. Luckily ARRG have paved the way for us with their frequent use of Meadowbank Stadium (thank you ARRG), just without having that initial cash it’s hard to kick start home bouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;If the crowdfunder is a success and you reach your total, will we see Capital City use this method again to help raise funds for your next bout?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully we’ll be able to use the proceeds from tickets and merch to put up the money for our next home game but never say never. We also have a number of other fundraising ideas… heard of a car wash? What about a skate wash?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/cg1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4047 size-full" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/cg1.jpg" alt="cg1" width="426" height="640"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture by Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;When Capital Chums took to the track to take on The Belter Skelpies it was the first bout for a few of the Capital City boys. On game day against the Vice Quads will we be meeting any new Unicorns for the first time?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of new and old faces will be making appearances. I am proud to say all of our skaters will be CCRD members (with the exception of one Bish Bash Josh who recently transferred back to his old hunting grounds of Manchester).  We can expect to see some of our Fresh Meat take to the track as well as some faces you might recognise minus the stripes. I’ll also be taking to the track for the first time with CCRD as I Benched our last Capital Chums game… EXCITING!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Its less than 2 months till the big day, what are all the Capital City boys doing to get ready to take on the Vice Quads?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s tough to fit in training with limited hall hours but we’ve developed a cohesive training programme that lets Fresh Meat integrate quickly into some more advanced drills. Also working together for just under 2 years has given us a bit of a pack mentality and we know what each other is capable of. Other than that it’s train, train, train: strong walls, agile jammers and kick ass endurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Can you tell everyone what to expect from Capital City at their first bout? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are going to be lean, mean, bad assed, mighty Unicorns! Definitely vocal, strong defence with a few cheeky moves to mix things up. Hey, it’s pretty near Christmas so there might be an apex jump or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital City will be taking on Bristol's Vice Quads on the 29th of November, to find out more information about the event please visit the event page below:
https://www.facebook.com/events/331510057008876/?fref=ts
For more information or if you ant to pledge to their crowd funder campaign then please visit:
https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/capital-city-roller-derby-s-double-header-29-11-14&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>crowd funder</category><category>inerview with tequila jammer</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mens roller derby scotland</category><category>tequila jammer</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/13/capital-city-get-ready-for-their-first-home-bout/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 15:51:11 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>