<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about merchandise)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/merchandise.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Brush with glory - new book puts you at the art of roller derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/04/20/brush-with-glory-new-book-puts-you-at-the-art-of-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;An inspirational new book celebrating the world of roller derby has been published – shining a light on the amazing artwork which has helped to immortalise its skaters and leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;From the birth of modern-day roller derby in Texas in the early years of &lt;img class="  wp-image-4617 alignright" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/bout-book1.jpg?w=194" alt="bout book1" width="306" height="463"&gt;the third millennium right through to the modern day, &lt;em&gt;Bout Book&lt;/em&gt; is packed full of glorious artwork from all over the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;From movie-inspired posters to surreal art, it's a highly-collectible, cult classic in the making - and it's supporting two terrific causes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bout Book&lt;/em&gt; has been created by roller derby skaters and fans to celebrate the sport and raise funds for the charities Regain
Sports and Womankind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The book traces the transition of the sport – from 2002 to the present day – and features more than 150 leagues, with posters from Australia, Austria, Belgium, Canada, Colombia, Czech Republic, Denmark, Egypt, Finland, France, Germany, Ireland, Japan, New Zealand, Norway, Spain, Sweden, Switzerland, UK and the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;It includes posters promoting tournaments hosted by Glasgow Roller Derby and Granite City Roller Girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;One of the unique character traits of derby wherever it's played in the world is the strong sense of community which surrounds it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;That is beautifully illustrated in &lt;em&gt;Bout Book&lt;/em&gt; – which shows the ingenuity, expansion and global progression of revival roller derby through its bout artwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Co-author Marie Danielle, a former Steam Roller with London Roller Girls, said: “The popularity of roller derby continues to roll on – with record numbers of people playing across the world – so this is a great time to celebrate its highs and history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;“We show the expansion of roller derby through its bout artwork and feature over 150 leagues’ artwork, across 20 countries, including the very first modern roller derby poster from ‘Bad Girl Good Women’ and the very first tournament artwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;“It’s a collector’s item for anyone who plays derby, loves the sport and supports the derby community – all in aid of two superb charities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Bout Book&lt;/em&gt; has been created by roller derby skaters and fans. Pivotal to the success of this book are the leagues and designers who kindly allowed us to include their bout artwork.&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/bout2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-4618 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/bout2.jpg?w=300" alt="Bout2" width="300" height="208"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;“One of the book's aims is to get people discovering who created their favourite artworks - who, where and when.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;“What better way of demonstrating the DIY ethic of roller derby as being for the skaters and by the skaters? This book simply couldn’t have happened without the support shown from the derby community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Regain Sports is a registered charity which aims to improve the independence of all British men and women who have become tetraplegic as a result of a sports or leisure injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Meanwhile, Womankind Worldwide is an international charity working to support women and girls to improve the lives and communities in Africa, Asia and Latin America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;For more information visit &lt;a href="http://www.regainsportscharity.com"&gt;www.regainsportscharity.com&lt;/a&gt; and www.womankind.org.uk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;To find out how to get the book or discover more about it, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BoutBook?fref=ts&amp;amp;ref=br_tf"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; or go to &lt;a href="http://www.boutbook.org"&gt;www.boutbook.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;There’s also a promo video to enjoy - &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OBn3VbGa2tk"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OBn3VbGa2tk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>in the news</category><category>interviews</category><category>merchandise</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/04/20/brush-with-glory-new-book-puts-you-at-the-art-of-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 19:01:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital City crowdfund to help put on their first bout</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/25/capital-city-crowdfund-for-first-bout/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we all know putting on a bout can be a very costly venture for any league especially when it comes to your first. So when Capital City announced last month that they would be hosting their first home bout they were a little nervous. Being a relatively small league (around 14 members), they know only too well how difficult it can be bringing in enough money to cover costs. So they have come up with a novel way to help raise the funds they need to put on their double header bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a first for Scottish roller derby, they are looking to crowdfund for their bout to help raise money ahead of the big day. The aim is to raise money to help cover the majority of costs that need to be paid ahead of the bout, which breakdown as:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Meadowbank Hall Hire: £930&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Public Liability Insurance: £200&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Emergency Medical Technicians: £100&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Track Rope and Tape: £100&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Programme Printing: £50&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Over on their crowdfunding page they allow you to pre order items such as bout tickets and merch (t-shirts/caps/tote bags) along with some more special one off items, such as picking a song on the bout day playlist, blowing the first whistle for the game, getting your very own Capital City Uniform and much more. They have even auctioned off their skate out song which was snapped up only minutes after their campaign went live.
&lt;p&gt;Purchasing items help items Capital City put on their bout, but it will also save you money. As bout tickets and merch are cheaper for those who pre-order than they will be on the day as a thank you to those helping them. You will have to be quick as you can only purchase items until the 1st of November when their crowdfunding campaign ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to pre-order your tickets or are feeling a little flush with cash and want to buy some other things then head over to their crowdfunding page at indiegogo via the link below to find out details of all the things on offer:
&lt;a href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/capital-city-roller-derby-s-double-header-29-11-14"&gt;https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/capital-city-roller-derby-s-double-header-29-11-14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out more about their crowdfunding campaign watch the video below from Capital city&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=66QK04yIVFU&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>crowdfunding</category><category>first bout</category><category>fundraising</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby edinburgh</category><category>merchandise</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>video</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/25/capital-city-crowdfund-for-first-bout/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 10:39:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Scottish Roller Derby T-Shirts</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/06/scottish-roller-derby-t-shirts/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scottish Roller Derby are rather excited to announce that a limited number of T-shirts are now available. As the blog is run on a not for profit basis, all profits from the sale of this run of t-shirts will go to support the next generation of skaters at the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/fiercevalleyrollercubs"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/imag0130.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/imag0130.jpg" alt="Photography-SandySRDBlog" width="614" height="921" class="size-full wp-image-3018"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photography-SandySRDBlog&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are Gildan Softstyle shirts in white, printed with the Scottish Roller Derby 'Lion Rampant Jammer' design in black. Available in small/med/large/xl and also as a ladies fitted medium. This is a limited run of shirts with a never to be repeated design/colour combination, priced at £10.
You can find them for sale at the upcoming Fierce Valley Roller Girls bouts, or contact the Cubs or Scottish Roller Derby directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reader can win one of these t-shirts, just find &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/scottish.rollerderby"&gt;Scottish Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook, like and share the competition post. A winner will be chosen at random and announced on Saturday the 9th of November.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>competition</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>merchandise</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/06/scottish-roller-derby-t-shirts/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 10:21:27 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>