<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about mrdwc2016)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/mrdwc2016.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>2016 in Review</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst on a general level, 2016 has been labelled a bad year (perhaps unfairly - it's been a mixed bag, it's just that the negatives have been big and prominent, and the positives less so), for Roller Derby, in Scotland and World wide, it's been pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're capping off the year by talking about the things that happened in the past 12 months, first in Scotland (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/1"&gt;page 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and secondly across the World (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/2"&gt;page 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), before rounding up our hopes for 2017 (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/3"&gt;page 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Scotland&lt;/h3&gt;
Scottish Roller Derby continued to Grow: several new leagues popped up, which we recently brought to you [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/06/scotlands-newest-coed-league-inverclyde-roller-derby/"&gt;Inverclyde Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/13/scotlands-newest-northernmost-league-orkney-viqueens/"&gt;Orkney ViQueens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/15/west-lothians-newest-league-west-lothian-roller-derby/"&gt;West Lothian Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/09/glasgow-mens-roller-derby/"&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/30/glasgows-new-inclusive-junior-derby-resistance-roller-derby/"&gt;Resistance Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] and others continued to grow.
Ayrshire Roller Derby had their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/08/16/ayshire-roller-derby-hit-the-track/"&gt;first public bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (against Lothian Derby Dolls) as did &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/12/granite-city-brawlers-debut-home-game/"&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and GMRD, and Helgin Roller Derby  and the renewed Fair City Rollers have scheduled their (joint) first bout for next year (if we were to bet, we'd expect Doonhame Roller Derby to be the next to be bout-ready).
Scotland's only bouting junior derby team, Fierce Valley Roller Cubs, also played their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/07/cubs-take-on-new-opposition/"&gt;first ever interleague bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, against a mixed team from Sheffield and Newcastle.
Even the larger leagues continued to expand, with Auld Reekie Roller Girls' ASTROs founded this year, and taking the number of ARRG travel teams to 3. As our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/19/yearrgly-review-2016/"&gt;Auld Reekie review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; shows, the whole league had a pretty good year, with the All-Stars qualifying for WFTDA Division 2 playoffs (after an impressive performance at The Big O in the USA), and sensibly declining in favour of working on longer term goals.
&lt;p&gt;Further north, both Dundee Roller Girls and Granite City Roller Derby had very good years as well. Both leagues' A-teams performed impressively in their Divisions at British Champs (Granite City qualifying for promotion to Tier 3 from Tier 4, and Dundee just missing out on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/17/british-champs-at-dundee/"&gt;the promotion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to Tier 2 at the Tier-3 playoffs). Whilst Dundee has withdrawn from Champs to focus on their national and international game (especially after playing their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/08/dundees-international-debut/"&gt;first international away&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, in Tenerife, just scant weeks ago), Granite City will indeed be in Tier 3 of Champs next year, alongside Auld Reekie's Reserves! The two leagues' B-teams also had very good years, with Dundee's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/16/a-chat-with-bonnie-colliders-captains-khilleesi-and-g-wrecks/"&gt;Bonnie Colliders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; winning basically every bout they played until ARRG's ASTROs late in the year, and GCRD's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/21/granite-citys-hawks-flock-to-the-arrgmageddon/"&gt;Fight Hawks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; playing three times as much derby as they did in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Central Belt, Bairn City Rollers' Skelpies managed a few bouts, despite many of them also making Power of Scotland, which prevented them taking fixtures in the first half of the year!. Alongside GMRD, they'll be joining the British Champs Men's T3 in 2017, and we expect good things of them. Meanwhile, BCR's &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/12/bairn-city-belters-captain-and-vice-interview-2016/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central Belters&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;continued their own upward rise in the rankings - a win against the newly-reformed Furness Firecrackers sealing that trend for the year, and setting the Belters the challenge of maintaining expectations in 2017 (the problem with upward growth is that people start expecting it to never stop!). The open-gender Belter Skelpers had a much quieter year, taking on just Mean City's coed-team and then hosting Granite City Brawlers and friends for BCR's 4th Anniversary event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Mean City, they were also extremely busy this year, hosting a vast range of events, including &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/24/powers-of-two-at-mean-city/"&gt;double-headers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; supporting Power of Scotland. With the growth of coed leagues in Scotland (several of our newer non-bouting leagues are open), hopefully Mean City will have an even busier year next year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the Scottish Men's National Team, Power of Scotland also had a very big year, representing well at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/30/mrdwc2016-rankings-and-statistics/"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Calgary, placing a creditable 10th, just below the tournament's surprise unseeded upset of Mexico. Several members of the 2016 team are also now involved with Team Scotland Roller Derby, who will be hoping (along with PoS) to represent the nation strongly in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not to say that there weren't some wobbles in Scottish Derby: due to an unfortunate series of retirements, Glasgow Roller Derby has spent the season with a very different roster to 2015, resulting in the 2015 British Champs Champions placing near the bottom of the Premier Division in 2016.  They'll be aiming to pull back their WFTDA ranking position over 2017... although they've retired from British Champs to focus their team on this goal.   Similarly, a series of transfers and other movements lead to Fierce Valley Roller Girls performing less well than they would have liked in the Champs Tier 3, resulting in potential relegation to Tier 4 in 2017. (Despite this, both FVRG and GRD have been drivers of many Scottish events in the past year - Fierce Valley hosting a pair of massive &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/18/the-team-who-sur5ed-fierce-valley-host-harry-potter-themed-open-event/"&gt;Sur5al&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; tournaments and hosting an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/23/international-roller-derby-in-the-forth-valley/"&gt;international&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; against Zurich, and Glasgow hosting &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/28/glasgow-roller-derby-close-the-year-with-festive-charity/"&gt;Charity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; events and playing &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/01/glasgow-at-europes-first-wftda-division-1-tournament/"&gt;all&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/25/glasgow-cross-the-irish-sea-dublin-v-irn-bruisers/"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Europe themselves, as well as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/29/international-derby-at-glasgow-and-edinburgh/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Berlin, and playing a big part in Vagine Regime UK.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another growing trend in Scotland (and the UK) this year was "cherry popper" or "rookie" bouts, with almost every league in Scotland hosting at least one such event this year, including Livingston's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/09/new-skaters-on-track-for-new-town-cherry-popper/"&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we shouldn't just talk about the Leagues themselves. Scottish Referees and NSOs also continued to represent at the highest levels of the sport, with Dundee's Righteous Oxide particularly visible at international level events like MRDWC and ; but many other referees like , and NSOs (many of whom were nominated in the TDTM Listener awards) travelled huge distances and devoted much time to supporting the sport.
Scottish photographers were also supporting international events this year, with Dave McAleavy and Laura MacDonald being both ubiquitous at Scottish games, but also travelling to Tenerife in Dave's case, and to the Men's World Cup in Laura's. (As the two are, between them, the photographers for the two national teams, we expect even more travel in their future.)
Our Announcers didn't do too badly either, with Helliverence near-ubiquitous across UK events, Bairn City's man of many names Graeme "Archie" McPhail supporting MEC [and announcing two tournaments in Scotland without a break in each],  MRDWC media director Chasing Katy appearing at several events, but especially MEC, and Granite City's sMACklemore doing both MEC and  Track Head Announcing at MRDWC itself. The latter two also helped to push on the Scottish contributions to Roller Derby media, with the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://tdtmpodcast.wordpress.com/"&gt;Talk Derby To Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; podcast [also hosted by King Crazy] going from strength to strength over the year (especially with their excellent coverage of tournament-level events), culminating in a rather huge Listener Awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(For us at the Scottish Roller Derby Blog, it's also been a good year - we've expanded our coverage again, introduced our own rankings, and even managed to expand into some new fields of video and audio interviews. We also &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/category/mrdwc2016/"&gt;covered&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the Men's Roller Derby World Cup in more depth than we have any previous event. In order to handle this, we &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/"&gt;launched our own annex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to the blog, which hosts links to content which doesn't work well with Wordpress.
We also managed to hit more then 1500 likes on our Facebook page just a few days ago, which was our own goal for 2016!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to Scotland (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/1"&gt;page 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) , forward to "The Future" (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/3"&gt;page 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;UK and Europe&lt;/h3&gt;
Obviously one of the most exciting developments of 2016 was the announcement of so much International Derby coming to Europe in the next two years. Both World Cups will be in Europe - the Men's in Barcelona and the Women's in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/05/a-rainy-day-for-international-roller-derby/"&gt;Greater Manchester&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - in 2018; but before that, one MRDA playoff and the Championship itself will be in Europe as well.
With so many Europe-wide international tournaments already happening in Europe (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/"&gt;ERDT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/27/a-quick-analysis-of-road-to-tbc/"&gt;The Road to...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, SKOD, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/17/first-time-tournament-announcing-or-how-chasing-katy-survived-mec-2o16/"&gt;MEC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/01/glasgow-at-europes-first-wftda-division-1-tournament/"&gt;European Smackdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and so on... with Newcastle's EuroClash joining the set in 2017), this was almost inevitable at some point, but no-one expected everything but WFTDA to happen at once.
&lt;p&gt;Another positive development in the UK was the coming together of Coaches at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/03/uks-first-coaching-summit-derby-stance/"&gt;Derby Stance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Coaching Summit (followed by the Summit at the Ramps, which brought together skaters from multiple disciplines) organised by Rule 56 and the Female Coaching Network. We're very much in favour of people working together to progress the community...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...which is also why we were cheered by the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/19/by-their-powers-combined-they-are-leeds-roller-derby/"&gt;announcement very recently&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that Leeds Roller Derby had formed from fusion of Hot Wheel and Leeds Roller Dolls. We'd love to report on more "collaborations" rather than the politics which leads to splits in Roller Derby, and hope this can be a trend for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Roller Derby media also had some growth in the UK as well, with two new podcasts - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hellyeahrollerderby.com/"&gt;Hell Yeah! Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Croydon and elsewhere] and the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://goodarrows.libsyn.com/podcast"&gt;Good Arrows Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Nottingham Roller Derby] both launching this year, with good content already!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;International&lt;/h3&gt;
Internationally, the most exciting places for Roller Derby are always where growth and development is still raring ahead.
&lt;p&gt;So, in East Asia, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/"&gt;Japan Open Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was possibly the most significant event of the year - the first ever international tournament in the region, hosted in Okinawa and with attendees from the Pacific Region, Australiasia and beyond (Alaska and Copenhagen!). We're very excited to see what the sequel (now managed directly by a consortium of the Japanese leagues) tournament - the Tomodachi in March 2017 - manages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also in East Asia, after literally years of development, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/"&gt;first ever public bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in China happened, with Beijing Roller Derby hosting a mixed team from the rest of the Asian leagues. This was also a great example of the still-political purpose of Roller Derby, as the event was in promotion of the UN HeForShe project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growth has also continued in other regions, with Latin America now hosting a huge number of teams (although their terminology for leagues and teams differs from the USA and Europe), including 3 now in WFTDA (as full members, with more Apprentices). Across Europe and the Middle East, increasing number of countries are growing not just one, but multiple teams - and in the more established countries we've seen huge growth in national level tournaments (the French Nationale is a mighty thing), and other regular events (for ex. the Finnish &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/06/the-pohjola-cup-finland-and-russia-compete/"&gt;Pohjola Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; now trans-national as it includes Russia's White Night Furies this year).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of National Teams representation, 2016 has seen continued growth in both the Men's and Women's parts of the sport - MRDWC 2016 saw a massive surge in teams attending, filling out Europe and Latin America [Colombia having a last-minute technical hitch which prevented this being even more impressive]; and there are already at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/22/new-nations-in-the-world-cup/"&gt;least 5 new Nations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the 2018 Roller Derby World Cup in Manchester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we were very pleased that WFTDA has started adopting positive policies such as releasing the (alpha) of their new bout stats management tool, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/19/bouttime-open-source-what-is-it-and-why-is-it-relevant-to-roller-derby-and-wftda/"&gt;bouttime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, as an open-source project, truly for the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And International Derby Media has also continued to grow, with the startling appearance of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://thederbyapex.com/@thederbyapex"&gt;The Derby Apex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; earlier this year, and their meteoric rise to popularity. We're sure we'll see more good things from them in 2017 and beyond. (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.derbycentral.net/"&gt;Derby Central&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, of course, continued to do great work, covering all of the international things above, and many more.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to Scotland (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/1"&gt;page 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and back to the World (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/2"&gt;page 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The Future&lt;/h3&gt;
So, what would we like to see in 2017?
&lt;h4&gt;National Teams leveraging PR to promote growth in their "home" nations.&lt;/h4&gt;
Whilst Teams Korea, Philippines and West Indies are all representing their nations, none of them have any leagues &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; those nations to draw skaters from. With all three declaring their intent to use their existence to promote the sport, we'd love to see this bear fruit. (Korea has a league, but like most leagues in East Asia [except Kamikaze Badass in Tokyo, and Tokyo Roller Girls' Neon Roller Monsters team] it is almost entirely composed of non-nationals.)
&lt;h4&gt;The Derby Apex's "Stat Rataissance" actually happening.&lt;/h4&gt;
One of The Apex's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://thederbyapex.com/our-10-favourite-things-from-the-2016-wftda-season-d516ae8284e4#.jmhiwv3pm"&gt;high points&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of the year has been the improved availability of stats for WFTDA bouts, alongside the promotion of bouttime. We're a little more skeptical of this as a global phenomenon - Roller Derby is not just WFTDA teams [in fact, they're still a minority, especially if you include the fact that only A teams count for WFTDA member leagues], and stats availability for the sport as a whole is still relatively poor, despite the best efforts of Flat Track Stats and others. We'd like to see this happen, though, and still have some hope. (Our own effort in this regard - the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; rating system - is still very much dependant on FTS's own records, which are themselves dependant on both the site's few volunteers and the Roller Derby community itself.)
&lt;h4&gt;Increased openness, transparency and collaboration.&lt;/h4&gt;
One reason why stats are an issue feeds into this next wish: Roller Derby still has problems with openness and transparency. The bouttime release was definitely a positive step from WFTDA, but we think that most Derby bodies (international and national) could improve on their transparency (the MRDA gets points for having a public forum!) and communication. Alongside this, we'd also like to see positive elements of collaboration continue to grow - more things like Derby Stance, more mergers of leagues to make stronger bodies, and generally more "derby spirit".
&lt;h4&gt;A WFTDA Playoff outside North America (and a non-US team winning Champs).&lt;/h4&gt;
As The Apex noted, WFTDA is now the only major entity with "international" contests not to have some component held outside North America. It would be great to see some movement on this, especially with the increasing number of ranked European teams at D2 and even D1 level. (We'd also love to see a non-US team win the WFTDA Championships - Victorian have come ever so close twice now [and they've beaten Rose on neutral ground this year], so 2017 could still be it.)
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what would you like to see in 2017 - from us, or from Roller Derby? Let us know via our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/scottish.rollerderby/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; page, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/scotrollerderby"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or just email (scottishrollerderbyATgmailDOTcom)!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>articles</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>international derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>review of the year</category><category>team scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 14:21:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>From Earth to orbit and back again</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/22/from-earth-to-orbit-and-back-again/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As the Winter Period is a time of reflection, we're very happy to be able to host this guest blog by Philth "Optimus Grime" Malloch on his past year and how it affected him.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will remember 2016 for the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started Roller Derby to save my life. I was Suicidal and depressed, and this sport gave me something I could absorb myself in. I could get lost in its infinite intricacies, hide in its diversity and heal in its embrace. It has been a teacher as much as a saviour and the best medicine to mend a gaping wound, more than any drug ever could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started with one moment. Sitting in a small room, hidden away watching the first Men's Roller Derby World Cup in secret, I had a thought. This thought became a desire, then a dream and finally a vow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"No matter what, I WILL be at the next one!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My vow was fulfulled, as part of a team that I could not fault. It felt like, what only dictionaries and ideals could define as a team. We achieved exactly what we said we would do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year's season has been something I could only dream of. I doubt I could have even imagined the opportunities this year has offered me. I'm still not sure if I am awake. Someone body-check me into the reality hotel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-13293" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/philth-mountains.jpg?w=1024" alt="philth-mountains" width="1024" height="768"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started in the mountains in Calgary. As a result of how we did, I came home high as a kite but with very few plans for the future. I had ideas, but nothing decided or set in stone. All I knew is that I wanted to get better and play more derby. I felt like I was holding a compass in the mist. I knew where I wanted to go, but no idea how to get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then BOOM!!!....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invitation 1: skate in St. Louis. (vs GK)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invitation 2: skate in Dallas. (MRDA Champs)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invitation 3: skate in Adelaide. (AMRD Nationals)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With each trip the euphoria and flattery builds. My chest was like an ever-expanding happy balloon. Its brightness and amazement growing like a wildfire. In shock and disbelief, I say yes with no hindrance or hesitation. I kept expecting to wake up. "This has to be a joke!" But, like Forest Gump, I thought, "Well I've come this far, might as well keep on going!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My body trains harder and harder, brain plans further and further, I feel I'm on the brink of losing control. Yet still I'm going higher, to the point I feel so euphoric and ever so surreal. It's like I'm sitting next to Red Bull guy on his magnificent shining balloon staring down at the Earth like a satellite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm on top of the world. What a rush. What a ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you look around..... and you're all by yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Far away from home and surrounded by people, it's amazing how isolated you can feel. Alone to the bone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Oh, but you're a guest. The lucky one." ...The outsider.
"You're part of the team now...but just for a few days!"
There's an emptiness and feeling if being completely lost. Lonely but surrounded by people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sad to say, I have received some presumptuous scrutiny and told I didn't deserve to be there. All taken in with a smile and a held tongue. Regardless of what I had done or achieved, all the time being mindful that this wasn't where I came from. You become very aware of yourself and at times feel like an intruder or unwelcome guest in someone else's house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of that aside, I am EXTREMELY grateful and thankful for every opportunity I have been given this year. I've enjoyed every positive to its utmost. I have learned some very many valuable lessons from the few negatives, both of which I will never forget and am equally grateful for. Looking back I would not change anything at all and would do it all again in a heartbeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13300 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/philth-bw.jpg" alt="philth-bw" width="1080" height="720"&gt; Photo: Jennifer M. Ramos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many things have been reinforced in me.
Every positive is a growing experience and every negative is a learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I Succeed or I Learn. I will never lose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE biggest thing I have learned, more than anything, is: Real TEAMS always prosper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They don't even have to come first. They are always the happiest and have true team spirit. When your team are your friends 1st and your team-mates 2nd. When you see them more off track, and out of practice more than you do on. When you start to see it as a family rather than team. (GateKeepers and St. Louis. You taught me this. And I will never forget, or stop being thankful for it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've felt at light-speed these past few months and I went alone. This truly engraved the
"Go fast, go alone. Go far go together" idea, more than anything ever could. I cannot express enough how important team spirit is in this and how it will always fulfil you more than any score, or win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've learned also to always say "yes".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And "Yes" to the best of my ability when opportunities arise. You will only truly regret what you didn't do, rather than the things you did. The only regret you must accept is that you didn't start sooner, but be grateful you DID start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be truly great at something, you must explore all its ways and options. Not just the good, the easy or the successful ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bad ones must never be forgotten. They are too valuable.
Like a disease we must keep them, study the details and use them to vaccinate us from negativity.
To reflect in the bad experiences is to teach us how to make the good ones greater. For we cannot see how good things can be without seeing things from the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To anyone that already truly knows this idea and is already filled with team spirit, I say: "Go be a satellite player". You will learn so much, so fast and be tested more than you thought you ever could. It's uncomfortable and it's far beyond your comfort zone. Like balancing on a tight rope. Every second, you're thinking about what every tiny twitch might change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You're a hired gun and the pressure to deliver seems overwhelming. They call you an ambassador, which is privilege and pressure in equal crushing measure. But it will always be worth it....every single second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-13296" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/philth-pos.jpg?w=1024" alt="philth-pos" width="1024" height="683"&gt; Photo: Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have grown from this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've become stronger from this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have gained so much practice and from that I have not become perfect.
Instead I feel permanent.
I have permanently sealed my decision to commit to this sport, and it has cured me of my fears and doubts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have learned so much and hope to share what I have learned. Most of all this year has made me Thankful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you Roller Derby. You saved my life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>guest articles</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/22/from-earth-to-orbit-and-back-again/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 15:12:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC2016 - Rankings and Statistics</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/30/mrdwc2016-rankings-and-statistics/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As regular readers know, we've been regularly performing statistical analyses of Roller Derby for 2 years now. One of the first things we did was a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/"&gt;comparison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of the rankings obtained at the 2014 Blood and Thunder World Cup with the inferred actual strengths of the teams present (as determined from the scores they achieved against other teams in the contest). We also performed a similar analysis against the first Men's Roller Derby World Cup, also in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, we noted that MRDWC 2014 did rather better than B&amp;amp;TWC2014, but that it was also much easier to run a tournament with good "true" rankings if you had less teams present. The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cerge-ei.cz/pdf/wp/Wp252.pdf"&gt;more teams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; you have, the more important seeding and tournament structure is in determining how close your final rankings are to the true orderings of team strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; has just completed, and it had rather more competitors than the first one (20, to the original's 15). This time, the teams were arranged in groups, carefully structured so that each group had 1 seed from the Top 4 of the 2014 MRDWC, 1 seed from the remaining Top 8, and the remaining 3 slots with teams from the bottom 7 from MRDC2014, or unseeded teams new to the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seeding system, assuming that teams were roughly ordered in performance similarly to 2014 (and that no unseeded teams were better than the old Top 8) was designed to reduce the probability of poor rankings for teams in the tournament, whilst still allowing for the favoured "group playoffs + single-elimination tournament and consolation tournaments" structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how did they do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although we no longer seriously use frequentist approaches to estimate team strength (as they're not capable of estimating the confidence range of the resulting estimates well, and have well-established deficiencies compared to Bayesian methods for these tasks), we will start with the (frequentist) Massey rankings for the teams, for comparison with the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/"&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
The table below shows Massey rankings (and calculated power) based on both Score Difference and Score Ratio, compared to the MRDWC official tournament placements. For both rankings, we've also calculated the rankings if you remove blowout bouts (defined here as bouts where the winner scored more than 10 times the loser), as blowouts particularly skew Ratio based rankings (as a single extra point scored by the loser can affect the ratio by a significant amount). We have &lt;strong&gt;bolded&lt;/strong&gt; the teams where positions have changed, relative to the Official Ranking.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table style="height:655px;" width="732"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt; All&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt; No Blowouts (10%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MRDWC Official
Ranking&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rank with respect to Score Difference&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rank with respect to Score Ratio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rank with respect to Score Difference&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rank with respect to Score Ratio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;USA&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ENG&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;AUS&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;CAN&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;FRA&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ARG&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;WAL&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;FIN&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;MEX&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;SCO&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;SWE&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;BEL&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;IRE&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;GER&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ITL&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;PR&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;JPN&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;CHI&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ESP&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;NED&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;USA 0.0&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ENG -136&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;AUS -192&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRA&lt;/strong&gt; -276&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;CAN -292&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEX&lt;/strong&gt; -416&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARG&lt;/strong&gt; -418&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WAL&lt;/strong&gt; -435&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FIN&lt;/strong&gt; -454&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;SCO -491&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;SWE -538&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;BEL -544&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;IRE -546&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;GER -618&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ITL -622&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHI&lt;/strong&gt; -624&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;JPN -630&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ESP&lt;/strong&gt; -693&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PR&lt;/strong&gt; -714&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;NED -803&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;USA 1.0&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ENG 0.338&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;AUS 0.194&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;CAN 0.119&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;FRA 0.113&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ARG 0.0554&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;WAL 0.044&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEX&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0382&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FIN&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0325&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;SCO 0.0209&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;IRE 0.0187&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;SWE 0.0183&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;BEL 0.0182&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ITL 0.0132&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;GER 0.0127&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHI&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0092&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PR&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0088&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JPN&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0073&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ESP 0.0060&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;NED 0.0031&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;USA 0.0&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ENG -118&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;AUS -218&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRA&lt;/strong&gt; -266&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;CAN -288&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ARG -409&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEX&lt;/strong&gt; -412&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WAL&lt;/strong&gt; -435&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FIN&lt;/strong&gt; -447&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;SCO -486&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;SWE -532&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;IRE -533&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;BEL -542&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;GER -614&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ITL -617&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHI&lt;/strong&gt; -630&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;JPN -637&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PR&lt;/strong&gt; -683&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ESP -692&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;NED -787&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;USA 1.0&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ENG 0.590&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;AUS 0.286&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;CAN 0.227&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;FRA 0.223&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ARG 0.106&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;WAL 0.0915&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEX&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0869&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FIN&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0800&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;SCO 0.0582&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;IRE 0.0465&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;SWE 0.0429&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;BEL 0.0413&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ITL 0.0306&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;GER 0.0283&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;PR 0.0236&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;JPN 0.0219&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;CHI 0.0194&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ESP 0.0144&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;NED 0.0099&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the previous World Cup article, we've developed the theory of our statistical approaches somewhat, and now use Bayesian inference techniques to estimate the underlying strength of teams. (For example, see our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/08/european-smackdown-the-statistics/"&gt;examination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of the European Smackdown).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the full set of bouts from MRDWC 2016 and performed a Bayesian Monte-Carlo inference on them, to determine the estimated strengths of each team, relative to the top-ranked team, Team USA. As we are using Score Ratio here as our ranking mechanism, we also performed the same inference on the set of bouts with blowouts (&amp;gt;1:10 ratio) removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8505" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/aus_wal_mex_fin_ire_can_ger_chi_itl_eng_arg_esp_sco_bel_fra_pr_jpn_swe_ned-mrdwc2016-all1.png" alt="AUS_WAL_MEX_FIN_IRE_CAN_GER_CHI_ITL_ENG_ARG_ESP_SCO_BEL_FRA_PR_JPN_SWE_NED-MRDWC2016-all" width="2000" height="1100"&gt; Fig 1 - full set of estimated strength distributions, calculated with respect to estimated score ratio against Team USA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8495" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/aus_wal_mex_fin_ire_can_ger_chi_itl_eng_arg_esp_sco_bel_fra_pr_jpn_swe_ned-mrdwc2016-noblowouts.png" alt="AUS_WAL_MEX_FIN_IRE_CAN_GER_CHI_ITL_ENG_ARG_ESP_SCO_BEL_FRA_PR_JPN_SWE_NED-MRDWC2016-noblowouts" width="2000" height="1100"&gt; Fig 2 - full set of estimated strength distributions, calculated with respect to estimated score ratio against Team USA, excluding bouts with blowouts (1:10 ratio)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be easy to see that, whilst removing blowouts does cause some global compression of the distributions (generally making the difference between the USA and everyone else look a bit smaller), there's a general maintenance of the relative features within the two results. The ordering of the results is the same as that for the Massey rankings derived from score ratios, although the precise values differ slightly (by less than 10% in all cases, and mostly less than 2%).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, England, Australia, Canada and France are clearly in a class of their own at the top of the distribution (with England clearly separate from the other 3 as well), and Netherlands are clearly separate at the bottom end.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[gallery ids="8507,8508" type="rectangular"]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fig 3: England and Australia highlighted in the results above.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8514" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/ned-mrdwc2016-noblowouts.png" alt="NED-MRDWC2016-noblowouts" width="2000" height="1100"&gt; Fig 4: Netherlands distribution of score ratios, in the case where blowouts are excluded.
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As can be seen, there are actually relatively few points of disagreement between the MRDWC rankings and the true ordering of team ability. There are even fewer if we eliminate statistically insignificant differences (for example, Sweden, Belgium and Ireland are statistically identical in strength, so any permutation of their ordering is a valid one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8517" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/mex_fin_wal-mrdwc2016-noblowouts.png" alt="MEX_FIN_WAL-MRDWC2016-noblowouts" width="2000" height="1100"&gt; Mexico, Wales, Finland highlighted&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first placement error we see is Mexico. Narrowly missing out on the second group place in Group Green to Wales, the highest rank that Mexico could attain in the tournament stage was 9th, which they happily took. In fact, Mexico's predicted strength is  (narrowly) higher than that of Finland, who placed bottom of the Top 8 teams, qualifying via the second spot in Group Red. This results in a small placement error of just one position, as a result of the tournament structure (and the fact that Mexico is actually stronger than a seeded team). [Mexico does much better when ranked with score difference, as their bout against Canada was particularly low scoring, thanks to exceptional Mexican defence.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, Mexico was originally in Group Red with Finland, only being moved to replace Colombia when they pulled out from the tournament only two weeks before. If they had remained in Group Red, they would likely have taken the second qualifier place, and attained that 8th place (while Finland would have taken 9th). In that instance, however, Scotland would have been significantly unfairly penalised for their group, being unable to attain the 10th place position that they did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8520" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/jpn_chi_pr-mrdwc2016-noblowouts.png" alt="JPN_CHI_PR-MRDWC2016-noblowouts" width="2000" height="1100"&gt; Japan, Puerto Rico, Chile highlighted (no-blowouts case)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further down, the only other significant placement error concerns Puerto Rico, Japan and Chile. Coming 4th in their Group, Puerto Rico qualified for the 13th to 16th place tournament, where they placed 16th. The 5th Group place in their Group, Blue, was taken by Netherlands, the lowest-placed team in the tournament - literally every other team in the tournament was assured at least 4th place in that Group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, Puerto Rico's estimated true strength is statistically equivalent to that of Japan or Chile, who finished last in their group, and therefore were limited to a maximum final placement of 17th. (Complicating matters is that the team with which PR are statistically tied depends on if we include blow-outs or not - including that no-score game against USA pushes Japan's strength low enough that they look worse than Chile and PR, but this is probably unfair to Japan.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming back to the statistically tied teams:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team France will be cheered, perhaps, to note that their estimated strength is statistically inseparable from that of 4th place Team Canada. The France/Canada game was particularly closely contested in the first period, with Canada only managing a convincing win thanks to a much better second. [Indeed, when ranked on Score Difference, France look stronger than Canada, to a low significance, thanks to that low-scoring CAN/MEX game.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8523" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/can_fra-mrdwc2016-noblowouts.png" alt="CAN_FRA-MRDWC2016-noblowouts" width="2000" height="1100"&gt; France, Canada highlighted, showing statistical inseparability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our second set of statistically tied competitors are Sweden, Belgium and Ireland. While Belgium and Sweden played a close game, to Sweden's advantage, on Day 4, Ireland never played the other two - we'd suggest that such bouts would be worth organising!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following them, Germany and Italy are also statistically inseparable, as are Puerto Rico and Chile (mentioned above).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we consider statistically tied teams to have the same rank, then all of this means that our rankings for MRDWC would be (&lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; indicates disagreement with MRDWC, colours that there's a statistical tie with all teams of that colour and MRDWC's result might change if you ran it again):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1. USA
2. ENG
3. AUS
4= &lt;span style="color:#ff00ff;"&gt;CAN&lt;/span&gt;
4= &lt;span style="color:#ff00ff;"&gt;FRA&lt;/span&gt;
6. ARG
7. WAL
8. &lt;strong&gt;MEX&lt;/strong&gt;
9. &lt;strong&gt;FIN&lt;/strong&gt;
10. SCO
11= &lt;span style="color:#3366ff;"&gt;IRE&lt;/span&gt;
11= &lt;span style="color:#3366ff;"&gt;SWE&lt;/span&gt;
11= &lt;span style="color:#3366ff;"&gt;BEL&lt;/span&gt;
14= &lt;span style="color:#993366;"&gt;ITL&lt;/span&gt;
14= &lt;span style="color:#993366;"&gt;GER&lt;/span&gt;
16= &lt;span style="color:#339966;"&gt;PR&lt;/span&gt;
16= &lt;span style="color:#339966;"&gt;JPN&lt;/span&gt;
16= &lt;span style="color:#339966;"&gt;CHI&lt;/span&gt;
19. ESP
20. NED&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Overall, MRDWC 2016 did particularly well for a "Groups+Single-elimination" style tournament of its size, with only ~2 significant placement errors, by only 1 or 2 ranks. Some of this is due to luck in the number of statistically-tied teams, but the construction of the seeded groups was clearly helpful in eliminating large-scale disparities - one of the two placement errors was specifically due to an unexpectedly high rank from an unseeded team. We hope that future tournaments will bear this in mind, if they decide to use a "Groups+Single-elimination" structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This blog still favours &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swiss-system_tournament"&gt;Swiss-system tournaments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, at least in place of Group stages; such a system would have eliminated both placement errors in this case, at the cost of a less easily read schedule on the second half of the first day, and much of the second.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, these analyses are based on code available at our GitHub &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/aoanla/ranking-chain-inference"&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. (Some tweaking of filenames may be needed.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>rankings</category><category>statistics</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/30/mrdwc2016-rankings-and-statistics/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 16:10:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Men's Roller Derby - Team Italy</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/22/mrdwc-2016-team-review-mens-roller-derby-team-italy/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://m.facebook.com/Mens-Roller-Derby-Team-Italy-922338461172325/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Team Italy&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are new to the &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; this year - and enter having played only one bout previously.
&lt;p&gt;In Group Orange, they face the tough seeds of England and Argentina, the slightly more defeatable Sweden, and fellow new team Chile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/wp-image-978261715jpg.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/wp-image-978261715jpg.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-8326 alignnone size-full" width="2000" height="1953"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught up with Italy's Fast &amp;amp; Furio before their first game today to find out how they felt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This is the first time Team Italy has attended MRDWC. What are you aiming for here in this contest?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're not really thinking about the contest because it's our very first time - we had just one bout before this World Cup. So we just want to go home with some good memories, good sharing, and a team spirit that will lead us to future games (maybe with results better than the ones we might get here - because we are going to play against teams that are very strong, very experienced,  so it is not going to be easy to get points, but we will try were we can)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;So how much time have you had to practice together as a team? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been practicing together for about a year; we seen each other once a month from October 2015 up to June this year. We have just one bout and a few scrimmages on top of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;And who are you most looking forward to playing? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've just seen the England [v Sweden] game and there's lots of skaters which inspire me a lot. We just watched Reaper, maybe the best jammer there is, certainly top 3... So, even if we're going to get zero points, we don't really care. You're going to play your heroes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How's Team Italy raised resources for MRDWC 2016?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have just one sponsor - Roll line - that provided us all our uniforms and some other gadgets. We have some partnerships with Officina Roller Derby, there is a shop back in Italy, and then we've been fundraising for donations, working on merchandising (we have t-shirts, wooden bowties...).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Italy's first game was against Chile on Thursday. Their next is against Sweden on Track 1, midday Calgary time Friday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>international derby</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/22/mrdwc-2016-team-review-mens-roller-derby-team-italy/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 03:08:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Seleccion Argentina de Roller Derby Masculino</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/16/mrdwc-2016-team-review-seleccion-argentina-de-roller-derby-masculino/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now heading into the last few teams for our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; profiles, we're in Latin America. Despite the popularity of co-ed roller derby in Latin America, only Argentina sent a team to the last Men's Roller Derby World Cup... and they're back this time, as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/seleccionargentinaRDM/"&gt;Seleccion Argentina de Roller Derby Masculino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time around, despite a very short roster, Argentina performed admirably, taking a 7th place draw with Power of Scotland in the final rankings. They handily defeated both Netherlands and Sweden, and only narrowly lost to Australia's Wizards of Aus in a close final bout. Only England and France defeated them, albeit by the same impressive margins they managed over most contenders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-8261 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/13029406_930304773750095_6815529119385752589_o.jpg" alt="13029406_930304773750095_6815529119385752589_o" width="1000" height="1000"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, Argentina have a larger roster, more experience, and less jet-lag to contend with. In Group Orange, they're a serious contender for the second "promotion spot" for a chance at the top placements - facing England and Sweden from last time, and new teams Italy and Chile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to Argentina to learn about their journey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Seleccion Argentina were the only Latin American team competing in the 2014 MRDWC. How does feel to be returning with so many other Latin teams this time around? [Since this interview started, Colombia dropped out of the WC, sadly]&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels just amazing. Not only because we get to reach a new goal with our new &amp;amp; full team, but also to see how much male derby has grown in Latin America!
&lt;b&gt;This time, your group places you against the mighty England, as well as Chile, Italy, Sweden. Last time around, you ranked much higher than Sweden, and most of the other teams are unknown. What are your aims for the group? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are expecting great difficult games with each team of our group. We know each other very well with our brothers from Chile, and we’re also aware how much they've grown this time to now, and the same for Sweden. We don`t know Italy, that's going to be a surprise of a game... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What teams are you most looking forward to playing (or seeing) at MRDWC this year?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, we are really excited to play against England, such a great and experienced team, it's gonna be a great experience for us. But what we're really looking forward is to see all teams, and every game. We don’t have many chances to play in Argentina, since there are no many leagues yet, and this is the chance to see lot of games, great teams, learn from it, and get to know skaters from all over the world. So the whole tournament is THE experience we´re looking forward to live, and see. 
&lt;b&gt; I know that both Women's and Men's (and Coed) roller derby is very popular in Latin America. Can you tell us how your recruitment worked for the team? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, most of the guys who get in to Roller Derby is because a girl who plays in a team brings him to see, and gets him in touch with the nearest male team. And so it was when the National team was founded. Always supported by our friends, women from Women's Team ARG, who encouraged us to aim higher in the begining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Are you mostly from Argentine teams?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly :P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Argentina has players from ThunderQuads RDM (Bs.As. city), Black Panthers RD (La Plata city, Bs.As.), Contragolpe RDM (Mendoza), Rayo Naranja RD (Tucuman), different Provinces of our country. AND one player from the Philadelphia Hooligans, Penn Jersey Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This year, MRDWC are promoting the lead up to the Cup with the "Road to Calgary" tag. In the spirit of this, what bouts and training have you been doing since the last selection? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, our "Road to Calgary" was full of hard work. Since last selection, we got to work in new try-outs as soon as possible. After that, we set a training schedule. Since most of the players were surrounding Buenos Aires area, we set 2 training day per week, despite the gym work needed. We get to play a few demos to test the improvements, a simple game White vs. Blue. It wasn't 'till our last "goodbye demo", 2 weeks ago, that we got to play against others who aren't of the team, a coed game with the bravest guys and women from the local teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Are you getting a lot of media support (and fans) for Seleccion Argentina in Argentina? How many fans can we expect in the stadium?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, if you take into account that derby is a really new sport around here, which isn&lt;code&gt;t popular at all (think that all media attention is always put on soccer), we could say we've had a lot of support. We&lt;/code&gt;ve worked a lot on public representation, and a few reporters got in touch, and invited us to radio inverviews, or local newspapers notes. That really moved our followers, that the other side, a lot of people, from friends, family, players from all over the country, showed us their support, on crowfunding campaigns, or or getting us in touch with media representatives, potential sponsors, or people they though might help us. Our biggest treasure is the people whom helped us to get here, and that love is the passion we're bringin to the MRDWC. It's a long and expensive ride from Argentina to Canada, even for us, the economy isn&lt;code&gt;t pretty well. But there&lt;/code&gt;s a few friends, crazy friends, traveling with us, so you'll see the light-blue and white among the crowd :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Argentina's first bout is against Chile on Track 2, 6pm UK time (11am Calgary)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Seleccion Argentina Roster is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="page" title="Page 24"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08&lt;/strong&gt; Pibe
&lt;strong&gt;087&lt;/strong&gt; Leandro, Oscares
&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; Sebastian, Castillo
&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; Mauro, Cruz
&lt;strong&gt;1618&lt;/strong&gt; Mingo
&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; Mr. Borderline
&lt;strong&gt;1753&lt;/strong&gt; Triske
&lt;strong&gt;1826&lt;/strong&gt; Itu Napolitanga
&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; Facundo Bentos
&lt;strong&gt;21&lt;/strong&gt;  Heavy Dolche
&lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt;  Pablo, Esquivel
&lt;strong&gt;235&lt;/strong&gt; Luke
&lt;span style="line-height:1.7;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28&lt;/strong&gt; Jose Augusto, Sanchez
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; Victor, Diaz
&lt;strong&gt;314&lt;/strong&gt; The Crow
&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Nicolas, Bergallo
&lt;strong&gt;44&lt;/strong&gt; Hector, Porro
&lt;strong&gt;666&lt;/strong&gt; Luis, Llorente
&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; Black Shadow
&lt;strong&gt;930&lt;/strong&gt; Rafael, Guevara
&lt;strong&gt;99&lt;/strong&gt; Gregorio, Donnet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bench&lt;/strong&gt; Maisa, Barbosa
&lt;strong&gt;Coach&lt;/strong&gt; Daiana, Sismael
&lt;strong&gt;Jammer Assist.&lt;/strong&gt; Jillian, Vidal
&lt;strong&gt;Stuff Assist.&lt;/strong&gt; Ana, Sylvia Anabel Chasampi
&lt;strong&gt;Staff&lt;/strong&gt; Elena T.F.
&lt;strong&gt;Staff&lt;/strong&gt; INI
&lt;strong&gt;Staff&lt;/strong&gt; Turbonegra&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentina</category><category>articles</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/16/mrdwc-2016-team-review-seleccion-argentina-de-roller-derby-masculino/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC Team Review: Team Chile Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/12/mrdwc-team-review-team-chile-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Completing our set of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; team profiles, we're covering the newest team from Latin America, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamChileRDM/"&gt;Team Chile Roller Derby Masculino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chile are in group Orange, facing England, Italy, Sweden and fellow Latin Americans Argentina. With England almost certain to take the top spot in the group, Chile will be in a difficult spot to take the other promotion slot, as only Italy is as inexperienced as they are. The Latin America match up between Argentina and Chile should also be fascinating to watch...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-8244 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/11051780_1459842104328566_1210320533841469507_n.jpg" alt="11051780_1459842104328566_1210320533841469507_n" width="720" height="705"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to Team Chile's Marmota at the team warmup in Calgary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Firstly, how does it feel representing Chile, as they attend the Men's World Cup for the first time?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, as Chile, and speaking f0r my teammates, I want to say that this is really an honour. Because this sport, especially in my country, is really really new - most of us have been playing roller derby for 2, 3 years at most. So we're a new team, and we're not playing the modern, modern roller derby where graces and new formations are used. So, I don't know - we're used to playing the walls, like all roller derby used to be played. We're used to playing the defensive game, this is mostly our strategy. So, then, we're trying to play a it little faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's an honour, and it was really hard, because each and every one of us had to pay for their ticket, their accommodation. The only thing we got [in sponsorship] from a Chilean company was the uniform. And this is really bad. But I think it's a mixed work - if we don't move, then who is going to move? But, we don't get much attention - we hope that for the next World Cup we will be bigger! I hope!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So that happened to Women's Team Mexico in 2011:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happened to the Women's Chilean team in 2014 too! But women seem more persuasive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who are you most looking forward to playing here?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Argentina!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ah, yes, you're both in the same group. Are you confident?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not a confident player now - my team is really more confident than I, because I expect to pay more attention for the first jams, and then decide how I feel after that. &lt;em&gt;But&lt;/em&gt;, we know them - most of our team have played the Argentine team, which is basically the ThunderQuads. My team, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ComplotDerbyClub"&gt;Complot&lt;/a&gt;, was in the first &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/64046"&gt;Torneo HARD&lt;/a&gt; [hosted by ThunderQuads] Tournament, and we came in second. So, we know how they play - and I don't know if they know how we play. I don't know if they've done their homework! [Our relative obscurity] is our one advantage - Argentina are strong, and they're bigger than us, I don't know if you saw some of the players! And they're really really fast - we have to pay a lot of attention to their lines and their offense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that game, that game I want to play right now! The other teams, we don't know - we watched them in the last World Cup on the streams, but Argentina is our neighbouring country, so the rivalry is there! Like Scotland/Ireland or Canada/USA!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you hope to get out of the World Cup, what are you aiming for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, personally, first: I am aiming to get to know as many people as we can. I think the only way the sport is going to grow and become stronger is if we all team up, and all team up together with the other team, and we work together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I think we are wanting, as a team, to develop our play more together. Because, Chile is a long country - it was really hard for all of the guys to get together for even one training a month. We don't have the advantage of some teams which just get to play together all the time...
Team Chile's first bout is against Argentina on Track 2 at &lt;strong&gt;6pm&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;UK time&lt;/em&gt; (11am Calgary)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Team Chile Roster is:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;1080&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Hijoeperra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;111&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Waffen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Kiltro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Memeiro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;27&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Viruta Thunder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Vieja&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Petit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Mr. Sokram&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;416&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Capitán Basuritas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Aquilez&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;7018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Kamikaze&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;77&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Manquelipe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Cy8org (Cyborg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;8000&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Mecánico&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;88&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Toro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;95&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Zakumi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;969&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Rocka&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;99&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Marmota&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;m30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Picóta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;s66&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Insane&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Bench Coach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Pony Tolueno&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Bench Manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="column"&gt;Loca Zeppelin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>chile</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/12/mrdwc-team-review-team-chile-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 07:22:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Team Finland</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/11/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-finland/</link><dc:creator>oneknownashaze</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our round up of the MRDWC teams continues with Team Finland! Here they tell us all about how they have prepared for Calgary and their thoughts going in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-8214 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/finland.jpg?w=300" alt="finland" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Answers from:
Menstruella - TFMRD head coach 2016
Domino F. Äkt - TFMRD head coach 2014
MIika Karttunen - TFMRD skater 2014-2016&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Questions:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;-How did your selection process for this year's World Cup differ from the 2014 selection? Did you find there were different factors you were looking for in skaters?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Dominå F. Äkt:
Since we didn’t have that much men’s roller derby activity in Finland, the first 2014 try outs were more of a minimum skills test assessing if we even had enough skaters to form a team. At the first try outs session, there was max 12 skaters and only one player that knew how to plough stop. We had to have multiple try out sessions for new skaters that had joined Tampere Rollin’ Bros (first men’s league in Finland, established 2013) after the first try outs, and by the World Cup in March 2014 we had a solid charter of almost 20 skaters and we did really well placing as number 9 in the world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Menstruella:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;All in all the level of individuals and teams has gone forward, but the numbers of participants haven’t gone up much, and while we now have new and dedicated players, many skaters from 2014 have stopped playing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;This time we encouraged everyone eligible to sign up and accepted all applicants in the training squad. The first training consisted of physical (off skates), skating skills and gameplay evaluations. The idea being to assess where were individuals at and what we needed to work on as a group. We started with about 25-30 applicants, some of them joining a few months into training. The levels ranged between non completed minimum skills to advanced players. Men’s Roller Derby in Finland is still very much in its beginning with only two teams, and only one, Tampere Rollin’ Bros, has played games so far. In February we selected our 20 players squad, and two of the main things we looked for and that made the difference between people were availability to attend upcoming trainings and motivation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;-At the last MRDWC you came a solid 9th which placed you the 5th highest European country which is definitely something to be proud of! What did you learn from the 2014 world cup?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Miika:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;As were said before we didn’t really have to qualify and drop people but the selection process was more like “do we even have 20 people that can afford to travel?”. Almost everyone had at least some kind of background in ice hockey so we knew how to skate but playing derby was a whole different thing. I went to the MRDWC really unsure since I had only played one small tournament against men’s teams before in Malmö, Sweden.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;I learned from my first MRDWC experience that a lot had to be done but we were on a good starting platform.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;-Compared to the last MRDWC you have a lot further to travel than before. How has the team been fundraising for the trip to Canada? Any unusual ways you have used to gain support?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Miika:
I’m also a photographer so I made a seminude calendar for our fundraiser which turned out really great. All 200 calendars sold out but you can still order postcards from those photos from our GoFundMe account that we are using to sell merch and get more funds to travel to Calgary.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gofundme.com/TFMRDtoCalgary2016" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#0068cf;"&gt;www.gofundme.com/TFMRDtoCalgary2016&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;-How are you finding your team training in the run up to the World Cup? With only a few months left how is that affecting your training schedule?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Menstruella:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;We have been training every month or month and half since March 2015, and the only thing different in 2016 is that all of our practices are full weekends, where before we alternated full weekends with single days. We’re now focusing mainly on building cohesion and teamwork in our line-ups and pairs, as well as fine tuning a few things. We’ve been scrimmaging regularly against Kallio Rolling Rainbow and Helsinki Roller Derby, they’ve been really supportive and we’re honoured to train against such strong opponents.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;-You have a pretty mixed group this year with the number one seed from 2014 (USA) being in the mix as well as the last placed seed (Japan). Is there anyone you are really excited to play against in your group?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Menstruella:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;I think it’s safe to say we’re keen to take on Ireland again! We won against them in 2014 but lost last summer by a few points in a rematch, so we’re really excited to face them again, they’re a great bunch. We’re also looking forward to play USA, we’re thrilled at the chance to go against the best in the world. We’re really happy with our group and looking forward to play all of those teams, we’re sure they’ll all bring interesting challenges and we’re ready to take on them!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;-Do you have any specific aims for Calgary that you are willing to share with us? (We're okay if there is any closely guarded secrets you don't want to give up yet!)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Menstruella:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;We want to show that Finland is up and coming! Despite lacking the means in term of weekly trainings or game opportunities, our players are skilled and work hard, they’re smart and have been building a real team in this past year. I’m extremely proud of how long they’ve come as individuals and as team, their constant progress keeps humbling me and they’re a joy to coach and work with. We’re gonna bring our best game and make the best out of this experience, and we’re sure we’ll learn a lot about ourselves as well. We’re hoping the tournament will boost motivation and interest to help men’s roller derby develop in Finland. We’re really stoked about this event and can’t wait to meet new and old friends!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8213" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/finland-roster.jpg" alt="finland roster" width="679" height="960"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Finland's first fixture will be against Ireland at 13:00 local time. For the full MRDWC schedule visit: http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/11/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-finland/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 09:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Team Mexico</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/08/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-mexico/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As one of six teams new to the Men's Roller Derby World Cup, Team Mexico are something of an unknown quantity.  When the first MRDWC was held, the sport was still growing in Mexico, but now they're heading to Calgary and the Red Group, alongside Finland, Ireland, Japan, Scotland and defending champions USA. [After this article was written, Colombia dropped out of MRDWC 2016, and Mexico was moved to Group Green to even out the groups. They now face Canada, Spain, Germany and Wales.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corina Fischer told us more about bringing together the team, and its aims for the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-8087 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/mexico-logo.png" alt="Mexico logo" width="454" height="454"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*Team Mexico will make their debut at the Men's World Cup.  What are your aims in the tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of all, we want to let the world know about the talent we have in our country, we look forward to sharing the track with all the amazing teams that are attending such an important event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*You are in the largest group in the tournament, which also includes defending champions Team USA and last time's fan favourites NinJapan.  Which teams are you most looking forward to playing?  If you have time, who are you most looking forward to watching play?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Playing Team USA is a pleasure that not everyone has, so we are really looking forward to playing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*What's the level of interest in roller derby in Mexico?  How did you go about recruiting and selecting the team for the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's several men's roller derby teams in Mexico, so getting skaters interested in trying out for Team Mexico wasn't an issue.  We did two tryout dates, both with good attendance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*What have you been doing in terms of fundraising and preparation for the trip to Calgary?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a GoFundMe campaign, we've been selling merch, and of course we have been able to reach our goals with the support of our sponsors Mota Skates en Espanol, S1 Helmets, DerbySkinz, Latin Roller and Roller Rey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*This year, MRDWC are promoting the lead up to the Cup with the "Road to Calgary" tag.  In the spirit of this, what bouts and training have you been doing in preparation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've had scrimmages all year, along with a preparation game against the MRDA 3rd place team, Texas Men's Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*After the last World Cup, several national saw increased awareness and interest in roller derby. What are your hopes for the sport in Mexico?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a growing sport, the feeling of community is what makes it greater.  And now with our participation in the MRDWC 2016 more men will want to try this amazing sport.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Team Mexico's first game is against Japan - at 12 noon Calgary time - on Thursday on Track 1, followed by Ireland at 5pm on Track 2. The official MRDWC schedule is located &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  More information on Team Mexico can be found &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamMexicoMensRollerDerby/?fref=ts"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. [Due to schedule changes, Mexico now face Wales on Track 1 (9am) followed by Canada on Track 2 at 1pm.]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/08/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-mexico/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 09:51:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Team Canada</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/06/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-canada/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Birmingham in 2014, Team Canada produced a strong performance, losing only once, to Team USA in the semi-final, to finish in third place.  On home soil in Calgary, placed in the Green group alongside Colombia, Spain, Germany and Wales, can they go one step better this time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain Jeff Tichbourne shared his thoughts on Team Canada's preparation and aims for the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-8119 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/canada-logo.jpg" alt="Canada logo" width="358" height="358"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Canada will be fielding a strong team for the World Cup. How did you go about recruitment and selection this time?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Much like in 2014 we held open tryouts in the 3 areas with the largest concentration of players across Canada. Montreal, Red Deer and Vancouver were the 3 cities we held tryouts. Our Head Coach, Lime, was at all 3 tryouts so he got to have eyes on all the people trying out. Selection of our long list was done by the coaching staff and the short list was the same but with input from the players voted as captains by the team.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last time, Team Canada played very strongly, recording some big wins and finishing in third place. Two years later, what are your aims for the tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;We want to be in the Gold Medal game.  We have many smaller goals but they all lead to that one bigger goal, and we've got our eye on the prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your group features two returning teams (Wales and Germany) and two new to the tournament (Spain and Colombia). Which nations are you most looking forward to playing?  If you have time between games, who are you most looking forward to watching play?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We had a very physical game last World Cup versus Wales and we look forward to that again. The other 3 teams in our pool we haven't faced yet but we expect different styles from each of them so that's always exciting. If things work out the way we predict then the team we're most looking forward to playing is England. Between games expect to see us studying our next opponents.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last time around, you made the trip to England to compete.  How does it feel to be the host nation this year?  How has this affected your preparations?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We're thrilled to host so many players, officials, volunteers and fans from around the world. We really want to show them why Canada is known for its hospitality. Our preparation has been more thorough this time around and everyone is working harder than ever. We've got our nation behind us and that driving force will be with us for the whole tournament.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*This year, MRDWC are promoting the lead up to the Cup with the "Road to Calgary" tag. In the spirit of this, what bouts and training have you been doing since the last selection?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Training sessions have been happening across Canada with many players racking up air miles between cities just for the chance to skate together for a few hours.  We've had numerous high level WFTDA teams play our squad in preparation for the World Cup.  Being such a large country and not having access to each other all the time, we've used a lot of video sharing with our coaches for feedback and tips.  Our team will arrive early in Calgary to get as much skate time in as possible before the big event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Team Canada open the tournament by facing Germany at 9am - Calgary time - on Thursday on Track 1, followed by Colombia at 1pm on Track 2.  The official MRDWC schedule is located &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  More information on Team Canada can be found &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamCanadaMensRollerDerby/?fref=ts"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Arial;"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-8120 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/canada-roster.png" alt="Canada roster" width="386" height="484"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/06/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-canada/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 09:06:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Team USA</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/04/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-usa/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving across the Atlantic as we continue our look at MRDWC contenders, next up is a team that needs no introduction: Team USA.  The defending champions from 2014's inaugural MRDWC, will we see a repeat of this feat in Calgary?  Team USA have been placed in the Red group, alongside Finland, Japan, Mexico, and of particular interest, Ireland and Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spoke to Tony Muse, AKA Peter Pan, about the team's preparation and objectives for the tournament.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="rmTop t_mbgc"&gt; &lt;img class="wp-image-7932 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/usalogo.jpg" alt="USAlogo" width="334" height="333"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ReadMessageScrollableSection" class="rmMessages ClearBoth"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="rmSubject"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="rmButtons"&gt;&lt;span class="rmPrev"&gt;&lt;img class="i_rm_p" src="https://dub113.mail.live.com/ol/clear.gif"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; The Team USA selection is, as expected, very strong. How did you approach recruiting and selecting the team?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
For the selection of Team USA, we wanted to give as many skaters the opportunity to try out and be noticed as we possibly could. We held two separate try outs, one in Des Moines Iowa, home of Your Mom Men's Derby and a second in Deland Florida, home of the Magic City Misfits. There was no recruiting as everyone was invited and given the opportunity to show their skills against other top level skaters. After multiple rounds of blind voting from coaches and managers, the final squad was selected.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As defending champions from the first MRDWC, what are your aims in performance this World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Coming in to the second World Cup and as defending champions, we know we will have a large target on our team. Some of the players on Team USA are returning and others will be playing for their country for the first time. We think the passion that some of the new players will bring mixed with some of the experience some of the veterans will bring will be the perfect blend to keep us in the right frame of mind. As elite players, we are all looking to play the "perfect" game so every time we gather to play with such high level teammates, we aim for perfection.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your group features several European teams, plus one of the last World Cup’s fan favourites Japan and debutants Mexico - what teams are you most looking forward to playing? If you have time between games, who are you most looking forward to watching play?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We get excited about playing teams from all over the world because the teams tend to all skate a bit different and somewhat take on their own unique temperament. At the last World Cup, some of the fans were as excited to be at the event as the players so it added even an additional level of energy to the game with particular teams. We think the teams from Japan and Argentina will continue to be fan favorites but I imagine we may have new teams like the Italian or Mexican  squads stealing hearts this time around. The home team from Canada should be strong and well supported and of course England as the previous World Cup runner's up will be a solid squad to play against. We really look forward to the entire event both playing and watching as the World Cup can't be compared or matched to any other tournament in the sport.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The tournament is a lot closer for you this time around; how have you been fundraising and preparing for the trip?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Because the World Cup is so much closer this year, I think many members of the USA team will be bringing over more family, friends and support. Although Canada is right above us, many of the team members have not had the opportunity to travel much in Canada so the event is a great reason to do so. The team has been working with sponsors to help with some expenses but many of the fund raising ventures for Team USA have not started as we still have one big team camp before the event.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*This year, MRDWC are promoting the lead up to the Cup with the "Road to Calgary" tag. In the spirit of this, what bouts and training have you been doing since the last selection?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
For our "Road to Calgary", Team USA has yet to compete against any other squad. That will all change soon as in mid May Team USA will be playing an exhibition bout against the reigning MRDA champions the St Louis Gatekeepers. This event will be accompanied by a training camp for the team.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Team USA's first game is against Scotland - at 11am Calgary time - on Thursday on Track 1, followed by Japan at 3pm on Track 2. The official MRDWC schedule is located &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  More information on Team USA can be found &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamusamensrollerderby/?fref=ts"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-7933 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/usaroster.jpg" alt="USAroster" width="960" height="960"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/04/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-usa/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 10:47:40 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>