<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about new town roller girls)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/new-town-roller-girls.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Mean City face the Lothians, twice, 16th June.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/13/mean-city-face-the-lothians-twice-16th-june/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend, there's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/153012025545908/"&gt;yet more Roller Derby action&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Glasgow, as Mean City Roller Derby, the city's open gender league, takes on two opponents at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Livingston + West Lothian's New Town Roller Girls, who have been pretty busy this year already, travelling up to Inverness to play ICRD in April. NTRG have been building up to this next bout with an open scrimmage against The World last month, and with one of their skaters having visited Rimini, Italy's Stray Beez in the last month, we assume that New Town will be buzzing with confidence on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NTRG will be taking on Mean City's WFTDA-gender-policy team ("Mean City Women"). The Mean City team have had a quieter year, last facing Lothian Derby Dolls towards the end of 2017, so it will be interesting to see how things have changed on track in the past 6 months...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flat Track Stats &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/101836"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;predicts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a close game, with the median result being a 19:21 points ratio in favour of the home team; with scores that close, however, it could be just a single power jam which decides the result!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second game, Fear &amp;amp; Lothian, the Midlothian-based open gender team, will face Mean City's open gender team. Fear &amp;amp; Lothian have had a less busy year to date than NTRG, with their last game in November 2017. Since then, however, the team have been holding regular scrims with their WFTDA-gender colleagues in Lothian Derby Dolls, and have undergone a round of recruitment. We may even see some new faces on track this Saturday!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City's Open Gender team have regularly faced F&amp;amp;L - one of the limitations of open gender derby is still the paucity of opponents - and the two teams know each other well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City overall has also had a new intake at the start of the year - and there's some changes in both rosters, to judge from their series of roster photos being run over on their Facebook page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26849 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/mcrdvflvntrd.jpg" alt="MCRDvFLvNTRD" width="1080" height="1080"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City President, Gord'n'Thorg told us:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Glasgow's first - and meanest - Open To All Roller Derby league return to The Arc at Glasgow Caledonian University this Saturday 16th of June.  After a false start ("yielding!") earlier in the year; we're getting back to the track with a Double Header against two of our friendly, neighbouring leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We start with a WFTDA-flavoured face-off between the home side and Livingston's New Town Roller Girls.  Members of both teams have had a tasty sample of each other at a few recent scrims.  We're looking forward to getting a proper look at each other across league lines.  I don't think anyone would be adverse to the idea of another semi-local rivalry getting up and rolling...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the subject of rivalries; we're following this with open-gender action, as Fear and Lothian array themselves against us once again.  Our contests have been fierce in the past, and we'll be looking for more of the same as we field some new faces against familiar foes...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can't believe that all of this can be yours and only lighten your purse by £5.00, we'll also be giving you your first chance to lay hands on our latest batch of Mean City Merchandise.  You'll wonder how you've managed without it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to seeing everyone there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, weather permitting..."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see both games on the &lt;strong&gt;16th June&lt;/strong&gt;, from &lt;strong&gt;12:15&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/zaDvW85FqFF2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in Glasgow Caledonian University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="auto"&gt;Tickets: &lt;strong&gt;£5.00&lt;/strong&gt;. Under-14s free when accompanied by a paying adult.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>articles</category><category>fear &amp; lothian</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/13/mean-city-face-the-lothians-twice-16th-june/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 15:00:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Who Are We? NTRG!: New Town's thoughts on their upcoming game in Inverness.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/15/who-are-we-ntrg-new-towns-thoughts-on-their-upcoming-game-in-inverness/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our game against Inverness City Roller Derby is less than a week away for us at NTRG and we’re eager to share our thoughts on it with you! 4 of our skating team have answered what they are most looking forward to; what they’ve been doing outside of training to prep for the game and who they think will win!
Storm in a D Cup, Millie Manslaughter, Mother Tucker and Hazzard are here to share their pre game insights with you all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storm in a D Cup 69
&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-26609" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/storminad.jpg?w=450" alt="StormInAD" width="225" height="300"&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing I am looking forward to most about game day is that feeling of team comraderie. The sick, excited and nervous butterflies-in-your-stomach feeling as we all pile into the bus or car. How we will all send a million messages to our team mates sharing experiences, offering support and motivation.  I am not someone who has ever been involved in sport. I now look back with a bit of regret that I did not do something like this when I was younger. I feel grateful for finding something that I am proud of, for finding all these amazing women who are completely different, but for one day the same. We are all trying our best to succeed, support and survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is my biggest challenge in most things. Full time work, family and trying to maintain a reasonable quality of life leaves me spread a bit thin. When it comes preparing for an upcoming game I find I absorb myself in You Tube videos for hints and tips, watch games on my phone during my commute, and practise in the kitchen while doing laundry and the dishes. I am lucky that my kids love skating, helping them and playing skatey games not only improves my skills but keeps me calm, it always reminds me that I am doing this for fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one thing I have discovered is that it’s not important who wins. After past games it is the last thing we talk about. We laugh and joke, while comparing bumps and bruises. We learn and grow from our experience playing with other teams. We become better players. I know we all will try our best, and if we lose we will still hold our heads high and celebrate with the victors without fear of being judged as inferior.  Just as I know we won’t judge them….when we kick their butts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Millie Manslaughter 5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-26610" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/millemanslaughter.jpg?w=450" alt="MilleManslaughter" width="225" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am looking forward to seeing how well the team comes together because we have been working and training hard so it will be great to see if our hard work has payed off or not. It will also be nice for the team to spend some time together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently bought a pushbike. I’m loving going out , having the wind in my face and the freedom of just pedalling with no end goal. I have also started doing the 5k parkrun on a saturday morning. It's so much more fun than a treadmill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentally I made myself a list of goals for this game at the beginning of march and I think about them each training. I have also been watching more derby online so that I canlearn more and improve my gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure who will win but I can predict it will be exciting!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch out Inverness, Millie Manslaughter's coming for you!! 😀😀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;whoarewe #NTRG&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mother Tucker 79&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-26611" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/mothertucker.jpg?w=450" alt="MotherTucker" width="225" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pre-match build up: Skating out with the team before the game - it’s great to go out and hear everyone cheering your team.  When your name’s announced, you feel all special for a moment or two, then you cheer all the other team members! Also, huddling round just and doing our chant is pretty awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try not to overthink games!  From a physical training point of view, I went along to a GMRD session recently which was a real eye-opener.  Their level of gameplay is so fast and tactical and I learned so much in just a couple of hours. I followed that up by playing in an ARRG event last week which was brilliant.  It gave me a chance to practice some of the things we’ve been working on at our team training sessions and I played really well and came out of it feeling amazing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it’ll be a good game to watch and if we can communicate well and put into practice what we’ve been focusing on at training, then I reckon NTRG will win!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hazzard 810&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-26612" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/hazzard.jpg?w=450" alt="Hazzard" width="225" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m very much looking forward to playing with the team! It’s the first time we’ve been able to train for and play games consistently within a short period of time and it’s a great bonding experience not just for the skating team but for the entire league as well! We have a host of supporters coming up for Inverness so it’s gonna be NTRG tastic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been hitting the gym a lot lately as I have some personal derby goals that I’m wanting to achieve which require me to up both my mental and physical derby game. For the mental side I’ve been watching tons of games online and just drilling derby in to my head even more so than it already is! It’s definitely helping me reach new derby heights and as Inverness is now just round the corner I’m eager to see if all the hard work has been paying off!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that it’s us but I think it’s going to be closely matched either way! We seem very similar to ICRD in the array of experience in our skating teams and that’s bound to make for a super exciting game between us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-
Inverness City Roller Derby host New Town Roller Girls as the first bout in their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/193321784726887/"&gt;double header &lt;/a&gt;21st April 2018&lt;/strong&gt;. (The second bout sees Team EPIC play Team Black.)
Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;12:30&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/15/who-are-we-ntrg-new-towns-thoughts-on-their-upcoming-game-in-inverness/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 10:22:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Skaters on track for New Town Cherry Popper</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/09/new-skaters-on-track-for-new-town-cherry-popper/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;March 19th&lt;/strong&gt; sees the Livingston area's &lt;strong&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; host a one of roller derby's traditions - a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1048868645164481/"&gt;cherry popper bout&lt;/a&gt;, showcasing new skaters from a mix of leagues. The bout will be held in New Town's current bouting venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/DSZTrnU8cYo"&gt;Blackburn Community Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6395" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/412387_204493976333497_2093997456_o.jpg?w=600" alt="412387_204493976333497_2093997456_o" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skaters from Auld Reekie Roller Girls, Bairn City Rollers, Lothian Derby Dolls, Doonhame Derby Dolls, Ayrshire Roller Derby, Fair City Rollers and Preston Roller Girls will join host New Town's own new skaters on track in two exhibition teams: The Morello Mashers (skating in hot pink) and the Women of Mass Destruction (skating in sapphire).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an ideal opportunity to see the potential of new roller derby skaters as they play their first bout in public. It's particularly exciting to see skaters from some of Scotland's leagues who are not publicly bouting yet, as this is a preview of perhaps what we might expect from Ayrshire, Doonhame and Fair City when they enter public bouts as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a slightly later game than we normally have in Scotland, with doors opening at &lt;strong&gt;4:45pm&lt;/strong&gt;, for a 5:15pm start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are available online from &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2521813"&gt;brownpapertickets&lt;/a&gt; for just &lt;strong&gt;£4&lt;/strong&gt;. Under 14s are free. Tickets will also be available on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>cherry poppers</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/09/new-skaters-on-track-for-new-town-cherry-popper/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 21:19:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Start Derby in the New Year</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/03/start-derby-in-the-new-year/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a New Year, and one resolution that you might have made is to Try Roller Derby. Certainly, many leagues across the country traditionally run a fresh meat recruitment in January or early February just to take advantage of any newly enthused skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, there's a good distribution of Fresh Meat sessions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, and a bit urgent for those who want to be involved - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/750196985110434/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are holding their Fresh Meat session on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 10th January&lt;/strong&gt; - just a week away! You'll need your own skates and pads to take part, and of course GRD recommend &lt;a href="http://www.5thblockerskates.co.uk/"&gt;5th Blocker Skates&lt;/a&gt; to get you the right kit. The initial signup session will be held at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Glasgow-Club-Drumoyne/190810237616343"&gt;Glasgow Club Drumoyne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;and entry is free for the first session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up in time, Edinburgh's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1652424528374019/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are holding their Fresh Meat session a week later on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday 17th January&lt;/strong&gt;. You only need to a mouthguard to attend their session, for hygiene reasons; ARRG will supply kit for the initial tryout session. The initial sesson, and all subsequent training is at the&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Jack-Kane-Sports-Centre/152896351412178"&gt; Jack Kane Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and entry to the initial session is just £5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elgin's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/168691136822816/"&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are holding a "learn to skate" session, co-hosted with Aberdeen's Granite City Roller Derby, on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 30th January&lt;/strong&gt;. As with ARRG, you'll need to bring a mouthguard, but other kit will be provided. The session will be held at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Elgin-Community-Centre/286953997983978"&gt;Elgin Community Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and entry is free. This is a &lt;em&gt;co-ed&lt;/em&gt; session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Livingston's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/636910396412245/"&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; have an extensive array of taster and meetup sessions across January and February. There's a chance to &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/551015165051330/"&gt;Meet The Skaters&lt;/a&gt; in a pub setting on &lt;strong&gt;Friday January 22nd&lt;/strong&gt;, in the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Wetherspoons/105356126214627"&gt;Wetherspoons&lt;/a&gt; in the Almondvale Centre . The actual taster session for would-be-skaters is on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday February 6th&lt;/strong&gt;, in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Blackburn-Community-Centre/298761240230260"&gt;Blackburn Community Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. NTRG request that attendees message them before the event to allow arrangements to be made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the North, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1732447053650457/"&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are holding a fresh meat/beginners session on &lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 3rd February&lt;/strong&gt;. Again, you'll need to bring a mouthguard, but some kit will be available (although you're advised to contact ICRD ahead of time with your shoe size). The initial session will be at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Hilton-Community-Centre-918990224784740/"&gt;Hilton Community Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;; we have no information in entry fees, but the session is &lt;em&gt;co-ed,&lt;/em&gt; as with Helgin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for guys who want to play Derby in the Aberdeen area, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1708084226107265/"&gt;Granite City Brawlermen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are holding their intake on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 6th February&lt;/strong&gt;. You'll probably want to bring a mouthguard, but if you contact GCB ahead of time, they can arrange a loan of the rest of the kit. The session will be held at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Aberdeen-Lads-Club-209093469130951/"&gt;Aberdeen Lads Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, there is no information on entry fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also know that several other leagues are planning intakes in the next few months; we'll keep you informed as and when those are announced!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>new town roller girls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/03/start-derby-in-the-new-year/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 10:26:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hallowe'en Extravaganza in Scotland</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/10/27/halloween-extravaganza-in-scotland/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Roller Derby community always enjoys a chance to add celebration to events, and Hallowe'en is a perennially popular time to indulge in a little theming of bouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/10/12074713_912348732167339_836768493785601939_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4930 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/10/12074713_912348732167339_836768493785601939_n.jpg" alt="12074713_912348732167339_836768493785601939_n" width="660" height="244"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, it's no surprise that &lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; are continuing their tradition of a Hallowe'en bout with a fancy-dress competition as part of their Saturday double-header. The sporting component will also be exciting, with &lt;a href="http://tampererollerderby.com/en/"&gt;Tampere Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; travelling across from Finland to face Glasgow's Maiden Grrders, and &lt;a href="http://lothianderbydolls.com/"&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; taking on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/NewTownRollerGirls"&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; in the opener.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event starts at 12:30pm Saturday, at the ARC Sports Centre, Glasgow Caledonian University. The eventbrite tickets page is: &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/glasgow-roller-derby-maiden-grrders-vs-tampere-roller-derby-ldd-vs-ntrg-registration-19060101276"&gt;https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/glasgow-roller-derby-maiden-grrders-vs-tampere-roller-derby-ldd-vs-ntrg-registration-19060101276
&lt;/a&gt;The Facebook events page is: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1093676273994184/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1093676273994184/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/wpid-wp-1442925115960.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4917" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/wpid-wp-1442925115960.jpg?w=660" alt="wpid-wp-1442925115960.jpg" width="660" height="244"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Meanwhile, up in Dundee, &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' Home Season continues, with the Jammin' Dodgers playing the Press Gangsters. Excitingly, the event will be a double-header, with Scotland's National Men's Derby team, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland"&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/a&gt;, engaging in a selection bout between the 30 training team members for the current squad. Not only will this bout feature the best of Scottish Men's Derby, but it will also feed into the final 20 Power of Scotland members to make up the National Squad going into the next Men's Roller Derby World Cup in Calgary 2016.
&lt;p&gt;The event starts at 12:30pm Saturday, at the Dundee International Sports Centre, Mains Loan. Tickets available from Brown Paper Tickets: &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2155922"&gt;http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2155922&lt;/a&gt;
The Facebook events page is: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/739368379522055/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/739368379522055/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/10/27/halloween-extravaganza-in-scotland/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 11:50:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Town Roller Girls - Round up of 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/19/new-town-roller-girls-round-up-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>oneknownashaze</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year one of our newly mins passed skaters interviews one of our long time skaters who is on the clutch of finishing off her own mins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introductions! Who are you?
&lt;/strong&gt;I’m Alison aka Woolly Thumper and I’ll have been with NTRG for 2 years in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What made you join roller derby and how long have you been playing?
&lt;/strong&gt;I was introduced to derby by my boss whose girlfriend was going through fresh meat with ARRG. He showed me some videos; I went to watch a couple of bouts and was hooked. I had a taster session with ARRG but their training venues and times didn’t work for me so derby went on the back burner until about a year later when I found out about NTRG. I met the team at a getting-to-know you night in the pub and strapped on a pair of skates the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What has NTRG been up to so far this year? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we have been working on running our fresh meat program in a more formal, organised way which has been very effective and the impact can be seen in the amazing progress our freshies have made. Although we haven't really bouted as a league, our skaters have been bouting as guests for other leagues, in charity bouts and mixed teams and the whole league has benefited from what they have learned. We also took part in the Sur5ors tournament in October which was an amazing experience. We really enjoyed skating against some much more experienced skaters and I think we represented ourselves well. We have had a lot of support from skaters from other leagues, Mean City and Dundee especially, giving up their time to help coach us. We have learned loads and are so grateful, hopefully next year we will be able to pay it forward to other leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What have been the highlights for the team &amp;amp; your own personal highlights?
&lt;/strong&gt;Highlights for the team would probably have to be Sur5ors and the great crop of new skaters we have coming through. I am making my way slowly through my mins so every extra lap on my 27/5 and every new skill nailed or fear faced is a highlight for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are this year's fresh meat shaping up?
&lt;/strong&gt;AWESOME, lots of talent, determination and a lovely bunch too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's next for NTRG?
&lt;/strong&gt;2015 is shaping up to be a pretty exciting year for us; in February we are taking part in Voodoo's Highland Rampage tournament which features 8 teams from across Scotland. We are also taking part in Tier 4 of the British Roller Derby Championships which will keep us busy throughout the year. We are not big enough to have our own home season (yet) so we are working to arrange some more bouts with other leagues both local and further afield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any final words?
&lt;/strong&gt;I'm really looking forward to 2015. Next year should see me popping my bouting cherry and skating out alongside my fantastic NTRG teammates. I consider myself very lucky to be part of such a lovely bunch of folk and I'm very proud to call myself a New Town Roller Girl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo Courtesy of Rudi Pateluch&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/ntrg-61.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4465" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/ntrg-61.jpg?w=660" alt="Courtesy of Rudi Pateluch" width="660" height="440"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>ntrg</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/19/new-town-roller-girls-round-up-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 19:13:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sur5ors: Charity Tournament</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/15/sur5ors-charity-tournament/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Team Scotland are off to Wales this weekend to skate in the Road to Dallas, the rest of us would be bereft of derby action if it weren't for the foresightedness of Alison Renton - following up last year's charity bout with a whole Sur5al tournament this time around!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/sur5ors.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-4067" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/sur5ors.jpg?w=614" alt="sur5ors" width="614" height="869"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/302622106565291/?fref=ts"&gt;Sur5ors&lt;/a&gt; will see teams from&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/auldreekierollergirls"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BlackpoolRollerDerby"&gt;Blackpool Roller Derby Team&lt;/a&gt;
Dundee Roller Girls
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/FierceValleyRG"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; (twice)
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/furnessfirecrackers"&gt;Furness Firecrackers - Roller Derby League&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GlasgowRollerDerby"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; (twice)
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/NewTownRollerGirls"&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/mhrollerderbyuk"&gt;Team Crazy Legs: Roller Derby, Mental Health &amp;amp; Chronic Illness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;and
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Voodoo-Roller-Dollies/571771319549241"&gt;Voodoo Roller Dollies&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to compete in the usual 5-person team endurance derby that is Sur5al.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All profits will go to &lt;a id="js_3" class="" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Glendrick-Roost-Animal-Welfare-Centre/295429747140376"&gt;Glendrick Roost Animal Welfare Centre&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/standrewsfirstaid"&gt;St Andrew's First Aid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are still available at: &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/838260"&gt;http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/838260&lt;/a&gt; , and the event kicks off at 11:30 am at The Peak, Stirling on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>blackpool roller derby</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>furness firecrackers</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>sur5al</category><category>team crazy legs</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>voodoo roller dollies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/15/sur5ors-charity-tournament/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 12:31:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Town Roller Girls present MURDERDROME</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/18/new-town-roller-girls-present-murderdrome/</link><dc:creator>oneknownashaze</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the 6th of September New Town Roller Girls play host to blood curdling display of roller derby as they put on showing of &lt;em&gt;'Murderdrome'. &lt;/em&gt;An Australian slasher film with strong roots in roller derby and horror film culture that was released in Britain earlier in the year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New Town Roller Girls were very lucky to have a member with a keen eye on Facebook who caught a post from '&lt;em&gt;Murderdrome&lt;/em&gt;'  saying they were looking for leagues to show their film for fundraising events within their own leagues. The event is also going to be held at Livingston's key theatre Howden Park Centre who are very supportive of local groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The doors open at 7:45pm with the film starting at 8. Tickets will be £5 on the door and the event will be 18+ only and attendees will be provided with a NTRG wrist band.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The event also boasts a rich display of raffle prizes from roller derby paraphernalia to special deals with local restaurants.  &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To check out the event, the film and New Town Roller Girls head on over to; &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/702042726509548/"&gt;NTRG present MURDERDROME&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/poss-banner-murderdrome.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter wp-image-3600 size-full" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/poss-banner-murderdrome.jpg" alt="poss banner murderdrome" width="860" height="314"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>murderdrome</category><category>new town roller girls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/18/new-town-roller-girls-present-murderdrome/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 18:05:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Review 2014: New Town Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/07/derby-review-2014-new-town-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To see in the new year, we at the Scottish Roller Derby blog have cast back our eyes over the past year of derby. We'll be presenting a series of interviews with the Scottish leagues about their 2013 over the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What better way to start than with one of our most newly bouting leagues, Livingston's &lt;a href="http://newtownrollergirls.tumblr.com/"&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;? We caught up with team captain and league manager Hazzard to look over the highlights of their year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/img_0129-2-copy.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3142" alt="New Town Roller Girls facing Furness Firecrackers B in their debut bout." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/img_0129-2-copy.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; New Town Roller Girls facing Furness Firecrackers B in their debut bout. (Photo Credit: Laura MacDonald)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This year saw skaters from New Town bout publicly twice: once as one half of the Co-ed "Mean Town", against Bairn City's Belter Skelpers, and then in New Town's own cherry popper, with New Town taking on Furness Firecrackers' Flaming Noras. How did it feel to be passing that important milestone?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It felt amazing! There are no other words to describe it! Thanks to our girls for their hard work and the help of some amazing leagues as hosts, guest skaters and opponents we pulled off our first two public appearances and took home a lot of experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As New Town took the unusual step of breaking their co-ed cherry before their "normal" one, can we expect to see more Co-ed outings for the league? Maybe even a co-ed team ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most likely not a co-ed team but we are fond of those guys over at Mean City! Our girls are free to choose if they participate in any mixed co-ed events in the Scottish derby world and we certainly don't discourage skating with the guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Town have built up strong connections with many of the other derby leagues in Scotland, including Mean City and Bairn City. How has the derby community helped New Town to grow this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much! From helping us out with coaching to hosting us in our first bouts they've done wonders for us! We hope that 2014 will see us engage with even more leagues and get involved in even more events and we're eager to see what the year has in store for us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That community spirit contributed to some other appearances by New Town skaters, with several playing in the "cherry popper" bout preceding Granite City and The Jakey Bites' Co-ed exhibition bout in July. Does a first appearance in a mixed team ease you into derby, or is it just as "real" as an outing of New Town as a team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally think it helps you get over some of the stresses of a competitive bout. It means that you're not too involved with getting your team to win (even though that's part of the fun) . You can focus on enjoying the atmosphere and playing to the best of your ability with people in the same position as you! We also had some skaters in the recent GRD charity bout who were popping their cherry or on their second bout and they loved it! Gets you more involved with the derby community as a whole!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growth as a league also means picking up new sponsors. I noticed that New Town have collected &lt;a href="http://sckrpnch.com/index.php?"&gt;Sckrpunch&lt;/a&gt; as a sponsor this year. Does this imply you'll be present at some of the &lt;a href="http://derbyrevolution.eu/"&gt;Derby Revolution&lt;/a&gt; events also organised by the store?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've not had anything about on an official level but I've seen the events floating around. (Recently it was announce Suzy Hotrod would be holding classes?!) But we're very happy to have such a well known derby name tied with ours and we're looking forward to whatever we do together in the future! Especially if a trip to the store in Belgium happens! I'm still hoping for another Skate Odyssey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And finally, what can you tell us about New Town's plans for 2014?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well I can't really say much as most of what we have happening behind the scenes is in its early stages but what I can tell you is that we are New Town Roller Girls and we're out to kick 2014's ass! We have some amazingly strong skaters coming through our ranks at the moment and we're growing as a team week in and week out! I feel more than privileged to skate with the girls who are working their butts off to make themselves and the team great! So watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>ntrg</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/07/derby-review-2014-new-town-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 15:24:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Monthly Diary of a League: New Town in September: Bump-Her Stick-Her</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/09/13/monthly-diary-of-a-league-new-town-in-september-bump-her-stick-her/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing &lt;a href="http://newtownrollergirls.tumblr.com/"&gt;New Town Roller Girls'&lt;/a&gt; Monthly insights, here's Bump-Her-Stick-Her... coming to a track near you, soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/bump-her-sm.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-2939" alt="Bump-Her Stick-Her!" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/bump-her-sm.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="909"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Bump-Her Stick-Her!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What first attracted you to Roller Derby?&lt;/strong&gt;
My awesome bestie used to play for ARRG (Bobscene Behaviour) and that was my introduction to the game. I watched her in her first bout and left wishing I could give it a try. Fast forwards a few years later and I was a new mum looking for an outlet, some exercise and something that I could do just for me - I saw an advert for New Town Roller Girls and pounced!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most skaters have inspirations in their own or other leagues. Who are your derby heroes?&lt;/strong&gt;
Bobscene Behavior for introducing me to roller derby (and blocking like a boss). Duke Box is amazing, agile and hits like a wall! Also Lois Maim is all round awesome and so patient when helping me learn hits and blocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby names are an important aspect of the sport, especially when you're starting out. How did you choose your name (and number), and does it reflect your personality on track?&lt;/strong&gt;
It came to me at work. I'm generally known for being shy and uncertain (unless you really know me well) . I wanted to channel a tougher side so I wanted an aggressive name. Bump-Her Stick-Her is a mantra i can use on track. My number is my daughter Roslyn's birthday 195.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's your favourite position and technique?&lt;/strong&gt;
I like jamming, I am still learning a lot but I hope I can be a useful jammer some day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lots of roller girls find it hard not to spread the word about their new sport. How have you been spreading the word?&lt;/strong&gt;
Facebook :) work, rambling on to hairdressers and by wearing my teams t-shirt whilst running or working out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the most important thing you've learnt/ done this month&lt;/strong&gt;
Practicing with the boys and girls for our &lt;a title="Bairn City Rollers presents “Day Of Reckoning”" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/09/10/bairn-city-rollers-presents-day-of-reckoning/"&gt;upcoming bout&lt;/a&gt; (my cherry popper)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And the most difficult and the best things?&lt;/strong&gt;
The most difficult is the frustration of not picking up a technique. The best is the first time you get it right. You may not always get it but you realise it's possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's new for the New Town this month?&lt;/strong&gt;
First bout. I'm simultaneously excited and terrified. Also the next wave of minimum skills skaters&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>monthly diary</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>ntrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/09/13/monthly-diary-of-a-league-new-town-in-september-bump-her-stick-her/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 09:40:32 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>