<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about newcastle roller girls)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/newcastle-roller-girls.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:34:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Europe's First Continental Cup: the UK's next International Derby fixture in 2018</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/04/europes-first-continental-cup-the-uks-next-international-derby-fixture-in-2018/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By any account, 2018 has been a very good year for Roller Derby's international profile, in both Europe and the UK. From the third Roller Derby World Cup in Manchester this February, and the third Men's Roller Derby World Cup in Barcelona a few months later, we've gone on to host an MRDA Playoffs, in Halifax/hosted by Manchester Roller Derby, and a WFTDA Playoffs, in A Coruña.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pendulum is, inevitably, swinging back again from Spain to the UK, with the last event in this sequence: the first ever &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wftdaecc2018.com/"&gt;European WFTDA Continental Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, bringing up the rear in this inaugural year for the new format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the MRDA Playoffs (hosted by Manchester, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; Halifax), this is hosted by Birmingham Blitz Dames, but physically &lt;i&gt;located&lt;/i&gt; in Telford... but the hosts have done a lot to make the brand of the tournament their own. The distinctive diamond logo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-27531 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/blitzdamesdiamon.png" alt="BlitzDamesDiamon" width="245" height="240"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;has both a general connection to Birmingham's jewellery industry, and to the Blitz Dames themselves - and even references their ex-skater, goldsmith Isabella Day, who made the trophy for the tournament!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27532" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/continental_map_logos.png" alt="Continental_map_logos" width="1562" height="1070"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Continental Cups framework is a response to the increasing spread of Roller Derby, and particularly the increasingly global membership of WFTDA. With more than 400 member leagues, an ever decreasing fraction of travel teams can hope to compete in a WFTDA Playoffs (and travel costs become increasingly prohibitive if you just extend the cut-off for Playoffs, or extend the old Division 2). &lt;i&gt;Regional&lt;/i&gt; "Continental Cups" provide a WFTDA-certified tournament, for every region with enough teams, at a level just below that of Playoffs - but with much less travel costs. (Next year, there will also be a set of regional "Development Cups", providing a WFTDA-certified tournament option for regions who aren't competitive at the old "D2" level, with guest "seed" teams from more "connected" regions to help improve ranking accuracy.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe's Continental Cup, then, has a familiar set of teams (and countries) represented (order from WFTDA announcement):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Kallio Rolling Rainbow (Finland)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dublin Roller Derby (Ireland)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dock City Rollers (Sweden)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers (Wales)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Central City Roller Derby (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby (England)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
The current FTS Europe rankings (which include a different subset of games to WFTDA rankings; excluding games against teams outside Europe, but including unsanctioned games) disagree somewhat with this ordering - FTS thinks that some of these teams were strong enough to make Playoffs ahead of some of the European representation there! - but predict a rather close set of games, regardless. In fact, FTS currently rates the two "local" teams - hosts Birmingham Blitz Dames, and Central City Roller Derby - as being exceptionally close in strength - sadly, the bracket prevents them from meeting unless they both lose their first games, or meet in the final.
Similarly, FTS expects some surprisingly close matches in the first round of the elimination bracket, despite WFTDA's usual slaughter pairing setup: Kallio versus Middlesbrough should be a near-draw by European data; although WFTDA sanctioned ratings place Kallio much higher than the UK team. If you're playing the Bracket Challenge for this contest, that's your best chance for an early upset...
&lt;p&gt;Despite, or perhaps causing, of the possibility of so many upsets and ranking disparities, the European Continental Cup should continue the example of the two North American CCs, in having a higher than "usual" number of close bouts, despite the tendency of elimination tournaments to start with a round of blowouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bracket is available here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.wixstatic.com/ugd/590519_be81975ec1304fcf96b32590ddbe2d8a.pdf"&gt;BRACKET PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (note for those not in the UK - this event is on the weekend that the UK changes over from Daylight Savings Time, so be careful checking timings for the Sunday, in particular).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-27324" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/officials_eur_map.png?w=2048" alt="Officials_EUR_map" width="1024" height="768"&gt; Geographical distribution of European Officials at the ECC! Stars may represent more than one official from a given location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as for the competition, the Continental Cup is also a great chance for more representation for our highly skilled European Officiating community. Just at the Tournament and Crew Head levels, we have officials from Karlsruhe, Newcastle, Dublin, Nottingham, Paris/Lutece, London/Southern Discomfort, (and Michigan...) - including all of the other crew positions adds (deep breath) Amsterdam, Antwerp, Bath, Belfast, Birmingham, Brussels, Cambridge, Cardiff, Chelmsford, Copenhagen, Darmstadt, Devon, Dresden, Dundee, Essex, Falkirk, Frankfurt, Gothenburg, Kallio/Helsinki, Manchester, Metz, Mons, Nantes, Northampton, Oxford, Riems, Ruhrpott, Southend, Southampton, Vicenza, Vienna, Wiltshire, Wuppertal,  (and Rochester, NY; Monterrey County, CA; St Louis, MO; Boston, MA; USA... and Adelaide, SA, Australia)! Just as with the other international events in Europe this year, this kind of exposure, and opportunity to both officiate at a high level, and meet up with a wider-flung segment of the Derby Community is fantastic for Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not all, as there's also fantastic line-up of (mostly...) European announcers, from Head Announcer Biertrix (Rainy City Roller Derby), through a host of UK announcers from London through Manchester to Durham and Newcastle; and from Germany, Denmark, as well as the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, as with all WFTDA post-season events this year, there will be a genuine chance for all members of the community (WFTDA-members or no) to connect with WFTDA Membership via the co-hosted "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/772801099579539/"&gt;WFTDA World Summit Satellite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" event. We're very impressed by WFTDA's increased commitment to listening to the voices of the whole community, and would encourage the community to also make use of these opportunities in return: listening should be rewarded with dialogue. (On that note, WFTDA are also surveying every league which does derby and are not WFTDA-members - regardless of their gender policy etc - and we'd encourage everyone eligible to respond to this too, here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.org/surveys"&gt;WFTDA.org/surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The European Continental Cup will run from &lt;strong&gt;October 27th to October 28th&lt;/strong&gt; at The International Centre, Telford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WFTDA Continental Cup page: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/events/wftda-continental-cups/"&gt;https://wftda.com/events/wftda-continental-cups/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Facebook Event for European Continental Cup: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>birmingham blitz dames</category><category>central city roller derby</category><category>continental cup</category><category>dock city rollers</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>kallio rolling rainbow</category><category>middlesbrough roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>tournament</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/04/europes-first-continental-cup-the-uks-next-international-derby-fixture-in-2018/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 15:54:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash 2018: Newcastle Roller Girls' tournament expands beyond the "Euro".</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/26/euroclash-2018-newcastle-roller-girls-tournament-expands-beyond-the-euro/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Readers of the blog will remember our coverage of Newcastle Roller Girls' first European Tournament, &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/365884340424845/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, back in 2017. Newcastle's first WFTDA Recognised Tournament brought together teams across Europe for some high level action, and prefigured performances as far ahead as WFTDA Playoffs; as well as presenting a sneak peak at two of the National teams (Scotland and Ireland) as they worked towards the 3rd Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the ridiculously tournament-filled start of this year has delayed us, we're also going to be bringing you as much coverage as we can of the return of EuroClash this year... although, given one of the attendees this time, the tournament has already outgrown its name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this initial article, we're just going to introduce you to the competitors, and their current placements in the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst 2018's edition is slightly smaller than 2017's - 9 attendees (6 returning from last time), rather than 11 - their geographic distribution is &lt;em&gt;substantially&lt;/em&gt; wider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning from 2017's inaugural event are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls (hosts)
Auld Reekie Roller Girls (soon to &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/25/auld-reekies-10-anniversary-rebrand-with-your-help/"&gt;rebrand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; to Auld Reekie Roller Derby) [Edinburgh]
Central City Roller Derby (competed last year as Central City Rollergirls) [Birmingham]
Dublin Roller Derby
Middlesbrough Roller Derby (EuroClash2017 was their first fixture after rebranding)
Tiger Bay Brawlers [Cardiff]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joining them to make up the full nine are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames
Dock City Roller Derby [Gothenburg]
Steel City Roller Derby [Pittsburgh]!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-26639" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/euroclash2018.png?w=2048" alt="EuroClash2018" width="1024" height="768"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, EuroClash served as the first step for several of the attending teams' campaigns to get into WFTDA Playoffs - Auld Reekie, Bear City, Paris and Dublin all gaining valuable ranking points from their attendance, as all bouts are WFTDA Sanctioned games.
Whilst EuroClash itself is not arranged to provide a final ranking, or a tournament cup, we did analyse the tournament itself &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Our analysis was good enough to predict the results of Paris Rollergirls' subsequent two games against other attendees, so it's probably as good as any other attempt at rating the teams...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since last year, the returning teams have played a lot of Roller Derby, with varying stories; so we can expect some changes in the matchups this time around. [We're using the FTS "WFTDA" ratings here, as not all the teams can be rated with the usually-more-accurate Europe ratings.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the time of writing, the attending EuroClash 2018 teams span a 41 position zone within FTS's rankings - but a fairly closely rated one. (FTS's built in predictor tool expects only a 2:1 score ratio between the highest rated - Dublin - and lowest rated - Auld Reekie - teams if they played today.) We've also included, in parenthesis, the WFTDA Official ratings and rankings for the teams - despite the different ordering, the "range" in strengths is about the same for WFTDA's own ratings, perhaps slightly larger.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="3" rowspan="1"&gt;FTS "WFTDA" Ratings 23 April 2018 (WFTDA Rating 31 March)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rank&lt;/strong&gt; (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Rating (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;53&lt;/strong&gt; (46)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7775/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;745.2 (391.51)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;62&lt;/strong&gt; (65)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/29732/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dock City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;732.4 (318.9)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;63&lt;/strong&gt; (68)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7948/rankings/wftda"&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;729.4 (307.57)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;70&lt;/strong&gt; (94)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7763/rankings/wftda"&gt;Central City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;713.3 (242.58)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;83&lt;/strong&gt; (62)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7949/rankings/wftda"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;691.7 (323.67)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;86&lt;/strong&gt; (95)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/3417/rankings/wftda"&gt;Steel City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;683.0 (241.15)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;88&lt;/strong&gt; (88)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7736/rankings/wftda"&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;682.2 (259.63)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;93&lt;/strong&gt; (85)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7953/rankings/wftda"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;676.0 (262.62)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;94&lt;/strong&gt; (87)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/5912/rankings/wftda"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;674.9 (259.86)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
Auld Reekie and Middlesbrough both suffered ratings reductions against 2x4 Roller Derby during the latter's Jan-Feb tour of Europe, where the Argentine team outperformed expectations against almost &lt;i&gt;everyone&lt;/i&gt;. The jury is out as to how much of this is due to 2x4's general under-ranking, and how much is due to over-ranking of the teams they played - in general, we'd expect better-than-ranking performances from both teams at EuroClash.
Middlesbrough could potentially surprise the current #1 seeds, Dublin; the gap between their WFTDA ratings is entirely due to that loss to the under-ranked 2x4, and their European rating, by comparison, places them above the Irish team (and only just below Paris)!
Similarly, Auld Reekie's European rating places them in the middle of the field, rather than at the bottom, although their trajectory is in the same direction - however, some of this is due to their bout against Leeds Roller Derby, who are almost certainly under-ranked at this point in the year.
&lt;p&gt;Hosts Newcastle have also had difficult bouts, against EuroClash 2017 returnees Central City Roller Derby - given CCR's stronger-than-previous performance against other recent opponents, we consider this to be more of a reflection on CCR than Newcastle - and Leeds Roller Derby (who, again, are simply improving themselves, as they knit together as a team after their first year). We suspect Newcastle are somewhat underranked due to their choice of opponents, and as the hosts they'll be wanting to show that at EuroClash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remaining steady, Tiger Bay Brawlers have still had a pretty good year - and even their recent loss to Central City is not a bad sign, as their performance was near identical to that at EuroClash 2017; if CCR show signs of being back on the up, then this is actually good for the Cardiff team too. The recent transfer of Kid Block back to TBB from London can only improve their strength further - we expect strong performances from the team, beyond what their current rating implies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dublin Roller Derby have also had a pretty good 2017, continuing their upward trend in the FTS European ratings, and remaining steady in the WFTDA rating. Their current placement at the top of EuroClash 2018's rankings seems solid, barring improvements from Dock City, or Middlesbrough. This could all change this weekend, however, as Dublin play some competitive sanctioned games over in the USA at Southern Discomfort 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also remaining steady for the past year, Steel City Roller Derby - after losing around 100 rating points in 2016, the team had a very stable 2017, sticking around the 680-690 rating they still reside at entering EuroClash. A return to their 2016 high would make them easily the strongest team in the tournament, but we suspect their middle-table ranking is more likely, especially given the effects of trans-Atlantic travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gothenburg's second league, Dock City Rollers, continued their generally upwards climb over 2017 (and 2016), and show no particular signs of stopping this progress in WFTDA bouts. They're one of two teams which could challenge expected #1, Dublin if they play against them. Looking at the more plentiful data in the European FTS rankings, they've suffered a "correction" to their ranking as a result of their performance in last year's Swedish national tournament, but their trend is still upward - if we believe the European values, however, they'll be better matched against Auld Reekie than Dublin's finest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representing Birmingham, we have both Birmingham Blitz Dames and Central City Roller Derby, and both seeing upwards movement in the rankings over the past year - Central City in the past month or two, and BBD earlier in 2017 - although the more detailed European ratings show signs of a correction in the Blitz Dames rating at the start of this year, albeit again against the probably-underranked Leeds Roller Derby.  We'll see if the Blitz Dames still have more rating gains to come in the WFTDA rating, as they play in the 2018 K Town Shakedown this weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be back with some more articles, and a guide to the schedule when its published, closer to the event...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash 2018&lt;/a&gt; will be hosted at the &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/6NHQpKxP5Em"&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; on the &lt;b&gt;19th&lt;/b&gt; and&lt;b&gt; 20th May&lt;/b&gt; 2018 - less than a month away! Tickets are on sale, for &lt;b&gt;£30&lt;/b&gt; in advance (£35 on the door), or at a limited special group discount price of&lt;b&gt; £100 for 4&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>birmingham blitz dames</category><category>central city roller derby</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>dock city rollers</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>euroclash</category><category>middlesbrough roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>steel city roller derby</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/26/euroclash-2018-newcastle-roller-girls-tournament-expands-beyond-the-euro/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 13:04:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Newcastle's Whippin Hinnies update: British Champs T2 and beyond</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/08/01/newcastles-whippin-hinnies-update-british-champs-t2-and-beyond/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Working our way up through the Northern Divisions of British Champs, we've found our way, via Tier 4 and Tier 3, to Tier 2.
Our team for Tier 2 North was &lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;' B-team, the Whippin Hinnies, who were one of three 3 B-teams added to British Champs this year. (London Rollergirls had led the charge the previous year, with the Brawl Saints competing in Tier 1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13711 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/newcastlerg_1.png" alt="newcastlerg_1" width="122" height="250"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend sees the final fixture in the Division, with Newcastle up against Wirral Roller Derby in &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/104769700121799/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manchester&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. With the Hinnies at the bottom spot currently, with Wirral just one place above them, this should be the closest bout of the tournament for them - SRDRank places them nigh-identically in ranking, whist FTS favours Wirral, but not much. At the top of the table, the other B team in the Division, Rainy City B (the Tender Hooligans) have a tight grip on the top spot, with Liverpool Roller Birds and hosts Manchester Roller Derby fighting it out for the second playoffs spot in the same event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to Hinnies' Co-Captain, Ania Marx about their first Champs experience...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's been a tough Tier for the Hinnies' first Champs experience, so far, with teams like Rainy B in the mix. How has the experience been for the team - and what has it taught you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a challenge ​but we​ always​ knew it would be - being seeded last​ in our Tier against alongside some really strong teams​ and also being a B team​ means that we've also​ needed to absorb a number of charter changes as players move up to our A team​, the Canny Belters​​​,​​ but we're grateful for the opportunity to play at this level - we've learnt a lot and have thoroughly enjoyed the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With just one game left in the season, what are your plans for the post-Champs period...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll have a short break from ​competitive bouts but hope to fit in a few more before the end of the year - we'll update the fixtures page on our website as soon as we've got more games confirmed. Immediately after our last Champs game on the 5th Aug we​'ll definitely be let​ting​ our hair down and enjoy​ing​ the after party and hope all the other leagues will be doing the same​!​&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;...and your thoughts about Champs next year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a great opportunity for the Whippin' ​Hinnies which was only possible due to our A team​'​s ​WFTDA ranking and our own European ranking​ going into Champs​ - if we remain eligible​ as a B team​ we will seriously consider​ taking part​ next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As hinted at in the interview, whilst the Hinnies will be taking a break post-Champs, there's more happening with Newcastle in the coming months.
We'd keep our eyes peeled for an away game in August, as well as the return of the Hinnies (and the Canny Belters) later in the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The British Champs Tier 2 North final fixture: &lt;strong&gt;5 August&lt;/strong&gt;, Manchester &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/104769700121799/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/104769700121799/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>british champs</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>interviews</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>whippin hinnies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/08/01/newcastles-whippin-hinnies-update-british-champs-t2-and-beyond/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 12:44:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash, Tomodachi and Quad Wars, Three Tournaments, One Weekend (stats)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outside of the USA, there were arguably three big "single date" tournament events last weekend:
Newcastle Roller Girls' &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;EuroClash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, hosting European leagues, a WFTDA Recognised Tournament
Okinawa and Japan's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, hosting East-Asia/Pacific and Alaskan leagues, with a WFTDA Sanctioned Tier
Mendoza, Argentina's Lado Oscuro Roller Derby's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quad Wars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, hosting B/C level Latin American leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of games in all of them, so there's plenty of meat for statistical inference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's start with EuroClash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-13774" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/euroclash.jpg" alt="euroclash" width="851" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash was arranged as a pure invitational tournament, with structure set mostly by the participants' desires for opponents. As a result, EuroClash did not post a "winner" of the tournament. All bouts were WFTDA Sanctioned, as befits a WFTDA Recognised Tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participating teams for all but the last fixture were: Newcastle Roller Girls, Leeds Roller Derby, Middlesbrough Roller Derby, Tiger Bay Brawlers, Central City Rollergirls, Bear City Roller Derby (Berlin), Paris Rollergirls, Auld Reekie Roller Girls (Edinburgh) and Dublin Roller Derby. (Interviews with the teams can be found on this very blog here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/tag/euroclash/"&gt;https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/tag/euroclash/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scores (from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/89165"&gt;FlatTrack Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) are:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;TBB [Tiger Bay Brawlers]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;161&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;CCR [Central City]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;167&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BCRD [Bear City]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;228&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NRG [Newcastle]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;94&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARRG [Auld Reekie]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;194&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MRD [Middlesbrough]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;99&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;LeedsRD [Leeds]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;94&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;DRD [Dublin]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;312&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;238&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;BCRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;177&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;ARRG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;176&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;PRG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;192&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;DRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;85&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;ARRG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;301&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;LeedsRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;93&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TBB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;117&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;203&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;135&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CCR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;177&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MRD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;238&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BCRD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;89&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
As commentators have noted (including The Derby Apex), there's some significant departures from prediction here, which we've highlighted in two different ways. Bolded results are surprising in both European and WFTDA rankings terms, whilst Italic are surprising in terms of WFTDA rank only [in this sense, we mean explicitly "from the WFTDA rankings, not from FTS's ranking based on WFTDA Sanctioned play].
&lt;p&gt;It's pretty clear that there are several patterns here: two ranking errors in WFTDA (Leeds Roller Derby inheriting the ranking from Leeds Roller Dolls, and Paris Rollergirls' known underranking) are responsible for the majority of the `surprises' between them. Anyone who had seen LeedsRD play in British Champs would have expected the same high individual-skill, but teamwork needing more time to gel playstyle we saw in EuroClash - which is to say that there were moments of brilliance, particularly from their jammer rotation (Killaroo, Shin Pain and Little Dark One standing out for us, and in the stats), but there's still some place to go with the cohesion.
And Paris Rollergirls' determination to reach Division 2 playoffs this year is backed by considerable skill and effort in training over the last year - and a consciously constructed schedule of fixtures designed to gain them WFTDA ranking as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this context, then, the real surprises are: Tiger Bay Brawlers holding Paris Rollergirls to their expected performance [including holding them to zero points for the first half of the first period], Central City, in turn, 's surprising win over TBB in the first bout of the tournament, Auld Reekie Roller Girls matching their European expectations of tying Bear City to a 1-point win...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and the curious case of Middlesbrough Roller Derby. The MRD bouts are the only bouts which are a really surprising result in terms of FTS - in the one case, MRD massively underperforming versus Auld Reekie, and in the second MRD massively overperforming against Bear City! (And we mean massively in both cases - Middlesbrough might have been expected to beat Auld Reekie with that kind of points margin, not lose to them by it!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibility, exists, of course, that it was the other teams which were unpredictable... but we can test that with the power of statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We performed a standard linear regression against the results from EuroClash, using score ratios as our measure of performance. As we've explained before, this assumes that the strengths of each team are simply related to each other by their performance - so if Team A is twice as strong as Team B, and three times as strong as Team C, then Team B versus Team C should give a 2/3 ratio win for the B team. Of course, performance varies from game to game, but we can use an "R-squared" value to measure just how good the approximation is for our results. A value close to 1 indicates that the results are very well described by this kind of model, whilst a value close to 0 indicates that no such relationship exists at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running the regression against the full set of results above gives an R-squared&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; of &lt;em&gt;0.39&lt;/em&gt;, a disappointingly low value for Roller Derby tournaments in general (which tend to be around 0.7 or higher).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, given that we know that the MRD results are inconsistent, we can rerun the regression on the results, minus one or both of the MRD games. In this case, we get an pleasingly high R-squared of around &lt;em&gt;0.93&lt;/em&gt; - actually very high for a tournament.
This suggests that, whilst the results might have been surprising when compared with WFTDA rankings, the performance of the teams (other than Middlesbrough) across EuroClash was remarkably consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For interest, then, the relative power-rankings (which should be in the ratio of the points scored between two teams) are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;184&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Paris Rollergirls&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;100&lt;/strong&gt;
Middlesbrough Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;76&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/em&gt;
Berlin City Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;69&lt;/strong&gt;
Auld Reekie Roller Girls &lt;strong&gt;62&lt;/strong&gt;
Tiger Bay Brawlers &lt;strong&gt;51&lt;/strong&gt;
Dublin Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;50&lt;/strong&gt;
Central City Rollergirls &lt;strong&gt;47&lt;/strong&gt;
Newcastle Rollergirls &lt;strong&gt;32&lt;/strong&gt;
Middlesbrough Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;31&lt;/strong&gt; *
Leeds Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where the three entries for Middlesbrough represent their performance against Berlin (184), Auld Reekie (31) and the average of the two (76). That average is around where we would expect MRD to actually have performed if they were consistent, which is interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally matching the results against the existing rankings produces the best matches if we assume that Paris, Dublin and perhaps Auld Reekie, are underranked, and LeedsRD are overranked, with smaller shifts for the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also means that, if we were awarding a Championship to any team, it would be the entirely expected Paris Rollergirls!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paris will be competing against Bear City only this coming weekend, so this will be a good test of their true strength...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-
Of course, the final event at EuroClash was the Team Scotland Roller Derby versus Team Ireland Roller Derby bout.
A rematch of the game played at Road to TBC, where both teams were in their training roster (and Ireland had barely selected that), where Ireland won - this time Team Scotland's competition 20 were playing a more-experienced, but still training, Ireland. (Both teams had many skaters from Auld Reekie and Dublin's rosters, respectively, as well as other teams.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's fair to say that there was a significant difference in the result, with Road to TBC's tough-but-convincing Irish victory replaced by a tight even score in at the end of the first period, becoming a strong Scottish victory by the end of the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final result, &lt;strong&gt;209&lt;/strong&gt; Scotland : &lt;strong&gt;128&lt;/strong&gt; Ireland is stronger than the expected result if Dublin had played ARRG, emphasising the importance of the other leagues making up each National Team; however, at half time, the result was a near tie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;For the statistically inclined, this is actually the adjusted R-squared, not the bare R-squared. We're also using the F-statistic for these regressions, but it closely follows adj. R-squared here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click here: for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/2"&gt;Tomodachi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and here: for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/3"&gt;Quad Wars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over in Okinawa, the Tomodachi Derby Tournament had three tiers - a WFTDA sanctioned tier, an unsanctioned women's tier, and the men's tier (with just two competitors). Interviews with all the participants are available here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/tag/tomodachi-derby-tournament/"&gt;https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/tag/tomodachi-derby-tournament/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-14076" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tomodachi.png?w=300" alt="tomodachi" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;WFTDA-Sanctioned Tier&lt;/h4&gt;
Competing in the Sanctioned Tier were: Okinawa Roller Derby, Tokyo Roller Girls, Devil Dog Derby Dames (the 3 Japanese leagues), Pacific Roller Derby (Hawai'i) and Fairbanks Rollergirls (Alaska, USA).
This was a full round-robin, for a total of 10 games between the 5 teams.
&lt;p&gt;The results were [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/88944"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D4 (Devil Dog Derby Dames)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;305&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FR (Fairbanks Rollergirls)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;156&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRG (Tokyo Rollergirls)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;167&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRD (Hawai'i Pacific Roller Derby)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;138&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ORD (Okinawa Roller Derby)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;124&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;232&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;138&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;188&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;164&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;170&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;126&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;127&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;251&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;174&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;167&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;169&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;172&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;108&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;212&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
The most surprising result is highlighted - Okinawa Roller Derby (which renamed from Kokeshi Roller Dolls just before the tournament) are usually ranked around the same as their fellow Okinawans in Devil Dog Derby Dames.
&lt;p&gt;Running our statistical regression on the tournament, we get an R-squared value (our measure of how "consistent" the games all are) of &lt;em&gt;0.44&lt;/em&gt;, which suggests that there's definitely at least one team which was variable in performance over the two days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, whilst you might expect that removing results such as the ORD v D4 score from the set would improve the R-squared factor for our fit, this is not the case - there's very little change in the R-squared for single-bout changes for the Tomodachi. We believe that this reflects the difference in tournament-experience of the teams involved, versus the higher ranked teams at EuroClash (who are more used to managing their rosters and effort across a long event).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resulting strengths of the WFTDA tier of Tomodachi, then, are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tokyo Roller Girls &lt;strong&gt;100&lt;/strong&gt;
Devil Dog Derby Dames &lt;strong&gt;100&lt;/strong&gt;
Okinawa Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;82&lt;/strong&gt;
Hawai'i Pacific Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;60&lt;/strong&gt;
Fairbanks Rollergirls &lt;strong&gt;60&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where we would give the "unofficial championship", by a whisker, to Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your next chances to see some of these teams: Devil Dog Derby Dames will be competing in Hawai'i's Big Island Brawl against the rest of Hawai'i, and teams from the continental USA (June), where you will also find Pacific Roller Derby. Okinawa Roller Derby are off to Europe to play in a tournament hosted by Rollergirls of the Apocalypse, in Kaiserslauten, Germany. Fairbanks are concentrating on their Alaskan neighbours, with the UWR State Tournament coming up in May. And Tokyo Roller Girls are looking for people to play them, so do ask!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Unsanctioned Tier&lt;/h4&gt;
With two of the three competing teams in the unsanctioned tier essentially exhibition teams (Pan-Asian Spring Rollers representing the Chinese and Thai derby leagues, and Team Women's Roller Derby Japan an open team for skaters who wanted to compete), and the third a Tokyo Roller Girls' home team (Yokosuka Sushi Rollers), there were no expectations on the three bouts.
&lt;p&gt;The results were:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;YSR (Yokosuka Sushi Rollers)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;307&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PASR (Pan-Asian Spring Rollers)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;51&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;YSR (Yokosuka Sushi Rollers)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;307&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PASR (Pan-Asian Spring Rollers)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;51&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;YSR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;152&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WRDJ (Women's Roller Derby Japan)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;167&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WRDJ&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;218&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PASR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;157&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
With just three teams and three bouts, there's not really much point in running statistical tests on the performance, as there's not enough data to produce a reasonable result. (The R-squared statistic is fairly poor for the set, due to the visibly wide variation in the teams' performance.)
&lt;p&gt;In fact, within statistical error, Yokosuka Sushi Rollers and Women's Roller Derby Japan are inseparable in performance, with the Spring Rollers' lack of time to train together evidence in their lower placing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establishing a winner really isn't the point of the unsanctioned tier, however - it's to give the teams a chance to get good experience against people they'd never reasonably be able to play. And, in particular, for the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers, this will be a great learning experience for them to take back to their home leagues in Hong Kong, Shanghai, Beijing and Bangkok.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Men's Tier.&lt;/h4&gt;
Glenmore Reservoir Dogs and Team Japan Men's Roller Derby (NinJapan Rollers) played each other twice over the tournament, with scores:
&lt;p&gt;GRD 273 : TJMRD 113
GRD 288 : TJMRD 138&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it should be fairly evident that, despite the Canadians winning both bouts, there's a close-to-significant improvement in NinJapan Rollers even in the second bout. (In both Men's Roller Derby World Cups, NinJapan have noticeably improved over the tournament, so this is in keeping with their character.)
These were Japan's first men's games since the last World Cup, in fact, and were more significant for the training opportunity, perhaps, than the resulting scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click here: for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/1"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and here: for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/3"&gt;Quad Wars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over to Argentina now, for the Quad Wars 2017 tournament, which saw teams from Argentina and Chile compete in a "B-tier" tournament (in the sense that Argentina uses "B", which is different to Europe - most of these teams are not actual B-teams).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-17011 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/qw.png" alt="QW" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competing were: hosts Lado Oscuro Roller Derby (LORD); Sailor City Rollers' B team, the Tsunami Bombs; Metropolitan Roller Derby's B team, the Bayonetas; Dirty Fucking Dolls; Brutal Lips; and the Sarcasticats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quad Wars has a Star Wars theme, fitting for a host league whose name is "Dark Side" in Spanish, and the teams were arranged in bracketed light and dark side groups, with a playoff for the championship at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results (from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/91785"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) are:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;LORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DFD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;215&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BRUTAL_LIPS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;51&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NERD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;203&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SARCASTICATS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;122&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BAYONETAS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;177&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NERD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DFD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;58&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;LORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;91&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BRUTAL_LIPS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;124&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BAYONETAS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;114&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TSUNAMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;142&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;LORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;57&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NERD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;209&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SARCASTICATS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TSUNAMI&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;157&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BRUTAL_LIPS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;34&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DFD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;131&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;BAYONETAS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;37&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;NERD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;247&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;DFD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;143&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;TSUNAMI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;78&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;BAYONETAS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;47&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;TSUNAMI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;63&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;NERD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;155&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;DFD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;27&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
The last four bouts (in red) represented a final playoff for the championship, which was won by NERD. We can't highlight surprising results using Flat Track Stats, as they do not have a Latin American ranking... but we can use our own &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to do this instead. In general, the big surprise here is the performance of Sailor City B, the Tsunami Bombs, which we rated as close to the winners, NERD in strength... but performed below expectations.
&lt;p&gt;NERD won the tournament overall, but we can provide the same analysis of the team ratings (and how consistent they were) as before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running the regression over all of the scores gives us a very good R-squared value of 0.8, suggesting that the tournament was well-run, and all the teams managed their schedules and fitness well over the multiple days of competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The estimated strengths of the teams from the regression are (with some confidence):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No Excuses Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;100&lt;/strong&gt;
Dirty Fucking Dolls &lt;strong&gt;41&lt;/strong&gt;
Tsunami Bombs (SCR B) &lt;strong&gt;21&lt;/strong&gt;
Brutal Lips &lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt;
Bayonetas (Metropolitan B) &lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt;
Lado Oscuro Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt;
Sarcasticats &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting feature here is the close grouping of most of the teams: we'd suggest that NERD and DFD could reasonably consider themselves high-B/low-A teams (in Latin American terms), rather than the B/C level of the other closely placed competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in seeing more Latin American Derby, then Metropolitan and Sailor City's A teams are competing at the Violentango 5, WFTDA Recognised Tournament in just a few weeks (13-15th April).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click here for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/1"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and here for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/2"&gt;Tomodachi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>euroclash</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>lado oscuro roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>quad wars</category><category>statistics</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 13:20:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: Newcastle Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/21/euroclash-interviews-newcastle-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Newcastle Roller Girls' first International Tournament, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, less than a week away, we just have time for one final interview topic...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...the hosts of EuroClash themselves, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. NRG's Canny Belters had a very good 2016, playing across in the USA for the first time, as well as topping British Champs Tier 1 (becoming the second ever Champions). Along the way, they also came up with the idea of hosting their first ever International tournament - and people will probably remember their campaign to win funding to support it. This being successful, the last few months have been spent on organising the very tournament which we're writing about...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13711 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/newcastlerg_1.png" alt="newcastlerg_1" width="122" height="250"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missy Pow Pow, Canny Belter's Co-Captain, and one of the driving forces behind EuroClash answered some of our questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Newcastle's Canny Belters had an exceptional year in 2016, topping British Champs Tier 1, after promotion from Tier 2 the previous year. You've now stepped down from British Champs this year, leaving the Hinnies to carry the torch - but was the Championship win your goal from the start, and how did it feel to win it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We always play to win! [laughs] But we didn’t think we’d necessarily will ALL the games. The first win against Glasgow came as a big shock to me, I just wasn’t expecting it. The game was actually a WFTDA strength factor challenge so we had a score in mind that we wanted to achieve, which was nowhere near a win. I remember looking at the score board during the game, unbelieving!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We quickly re-assessed our goals and from that point our aim was to win the whole Championship. It was an amazing experience, watching not only your team mates, but the rest of the league, friends and family come together to support and push us forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You also played over in the USA, at the most popular destination for EuroClash attendees - Beach Brawl in Florida. This was Newcastle's first trip to the USA, and, as is traditional, you beat expectations about the US teams you played. How was the transatlantic experience - the environment, and the potentially different style of play? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were really excited to play US teams for the first time; it felt like a good way to benchmark where we were, as it can be hard to gauge from rankings alone. The tournament was an amazing experience – being in one place that was all about roller derby, being surrounded by different teams, most of which were from the USA and Canada, and of course having the opportunity to bond as a team away from the pressures of work, and derby admin, was wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With regards to style of play I don’t think there is a European style or an American style. Each team is different. We played two American teams, Blue Ridge, and Oklahoma, and they were entirely different. What I liked best though is not knowing a lot about who we were playing, therefore we were able to go in to each game just playing our own game without thinking about the style, strengths or weaknesses of the opposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your brother league, Tyne and Fear, have been hosting the Men's European Cup for several years now - it almost seems surprising that there's not been a women's equivalent in Newcastle until now. What led to the decision to organise EuroClash this year? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've been working hard to climb the rankings so we know how hard it can be for teams to get high level WFTDA sanctioned games. In 2015 we played our first European tournament at SKOD, then last year Beach Brawl; both tournaments not only boosted our rankings but really raised our game - we learned a lot. Having had such a great experience abroad, we decided we wanted to create opportunities like that here in the UK, to play our part in developing the sport. So we're really excited to put on a whole weekend of high level European games, including teams who don't often play in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you select the teams attending EuroClash - they're all pretty close in the European Rankings, but were there other considerations? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It mostly came down to where teams were ranked as all of the games will be WFT-DA sanctioned. We really wanted to play (and watch!) some exciting games and we also thought about which teams had never played each other before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017/8 has really become the "year of European Roller Derby" - with so many tournaments, new and established, located or relocated to Europe. How would you place EuroClash in all of this? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve been planning EuroClash since last year so we like to think we were ahead of the curve there! [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting the opportunity not just to play but also to watch more high level live roller derby at the likes of the first WFTDA Playoffs in Europe this autumn and the 2018 Roller Derby World Cup is fantastic - it makes everyone raise their game and that can only be a good thing for the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which teams are the Canny Belters most looking forward to playing at EuroClash? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve never played Bear City or Paris before so we’re really excited to play both of those teams. We watched Paris play at Beach Brawl last year, and the year before at SKOD and they’re such a strong team that keep going from strength to strength. I’m really looking forward to seeing how we fare against them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that I’ve never seen Bear City play. They are a complete mystery to me, which in itself is super exciting! As for Central City, we played last in 2015, it was a close game with CCR narrowly taking the win. This game is bound to be an-other nail biter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And which teams, or matchups, are you most excited to be able to watch when you're not skating? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bear City v MMR looks like it’ll be an edge of the seat game - they’re even closer now the new WFTDA rankings have just come out. And we’re really looking forward to seeing some of our NRG team mates in action in the Team Ireland v Team Scotland re-match - we didn’t get to see them at Road to TBC last year, but even just following the game on Twitter had our hearts racing so we think that game will be a brilliant way to end the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, after EuroClash, what's next for the Canny Belters in 2017? (And is it too early to predict a 2018 EuroClash?) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve got some home fixtures still to confirm for this season, but the big news is that we’re off to Colorado in June to play at Mayhem. And if EuroClash 2017 is a success then we’d love to make it an annual event; watch this space…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash will be held from the &lt;strong&gt;25th&lt;/strong&gt; to the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/strong&gt;, Newcastle. Ticket available here:&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets"&gt;https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; , and on the door.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>euroclash</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/21/euroclash-interviews-newcastle-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 09:57:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Newcastle's Hinnies off to Champs</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/14/newcastles-hinnies-off-to-champs/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're tracking the Northern divisions of the British Champs this year, via a focus on particular teams in each Tier. The Whippin' Hinnies, Newcastle B, are our Tier 2 North team, and we're starting by giving you a bit of background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls have had a good relationship with British Champs over the last two years - in 2015, the Canny Belters took the win in the Tier 2 tournament (after winning the Tier 2 North itself), while in 2016, promoted to Premier Tier, they won the entire thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, though, Newcastle A have decided to step down from the tournament to pursue more international fixtures, and have handed the baton of British Champs to their B-team, the Whippin' Hinnies. Competing in the Tier 2 North, the Hinnies will have their first game of the Championships &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/233103117140662/"&gt;this weekend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, against Cambridge Rollerbillies [hosted by Rainy City Roller Derby].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Flat Track Stats, the Hinnies have the most difficult spot in the tier; but start-of-season rankings are the least accurate, due to the tendency for roster changes in the off-season, and other significant changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14901 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/02/hinniesvroyalsweden.jpg" alt="hinniesvroyalsweden" width="960" height="460"&gt; The Whippin' Hinnies with Royal Swedish Roller Derby, 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whippin' Hinnies Co-Captain Method Mam talked to us about how the team are feeling about their first Champs challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;strong&gt; Compared to some B teams, the Whippin' Hinnies always have quite a busy schedule, and 2016 continued that trend with plenty of action. What was your highpoint of the previous season?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, that's tough one. We certainly enjoyed playing The Royal Swedish Roller Derby, they were a super fun team and it was an exciting game. We were also really proud to play a double header with our Belters against ARRG All-Stars and All-Star Reserves and to manage a double win at home at the end of last season. ARRG was one of the first teams NRG ever played and are a league we've always looked up to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;strong&gt; The Hinnies are one of two B teams in the Tier 2 North, along with Rainy B. In your case, though, you're replacing the A team as Newcastle's Champs representatives. With the Canny Belters having won the Tier 1 last year, is there additional pressure to live up to the standard they've set?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think the Hinnies feel any extra pressure due to the Belters knock out performance last year. We're one big league; we have three competitive teams now, we practise together, coach each other and celebrate each others' successes. The Hinnies are in it this year for the learning experience and the opportunity to play a super high standard of competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Tier 2 North contains a few teams which the Hinnies have played pretty recently - the aforementioned Rainy B, and your first opponents this weekend, Cambridge Rollerbillies. Both of those teams gave you very tough games last year: how do you feel about facing them again in Champs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excited! Both games were really good and given our ranking differentials we were happy with the results. We also experienced quite different styles of play from these two teams which meant both games were interesting. We can't wait to get stuck into the next 'round' this weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outside of Champs, which admittedly is a pretty packed schedule, is there anything else planned for the Hinnies this year? [You've managed an international bout every year since 2014…]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That would be telling! (entire team adopts air of mystery...) You'll just have to keep an eye on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.org.uk/buy-tickets"&gt;fixtures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; page on our website &lt;img class="_1ift _2560 img" src="https://www.facebook.com/images/emoji.php/v7/zeb/2/16/1f642.png" alt="🙂"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/14/newcastles-hinnies-off-to-champs/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 11:51:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The North Sea and the Stars: Auld Reekie 's and Newcastle's C Teams.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/24/the-north-sea-and-the-stars-auld-reekie-s-and-newcastles-c-teams/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;28&lt;/strong&gt;th of &lt;strong&gt;January&lt;/strong&gt; sees the first full Roller Derby bout of the year in Scotland, and it's looking like being a great match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; have had a long tradition of playing &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; over the years - both their A teams and their B teams have taken on multiple rematches, and both wins and losses (in the case of the All Stars versus Canny Belters, both in the last year!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was inevitable, then, with both leagues launching their C teams in 2016, that it wouldn't be long before they ended up playing each other!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14116" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/astrosvnc1.jpeg" alt="astrosvnc1" width="1300" height="861"&gt; The ASTROs on track in 2016...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie's ASTROs have had a very busy first year, as we covered a month or two back in an interview with their captain [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/12/an-interview-with-astros-captain-princess-die/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;], playing 4 stand-alone bouts (including one over in Belfast), and also a mini-tournament at the end of the year (which they won). Playing at home, as well, the advantages all look like being on their side...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASTROs Captain Princess Die told us, "We are very excited to be back after our incredible win at the ARRGmageddon tournament. It was 8 weeks ago, but we've had our winter break so we're all working intensively to get ourselves game ready! We’ve lost a couple of players since our last game but the newly refreshed team who will face Newcastle are fiercely solid and determined. We are as strong as ever and ready to show Newcastle what we've got and continue ASTRO’s winning form into 2017."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Newcastle's North Cs have had a more sedate opening season, with just two bouts in the last year - a loss against Spa Town, and a win against York Minxters (putting the North Cs somewhere around "high British Champs T4" level). That said, despite the experience differential, Newcastle C have a particular incentive to do well here, as their Captain, McSlay, explained :
"We're very excited to be kicking Newcastle Roller Girls' 2017 season off against our good friends at ARRG. The Whippin' Hinnies (B) and Canny Belters (A) took a double win at home to end our 2016 season and the North Cs are looking to continue that winning streak in our first away game."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, winning isn't everything, and the real point of this event is for both ARRG and Newcastle to find a new excuse to travel to play each other! (With both of their B teams in British Champs this year, we might expect more C team bouts in the future, as well...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event page for this bout is here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/250628665359800/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/250628665359800/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tickets&lt;/strong&gt; are available for £&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2792585"&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, £&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; (£6 concessions) on the door, free entry for under 14’s
Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;14:20&lt;/strong&gt; at ARRG's usual venue of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Meadowbank+Sports+Centre/@55.956619,-3.1584973,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4887b86eb150070f:0x6955a8c9b9a10cc5!8m2!3d55.956619!4d-3.1563086"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium, Edinburgh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/24/the-north-sea-and-the-stars-auld-reekie-s-and-newcastles-c-teams/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 10:52:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash 2017 - The Teams</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/12/euroclash-2017-the-teams/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;When Newcastle Roller Girls announced their intent to host a women's derby equivalent of the Men's European Cup (hosted by their sibling league, Tyne and Fear), there was understandable excitement... but the hosts have been remarkably secretive about the leagues involved, with the only hints being that the attendees were amongst the best teams in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Now, finally, the roster of competitors is announced, so we've made this quick guide to the teams (and will have individual features later on). EuroClash will be March 25th to 26th, at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Walker+Activity+Dome/@54.968707,-1.558266,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487e7068944e76d1:0xe1a6394d9f25325!8m2!3d54.968707!4d-1.556072"&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Newcastle. Tickets available &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.org.uk/buy-tickets/euroclash-2017"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-13774" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/euroclash.jpg" alt="euroclash" width="851" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, who are the teams competing in the first ever &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/365884340424845/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13711 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/newcastlerg_1.png" alt="newcastlerg_1" width="122" height="250"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Starting with the hosts, we have &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;. British Championships 2016 Premier Tier Winners, and currently ranked 76th by WFTDA (13th in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/europe"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and 13th by &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;*), the Canny Belters have had a strong 2016 - competing in the USA for the first time, at Beach Brawl in Florida (losing only to the mighty Rainy City) almost immediately after taking that British Championships win. In fact, the Belters have only lost to two teams in the last year - Rainy City and Edinburgh's Auld Reekie (who they also defeated in a rematch). As the hosts, home team advantage will also help their performance, and it would be a mistake to underestimate their chances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13716 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/leedsrollerderby-09.jpg" alt="leedsrollerderby-09" width="200" height="200"&gt;Staying within the UK, &lt;strong&gt;Leeds Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; are "technically" a new league, formed by merger of Hot Wheel Roller Derby and Leeds Roller Dolls at the end of 2016. Leeds Roller Dolls were ranked 65th by WFTDA, and their European Rankings were 23rd FTS, 22 SRD Rank; whilst Hot Wheel had Euro rankings of 31 and 25 respectively. We &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/19/by-their-powers-combined-they-are-leeds-roller-derby/"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on their merger at the time, and are excited to see what the combined pool of talent can accomplish in a single roster. Leeds Roller Dolls had their second trip to the USA in 2016, performing significantly above expectations; after placing solidly in the middle of the Champs Premier Tier rankings. Hot Wheel, by contrast, played their first European tournament in 2016, attending A Skate Odyssey, where they met surpassed expectations (beating their seeding by 4 places); they also managed to come second-from-top in British Champs Tier 2, clearly on the up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13765 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/mmr1.jpg" alt="mmr" width="222" height="200"&gt;Middlesbrough Milk Rollers&lt;/strong&gt; are possibly the highest ranked English team attending Euro Clash, with an impressive 56th position on the WFTDA rankings (9th in Europe by FTS, and 4th by SRD Rank)! MMR declined to participate in British Champs in 2016, but had an absolutely impressive year of competition, defeating almost all comers (including Connecticut and New Jersey) despite playing away for each and every bout. The only team to defeat them was London B, the Brawl Saints, which is not a bad record at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13730 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/central-city.png" alt="central-city" width="200" height="200"&gt;Central City Rollergirls&lt;/strong&gt; are the 83rd WFTDA ranked team (16th in Europe by SRD, and 20th by FTS), and one of the first Roller Derby leagues in the UK, representing Birmingham. CCR are the second team in this list to have spent their 2016 breaking into the USA via Beach Brawl, where they won more than they lost. They also defeated London B earlier on in the year, still a rare accomplishment for a UK team. The Birmingham team had quite a quiet year by comparison with the hectic adventures of some of the others in this list, and will have a lot of energy for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13735 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tigerbay.jpg" alt="tigerbay" width="200" height="183"&gt;Moving outside England, Wales' &lt;strong&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/strong&gt; are the best that their country has, ranked 75th by WFTDA (14th FTS, 12th SRD Rank in Europe). Declining to compete in British Champs in 2016, TBB instead competed against a wide range of European opponents, defeating London B, but narrowly failing against the mighty Rainy City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;After a lull in 2015, the general feeling is that Cardiff's all-stars have regained their best performance and are ready to go further in 2017; they're also a strong component of the current, and very strong, Welsh National Team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13740 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/arrg-logo.png" alt="arrg-logo" width="200" height="89"&gt;And representing the northern part of the UK, Edinburgh's &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; are the strongest team in Scotland, placing 60th in WFTDA (16th FTS, 20th SRD Rank in Europe). Auld Reekie made some waves last year by declining the offer to compete in WFTDA Playoffs, using the time to work more on their own performance - and they also declined British Champs 2016 as well. They did spend some time in the USA earlier in the year, competing at The Big O 2016, but had perhaps a more impressive start to 2016 where they defeated both our hosts Newcastle and Ireland's finest, Dublin. They'll be wanting to recapture that energy for the start of 2017... and will have a boost from their significant presence in the Team Scotland training squad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;For our remaining teams, we have to head outside the UK, so by distance, we first have...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13744 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/drd-logo.png" alt="drd-logo" width="200" height="213"&gt;...&lt;strong&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;, ranked 86th by WFTDA (but 11th in Europe by FTS and SRD Rank). Dublin have had a very exciting 2016, playing their first bouts in the USA at (yes!) Beach Brawl and winning against everyone except Newcastle Roller Girls! This performance didn't slow them down at all, as they also had one of the busiest schedules of 2016 as well, playing 15 bouts over the year, 10 of them away! With strong representation in Team Ireland, the Dublin team is definitely a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13749 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/paris.png" alt="paris" width="200" height="200"&gt;Moving a little further into Europe, &lt;strong&gt;Paris Rollergirls&lt;/strong&gt; are one of the two most exciting teams in France, ranked 71st by WFTDA, but 8th (or 9th) in Europe by FTS (SRD Rank). Hotly tipped for greatness in 2017 by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://thederbyapex.com/trending-french-roller-derby-56c5e691b036"&gt;The Derby Apex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the potential strength of Paris is also reflected in the performance of the French National Team, which they are a significant contributor to - Equipe de France is yet to lose a game with their current roster! Paris also burst onto the USA scene in 2016 at... (you've guessed it!) Beach Brawl, losing only the single bout. Much of the rest of their busy 2016 schedule was consumed by the French Nationale Elite Tier, which they topped, winning each and every bout in the 2015/6 season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13756 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/bcrd-bear-city-roller-derby_0.png" alt="bcrd-bear-city-roller-derby_0" width="200" height="200"&gt;From Berlin, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;Bear City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; are also one of the older teams in Europe, established back in 2008 . Ranked 50th by WFTDA (and 12th in Europe by FTS, 14th by SRD Rank), the Berlin Bombshells are the only team in this competition to have competed in WFTDA (Division 2) Playoffs in 2016, placing a strong 5th out of the 10 competitors, and defeating 4th seed Cincinnati on the way. In fact, Bear City spent more time competing in the USA than anywhere else in 2016, as the majority of their remaining bouts were at the Midwest BrewHaHa, with only two bouts in Europe (against Kallio Rolling Rainbow and Glasgow Roller Derby). Whilst Bear City the league also won the German Nationals (the Bundesliga), we believe this was strictly an exhibition team which differed from BCRD's normal A roster...
EuroClash sees the Bombshells return to Europe to take on the other rising stars of the continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;But that's not all, as we also have the excitement of a National Teams bout as well!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13777 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/ireland.jpg" alt="ireland" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13779 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/scotland.png" alt="scotland" width="200" height="200"&gt;Teams &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; met at the Road to TBC in Cardiff this November, with the Irish taking the win... but neither team had finalised their roster at that point. This rematch is taking place after final selections for Team Scotland [their selection bout is February 11th], and the Scots will be keen to show what they can do with the team that will be heading to the World Cup in Manchester. Meanwhile, Team Ireland were exceptionally green at the Road to TBC, and they will be that much more experienced as a squad by March...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We will be posting interviews with each of the teams competing at EuroClash over the next few weeks, to get into more depth about each of the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;* European rankings on SRD Rank computed from the set of all Women's Travel Teams in Europe known to the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bear city roller derby</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>euroclash</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>middlesbrough milk rollers</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>paris rollergirls</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/12/euroclash-2017-the-teams/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 19:15:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs Schedule 2017</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/03/british-champs-schedule-2017/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, by now you're probably aware that the British Championships 2017 schedule is out (it's hosted here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/2017-british-roller-derby-champs-fixtures/"&gt;http://www.britishchamps.com/2017-british-roller-derby-champs-fixtures/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in a big, searchable, list).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the list is pretty long, we thought we'd pull out some key dates for you (and also tip our hand a bit as to teams and divisions we'll be focussing a little more on - Talk Derby To Me will be continuing their excellent overall Champs coverage this year for those who want to cover the whole thing):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; kicks off on the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Feb&lt;/strong&gt;ruary, with a double header featuring Tiger Bay Brawlers against newly-merged Leeds Roller Derby, and Birmingham Blitz Dames against Bristol Roller Derby hosted by TBB in Cardiff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; also begins a few weeks later in Wales, as South West Silures host the Crash Test Brummies on the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, by then, most of the other Tiers will have had their first bouts, with the whole British Champs schedule starting on the &lt;strong&gt;4th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Feb&lt;/strong&gt;ruary, as the &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 2&lt;/strong&gt; begins with Barrow Infernos hosting Southern Discomfort B (the first B team in the Men's tiers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friends of the blog, &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;, see their B-team, the Whippin' Hinnies, compete for the first time in &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 2 North&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch, in a battle of the B-teams against Rainy City Roller Derby's formidable Tender Hooligans; hosted by Wirral Roller Derby, this is also somewhat Manchester area themed, as the second bout of the fixture is hosts versus Manchester Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you'll have to wait until April to see some &lt;em&gt;Scottish Women&lt;/em&gt;'s action in the Champs, as &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; host a &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; double header on the &lt;strong&gt;22nd&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Apr&lt;/strong&gt;il. &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;' Reserves are travelling up to Aberdeen to take on the hosts, whilst Furness Firecrackers and Halifax Bruising Banditas will be coming up to play each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scottish Men&lt;/em&gt;'s Derby also has its first showing in Champs that month, as Men Behaving Derby host a &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; fixture on the &lt;strong&gt;16th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Apr&lt;/strong&gt;il; pitting &lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt;' Skelpies against the hosts, followed by Teeside Skate Invaders facing off against &lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, whilst the &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 4&lt;/strong&gt; North starts its series a few weeks earlier, we'll be following friends of the blog (and some of our first interviewees!) &lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt; - their first bout is on the &lt;strong&gt;25th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch against Wakey Wheeled Cats, in Mansfield; the second bout is hosts against Durham Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>york minxters</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/03/british-champs-schedule-2017/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 09:44:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls: Home and Away</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/18/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-and-away/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With winter fast approaching, Edinburgh's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.arrg.co.uk"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are not slowing down in their schedule one bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend,&lt;strong&gt; October 22nd&lt;/strong&gt;, Auld Reekie travel down to Newcastle to play the second "double fixture" of the month. On the 8th, ARRG A and B took on London B and C; this time, Auld Reekie's A and B teams &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1775971736017021/"&gt;will be playing their opposite numbers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from British Champs Premier Tier Champions (2016), &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.org.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-9658 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14324272_1145590692150681_7010713698933643507_o.jpg" alt="14324272_1145590692150681_7010713698933643507_o" width="3366" height="1245"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our ranking scheme, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/08/ranking-the-world-and-other-fts-visualisations/3"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, places Auld Reekie's All-Stars and Newcastle's Canny Belters at very close rank indeed (107th and 101st in our international, cross-gender rankings, in fact), and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85476/rankings"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; agrees, giving Newcastle A just a 53% chance of winning using the larger European dataset.
The B bout might be a fraction safer for the home team - we rank the Whippin' Hinnies at 39 spots above ARRG B, and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85477/rankings"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; suggests that the hosts have an 87% probability of victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can make it down to Newcastle's&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Walker+Activity+Dome/@54.968707,-1.5582607,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487e7068944e76d1:0xe1a6394d9f25325!8m2!3d54.968707!4d-1.556072"&gt; Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, then doors open at &lt;strong&gt;11:45am, &lt;/strong&gt;tickets &lt;strong&gt;£10 for two&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.org.uk/buy-tickets/22-oct-canny-belters-vs-arrg-a-whippin-hinnies-vs-arrg-b"&gt;online from the NRG website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;£7 each&lt;/strong&gt; on the door (under 12s free).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, only a few weeks later, the All-Star Reserves will be playing again, this time hosting &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.granitecityrollerderby.co.uk/"&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s Northern Fights on &lt;strong&gt;November 5th&lt;/strong&gt; at their usual venue,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Meadowbank+Sports+Centre/@55.956619,-3.1584973,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4887b86eb150070f:0x6955a8c9b9a10cc5!8m2!3d55.956619!4d-3.1563086"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The Fights, GCRD A, have had an exceptional year, topping the British Champs Local North tier and earning promotion to Tier 3 in 2017. (You can read more about their year &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/08/23/granite-citys-sparkling-year-peaks-with-glasgow-rematch/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-9663 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14581343_10157587090110224_3258736097020786394_n.jpg" alt="14581343_10157587090110224_3258736097020786394_n" width="784" height="295"&gt;
Whilst Granite City will be looking to maintain their 14 month win streak, the Reserves will be keen to defend the honour of Edinburgh, after a narrow loss to Dundee earlier in the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The statistics are on Granite City's side - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/08/ranking-the-world-and-other-fts-visualisations/3"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; places them more than 200 places above the Reserves, and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85859/rankings"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; gives them a 88% probability of victory. However, Auld Reekie tend to dig especially deep when playing at home, so we're not going to rule out an upset, especially for their last bout of the season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this event, the event page is: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1594409394188095/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1594409394188095/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;1.20pm&lt;/strong&gt;, with tickets &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; (plus booking fee) &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2684699"&gt;online from Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;£8&lt;/strong&gt; on the door (concessions available, and under-14s free).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/18/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-and-away/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 10:35:26 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>