<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about news)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/news.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 11:56:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>UKRDA Elections Update: your new Directors!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/26/ukrda-elections-update-your-new-directors/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a democratic organisation, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://ukrda.org.uk/"&gt;UK Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; undergoes a yearly AGM, in which vacancies for its Directorships can be filled by vote within the member leagues. The most recent AGM was held this month, 5th of June, and resulted in a particularly large number of changes to the Directorships, due to retirements and the filling of previously empty posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're giving you a quick overview of the current Directorships and their holders, to help you get to know your organisation.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26918" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/ukrdadirectors2018.jpg" alt="UKRDADirectors2018" width="960" height="720"&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Halo Jones - Secretary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halo Jones remains in the position of Secretary for UKRDA from before the AGM. Outside of UKRDA, she is well known in the world of NSOing around the Oxford area (especially for &lt;a href="https://www.oxfordwheelsofgory.co.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oxford Wheels of Gory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), and beyond. A nominee for the Talk Derby To Me NSO Listener Awards in 2017 and 2016, she has officiated at multiple high level events, including the 2017 MRDA Championships, and both the Roller Derby World Cup and the Men's Roller Derby World Cup 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maw Deuce - Director for Internal Communication&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maw Deuce continues in her role as Director for Internal Communication from the last elections. The longest term member of the UKRDA family, Maw previously served as the UKRDA National Squads chair, responsible for interactions with and support of the affiliated national teams, and has held additional roles before then.
Outside of UKRDA, Maw is a member of &lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and a referee and official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rollin Rat - Director for Officials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rollin Rat continues as a Director from before the AGM, moving from the position of Director of Policy &amp;amp; Strategy to Director of Officials. Outside of UKRDA, he is a Referee for &lt;a href="https://centralcityrollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Birmingham, and has refereed at many high level events, including the Roller Derby World Cup 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stat Man - Director for Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stat Man has a long history in Roller Derby, as both an Announcer and an Official. As well as starting one of the first attempts to rate and rank European teams, he was one of the individuals responsible for establishing the ongoing &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;s, of which he remains the Chair of the Organising Committee. He may also have been involved in the short-lived attempt to have a roller derby team based in Sealand. He has also continued to announce at high level events, including both World Cups this year.
Stat Man has also previously served as Executive Director of Sanctioning and Games for the MRDA (2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smacktivist - Director for Communications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smacktivist is new to the Director of Communications role. She hails from &lt;a href="http://rollerbillies.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cambridge Rollerbillies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where she's currently Line Up Manager for their B-Team, the Punt Rockers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dorkmistress - Director for External Engagement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dorkmistress has a very strong history in Roller Derby, as both an Announcer and an Official. She has previously Managed several iterations of Team Wales Roller Derby, as well as announcing for &lt;a href="http://www.swanseacityrollerderby.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swansea City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and announcing and officiating for &lt;a href="http://www.sws.pizza/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;South Wales Silures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; she's also been seen announcing across a gamut of high level events, including the most recent Men's Roller Derby World Cup, and Newcastle Roller Girls' EuroClash tournament.
As well as UKRDA External Engagement, she currently holds the position of &lt;a href="http://www.rollerderbynationscommittee.org/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roller Derby Nations Committee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Regional Representative for Northern Europe, representing all the World Cup Nations from that region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buckfast - Head of Tech&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buckfast is new to the role of Head of Tech (which is not a Directoral role, and has been semi-empty since the last AGM). He's relatively new to Roller Derby - having recently begun Bench Coaching at &lt;a href="https://www.yorkminxters.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>agm</category><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>in the news</category><category>news</category><category>ukrda</category><category>ukrda directors</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/26/ukrda-elections-update-your-new-directors/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 11:22:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Big Blether: Scotland Together</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/18/the-big-blether-scotland-together/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's often been commented that Scotland has seen some of the more dramatic growth (and changes) in Roller Derby, with respect to its population. Since the first league started in Glasgow in 2007, Roller Derby has spread across the Nation - but not always uniformly, or consistently. Whilst there's certainly a lot of Roller Derby in Scotland now - with 19 leagues in existence (by one count) now - communication and organisation across the community has not always been as good as it could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;October 7th&lt;/strong&gt;, in Edinburgh's Charteris Centre, three people aim to change this. Auld Reekie Roller Girls' Crazylegs and (Steph) Skinner, and Glasgow Roller Derby's head referee Candy Moho, are organising what they hope will be the first of a regular series of gatherings of the Scottish Roller Derby Community in one place and one time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-24409 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/screen-shot-2017-09-13-at-16-17-08.png" alt="Screen Shot 2017-09-13 at 16.17.08" width="335" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Big Blether&lt;/em&gt;, as it's now known, aims to bring together all of the extant leagues and clubs in Scotland, as well as others in the sport, in order to share and discuss the future and present of the sport. Every active league in Scotland has been invited to the event as part of the organisation process,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to two-thirds of the Organisers - thrice Team Scotland skater,  founding Roller Derby Nations Committee rep, and founding Auld Reekie Roller Girls member, &lt;em&gt;Crazylegs&lt;/em&gt;; and long-standing Glasgow Roller Derby Head Referee and organiser of the Scottish Roller Derby Events Spreadsheet, &lt;em&gt;Candy Moho&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crazylegs was inspired to kickstart this idea at the last European Rollerderby Organisational Conference, as she told us. "I guess for me the inspiration came from EROC - I love attending that event, and I guess the more I go to events like that and attend sessions, and deliver talks,  I kind of think, we've got such a compact community in Scotland - and I don't think we take advantage of it enough.
Our league [ARRG] gets so much out of events like EROC in terms of knowledge and new ideas to refresh you. It's so much easier for us to get together in Scotland - the leagues in Australia might find it harder to all meet up, for example - but we're so close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chatted to Candy at the end of EROC, and she mentioned that she'd been thinking of something similar, so it was in my mind from then."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candy, meanwhile, had a slightly different perspective. "My main focus was the Officials side, off of the back of a project I'd done for the Open Uni. And also being in the Event Organising Group, the Interleague Liasion group, a lot of the issues there - it just seemed it would be easier to get people in the same room to talk to each other!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;One of the things I am planning to do at The Big Blether is to present the findings from my OU project, which focussed on Scottish Derby Officials - I've not had a chance to pass on the results of that to the community, and I thought this is the perfect forum to do it, and make the results public after. That took in feedback from Officials as well as skaters from leagues. A lot of the stuff from that is still very relevant, and it's relevant to UK officials as well."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Unlike EROC's speaker-centered sessions, The Big Blether is intended to foster a less hierarchical approach - each topic will have a "facilitator" to moderate, but will emphasise communication and discussion between peers, not a top-down dissemination of from on-high.&lt;/p&gt;
Topics on the agenda currently cover the spectrum of community concerns and interests, from best practice in Training, through the creation of better links for interleague support and with local communities, and how to move the sport on in terms of recognition on both local and National/International scales; however, in keeping with the design of the event, there are no topics which are out of bounds if attendees wish to discuss them.
&lt;p&gt;Speaking to the organisers, again, they each have their own favourite areas from the menu presented. For Crazylegs, a key topic is governance and organisation, on all scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We want to cover topics like League Governance - so: the legalities of how you set up a league, how you structure a league, what works for different leagues, of different sizes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I guess leading on from that you'd look at&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt; sports &lt;/span&gt;governance - as in governing bodies, as in the national teams, UKRDA, WFTDA [MRDA], just I think maybe putting a bit of information out there for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I think there's a lot of myths out there concerning the various bodies - but we also need to talk about what Scotland itself needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I know Stef's driving force for this comes from her job, she's a community sports officer, and she's been has been doing a lot of research around the growth of sport, how we can better use Sport Scotland, and have better links with them for funding and support. We were also discussing working on having clear pathways, to show people how they can get to where they want to go - if that's high level competition, or having fun - from where they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;And I think training as well - what support setups different leagues need, if we feel that there needs to be more information out there about training and structures, and how to set things up from beginning to getting wherever your league or team wants to go."&lt;/p&gt;
Candy, with her other hat on, is most concerned with another topic. "On the Events side: getting a Scottish Tournament (doing another "Highland Fling", perhaps) but also the topic of if we need to look into a League structure - as they have in Germany  and France. I think you tend to find that when you have that kind of structure, and people working well together, then you also drive the sport, and the level of competition as well. "
&lt;p&gt;But, most of all, the event is about everyone meeting up and building the community links that can make Scottish Derby stronger together. As Crazylegs notes, "having a relaxed chat to people that you don't know, but you've heard of their leagues - if you get that kind of face-to-face conversation with people you've only interacted with on social media, then you make better connections, and everyone learns something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The venue's amazing, it's close to town, we'll get some nice stuff going on in the breaks to build connections - and we'll be providing a delicious lunch!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Charteris Centre can be found &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Greyfriars+Charteris+Centre/@55.9455414,-3.1817633,19.53z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x104319695d91d9d9!8m2!3d55.9456793!4d-3.1812937"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here on Google Maps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
Sign up for leagues (who are already contacted) is for the &lt;strong&gt;23rd September&lt;/strong&gt;, with potential for other slots for non-league attendees after the initial numbers are known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All questions can be sent to the event organisers at &lt;a href="mailto:scottishderbyevent@gmail.com"&gt;scottishderbyevent@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial shortlist of topics is:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Training: Creation of clear pathways and sharing best practice&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sport recognition (Leagues, National/International Governing Bodies and National Teams)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Club governance; sharing best practices / resources / contacts, league support.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Scottish Events Scheduling: game scheduling, events, opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Partnership working, local communities&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Officiating: recruitment and retention, development pathways, national association&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Volunteering (development, pathways, recruitment, training)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
The organisers would like to thank Auld Reekie Roller Girls for funding both the event, and travel subsidies for the more distant leagues.&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>news</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>the big blether</category><category>training</category><category>upcoming events</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/18/the-big-blether-scotland-together/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 07:09:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UKRDA announces new Transgender Policy, Liasion Roles.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/04/16/ukrda-announces-new-transgender-policy-liasion-roles/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you may have seen elsewhere, UKRDA has announced the ratification of a new Transgender Policy, which will be published for non-UKRDA members to see in due course. They have also appointed a Transgender Liaison co-held by two of Glasgow Roller Derby's own:  Jodie Stanley and Freyja Gosnold, both of whom have huge experience and expertise in LGBT topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is definitely a very positive thing, and look forward to seeing the policy document itself. Certainly, the rapid development of a Transgender Policy given the relative youth of UKRDA and Modern Roller Derby once again shows how positive and inclusive Derby can be, especially compared to other sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article was edited after the fact to include a link to the Derby News Network article, which includes a copy of the policy document itself ( &lt;a href="http://www.derbynewsnetwork.com/2014/04/ukrda_ratifies_no_questions_asked_trans_policy"&gt;http://www.derbynewsnetwork.com/2014/04/ukrda_ratifies_no_questions_asked_trans_policy&lt;/a&gt; ). Having had a chance to read it quickly, it seems to be as well thought out and constructed as I could expect such a policy to be, and is definitely at the forefront of such policies in sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full UKRDA press release is included below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roller derby organisation unveils transgender policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United Kingdom Roller Derby Association (UKRDA) has today [Wednesday, April 16] announced the appointment of their new Transgender Liaison and the ratification of their Transgender Policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The policy creates a uniform standard of treatment of transgender skaters, and ensures the protection and safety of transgender skaters throughout the UK, with UKRDA member leagues committing to adhere to the policy. This includes safeguarding the confidentiality of trans* skaters, and ensuring that they are supported not just by the law, but by UKRDA policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mistress Malicious, chairwoman of the UKRDA, welcomed the announcement. She said: “This policy makes the UKRDA one of the most forward-thinking and inclusive sports organisations in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Skaters in our member leagues come from all walks of life and with this policy, we ensure that transgender skaters feel safe, supported and welcome within the UK roller derby community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To oversee the integration of the Transgender Policy, the UKRDA has appointed Glasgow Roller Derby skater Jodie Stanley as the organisation's Transgender Liaison. Jodie is a policy manager within a national LGBT organisation. "I hold a Senior Management position within a national LGBT organisation, and bring to the role vast experience in creating and influencing national and local policies and frameworks, ensuring that they represent lgbt people as widely as possible and reflect their differing needs."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jodie will be co-performing this role with fellow GRD skater Freya Gosnold, who Freya has a great personal and political investment in trans* advocacy and support, and will be a wonderful asset to this role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jodie said: “I'm excited that UK roller derby is creating a breakthrough arena for transgender representation in our sport. Transgender people statistically engage far less in sport, partly due to structural discrimination - and I am delighted that roller derby is the sport which is breaking the barriers of gender, making it all about the sport and not about anatomy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freya added: “Roller Derby has the potential to really pave the way for trans&lt;em&gt; representation in sport, at all levels of competition, and I am thrilled to have the opportunity to use my experience as a trans&lt;/em&gt; person and activist to support our sport and our community on this journey.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>news</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/04/16/ukrda-announces-new-transgender-policy-liasion-roles/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 14:36:59 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>