<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about nnrg)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/nnrg.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 11:56:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Nasty Nessies One Year Later: Scarlett O'Horror/Scarolott</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/18/nasty-nessies-one-year-later-scarlett-ohorrorscarolott/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing in our look back at how our &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/18/nasty-nessies-one-year-later-scarlett-ohorrorscarolott/nastynessiesrollergirls.wordpress.com"&gt;Nasty Nessies&lt;/a&gt; diarists feel now, one year later than their initial diary, we have the case of Scarlet O'Horror (or is it Scarolott?). &lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/06/23/monthly-diary-of-a-league-nasty-nessies-in-june-scarolott/"&gt;Her original diary is here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/skate-pic.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-2524 " alt="Scarolott at practice, yesterday." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/skate-pic.jpg?w=614" width="430" height="575"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Scarolott at practice, yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's been more than a year since you became one of the first Nasty Nessies.  Looking back at yourself then, what advice would you give your earlier self?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I would sit myself down and say: you will LOVE this sport, so buy better gear to start with. You're just going to have to keep upgrading otherwise. Also, working on your crossovers pays huge rewards!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last year, you mentioned that most of your derby heroes were drawn from bouts and training videos you'd seen online. Since then, have your heroes changed, as you've hopefully managed to see more derby first-hand?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a blast at ARRG's bootcamp - all the women who were teaching there were wonderful and really encouraging. I think my heroes of the moment though are my team mates, who have kept us going through recruitment, getting through mins, and encouraging us all on our way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Of course, you're now mins-passed (under the old WFTDA mins, at least ;) ), and so one difference between last year and how is that you'll have been scrimming. Given your enjoyment of blocking last time we spoke, I guess you're enjoying scrimming even more?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I LOVE it!! We've been to Dundee's open scrim, and some of the girls were able to scrim in a mixed team in Edinburgh, and it's just such an adrenaline kick to get on track and be working in a team. It'll be even better when it's an all-Nessie team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Around the time of the last diary, you'd just decided to change your skatename from Scarlett O'Horror to Scarolott, as that skatename was already in use. Now we hear you're thinking of changing back...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I'd always loved Gone With The Wind, so was gutted that my chosen name of Scarlett O'Horror was already in use by a skater in the States, so went and chose a new name. However, I've recently had some advice that some skaters have agreed to share a name - especially if they're in different continents and unlikely to bout together. So - if anyone from the TSDD is reading, I'm trying to get in touch to see if your Scarlett O'Horror would mind a Kiwi/Scottish namesake with a different bouting number...!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting out, the Nessies got some help from the derby community, with Granite City running the first bootcamp to push your skills up. Now you're in a position to pay it back, what have you been adding to the derby community?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NNRG went up to Shetland to help out when they first started up, so I'm really looking forward to them coming to see us for a friendly scrim. I'm doing my best to get as many folk involved as I can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What're your plans for the future? The Nessies have been tight-lipped about their plans for the next year, although we've seen the first ever public bout featuring two of your skaters in the past month! Will we see a Nasty Nessies bout by the end of the year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;It would be awesome if we could. In the meantime, we're getting more skaters through mins, and will keep going to open scrims when we can - we're all really keen to get a bout up and running!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>nnrg</category><category>one year later</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/18/nasty-nessies-one-year-later-scarlett-ohorrorscarolott/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 09:39:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Nasty Nessies 1 Year Later: Nat-orious Red</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/02/nasty-nessies-1-year-later-nat-orious-red/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Continuing our new series looking back at the &lt;a href="http://nastynessiesrollergirls.wordpress.com/"&gt;Nasty Nessies&lt;/a&gt; monthly diarists from the past year to see how 12 months of experience has changed them, we come to the most strikingly coiffed member of the league, Nat-orious Red!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/241375_2587400860612_1101822270_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-2399 " alt="Nat-orious Red, Santa, and Irn Bruzer at the Nessies' Christmas skate." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/241375_2587400860612_1101822270_o.jpg?w=614" width="430" height="613"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Nat-orious Red, Santa, and Irn Bruzer at the Nessies' Christmas skate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's been more than a year since you became one of the first Nasty Nessies.  Looking back at yourself then, with your worries about being clumsy and falling, what advice would you give your earlier self?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;I would tell myself to remember that its roller derby and everyone falls thats why we are sooo well padded, i am actually impressed though that i never was as clumsy as i thought i would be, i can skate better than i can walk!!&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now you've been skating and absorbing Derby for longer, have you picked up any Derby heroes along the way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I am going to say yes and they are both my closest team members, Bee-Yatch and Irn Bruzer just because they have both been there since the beginning and through all the hard work and struggling to recruit they are still just as committed to the league and if it wasn't for them I'm not sure the nessie's would still be around.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A year ago, you were focussing on endurance, and aiming for your 25/5. What are your current challenges, as a mins-passed skater with much more experience?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The biggest challenge since passing mins is keeping team moral up whilst recruiting for newbies so we have a big enough team to bout soon! Bee-yatch and myself do have our first bout on saturday which we are really excited about but at same time we are sad our first game isn't as Nessie's with all our lovely members.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting out, the Nessies got some help from the derby community, with Granite City running the first bootcamp to push your skills up. Now you're in a position to pay it back, what have you been adding to the derby community?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Our training committee traveled  to shetland in december to do a bootcamp for the lovely shetland roller derby, it was a great day and the all the team were such fast learners they picked everything up really fast and were such lovely hosts.  We are looking forward to them passing their mins and visiting us!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What're your plans for the future? The Nessies have been tight-lipped about their plans for the next year…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;As for the Nessie's in the future... You'll just have to stay tuned. &lt;em&gt;(Ed: In fact, a little birdie tells us that the Nessies will be appearing somewhere sooner rather than later...)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>nnrg</category><category>one year later</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/02/nasty-nessies-1-year-later-nat-orious-red/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 11:59:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Happy Mother's Day!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/10/happy-mothers-day/</link><dc:creator>frockyhorror</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h6&gt;To all the inspirational Scottish Derby Maws (and Maws-to-be!)&lt;/h6&gt;
So, this is my 9th Mother's Day (as a mum, obviously - it's my 37th one as a daughter!), and all I want from today is peace and quiet! And breakfast in bed. And maybe some chocolates.
&lt;p&gt;Being a mum is awesome! Don't get me wrong, it's not all breakfast in bed, and cards and chocolates. It's the hardest, most challenging job I've ever had - but it's also the most rewarding. 9 months of sacrificing all the fun stuff you love to do is well worth it - right? Well, I don't know about that. My first pregnancy was fairly short - 3 months to be exact. I was 26 weeks 'gone' with my son before we knew I was pregnant. So during that first vital 6 months of my baby's development I was blissfully unaware of his existance and was therefore doing all the 'wrong' things. Drinking, dancing, cycling, camping, eating tuna, peanuts and soft cheese (not together - boak), and just having fun. If I'd been part of a derby league at that time I would have been skating, and I wouldn't have been cautious about it, because I had no idea I was pregnant! Pregancy number 2 was quite different. I knew straight away (at about week 5) and although I had living, breathing proof that you don't need to wrap yourself in cotton wool during pregnancy, I was a wee bit more cautious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This rather revealing insight into my private life brings me, tenuously, to the point of my Mother's Day blog - skating during pregnancy! During the 2 years I've been involoved in roller derby, all the pregnant skaters I know stopped skating immediately. I'm of the opinion that this is the sensible thing to do - after all, derby is a contact sport and no-one wants to see a pregnant skater get injured. Roller derby is one of those wonderful all-inclusive sports, so there's no need for pregnant skaters to disappear off the radar for 9 months. There are so many ways to stay involved off-skates that mums-to-be can remain right in the thick of things for the duration of their pregnancy. Bench, Line-Up, committees, baking - you could well wonder how you ever had time to skate pre-pregnancy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what about those who want the best of both worlds? It's well documented that remaining active and fit during pregnancy is a good thing. In fact, the &lt;a href="http://www.nhs.uk/conditions/pregnancy-and-baby/pages/pregnancy-exercise.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;NHS&lt;/a&gt; encourages mums to be to keep up their normal physical activies and sports for as long as they're comfortable. If skating is part of your normal physical activity, then with a bit of caution, is it necessary to stop straightaway?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently had a chat about this with Irn Bruzer from &lt;a href="http:/http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/tag/nasty-nessies-roller-girls//" target="_blank"&gt;Nasty Nessies &lt;/a&gt;who is currently 17 weeks pregnant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-384" alt="Nasty Nessies Chair Irn-Bruzer" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/10/laurna-600x400.jpg?w=201" width="201" height="300"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, huge congratulations on your pregnancy! &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did your Nasty Nessies team-mates react to the news?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color:#3366ff;"&gt;They were all over the moon for me which was great. I was mostly worried about telling Bee-Yatch and Nat-orious Red as we have all been together from the very start and was worried how they would react. They were so happy for me though so made it a happy time :) &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you stopped skating?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#3366ff;"&gt;I have not stopped skating yet, but I am not on track any more. I am confined to the middle for now. Although I do get a few careful laps in while the others kit up.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you done much research into skating (recreationally or derby) while pregnant? If so, has that helped influence any of your decisions regarding on skates or off?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color:#3366ff;"&gt;I have spoken to a few other skaters who have become pregnant but they have all stopped straight away  The only person that I know so far who has continued to skate was an American skater. I understand why the others stopped and I understand how people will feel that I have not, but everyone is different. I do not have a time scale when to stop, I think I will know when it comes, but not yet. I'm not trying to prove anything, I just don't feel that I need to yet. I am not doing any contact or on track, I am not putting anyone in danger and I am very aware of my surroundings. My midwife knows my plans and I was told that starting new exercise routines or sports are not reccomended but just toning down what your body is used to is fine. Well my body is used to skating, and so will my baby hehe.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;I know you're very passionate about Nasty Nessies - how will you be applying that passion to an off-skates role? And what off-skates role (if any) will that be? &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color:#3366ff;"&gt;For now, I am helping with our fantastic newbies and with coaching. I will take on any role off-skates that I can do in the near future, Hopefully I will bench manage our first bout sometime but time will tell ;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Have you given any thought to when you'll return to skates?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#3366ff;"&gt;I hope to be back on skates as soon as possible, even if its only for five minutes :) I was chatting to one of the girls last night ans we were joking about an active birth on skates! How awesome? I think the hospital may frown about that though! &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you think you'll still be able to commit the same time to derby as before?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color:#3366ff;"&gt;I hope to be able to commit as much as I can, I mean, babies sleep a lot right? And you can do lots online and via laptop. I don't think I can plan how much I can do, best to just take it as it comes, but I still plan to be a very familiar face within the team whatever happens.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Have you chatted to any other Scottish "derby-moms" who have recently given birth? If so, have you been given any good advice that you'd like to pass on to others?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color:#3366ff;"&gt;I have spoken to a few of the girls from Dundee who have had babies, just really how they have kept committed to the team and went back when they are ready which is good. I expect there have been many pregnancies in derby where the girls have never gone back from some reason or another and I will make sure that doesn't happen to me. Even if the worst happens and I cannot skate competitively again, I will still be involved somehow, its too much part of my life now to give up.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any Scottish "derby-mom" heroes? (Skaters with kids, that still find the time to help run a league, train, coach and bout?) What makes them so inspirational?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color:#3366ff;"&gt;I think the one that seemed to do the most up until birth and now back on skates is Crown Jules from Dundee. I went to a bout in November and she was Bench Managing while heavily pregnant. Definitely someone to admire.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color:#3366ff;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#3366ff;"&gt;I'm aware there may be mixed reactions to my interview but I feel that everyone is different and what works for you and feels right is always best. But each to their own. I would never put myself or my baby in any danger and I don't feel that being on skates out of everyone's way is doing that. Also I'm a clumsy oaf, I can get into more harm walking down the stairs! Also I have a very supportive partner and fantastic team! :)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Whatever your feelings on skating during pregnancy, there's no denying Bruzer has really thought this through. And I think that's the key. Life is a series of risks - some you can control, and others that you can't. By thinking through the risks you can control and being open and discussing your plans with your league (and your midwife!), then maybe recreational skating is something of a third option. I don't think anyone would be able to skate for 9 months of a pregnancy - just putting your skates on in the third tri-mester would represent a significant challenge, but in the early days of pregnancy, tentative laps around the track while others are kitting up might be a way to "wind down" your exercise routine.
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Next time: I'm looking for skaters who are returning to the track after having a baby. If you'd like to share your story, then please get in touch.
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
In the meantime - Happy Mother's Day :-) Enjoy the day with the weans, whether they be kids, cats, dogs, guinea pigs, chickens, fish ...
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>nnrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/10/happy-mothers-day/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 07:00:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Nasty Nessies 1 Year Later: Bee-Yatch</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/02/21/nasty-nessies-1-year-later-bee-yatch/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/02/21/nasty-nessies-1-year-later-bee-yatch/nastynessiesrollergirls.wordpress.com"&gt;Nasty Nessies&lt;/a&gt; founder Irn Bruzer launched our series of retrospective interviews with previous Nessie monthly diarists in Jan, this month we have &lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/03/21/monthly-diary-of-a-league-nasty-nessies-in-march-bee-yatch/"&gt;Bee-Yatch&lt;/a&gt; to talk about how her feelings for derby have changed over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/02/comic-con.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2213" alt="Bee-Yatch (centre) promoting the Nessies at Inverness Comic Con." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/02/comic-con.jpg" width="453" height="548"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Bee-Yatch (centre) promoting the Nessies at Inverness Comic Con.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like many skaters, you first encountered Roller Derby through watching "Whip It". Now you're mins-passed and scrimming, how do you feel about the reality of derby, compared with the image you first experienced?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reality of derby is much better than any film! Getting to know a great bunch of girls and to do a sport that I never imagined I would be capable of is great. It’s hard work and requires a lot of commitment but I love every second of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now you've been skating and absorbing Derby for longer, have you picked up any Derby heroes or inspirations along the way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspiration for me comes from my own team mates, they share the good, the bad and the ugly and are always there to help you up and push you past the mental block that can prevent you from moving forward. I genuinely couldn’t ask for a better bunch of mishmashed people! As for heroes, well anyone who plays Roller Derby is an instant hero to me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The last time we talked, you mentioned that the most difficult and important challenges for you had been training related - building endurance and building skills and confidence. Looking back a year, would you give yourself different advice now than you thought then?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My advice to myself would be that everyone learns at a different pace, some people pick things up simply by watching then trying it themselves and others have to break it down more, either way keep on trying and never give up. You just have to learn to get up, dust yourself down and keep on going, you will get there in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, following on from that, how do you see yourself as a skater now; what are your current challenges and inspirations?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current challenge is to learn to put together all we have learned in training and apply it to the game. It’s good to build on endurance and skills but you need to know what to do with it all. There’s so much to think about, strategy, where you should be on the track, where’s your jammer, where’s their jammer, who is trying to push you off the track, who is about to land a hit on you….phew it’s a lot to think about/put into action all at once! ;-) How do I see myself as a skater now…hmm I think I will always be a newbie at heart!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Nessies have, of course, recruited more fresh meat since we talked. Being one of the Experienced Skaters in the league, how do you feel about the new blood coming in? (Are they scarily better than you were, do you empathise with their initial problems?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We currently have a great bunch of newbies, they seem to be so fearless! I see some girls after a few weeks and am so impressed with their abilities. I am not a natural born skater so I think I can relate to the more nervous newbie and keep them going with encouragement and be an example of how perseverance can keep you upright, in derby stance of course ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, finally, what's new for the coming year with the Nessies?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
A few of the Nessies went to Dundee last Friday and did some scrimming with the lovely Dundee Roller Girls. We were made to feel really welcome by all the girls and had an excellent time, we literally buzzed all the way home so thank you Dundee! :-)
&lt;p&gt;As for what we have up our sleeve for this coming year, 2013 is going to put NNRG on the map so keep your eyes peeled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next month's retrospective will be by Natorious Red!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>monthly diary</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>nnrg</category><category>one year later</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/02/21/nasty-nessies-1-year-later-bee-yatch/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 14:22:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Monthly Diary Special: Nasty Nessies 1 Year Later: Irn Bruzer</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/01/20/monthly-diary-special-nasty-nessies-1-year-later-irn-bruzer/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://nastynessiesrollergirls.wordpress.com/"&gt;Nasty Nessies&lt;/a&gt; have been writing to their dear monthly diary on the blog now for more than a year. In the spirit of self-improvement and the new year, we decided to go back to the first ever Nasty Nessies diarist, founder Irn Bruzer, and ask her what's changed since she was interviewed way back in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/472039_507739752593196_968145019_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-2110" alt="Irn Bruzer (now with appropriately blue hair!) poses with derby-wife Natorious Red at their Christmas skate." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/472039_507739752593196_968145019_o.jpg?w=460" width="460" height="614"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Irn Bruzer (now with appropriately blue hair!) poses with derby-wife Black Death at their Christmas skate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So: Way back in October 2011, you told us how Whip It had alerted to you to the existence of Roller Derby; how has the past year changed and affirmed your initial impressions of derby?&lt;/strong&gt;
Well firstly it’s definitely a way to find and make amazing friends. Some of the girls would be the kind you would walk past in the street, but now you wouldn't know where you would be without them! It’s definitely got the excitement and community that you see in the film, just not as much theatrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Nessies have gotten a lot of local awareness from appearing at various events (the Inverness comic con, for example). How hard is it to organise these things, and what's the experience and reaction been like from spectators.&lt;/strong&gt;
Well luckily for us, Comic Con was a huge event already organised. All it took was a few emails and a meeting. It was also even better as we were allowed to skate around the venue which helped greatly with gaining interest. We got a lot of interest but many of them were 16. Hopefully they will keep in the loop for the next two years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now the Nessies have a large number of mins-passed skaters, how close do you feel you are to your first bout? Do you have anyone in mind to pop your bouting cherry?&lt;/strong&gt;
2013 is definitely our year! We have some great newbies who show a lot of potential too. It's taken a bit of time to find our groove but now we have, there will be a Nessie takeover!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Over the past year, what've the best and most difficult things been for the Nessies in general? What advice would you give now to a league just starting out?&lt;/strong&gt;
The biggest issue we have had is recruitment and keeping people! I know all teams go through this, but Inverness just hasn’t been taken by the derby bug yet which is disappointing. We are planning a fresh recruitment drive and we have a few things in the pipeline so hopefully we can get more people on eight wheels! I think the best advice I could give is just constantly recruit, never give up or push it back for a while. You can never have enough people as you never know who you will lose unexpectedly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recently, the Nessies popped up to Shetland to help out Shetland Roller Derby training. How does it feel to be at the level now where you can "pay back" to the community by helping out in the same way that GCRG et al helped you out at the start?&lt;/strong&gt;
Our trip to Shetland was fantastic; being on the opposite level was great as we could see how far we have come! We saw some great up and coming skaters up there and amazing determination from some newbies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, the next year looks like being a potentially exciting one for Scottish Roller Derby in general. What've the Nessies got planned?&lt;/strong&gt;
Now that would be telling wouldn't it! You’ll just have to wait and see!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>monthly diary</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>nnrg</category><category>one year later</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/01/20/monthly-diary-special-nasty-nessies-1-year-later-irn-bruzer/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 13:07:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Monthly Diary of a League: Nasty Nessies in (yes) September: Schneck Breaker</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/10/05/monthly-diary-of-a-league-nasty-nessies-in-yes-september-schneck-breaker/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;Okay, so it's a little late. But all you fans of &lt;a href="http://nastynessiesrollergirls.wordpress.com/"&gt;Inverness's&lt;/a&gt; finest will forgive us when you read about Schneck Breaker's answers, and for the photo below!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/10/470456_10150902614433494_873078318_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1774" title="Schneck Breaker" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/10/470456_10150902614433494_873078318_o.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="1014"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Schneck Breaker, showing her sensitive side!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What first attracted you to Roller Derby?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I had noticed comments made by friends on a social network site, and because of their enthusiasm about the sport, so i did some research. I was immediately attracted to the vibrancy and positiveness I saw on the track. I got in touch with NastyNessies and went to their New Meat session, and was hooked!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;If you've seen enough derby to comment: who are your derby heroes?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've only seen one live bout so far, Dundee Roller Girls VS Belfast Roller Derby,  and it was fantastic. There were amazing women on the track. I watch a fair bit of Derby on youtube, and I really admire Blast Unicorn. She seems to read the situation on the track before others realise what's happening, and she's off, another 5 points!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby names are an important aspect of the sport, especially when you're starting out. How did you choose your name, and how does it reflect your personality on track?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I did have a list of names as long as my arm at one point! I finally settled on Schneck Breaker as a salute to Inverness and as an alter ego I wanted it to reflect the determination I have on track, and possibly it sounds slightly scary to opposing teams! I found it more difficult choosing a number to be honest, I wanted something to suit my personality so went for 404!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;What was your biggest initial difficulty?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My lack of strength, although I climb hills when I can, it's a different areas of your body you are using in Derby. Also using the non-dominant side of my body was, and still is a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lots of roller girls find it hard not to spread the word about their new sport. How have you been spreading the word?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;At every opportunity, to be honest, I've put leaflets in the staffroom at work, my facebook page has Derby links all over it and trying to persuade friends who go to the gym that Derby is a much better workout. Oh, and showing off my Derby bruises.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;What’s the most important thing you’ve learnt/ done this month?&lt;/strong&gt;
I passed my Mins a couple of weeks ago, the final part was the Official Rules test, so when I passed that I was jumping the height of myself! The most important things I have  learnt was to not be scared when trying out a new way of doing things, and not to get too frustrated at myself when things aren't coming together the way I think they should. T-stops being an example!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;What were the most difficult and the best things?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most difficult things for me were my T-stops, plough and falling. At first it was hard just to let myself fall, because the sense of self preservation would take over, and I would just hurt myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The best thing was my 25 in 5, although it was physically draining and  by lap 17 I felt I couldn't  continue, I summoned up the energy and determination, and completed it in 4.46. All my fellow Nessies were sitting on the bench in silence, apart from the odd words of encouragement. That meant a lot to me, as the rest of the team recognised what I needed to succeed.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Also the Nessies themselves, I've had a particularly difficult year, but I know when I get to training I will be met with friendship and encouragement.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;What's new for the Nessies this month?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this month Nessies are going to continue with putting into practice the skills and methods of training picked up when Viper was our guest trainer a few weeks ago. and of course recruiting new members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;skatey fun times to all the Derby folk!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>monthly diary</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>nnrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/10/05/monthly-diary-of-a-league-nasty-nessies-in-yes-september-schneck-breaker/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 19:59:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Monthly Diary of a League: Nasty Nessies in August: Kazziklysm</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/08/27/monthly-diary-of-a-league-nasty-nessies-in-august-kazziklysm/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delayed only slightly by pretty much the entirety of the Scottish Roller Derby blog contributors attending Chaos on the Clyde, here's August's Monthly Diary Entry from the &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/08/27/monthly-diary-of-a-league-nasty-nessies-in-august-kazziklysm/nastynessiesrollergirls.wordpress.com"&gt;Nasty Nessies&lt;/a&gt;: Azeroth's finest, Kazziklysm!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/08/kazzi-k.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1662" title="Kazzi k" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/08/kazzi-k.jpg" alt="" width="308" height="429"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Kazziklysm Skates On!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What first attracted you to Roller Derby?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few of my friends had started training with the Nasty Nessies, and were talking about it on a night out. They badgered me to come along, so I gave in, and haven't looked back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby names are an important aspect of the sport, especially when you're starting out. How did you choose your name, and how does it reflect your personality on track?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent ages trying to think of something, and I asked loads of my friends for ideas. A good friend of mine suggested I use a play on words to incorporate my love of World of Warcraft, and the expansion pack Cataclysm, so I became Kazziklysm. I think it reflects the fact that im a destructive force on the track, that and when you know the story it shows I'm just a big geek at heart!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was your biggest initial difficulty?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My biggest difficulty to begin with was my weight and general fitness level. At 17st and a size 22 i hadn't exercised in a very long time, but Derby is so much fun that I kept at it, and I'm now fitter than I have ever been (not to mention 2 st lighter)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lots of roller girls find it hard not to spread the word about their new sport. How have you been spreading the word?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find it so hard not to speak about derby 24/7, it's like an odd compulsion. My Facebook is literally full of derby posts and I love telling people who have never heard about it before what the sport is all about. I've pestered all of my friends to join up, and working for the local newspapers, they've have been great popping in articles and pictures for me about the Nasty Nessies, raising our profile throughout the Highlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the most important thing you’ve learnt/ done this month?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month has been a biggy for me: on the 23rd July I managed to complete my 25 in 5 (finally!) and pass my mins. We had a fantastic training session with [Glasgow Roller Derby's] Viper, who taught us so many new skills, drills and ways to improve our play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What were the most difficult and the best things?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most difficult thing was definately the 25 in 5. For a couple of months I had been getting closer and closer, and it was gutting to miss out just by a few seconds but the feeling of sheer elation and relief when I finally managed it was worth all of the failures. I can't pick one best thing, there are so many, but the team banter is right up there, and my lovely derby wife Desperate Measures, who makes me go to practice even on the odd occasion that i wanna be lazy and stay home!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's new for the Nessies this month?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're putting into practice a lot of the drills and skills Viper taught us, improving our game so hopefully we will be ready to skrim in the near future :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kazziklysm has nominated Schneck Breaker as the Nessies' diarist for next month, so come back then to see what she has to say!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>monthly diary</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>nnrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/08/27/monthly-diary-of-a-league-nasty-nessies-in-august-kazziklysm/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 15:47:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Monthly Diary of a League: Nasty Nessies past July: Desperate Measures</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/08/08/monthly-diary-of-a-league-nasty-nessies-past-july-desperate-measures/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don't worry, it is actually August. Still, because they won't be dictated to by anyone, especially dead Romans, the &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/08/08/monthly-diary-of-a-league-nasty-nessies-past-july-desperate-measures/nastynessiesrollergirls.wordpress.com"&gt;Nasty Nessies&lt;/a&gt; are having their Monthly Diary for July right now. This month it's Desperate Measures telling us all about herself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/08/551796_3842887804958_1321151135_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1587" title="Desperate Measures" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/08/551796_3842887804958_1321151135_n.jpg" alt="" width="389" height="698"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Desperate Measures!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What first attracted you to Roller Derby?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing that attracted me to derby was my sister: she was part of NNRG but now she is in Glasgow. When she started, she kept going on about it but I was only 17 at the time, so I could not join at that point. After, when I turned 18, my sister dragged me along and I just fell in love with the sport; everyone was so nice that just kept me going until now I can't even miss a session without hating the fact I can't go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby names are an important aspect of the sport, especially when you're starting out. How did you choose your name, and how does it reflect your personality on track?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;It was so hard of me to pick my name, it took me weeks! When I was driving one of my favourite songs, Desperate Measures by Marianas Trench, came on and I just started picturing a bout and thought it was perfect. I think it reflects me on the track because if it was going to come down to taking  desperate measures to win I would do what is needed.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was your biggest initial difficulty?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;My biggest difficulty was doing jumps: they scare me so much. I can do them but I just had a mental block for so long when I came to the jumps because I kept hurting myself when doing them. But thanks to Mrs Cherry Bow our bench manager I can do them now.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lots of roller girls find it hard not to spread the word about their new sport. How have you been spreading the word?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I tell everyone I meet about derby: most of the time no-one cares or they laugh because they think all you do is go around and hit people, but then you get some people that are very interested and end up coming along to see if they will enjoy it.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the most important thing you’ve learnt/ done this month?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The most important thing I have done this month is redoing my 25 in 5 and getting the 25 in 4 minutes 18 seconds.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What were the most difficult and the best things?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The most difficult thing was the jumping and the best thing is the derby community: everyone is so nice and the NNRG's are so amazing.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's new for the Nessies this month?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The Nasty Nessies have just started doing training outside in the sun so hopefully I won't fall tonight!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>monthly diary</category><category>nasty nessies</category><category>nnrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/08/08/monthly-diary-of-a-league-nasty-nessies-past-july-desperate-measures/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 21:01:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Monthly Diary of a League: Nasty Nessies in June: Scarolott</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/06/23/monthly-diary-of-a-league-nasty-nessies-in-june-scarolott/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;All those people anxiously checking their calendars will no doubt be relieved to find the last &lt;a href="http://nastynessiesrollergirls.wordpress.com/"&gt;Nasty Nessies'&lt;/a&gt; latest diary entry, from ex-Scarlett-O'Horror, Scarolott!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/06/charlotte.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1430" title="Scarolot" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/06/charlotte.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="917"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Scarolott captured by Nessies photographer James King&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What first attracted you to Roller Derby?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;em&gt;It just looked really exciting! We used to play a sort of version of derby at home when I was little in the playground, and I always loved being on skates and going fast...at least now when I fall I have some protective gear!
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you've seen enough derby to comment: who are your derby heroes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Haven't&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; really seen very much derby here, but have a few internet heroes - especially those
kind souls who make instructional videos like Bonnie D. Stroir and others.
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby names are an important aspect of the sport, especially when you're starting out. How did you choose your name, and how does it reflect your personality on track?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I initially chose Scarlett O'Horror in homage to my favourite film - in Gone With the Wind, Scarlett O'Hara has a moment where she says "I guess I've done murder...I'll think about that tomorrow". My attitude on track is similar - go for it and figure out the consequences later! Unfortunately, I've since discovered that another derby skater loves that film too and has already taken the name, so i'm going to switch to Scarolott. Almost like my actual name, too!
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was your biggest initial difficulty?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Finding a team - the Highlands is a big place and I live an hour and half's drive away from our training venue! I love it though, so am happy to cover the miles.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lots of roller girls find it hard not to spread the word about their&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;new sport. How have you been spreading the word?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I don't shut up about it! I have pics/links/updates on facebook, and I bore everybody I know stupid with the topic. I figure I can talk them into submission (and make them come along when we start bouting!).&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the most important thing you’ve learnt/ done this month?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I've been getting better at transitioning between backwards and forwards skating. Have had some great training sessions on blocking too, which I really enjoy!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What were the most difficult and the best things?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Most difficult - the first time I went for my 25/5 and missed it. Was gutted. Got it second time round though! The best bit - the team spirit, definitely. I've met such great folk through derby.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's new for the Nessies this month?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have lots of newbies, some of whom have graduated to the team skate practies - woohooo!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>monthly diary</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>nnrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/06/23/monthly-diary-of-a-league-nasty-nessies-in-june-scarolott/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2012 09:26:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Monthly Diary of a League: Nasty Nessies in May: Trixy Whips!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/05/25/monthly-diary-of-a-league-nasty-nessies-in-may-trixy-whips/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another month comes around for the &lt;a href="http://nastynessiesrollergirls.wordpress.com/"&gt;Nasty Nessies&lt;/a&gt;, and this time it's a pithy interview with Trixy Whips being served up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/05/trixie.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1267" title="trixie" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/05/trixie.jpeg" alt="" width="560" height="898"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Trixy Whips, by James King&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What first attracted you to Roller Derby?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember seeing it on TV ages ago. Later, I saw a roller girl on one of these tattoo reality type shows getting a derby pin-up tattoo: she was so enthusiastic about the sport that I thought I would like to give that a go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Derby names are an important aspect of the sport, especially when you're starting out. How did you choose your name, and how does it reflect your personality on track?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend has called me Trixy since we were children so that just fell into place. On the track its great to get whips so there it was!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was your biggest initial difficulty?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having not skated for 21 years was a bit of a worry at first but it all came flooding back !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Lots of roller girls find it hard not to spread the word about their new sport. How have you been spreading the word?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell my friends and family and people at work about practice and try to explain (probably badly) the rules  and obviously sharing the joy of passing my MINS, although the state I was in after my 25 in 5 would probably put them off !! That was one of the hardest things I have done: my lungs were on fire !!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; What’s the most important thing you’ve learnt/ done this month?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I cant think of one thing this month; each practice you are learning and improving on something! Oh, I have learned the difference new wheels can make though (-:    !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What were the most difficult and the best things?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most difficult can be time: sometimes it is not possible to make every practice due to other commitments; work, etc. But the best has been getting fit, meeting a really friendly bunch of girls and having a laugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's new for the Nessies this month?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More new Nessies! We are still looking for new skaters to come along and we also have more practice time every MON and SUN with a newbies night on a WED.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>monthly diary</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>nnrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/05/25/monthly-diary-of-a-league-nasty-nessies-in-may-trixy-whips/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 15:11:54 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>