<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about ntrg)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/ntrg.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>New Town Roller Girls - Round up of 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/19/new-town-roller-girls-round-up-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>oneknownashaze</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year one of our newly mins passed skaters interviews one of our long time skaters who is on the clutch of finishing off her own mins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introductions! Who are you?
&lt;/strong&gt;I’m Alison aka Woolly Thumper and I’ll have been with NTRG for 2 years in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What made you join roller derby and how long have you been playing?
&lt;/strong&gt;I was introduced to derby by my boss whose girlfriend was going through fresh meat with ARRG. He showed me some videos; I went to watch a couple of bouts and was hooked. I had a taster session with ARRG but their training venues and times didn’t work for me so derby went on the back burner until about a year later when I found out about NTRG. I met the team at a getting-to-know you night in the pub and strapped on a pair of skates the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What has NTRG been up to so far this year? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we have been working on running our fresh meat program in a more formal, organised way which has been very effective and the impact can be seen in the amazing progress our freshies have made. Although we haven't really bouted as a league, our skaters have been bouting as guests for other leagues, in charity bouts and mixed teams and the whole league has benefited from what they have learned. We also took part in the Sur5ors tournament in October which was an amazing experience. We really enjoyed skating against some much more experienced skaters and I think we represented ourselves well. We have had a lot of support from skaters from other leagues, Mean City and Dundee especially, giving up their time to help coach us. We have learned loads and are so grateful, hopefully next year we will be able to pay it forward to other leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What have been the highlights for the team &amp;amp; your own personal highlights?
&lt;/strong&gt;Highlights for the team would probably have to be Sur5ors and the great crop of new skaters we have coming through. I am making my way slowly through my mins so every extra lap on my 27/5 and every new skill nailed or fear faced is a highlight for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are this year's fresh meat shaping up?
&lt;/strong&gt;AWESOME, lots of talent, determination and a lovely bunch too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's next for NTRG?
&lt;/strong&gt;2015 is shaping up to be a pretty exciting year for us; in February we are taking part in Voodoo's Highland Rampage tournament which features 8 teams from across Scotland. We are also taking part in Tier 4 of the British Roller Derby Championships which will keep us busy throughout the year. We are not big enough to have our own home season (yet) so we are working to arrange some more bouts with other leagues both local and further afield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any final words?
&lt;/strong&gt;I'm really looking forward to 2015. Next year should see me popping my bouting cherry and skating out alongside my fantastic NTRG teammates. I consider myself very lucky to be part of such a lovely bunch of folk and I'm very proud to call myself a New Town Roller Girl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo Courtesy of Rudi Pateluch&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/ntrg-61.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4465" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/ntrg-61.jpg?w=660" alt="Courtesy of Rudi Pateluch" width="660" height="440"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>ntrg</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/19/new-town-roller-girls-round-up-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 19:13:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Town Roller Girls: Fresh Meat</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/14/new-town-roller-girls-fresh-meat/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/ntrg-fm.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/ntrg-fm.jpg" alt="Photography by Dave McAleavy" width="420" height="594" class="size-full wp-image-3289"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photography by Dave McAleavy
&lt;p&gt;Livingston's finest Roller Derby league are recruiting!. On Sunday the 2nd of March New Town Roller Girls will host their first Fresh Meat session at the Craigswood Sports Centre, Livingston.
NTRG are looking for skaters aged 18 and over who are dedicated, enthusiastic and want to be part of their awesome team. You can register your interest and have your questions answered at the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/250085348504987/"&gt;Facebook event page&lt;/a&gt;.
See you on track!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fresh meat</category><category>ntrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/14/new-town-roller-girls-fresh-meat/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 23:18:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Review 2014: New Town Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/07/derby-review-2014-new-town-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To see in the new year, we at the Scottish Roller Derby blog have cast back our eyes over the past year of derby. We'll be presenting a series of interviews with the Scottish leagues about their 2013 over the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What better way to start than with one of our most newly bouting leagues, Livingston's &lt;a href="http://newtownrollergirls.tumblr.com/"&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;? We caught up with team captain and league manager Hazzard to look over the highlights of their year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/img_0129-2-copy.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3142" alt="New Town Roller Girls facing Furness Firecrackers B in their debut bout." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/img_0129-2-copy.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; New Town Roller Girls facing Furness Firecrackers B in their debut bout. (Photo Credit: Laura MacDonald)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This year saw skaters from New Town bout publicly twice: once as one half of the Co-ed "Mean Town", against Bairn City's Belter Skelpers, and then in New Town's own cherry popper, with New Town taking on Furness Firecrackers' Flaming Noras. How did it feel to be passing that important milestone?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It felt amazing! There are no other words to describe it! Thanks to our girls for their hard work and the help of some amazing leagues as hosts, guest skaters and opponents we pulled off our first two public appearances and took home a lot of experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As New Town took the unusual step of breaking their co-ed cherry before their "normal" one, can we expect to see more Co-ed outings for the league? Maybe even a co-ed team ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most likely not a co-ed team but we are fond of those guys over at Mean City! Our girls are free to choose if they participate in any mixed co-ed events in the Scottish derby world and we certainly don't discourage skating with the guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Town have built up strong connections with many of the other derby leagues in Scotland, including Mean City and Bairn City. How has the derby community helped New Town to grow this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much! From helping us out with coaching to hosting us in our first bouts they've done wonders for us! We hope that 2014 will see us engage with even more leagues and get involved in even more events and we're eager to see what the year has in store for us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That community spirit contributed to some other appearances by New Town skaters, with several playing in the "cherry popper" bout preceding Granite City and The Jakey Bites' Co-ed exhibition bout in July. Does a first appearance in a mixed team ease you into derby, or is it just as "real" as an outing of New Town as a team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally think it helps you get over some of the stresses of a competitive bout. It means that you're not too involved with getting your team to win (even though that's part of the fun) . You can focus on enjoying the atmosphere and playing to the best of your ability with people in the same position as you! We also had some skaters in the recent GRD charity bout who were popping their cherry or on their second bout and they loved it! Gets you more involved with the derby community as a whole!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growth as a league also means picking up new sponsors. I noticed that New Town have collected &lt;a href="http://sckrpnch.com/index.php?"&gt;Sckrpunch&lt;/a&gt; as a sponsor this year. Does this imply you'll be present at some of the &lt;a href="http://derbyrevolution.eu/"&gt;Derby Revolution&lt;/a&gt; events also organised by the store?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've not had anything about on an official level but I've seen the events floating around. (Recently it was announce Suzy Hotrod would be holding classes?!) But we're very happy to have such a well known derby name tied with ours and we're looking forward to whatever we do together in the future! Especially if a trip to the store in Belgium happens! I'm still hoping for another Skate Odyssey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And finally, what can you tell us about New Town's plans for 2014?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well I can't really say much as most of what we have happening behind the scenes is in its early stages but what I can tell you is that we are New Town Roller Girls and we're out to kick 2014's ass! We have some amazingly strong skaters coming through our ranks at the moment and we're growing as a team week in and week out! I feel more than privileged to skate with the girls who are working their butts off to make themselves and the team great! So watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>ntrg</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/07/derby-review-2014-new-town-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 15:24:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Monthly Diary of a League: New Town in September: Bump-Her Stick-Her</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/09/13/monthly-diary-of-a-league-new-town-in-september-bump-her-stick-her/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing &lt;a href="http://newtownrollergirls.tumblr.com/"&gt;New Town Roller Girls'&lt;/a&gt; Monthly insights, here's Bump-Her-Stick-Her... coming to a track near you, soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/bump-her-sm.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-2939" alt="Bump-Her Stick-Her!" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/bump-her-sm.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="909"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Bump-Her Stick-Her!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What first attracted you to Roller Derby?&lt;/strong&gt;
My awesome bestie used to play for ARRG (Bobscene Behaviour) and that was my introduction to the game. I watched her in her first bout and left wishing I could give it a try. Fast forwards a few years later and I was a new mum looking for an outlet, some exercise and something that I could do just for me - I saw an advert for New Town Roller Girls and pounced!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most skaters have inspirations in their own or other leagues. Who are your derby heroes?&lt;/strong&gt;
Bobscene Behavior for introducing me to roller derby (and blocking like a boss). Duke Box is amazing, agile and hits like a wall! Also Lois Maim is all round awesome and so patient when helping me learn hits and blocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby names are an important aspect of the sport, especially when you're starting out. How did you choose your name (and number), and does it reflect your personality on track?&lt;/strong&gt;
It came to me at work. I'm generally known for being shy and uncertain (unless you really know me well) . I wanted to channel a tougher side so I wanted an aggressive name. Bump-Her Stick-Her is a mantra i can use on track. My number is my daughter Roslyn's birthday 195.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's your favourite position and technique?&lt;/strong&gt;
I like jamming, I am still learning a lot but I hope I can be a useful jammer some day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lots of roller girls find it hard not to spread the word about their new sport. How have you been spreading the word?&lt;/strong&gt;
Facebook :) work, rambling on to hairdressers and by wearing my teams t-shirt whilst running or working out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the most important thing you've learnt/ done this month&lt;/strong&gt;
Practicing with the boys and girls for our &lt;a title="Bairn City Rollers presents “Day Of Reckoning”" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/09/10/bairn-city-rollers-presents-day-of-reckoning/"&gt;upcoming bout&lt;/a&gt; (my cherry popper)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And the most difficult and the best things?&lt;/strong&gt;
The most difficult is the frustration of not picking up a technique. The best is the first time you get it right. You may not always get it but you realise it's possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's new for the New Town this month?&lt;/strong&gt;
First bout. I'm simultaneously excited and terrified. Also the next wave of minimum skills skaters&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>monthly diary</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>ntrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/09/13/monthly-diary-of-a-league-new-town-in-september-bump-her-stick-her/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 09:40:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Monthly Diary of a League: New Town in August: Devil Drives'er</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/08/16/monthly-diary-of-a-league-new-town-in-august-devil-driveser/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing our regular coverage of Livingston's Finest Roller Derby League, here's &lt;a href="http://newtownrollergirls.tumblr.com/"&gt;New Town&lt;/a&gt;'s next monthly diarist: Devil Drives'er!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/08/leona-headshot.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-2892 " alt="Devil Drives'er!" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/08/leona-headshot.jpg" width="473" height="768"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Devil Drives'er!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-
&lt;strong&gt;What first attracted you to Roller Derby?&lt;/strong&gt;
I loved skating as a kid with weekends at the rollerina, and saw posters for AARG years ago which got my attention but after awhile kinda forgot about it. I was talking about it with one of my friends who told me that a league had started in Livingston and knew Hazzard. from there I just knew I had to get involved!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most skaters have inspirations in their own or other leagues. Who are your derby heroes?&lt;/strong&gt;
I'd have to say Teenie Bash from ARRG since she got my little girl hooked after giving her a giant foam finger :P and from my own league Nettie Napalm and Bump-Her Stick-Her, because being mummies and working is hard enough to fit into a week, and your determination and drive at derby inspires me to do as well as you guys are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby names are an important aspect of the sport, especially when you're starting out. How did you choose your name (and number), and does it reflect your personality on track?&lt;/strong&gt;
My name comes from one of my fave bands devildriver, and I chose number 13 because it may be unlucky for some but it's my favourite number, and I already have it tattooed on my arm so that's handy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's your favourite position and technique?&lt;/strong&gt;
Blocking, using my ass-ets ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lots of roller girls find it hard not to spread the word about their new sport. How have you been spreading the word?&lt;/strong&gt;
I think I pretty much talk about it constantly! I've been flyering in work and in my local pub, as well as fundraising with the league and of course wearing my hoodie constantly for advertising!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the most important thing you've learnt/ done this month?&lt;/strong&gt;
To make sure I concentrate on my pacing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And the most difficult and the best things?&lt;/strong&gt;
I'd say learning to get on with it when you feel rubbish, and getting used to my weird new lump in my arm :P. And as for best getting faster and closer to being mins passed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's new for the New Town this month?&lt;/strong&gt;
Our article in the Konect, and trying to sort out some extra skatey days :D&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>monthly diary</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>ntrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/08/16/monthly-diary-of-a-league-new-town-in-august-devil-driveser/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 14:52:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Scotland's Newest Leagues: A Year in Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/31/scotlands-newest-leagues-a-year-in-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the bigger leagues have had their 2012 filled with bouting, the rapid growth of derby in Scotland means that there are many other leagues who have been spending the past year growing and moving towards bout readiness. With Inverness' Nasty Nessies covered in a special edition of their Monthly Diary to come, we thought that &lt;a href="http://newtownrollergirls.wordpress.com/"&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/31/scotlands-newest-leagues-a-year-in-derby/deadlydivasrollerderby.webs.com"&gt;Deadly Divas Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.shetlandrollerderby.com/"&gt;Shetland Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://lothianderbydolls.com/"&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; all deserved the time to tell us how they'd been doing over the past 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Town, based in Livingston, and the Derby Dolls, based in Edinburgh and the Lothians, are near contemporaries, and both have been growing and developing over the past year. Both leagues have spent the past year growing and developing their skills towards passing mins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, after a slow start to the year, everything started coming together for New Town Roller Girls in the last 6 months, their numbers swelling to 18 by the end of this year, with 4 skaters, and referee The Real Scrim Shady, already mins-passed. The league's founder, Hazzard, was keen to credit "Reff Goldblum of FVRG," as "the man that helped us pass our mins and has been a great help to us!", with others being equally positive about the recent attendance by Auld Reekie's Circuit Breaker, and the many other skaters from other leagues who have visited them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ladies in black and electric blue also held their first fundraiser in November, the event also serving as the official unveiling of their newly printed boutfits. If Hazzard was upbeat about roller derby and their place in the community,  "I thought [derby] was amazing from when I first found out about it and all that's really changed is that I've come to know the sport better and love the camaraderie of the community and the sheer fun of being involved!", The Real Scrim Shady was even more positive, stating "First time I went along, it was a bunch of people who didn't even know each other's names, nervously skating round the hall following the instructions of Hazzard and Reff Goldblum. It was fun for sure, but since then everyone knows each other, people push each other to do better and give pointers where needed, there's a noticeable anticipation in the run-up to each session. People look forward to it and, as far as I can see, great progress has been made. It feels like a team now instead of just a bunch of friendly strangers."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/31/scotlands-newest-leagues-a-year-in-derby/tumblr_mde5ngyydu1rfp2kio3_1280/" rel="attachment wp-att-2025"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2025" alt="New Town Roller Girls at their Fundraiser this year." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/tumblr_mde5ngyydu1rfp2kio3_1280.jpg" width="614" height="408"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; New Town Roller Girls at their Fundraiser this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Town are very much looking forward to having enough team members mins-passed to bout, although the team is divided on who their first opponents should be, with skater Bump-Her Stick-Her feeling that "Fierce Valley seem to be our closest 'buddies' but bouting against them would be terrifying as they are amazing", with Hazzard taking the more conservative choice of close buddies "Deadly Divas Roller Derby could well be our first bout partners but you do never know..."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lothian Derby Dolls have advanced slightly faster than their peers in attaining a full roster of mins-passed skaters, aided by their acquiring of experienced derby coach Cain Unstable. Duke Box, speaking to us for the league, mentioned both Cain, and offered "thanks to Lead Jammer Magazine, Inkabilly and Into The Nitemare [derby store]" for their donations and sponsorship. The league also held a successful Halloween themed roller-disco, which had good attendance and promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duke Box was also clear that the Derby Dolls, while branding themselves "a team for the Lothians" with "skaters from all across the Lothian area; Mid, West, East and Edinburgh" have been getting on well with the well-established Auld Reekie in the capital itself. "Having ARRG in Edinburgh has allowed us opportunities both to watch them play and support them" she said, adding that the Derby Dolls "have also had some of our skaters join them in scrimmaging this year and hope to have the chance to more in the future, as we wish for all leagues close to us."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Derby Dolls are now capable of fielding a full roster of skaters, they are cagey about their first bout; an initially prematurely announced inaugural fixture has since been delayed or rescheduled. Whenever their initial bout is held, LDD will be attending the Into The Nitemare store-sponsored 'Battle of Britain' tournament in November. As one of the two unseeded competitors, it will be interesting to see how they fare, and a good learning experience for them in the process (even experienced teams like Glasgow Roller Derby and Auld Reekie find extended tournaments to be an exhausting endeavour).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/31/scotlands-newest-leagues-a-year-in-derby/459658_316736258439825_267676052_o/" rel="attachment wp-att-2039"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2039" alt="A Christmas-themed group photo from the Lothian Derby Dolls 2013 calendar." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/459658_316736258439825_267676052_o.jpg" width="614" height="417"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A Christmas-themed group photo from the Lothian Derby Dolls 2013 calendar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Deadly Divas and Shetland Roller Derby, meanwhile, have both only been recruiting since partway through the year, Shetland having been actively growing since July, and the Divas since September! At this early stage in their existence, a lot of the focus has been on gaining numbers and experience. Shetland's Shock Blocker put a lot of effort into outreach via local press and radio appearances, also providing taster sessions for those unsure to experience the meaning of derby. The Divas leveraged some less conventional internet media, including Gumtree and eBay, but also the Glasgow press. In the end, word-of-mouth, both online via their Facebook and Web pages, and offline via the inability of new roller girls to speak about anything else, may have been their most significant factors, taking them, in the words of founder AJ La Kaos, from "only 3 of us then 2 left; As it stands now in less than 3 months we have around 20 members which is phenomenal!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both have also been welcomed by the derby community, the Divas getting regular support from Glasgow's men's derby team Mean City Roller Derby, as well as the Pan-Scotland Jakey Bites, and turning up to New Town Roller Girls' open practices on Sunday afternoons; Shetland via their closest neighbours Nasty Nessies, who made a flying visit, following on from a visit from the Forth Valley's Bairn City Rollers earlier in the year. For the Divas, AJ La Kaos noted that "Being the second league in Glasgow has brought up a few complications especially with recruiting and sourcing a venue. We try very hard not to step on GRD's toes in both respects with branding ourselves as a south side team", while the advantage of being in the middle of things allows them to "go to as many bouts as possible, its a great way to see the sport in its full glory. It also keeps us motivated seeing what we're all working towards." The Divas have the advantage of ex-GRD skater Viper as their coach, who also serves as their "biggest inspiration in the derby world" according to La Kaos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/31/scotlands-newest-leagues-a-year-in-derby/704125_411805645558435_407723866_o/" rel="attachment wp-att-2042"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2042" alt="The Deadly Divas even managed to get themselves into the papers!" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/704125_411805645558435_407723866_o.jpg" width="614" height="421"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Deadly Divas even managed to get themselves into the papers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being the most remote roller derby league in the UK causes the opposite problem for Shetland Roller Derby,  preventing easy access to live derby hosted on the mainland, and to physical skate stores. Shock Blocker said that the team "owes a special place in our hearts to Marshall Lawless (of 5th Blocker Skates [and Glasgow Roller Derby]) for answering all of our questions, and managing to get stuff up to Shetland at a reasonable price".
The remoteness of Shetland also has another effect on the league, in terms of its makeup. While all roller derby leagues have a mix of ages present, Shetland's overall deficit of University-age individuals is reflected in the more mature demographic of the league, as well. This has not limited their advancement, Shock Blocker commenting that "Our skaters have really grown as a team, and we've been supporting each other learning together. It's been amazing to watch people that have never skated get better and better, and we've all certainly learned a lot."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2012 has been a year of great expansion for Scottish Roller Derby, with the four teams above, and Inverness' Nasty Nessies, all making strides towards doubling the number of bouting leagues in the country. By the end of 2013, the community will only be enriched further as each league passes their mins and becomes bout-ready. We asked each of the league representatives what their aims for 2013 were, and they kindly responded with many words. Rather than take them out of context, we present them here unedited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadly Divas Roller Derby (AJ La Kaos):
&lt;em&gt;2013 will hopefully be a huge year for us as a team, we're working hard towards getting everyone mins passed and having our first proper bout! For me personally, I'm looking forward to that first day on track watching my new family kick some ass: win or lose it won't matter as we're all there for each other and that's all that really matters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shetland Roller Derby (Shock Blocker):
&lt;em&gt;2013 will be our year of getting our team mins passed, trying to attract more skaters, and educating the public a bit more about the sport. We are delighted to receive any skaters who'd like to come up to Shetland, and show them around. If we can gather enough funding, maybe plan a trip to the mainland.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Personally, I'd like to improve my skating skills, my understanding of the rules, and hopefully see more bouts in person.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the meantime, we at Shetland Roller Derby would like to wish all the Scottish teams a big thank you, Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year! xx&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Town Roller Derby:
(Hazzard)
&lt;em&gt;In the next year we hope to have enough skaters mins passed and experienced to start having some closed door bouts atleast! Then on to the big scary world of open bouts and trying to find somewhere to hold them at home too!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The Real Scrim Shady)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There's still much work to be done, but over the next wee while I'm interested in helping NTRG improve their skating and developing the fitness levels necessary for a bout. I've been skating for years and I like helping other people avoid some mistakes that I made in the process of learning to be comfortable on skates. I want to see all NTRG members be comfortable enough on skates that they can be thinking about the bout rather than worrying about staying on their feet. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I've seen progress in the short time I've been involved, for example 4 skaters passing mins. But I'd like to see training become a bit more intense. Circuit Breaker is coming back to help us with exactly that and I'll try to help Hazzard maintain the level of training and push it harder when the time’s right. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em id="__mceDel"&gt;&lt;em id="__mceDel"&gt;&lt;em id="__mceDel"&gt;&lt;em id="__mceDel"&gt;&lt;em id="__mceDel"&gt;&lt;em&gt;As for what I see for myself within the next year, I'm learning about the game pretty quickly right now and I'm looking to get a set of quads (I’m a fruitbooter btw). I aim to gain enough knowledge and understanding of bouts to move on from the role I've already had as NSO. The eventual goal is to become a ref but I don't know just now how long I can expect that to take.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls (Duke Box):
&lt;em&gt;Well 2013 so far does have us taking part in The Battle of Britain; a tournament that is being organised by Into The Nitemare. We also have a couple of things that are being organised bouting wise and will be announced next year when finalised and confirmed. Just a lot more hard work in training and some fun events in store for us also. It is definitely the year the Dolls will make a great one for all our skaters and those who supports us. So a big thanks to all who have got us to the end of 2012 it has been a great start.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Thanks to: Lothian Derby Dolls' Duke Box; New Town Roller Girls' Hazzard, Millie Manslaughter, Bump-her Stick-her and The Real Scrim Shady; Shetland Roller Derby's Shock Blocker; and Deadly Divas Roller Derby's AJ La Kaos for their contributions to this report.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ddrd</category><category>deadly divas roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>ldd</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>ntrg</category><category>shetland roller derby</category><category>srd</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/31/scotlands-newest-leagues-a-year-in-derby/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 17:21:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>November Fundraisers</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/10/31/november-fundraisers/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First up in this months fun filled fundraising events is Glasgow Roller Derby's &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/351592554933159/?suggestsessionid=1351676532"&gt;Blingo Night&lt;/a&gt; at the Cathouse,Glasgow on Friday the 2nd ,a night of prize bingo with prizes courtesy of Tatty Bon, Hauswife and Bunny's Beads.Fancy Dress optional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up on Saturday the 3rd is New Town Roller Girls &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/154523541356097/"&gt;Rock And Rollers night&lt;/a&gt; at the Black Bull Inn,Mid Calder.Live music from The Scabby Queen ,crafts ,merch ,prizes and cake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the same night,Fierce Valley Roller Girls,host &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/438047632908510/"&gt; a Fierce Halloween Party&lt;/a&gt; at  &lt;br&gt;
Thornhill Community Hall, Falkirk.The night will feature music, baking, food, merch ,Halloween games and a raffle with a star prize courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.intothenitemareclothing.co.uk/"&gt;Into The Nightmare&lt;/a&gt;.This event is fancy dress with best costume winning a prize.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fundraiser event</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>fvrg</category><category>grd</category><category>ntrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/10/31/november-fundraisers/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 21:50:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Lothians Get Rolling!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/06/04/the-lothians-get-rolling/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the foundation of Fierce Valley Roller Girls, and Nasty Nessies Roller Girls last year, many thought that that would be about it for new roller derby leagues in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No sooner had we issued that opinion, however, then two more showed up!
Lothian Derby-Dolls, declaring themselves as a "Mid-Lothian" based league, founded by a group of experienced skaters late of Auld Reekie; and New Town Roller Girls, based in West Lothian's Livingston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both teams are aware of the recruitment pressure exerted on them; by Edinburgh's Auld Reekie to the North-East, and Fierce Valley to the North-West, but they feel there's enough demand for derby that they can prosper in addition. Indeed, New Town recruit Gill Brannan explained: "the first team I found was Auld Reekie, but the fresh meat seemed infrequent, and New Town is local to me. I was really surprised and happy there was a team here." (Gill has since had to leave New Town for personal reasons).
New Town's initial founders, Hazel "Hazzard" Mochan, Jennifer "JPow" Powell* and Becki "Darko" Lawrie, decided to start the new league in a burst of enthusiasm after having watched Whip It! on DVD. Unaware of the existence of Fierce Valley Roller Girls to the north, and seeing the long wait for the next fresh meat at Auld Reekie, it seemed like the fastest way to get skating would be to do it themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/06/dsc01079.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-1302 " title="SONY DSC" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/06/dsc01079.jpg" alt="" width="430" height="410"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; New Town co-founder Hazzard directs training at a Sunday session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The going has been slow but steady for New Town in the months since; after growing quietly on a Facebook group page for several months, they exploded into the awareness of the Scottish Roller Derby community after Lead Jammer magazine gave them a plug, but gaining awareness outside of the existing derby community has proved difficult. A concerted leafleting campaign is planned in the near future, as most of the team's previous outreach has been via Facebook and Twitter. Skaters from both Auld Reekie and Fierce Valley have helped with the occasional practise session, as New Town have no experienced coaches amongst them. Initially, the team benefited from sharing practise sessions with Lothian Derby-Dolls, but with LDD growing bigger this has become less possible. Team founder Hazzard has been developing her own coaching skills as a consequence.
New Town's practices are weekly on Sundays, 3 to 6pm at Craigswood Sport Centre, Livingston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While New Town's band of skaters are all new to Derby, Lothian Derby-Dolls have well-experienced founding skaters Psychobeing and Skate-tastrophy, formerly of Auld Reekie. In addition, they've recruited the legendary Cain Unstable as their coach. Cain was involved in the early days of both Glasgow Roller Girls and coached Auld Reekie for their first couple of years, bringing them up to an extremely high standard. The lure of Cain, and the presence of experience skaters hasn't hurt LDD's recruitment; one skater I spoke to had even been recommended to join the league by Dundee's Psychomilly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/06/dsc02485.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-1301 " title="SONY DSC" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/06/dsc02485.jpg" alt="" width="430" height="286"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Lothian Derby Dolls recruits lining up for practise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engaging in an impressive structured training plan, Cain hopes to get the first recruits for the Derby-Dolls mins passed and bout ready before the end of the year. With already more than enough members to form a full bouting team, it looks like they might even manage a bout next January.
The Derby-Dolls started with a single practice on Fridays, 7-9pm at Danderhall Community Centre, sharing a Sunday practise with New Town. Since then, Lothian Derby-Dolls have been looking for a new venue for their own Sunday practise, and are no longer sharing with New Town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growth spurt for Scottish Roller Derby has not stopped even here. During the process of writing this article, a second Glasgow-based team has just emerged, Glasgow Slayers positioning themselves somewhat in the same relation to GRD as the Derby-Dolls are to Auld Reekie. Unlike LDD, Glasgow Slayers don't come with any direct derby experience; while co-founder Teri Fiher has skated on inlines for years, she's new to quads, let alone hitting people while wearing them, and her comrade-in-derby Lou Natic has no previous skating experience at all. Recruitment is in the initial stages, but seems to be very positive, and Glasgow Roller Derby are being very supportive themselves. As yet, the Slayers have not located a suitable practise venue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More speculatively, even Shetland is potentially getting into the act, with a Facebook page only recently renamed from "Anyone interested in Roller Derby in Shetland?" to "Shetland Roller Derby". Despite the remoteness of Shetland, they have already hosted an initial recruitment meeting, and are positive that they can recruit enough members to form a team. This would make them the new holders of the "Most Northerly Team in UK Roller Derby" record, previously held by Nasty Nessies in Inverness (in Europe proper, Scandinavia hosts several new leagues which are much further north than the rest of Europe could ever match, of course).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two taster events for Shetland Roller Derby are planned: one next Sunday on the 10th of June, the other on the 24th. They are linked to from the league's Facebook page.
New Town Roller Girls have a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/New-Town-Roller-Girls/165340106915551"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; page: and a very new &lt;a href="http://newtownrollergirls.wordpress.com/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.
Lothian Derby-Dolls have a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/lothianderbydolls"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; page and a &lt;a href="http://lothianderbydolls.com/index.php"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.
Glasgow Slayers can be found on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100003637390000"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;
Shetland Roller Derby can also be found on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ShetlandRollerDerby"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[*JPow has since left New Town in favour of a skating role with Lothian Derby-Dolls; the current chairs of New Town are the remaining two founders, Hazzard and Darko.]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>glasgow slayers</category><category>ldd</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>ntrg</category><category>shetland roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/06/04/the-lothians-get-rolling/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 12:14:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Town Roller Girls:Fresh Meat</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/23/new-town-roller-girlsfresh-meat/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/ntrg-recruit.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/ntrg-recruit.jpg" alt="" title="ntrg recruit" width="509" height="720" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1151"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of New Town Roller Girls&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Town Roller Girls are recruiting in the Livingston area,drop them a line at the email address on the flyer or drop by their &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/New-Town-Roller-Girls/165340106915551"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; to register your interest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fresh meat</category><category>ntrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/23/new-town-roller-girlsfresh-meat/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 21:39:09 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>