<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about one year later)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/one-year-later.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Nasty Nessies One Year Later: Scarlett O'Horror/Scarolott</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/18/nasty-nessies-one-year-later-scarlett-ohorrorscarolott/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing in our look back at how our &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/18/nasty-nessies-one-year-later-scarlett-ohorrorscarolott/nastynessiesrollergirls.wordpress.com"&gt;Nasty Nessies&lt;/a&gt; diarists feel now, one year later than their initial diary, we have the case of Scarlet O'Horror (or is it Scarolott?). &lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/06/23/monthly-diary-of-a-league-nasty-nessies-in-june-scarolott/"&gt;Her original diary is here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/skate-pic.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-2524 " alt="Scarolott at practice, yesterday." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/skate-pic.jpg?w=614" width="430" height="575"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Scarolott at practice, yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's been more than a year since you became one of the first Nasty Nessies.  Looking back at yourself then, what advice would you give your earlier self?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I would sit myself down and say: you will LOVE this sport, so buy better gear to start with. You're just going to have to keep upgrading otherwise. Also, working on your crossovers pays huge rewards!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last year, you mentioned that most of your derby heroes were drawn from bouts and training videos you'd seen online. Since then, have your heroes changed, as you've hopefully managed to see more derby first-hand?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a blast at ARRG's bootcamp - all the women who were teaching there were wonderful and really encouraging. I think my heroes of the moment though are my team mates, who have kept us going through recruitment, getting through mins, and encouraging us all on our way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Of course, you're now mins-passed (under the old WFTDA mins, at least ;) ), and so one difference between last year and how is that you'll have been scrimming. Given your enjoyment of blocking last time we spoke, I guess you're enjoying scrimming even more?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I LOVE it!! We've been to Dundee's open scrim, and some of the girls were able to scrim in a mixed team in Edinburgh, and it's just such an adrenaline kick to get on track and be working in a team. It'll be even better when it's an all-Nessie team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Around the time of the last diary, you'd just decided to change your skatename from Scarlett O'Horror to Scarolott, as that skatename was already in use. Now we hear you're thinking of changing back...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I'd always loved Gone With The Wind, so was gutted that my chosen name of Scarlett O'Horror was already in use by a skater in the States, so went and chose a new name. However, I've recently had some advice that some skaters have agreed to share a name - especially if they're in different continents and unlikely to bout together. So - if anyone from the TSDD is reading, I'm trying to get in touch to see if your Scarlett O'Horror would mind a Kiwi/Scottish namesake with a different bouting number...!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting out, the Nessies got some help from the derby community, with Granite City running the first bootcamp to push your skills up. Now you're in a position to pay it back, what have you been adding to the derby community?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NNRG went up to Shetland to help out when they first started up, so I'm really looking forward to them coming to see us for a friendly scrim. I'm doing my best to get as many folk involved as I can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What're your plans for the future? The Nessies have been tight-lipped about their plans for the next year, although we've seen the first ever public bout featuring two of your skaters in the past month! Will we see a Nasty Nessies bout by the end of the year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;It would be awesome if we could. In the meantime, we're getting more skaters through mins, and will keep going to open scrims when we can - we're all really keen to get a bout up and running!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>nnrg</category><category>one year later</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/18/nasty-nessies-one-year-later-scarlett-ohorrorscarolott/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 09:39:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Nasty Nessies 1 Year Later: Nat-orious Red</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/02/nasty-nessies-1-year-later-nat-orious-red/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Continuing our new series looking back at the &lt;a href="http://nastynessiesrollergirls.wordpress.com/"&gt;Nasty Nessies&lt;/a&gt; monthly diarists from the past year to see how 12 months of experience has changed them, we come to the most strikingly coiffed member of the league, Nat-orious Red!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/241375_2587400860612_1101822270_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-2399 " alt="Nat-orious Red, Santa, and Irn Bruzer at the Nessies' Christmas skate." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/241375_2587400860612_1101822270_o.jpg?w=614" width="430" height="613"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Nat-orious Red, Santa, and Irn Bruzer at the Nessies' Christmas skate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's been more than a year since you became one of the first Nasty Nessies.  Looking back at yourself then, with your worries about being clumsy and falling, what advice would you give your earlier self?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;I would tell myself to remember that its roller derby and everyone falls thats why we are sooo well padded, i am actually impressed though that i never was as clumsy as i thought i would be, i can skate better than i can walk!!&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now you've been skating and absorbing Derby for longer, have you picked up any Derby heroes along the way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I am going to say yes and they are both my closest team members, Bee-Yatch and Irn Bruzer just because they have both been there since the beginning and through all the hard work and struggling to recruit they are still just as committed to the league and if it wasn't for them I'm not sure the nessie's would still be around.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A year ago, you were focussing on endurance, and aiming for your 25/5. What are your current challenges, as a mins-passed skater with much more experience?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The biggest challenge since passing mins is keeping team moral up whilst recruiting for newbies so we have a big enough team to bout soon! Bee-yatch and myself do have our first bout on saturday which we are really excited about but at same time we are sad our first game isn't as Nessie's with all our lovely members.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting out, the Nessies got some help from the derby community, with Granite City running the first bootcamp to push your skills up. Now you're in a position to pay it back, what have you been adding to the derby community?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Our training committee traveled  to shetland in december to do a bootcamp for the lovely shetland roller derby, it was a great day and the all the team were such fast learners they picked everything up really fast and were such lovely hosts.  We are looking forward to them passing their mins and visiting us!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What're your plans for the future? The Nessies have been tight-lipped about their plans for the next year…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;As for the Nessie's in the future... You'll just have to stay tuned. &lt;em&gt;(Ed: In fact, a little birdie tells us that the Nessies will be appearing somewhere sooner rather than later...)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>nnrg</category><category>one year later</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/02/nasty-nessies-1-year-later-nat-orious-red/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 11:59:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Nasty Nessies 1 Year Later: Bee-Yatch</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/02/21/nasty-nessies-1-year-later-bee-yatch/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/02/21/nasty-nessies-1-year-later-bee-yatch/nastynessiesrollergirls.wordpress.com"&gt;Nasty Nessies&lt;/a&gt; founder Irn Bruzer launched our series of retrospective interviews with previous Nessie monthly diarists in Jan, this month we have &lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/03/21/monthly-diary-of-a-league-nasty-nessies-in-march-bee-yatch/"&gt;Bee-Yatch&lt;/a&gt; to talk about how her feelings for derby have changed over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/02/comic-con.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2213" alt="Bee-Yatch (centre) promoting the Nessies at Inverness Comic Con." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/02/comic-con.jpg" width="453" height="548"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Bee-Yatch (centre) promoting the Nessies at Inverness Comic Con.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like many skaters, you first encountered Roller Derby through watching "Whip It". Now you're mins-passed and scrimming, how do you feel about the reality of derby, compared with the image you first experienced?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reality of derby is much better than any film! Getting to know a great bunch of girls and to do a sport that I never imagined I would be capable of is great. It’s hard work and requires a lot of commitment but I love every second of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now you've been skating and absorbing Derby for longer, have you picked up any Derby heroes or inspirations along the way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspiration for me comes from my own team mates, they share the good, the bad and the ugly and are always there to help you up and push you past the mental block that can prevent you from moving forward. I genuinely couldn’t ask for a better bunch of mishmashed people! As for heroes, well anyone who plays Roller Derby is an instant hero to me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The last time we talked, you mentioned that the most difficult and important challenges for you had been training related - building endurance and building skills and confidence. Looking back a year, would you give yourself different advice now than you thought then?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My advice to myself would be that everyone learns at a different pace, some people pick things up simply by watching then trying it themselves and others have to break it down more, either way keep on trying and never give up. You just have to learn to get up, dust yourself down and keep on going, you will get there in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, following on from that, how do you see yourself as a skater now; what are your current challenges and inspirations?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current challenge is to learn to put together all we have learned in training and apply it to the game. It’s good to build on endurance and skills but you need to know what to do with it all. There’s so much to think about, strategy, where you should be on the track, where’s your jammer, where’s their jammer, who is trying to push you off the track, who is about to land a hit on you….phew it’s a lot to think about/put into action all at once! ;-) How do I see myself as a skater now…hmm I think I will always be a newbie at heart!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Nessies have, of course, recruited more fresh meat since we talked. Being one of the Experienced Skaters in the league, how do you feel about the new blood coming in? (Are they scarily better than you were, do you empathise with their initial problems?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We currently have a great bunch of newbies, they seem to be so fearless! I see some girls after a few weeks and am so impressed with their abilities. I am not a natural born skater so I think I can relate to the more nervous newbie and keep them going with encouragement and be an example of how perseverance can keep you upright, in derby stance of course ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, finally, what's new for the coming year with the Nessies?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
A few of the Nessies went to Dundee last Friday and did some scrimming with the lovely Dundee Roller Girls. We were made to feel really welcome by all the girls and had an excellent time, we literally buzzed all the way home so thank you Dundee! :-)
&lt;p&gt;As for what we have up our sleeve for this coming year, 2013 is going to put NNRG on the map so keep your eyes peeled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next month's retrospective will be by Natorious Red!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>monthly diary</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>nnrg</category><category>one year later</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/02/21/nasty-nessies-1-year-later-bee-yatch/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 14:22:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Monthly Diary Special: Nasty Nessies 1 Year Later: Irn Bruzer</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/01/20/monthly-diary-special-nasty-nessies-1-year-later-irn-bruzer/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://nastynessiesrollergirls.wordpress.com/"&gt;Nasty Nessies&lt;/a&gt; have been writing to their dear monthly diary on the blog now for more than a year. In the spirit of self-improvement and the new year, we decided to go back to the first ever Nasty Nessies diarist, founder Irn Bruzer, and ask her what's changed since she was interviewed way back in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/472039_507739752593196_968145019_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-2110" alt="Irn Bruzer (now with appropriately blue hair!) poses with derby-wife Natorious Red at their Christmas skate." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/01/472039_507739752593196_968145019_o.jpg?w=460" width="460" height="614"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Irn Bruzer (now with appropriately blue hair!) poses with derby-wife Black Death at their Christmas skate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So: Way back in October 2011, you told us how Whip It had alerted to you to the existence of Roller Derby; how has the past year changed and affirmed your initial impressions of derby?&lt;/strong&gt;
Well firstly it’s definitely a way to find and make amazing friends. Some of the girls would be the kind you would walk past in the street, but now you wouldn't know where you would be without them! It’s definitely got the excitement and community that you see in the film, just not as much theatrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Nessies have gotten a lot of local awareness from appearing at various events (the Inverness comic con, for example). How hard is it to organise these things, and what's the experience and reaction been like from spectators.&lt;/strong&gt;
Well luckily for us, Comic Con was a huge event already organised. All it took was a few emails and a meeting. It was also even better as we were allowed to skate around the venue which helped greatly with gaining interest. We got a lot of interest but many of them were 16. Hopefully they will keep in the loop for the next two years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now the Nessies have a large number of mins-passed skaters, how close do you feel you are to your first bout? Do you have anyone in mind to pop your bouting cherry?&lt;/strong&gt;
2013 is definitely our year! We have some great newbies who show a lot of potential too. It's taken a bit of time to find our groove but now we have, there will be a Nessie takeover!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Over the past year, what've the best and most difficult things been for the Nessies in general? What advice would you give now to a league just starting out?&lt;/strong&gt;
The biggest issue we have had is recruitment and keeping people! I know all teams go through this, but Inverness just hasn’t been taken by the derby bug yet which is disappointing. We are planning a fresh recruitment drive and we have a few things in the pipeline so hopefully we can get more people on eight wheels! I think the best advice I could give is just constantly recruit, never give up or push it back for a while. You can never have enough people as you never know who you will lose unexpectedly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recently, the Nessies popped up to Shetland to help out Shetland Roller Derby training. How does it feel to be at the level now where you can "pay back" to the community by helping out in the same way that GCRG et al helped you out at the start?&lt;/strong&gt;
Our trip to Shetland was fantastic; being on the opposite level was great as we could see how far we have come! We saw some great up and coming skaters up there and amazing determination from some newbies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, the next year looks like being a potentially exciting one for Scottish Roller Derby in general. What've the Nessies got planned?&lt;/strong&gt;
Now that would be telling wouldn't it! You’ll just have to wait and see!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>monthly diary</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>nnrg</category><category>one year later</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/01/20/monthly-diary-special-nasty-nessies-1-year-later-irn-bruzer/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 13:07:23 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>