<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about orkney viqueens)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/orkney-viqueens.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 11:57:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Orkney's ViQueens invade Inverness!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/15/orkneys-viqueens-invade-inverness/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend marks a particular piece of history, as Scotland's northernmost league make their public debut. Orkney's ViQueens have been working hard on becoming bout ready since their founding in January 2017, and have taken less than 20 months to do so, which is fairly impressive work. This will be an away game, as is common for debut bouts, hosted in the Capital of the Highlands, Inverness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Inverness City Roller Derby are the closest bouting league to Orkney, it will still be a 180 km trip, as the crow flies, for the skaters attending their first ever bout as a team. (Whilst Elgin is a closer location, direct, it's faster to get to Inverness, due to the need to land at a sea- or airport at the mainland.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby themselves, whilst very experienced, have only 2 public bouts on record themselves, as the travel costs for Highlands teams are difficult in general. (We'd hope that, together with Helgin Roller Derby, and potentially new league Ullapool Slayers, the newly bouting Orkney would allow a small "Highlands Leagues" cluster to support more sustainable competition in the future.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught up with Orkney ViQueens founder, DeafWish, to learn about the team's history and feelings at this critical point in their existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-27229 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/orkneyviqueens.jpg" alt="OrkneyViQueens" width="370" height="370"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Orkney is a bit more isolated than the majority of locations for Roller Derby leagues. How have you been coping with the higher cost of travel - for your skaters, and for guests? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We know it’s not the easiest place to get to, so we offer to accommodate visiting skaters and coaches wherever possible.  We can also advise on cheaper routes and travel options. We try to make dates known as far in advance as we can, to help with being able to get cheaper options.  We also have some great support and sponsorship: [Orkney-based jewellers] Ortak will allow us to use some of their self-catering accommodation to host officials for when we have a game at home (hopefully next year!) and when we travel [Northern isles ferry operator] Northlink offer us a discount on ferry travel, which really helps.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Whilst this is your first public bout, Orkney ViQueens have had a very active first year and half. What's been the most important thing the team has done? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Undoubtedly it’s been our bootcamps.  We had four in the first year, which let us progress to the next stage of our skills, learn from some amazing skaters, and meet people from other leagues who came to skate with us.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What have you been working on most, ahead of your first game? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The biggest challenge we have is being so isolated. We have no referees, NSOs or experienced skaters to help us navigate some of the more intricate penalties or elements of gameplay. We have been focusing on gameplay aspects like jam starts, responding to penalty calls, maintaining a pack and identifying people’s preferred roles.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;b&gt;
Inverness City have been a fixture of the ‘Northern’ cluster of Scottish Derby for a long while - how do your teams get on?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Both Inverness and Aberdeen's Granite City (our other nearest neighbour [by travel distance]!) are brilliant. We have had coaches and skaters from both come up to bootcamps with us, and they are always ready to answer our questions and offer advice and help. Natorious and Monica Yeller were our first bootcamp coaches so we are thrilled that Inverness are now our first opponents.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;b&gt;
What are your aims for your debut bout? Do you have a target score, just looking to play the game, or something else you want to do?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We would like to play the game well as a team. For us that means working together, developing confidence in our roles, keeping our penalty count down and having fun.  Inverness are an experienced team so they are going to be a challenge for us, which we are looking forward to!
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;b&gt;What's next for Orkney ViQueens? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Building our pool of officials to help us have a better grasp of the game and have more effective scrims, and also recruiting and training bench and LUM staff. We are lucky for this game to have Hydra (Rule 56 and Rainy City Roller Derby) benching for us and some of our pre-mins skaters and family having the opportunity to learn NSO and LUM roles in this game. We will then build on this knowledge going forward.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We have a busy few months coming up, with plans for another bootcamp with (Pay as you Feel Coaching's) Nuke and Udder in October; Granite City Roller Derby are coming for a skating holiday with us and we are hoping to have another away game in November. We are also continuing to develop our youth team, Orkney ViTeens, with after-school sessions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inverness City Roller Derby versus Orkney ViQueens Roller Derby will be held at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/DZjmoUJMWVE2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inverness Royal Academy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;18th August&lt;/strong&gt;, from &lt;strong&gt;midday&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>orkney viqueens</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/15/orkneys-viqueens-invade-inverness/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 10:25:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UK Coaching: Derby Form Check</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/05/uk-coaching-derby-form-check/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;One of the hot topics in Roller Derby, always, is Coaching. In recent times, since the Derby Stance Coaching Summit, we've seen even more collaboration and discussion in the area of UK Coaching - with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com"&gt;Rule56&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s Coaching Webinars a direct follow on from this. However, there's initiatives happening even in the furthest reaches of the UK's geography... as our guest writer, and founder of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/403911146657994/"&gt;Derby Form Check&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Ronie Walters (of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/OrkneyViqueens/"&gt;Orkney ViQueens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) explains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-18605" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/derbyformcheck.jpg?w=300" alt="DerbyFormCheck" width="300" height="210"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the great things about roller derby is the grassroots ethos. We all know the ethos: "by the skaters for the skaters". You don’t need to jump through a lot of hoops and regulations to set up a roller derby league, you can just have the idea and get going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly what we did in Orkney. Orkney is a small group of islands, off the North coast of Scotland. To get to us you need to get either a plane or a ferry. Obviously travelling to train with a local league is not really an option in this situation, so when we wanted to get started, we had to start from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roller Derby Community is lovely. Everyone is really supportive and I’ve made some great contacts whom I consider friends I’ve just not met yet, which has been awesome. But... it kind of feels like everyone is re-inventing the wheel.
Every single league I’ve encountered is using the WFTDA min-skills in some form as their standard for knowing when a skater is safe to play.
Every single league runs some form of “fresh meat” training program to get their skaters through those min skills.
Yet trying to find a training program to use as a template has been almost impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went to join the UKRDA to use that as a resource, yet, at present, you have to have been skating for 6 months as a team to be eligible to join – leaving you alone to muddle through until that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were lucky enough to manage to get a couple of people to do the BRSF [British Roller Sports Federation] level 2 coaching course recently in Luton (from what I can gather, it’s not been run for a while) so that was amazing for us, and we learnt a lot from it in terms of coaching cues and coaching skills. We also attended the Rule 56 online coaching pilot, and are excited for the next sessions coming up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule 56, like us, are looking for more joined up approaches to Roller Derby Coaching. They also believe we have some incredibly awesome coaches and skaters amongst us, we just need a more effective way to share them. The more we can share resources and skills, the faster we can progress as a sport, and the better the experience for those coming into the sport as new skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be nice if, one day, new leagues starting in the UK could simply go to one place, and find all the information they needed.
This could be something as simple as UKRDA offering an associate membership so leagues can have access to the resources they need for that six month waiting period. This could then offer things like policies and constitutions, a clearly laid out min skills program, information on how to test a min skill and tell if your skater has mastered it, a resource for learning how to coach effectively, and access to a library of videos of real skaters complete with feedback on where they can improve, as well as video of ideal form to know what you are looking to get your skaters to.
The latter part of this has taken a step forward recently, with the introduction of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCoWo7DaL7OZGmG6gijWd7SQ"&gt;WFTDA Ed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; min skills videos. For the first time, there is some standardised indication of what a skill should look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, how do you get from where you are now, to that perfect form? Something I read recently in PEAK, when it was being discussed in the roller derby book club, was the notion of deliberate practice. Peak posits that there is no such thing as people with innate talent or ability. Even the likes of Beethoven or Tiger Woods are great because they have put in a lot of practice.
But this is not just about spending time; it’s about deliberate practice. Taking a skill and breaking it down into its elements, then practicing the elements making use of effective feedback to help you master the different parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a new club, we are learning together. We have some skilled skaters, but no-one with roller derby experience, or with experience in how to observe a skater and break the skill down for them with feedback to allow them to practice the elements and build it back up. It occurred to me that if we as a wider roller derby community could share video footage of us skating, we could all benefit from the feedback experienced skaters could provide. We are all individual, and we all learn differently. Sometimes the way someone explains something just clicks for you and, all of a sudden, you master that tricky bit you have been stuck on for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roller Derby Form Check&lt;/em&gt; aims to provide this opportunity. As a new Facebook group, it only has a few videos at present, but with over 370 members, it has the potential to be a very powerful resource. The hope is that gradually people will start to post a video of themselves doing a skill they are struggling with. So rather than a written post of how you're struggling with your 27/5 or you just can’t get transitions but don’t know why, you can film yourself. You will then get personalised feedback, rather than generic answers, or written descriptions which can be hard to visualise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our dream for the group is that over time we build a library of people demonstrating common issues with the minimum skills, with a whole range of ways of explaining how they can work to improve from different people.
Some of those explanations will hopefully also come with a video of them demonstrating the techniques they are suggesting. Using this, coupled with the “perfect” examples from WFTDA Ed, will really allow for some really powerful coaching resources to develop. We can already see that coaches are finding it helpful to learn additional ways to explain things and break skills down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you are stuck on a skill you just can’t seem to master, no matter how often your coach explains it, post a video. Maybe someone else’s tips will help you. If you are a coach and you have one skater that you just can’t figure out how to help, ask them if they are OK with posting a video and see if other people’s explanations can help them break through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Derby Form Check is a (closed) Facebook Group, open for registration: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/403911146657994/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/groups/403911146657994/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coaching</category><category>orkney viqueens</category><category>rule56</category><category>video</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/05/uk-coaching-derby-form-check/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 09:36:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Scotland's newest, Northernmost league... Orkney ViQueens!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/13/scotlands-newest-northernmost-league-orkney-viqueens/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We hinted a few articles ago that there's lots of new Roller Derby leagues popping up still.. and then we discovered that we'd underestimated even then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/OrkneyViqueens/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orkney ViQueens&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are, to our knowledge, both the newest Roller Derby "league" (they style themselves a "Club" currently), and also now Scotland's northernmost, taking the top spot from Helgin Roller Derby (and returning it to the Isles, after Shetland sadly stopped).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby in the Northern Isles introduces a number of complexities, in addition to the usual issues of starting a new league, and so we were excited to get in touch with the founders and see what their plans are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We managed to catch up with founder DeafWish (Ronie Walters) to find out what kind of person would start a league on an Island!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a longstanding fascination with Roller Derby ever since I first heard about it. I love the culture, the names, the speed – let’s face it, being able to skate round and play full contact sounds awesome (though I might not still be saying that when I have fallen over a few times!) From my Master's research in applied positive psychology, I know that physical activity is extremely beneficial for mental and physical wellbeing. It’s also known that women in general are less likely to play sport – particularly team sports and contact sports - so I wanted to try and change that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love how Roller Derby has benefits on so many levels – physical, social, confidence, body positivity and mental strength. Skating is great fun, and it is a very effective workout. I love that a lot of people start Derby with minimal (or no) skating experience. There's room for a lot of different body shapes and sizes and so it really is open to pretty much anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I moved from one of the smaller Orkney islands (~130 people) to the larger Mainland island I decided to see if anyone else was interested. I half expected to get no response, so I was pretty shocked when the initial FaceBook post resulted in a closed group with 30-odd members within 48 hours!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group was set up on the 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; November and since then we have been busy. I am so lucky to have such a great team of people willing to work with me to make this happen. Our committee currently has 7 members, we have a logo (thanks to a wonderful graphic designer who plans to join us) and we have our first event booked for the &lt;strong&gt;28&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; December&lt;/strong&gt; – a social and information evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a venue booked for twice a week skate sessions, starting &lt;strong&gt;17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; January&lt;/strong&gt;. We will do an hour of recreational skating, followed by 2 hours of more structured skate training. 2 of our members have skating experience so they will be attempting to whip the rest of us into some form of basic skating ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been lucky enough to have our first donation of £300 from my employer [Orkney Micro-Renewables], so that will let us get 3 or 4 sets of basic club kit to lend out, and we are applying to Awards For All for funding to help us establish – we are running on zero budget at the moment! We are also seeking links with local businesses to offer member discounts – the hope is that they will benefit from increased publicity, and we will benefit by making a monthly membership subscription seem more appealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have had some wonderful advice from Krusty and Laura at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.granitecityrollerderby.co.uk/"&gt;Granite [City Roller Derby]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Natorious Red from I&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/InvernessCityRollerDerby/"&gt;nverness [City Roller Derby]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and Hydra-el from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/"&gt;Rule 56&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. We are hoping, once we can all skate at a basic level, to have some of these guys come up and run some bootcamps for us to teach us more derby specific skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think some of the biggest challenges for us are our location, and our lack of derby knowledge. We are all on a steep learning curve over everything from what skates and equipment to suggest and how to stop floors getting marked through to more complicated stuff that is harder to get answers to - like is there an etiquette around when to take a derby name? How do you decide on a number? What the heck is a derby wife and do I need one? And most importantly – deciphering the rules of the game and how to teach them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have also had some issues in finding venue space – in Orkney pretty much every sports team comes inside for the winter, so the venues that are big enough for a track are full. We have found a smaller hall for use till April and then we hope to switch to somewhere bigger, ready for when we are more likely to be benefiting from the increased space (and will hopefully have figured out how to lay a track and have it stay there while you skate!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have big dreams as a club – we would like to be able to get to a level where we can travel and compete. We are really keen to start developing a junior league once we know what we are doing, and we would love to create a dedicated skate venue here in Orkney!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we are at a position to play scrims and bouts we hope folk will be willing to make a trip up here – it’s a beautiful place, and I’m guessing we will be the UK’s most northerly team – and possibly the only island team?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orkney ViQueens' first ever event is scheduled for &lt;strong&gt;28th&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;December 2016&lt;/strong&gt;, a meet-and-learn information event at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Bothy+Bar/@58.9840072,-2.962384,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x489b0163fd0eab57:0x9c0d24c24d68a482!8m2!3d58.9840072!4d-2.96019"&gt;The Bothy Bar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Kirkwall. The event page is here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/346341755740009/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/346341755740009/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>northern isles</category><category>orkney viqueens</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/13/scotlands-newest-northernmost-league-orkney-viqueens/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 13:47:24 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>