<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about pan-asian spring rollers)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/pan-asian-spring-rollers.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:36:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>UAE All-Stars: A National Team for the Emirates</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/03/20/uae-all-stars-a-national-team-for-the-emirates/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst we often talk about Roller Derby in North America, and Europe and Australasia, and somewhat less about Latin America (at least, in English - &lt;em&gt;en español,&lt;/em&gt; a lot is said) we speak much less about Roller Derby in the rest of the World. Part of this is because of a similar tendency to only talk about teams which compete internationally... of which there are much fewer outside of those above regions. This is a self-fulfilling prophecy, of course, since isolated teams, inherently, find it hard to find any local opponents: and they can't find international opponents if people don't talk about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United Arab Emirates has had two Roller Derby leagues: Dubai Roller Derby, and Abu Dhabi Roller Derby, for more than 6 years, the two forming within a few months of each other in late 2012. It's been hard for them to find opponents elsewhere, however, especially given the roster sizes for the two. 
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this year, members of both teams decided to collaborate on a bigger thing: a Emirates-wide Travel Team, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/UAERollerDerby/"&gt;UAE Roller Derby All-Stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, representing the country on the international stage. (Between them, Dubai and Abu Dhabi represent about 2/3s of the population of the UAE, but there are 5 other Emirates which could still develop teams.)
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spoke to two of the main agents of this initiative, Mean Curls and Inga Knee’her, about how this got organised, and what their plans are.
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27922} --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="UAE Roller Derby Logo (&amp;amp;quot;UAE All-Stars&amp;amp;quot; forming part of a circle in grey, with the Arabic name in green on top, designed to include the image of a roller skate in the negative space)" src="https://scottishrollerderby.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/52672994_267004467546689_505072778026680320_n.jpg" title="UAE Roller Derby Logo ('UAE All-Stars' forming part of a circle in grey, with the Arabic name in green on top, designed to include the image of a roller skate in the negative space)"&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As long ago as 2013, Dubai and Abu Dhabi Roller Derby had discussed the possibility of forming a national, potentially WFTDA-sanctioned, joint team. However, with both leagues also organising their individual affairs, it wasn't possible to achieve this until recently: there wasn't enough time, or experience, in the teams to build the bigger plan.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018, however, Inga Knee'her became one of the most experienced new members of Dubai Roller Derby - transferring to the team after 10 years of experience in Steel City Roller Derby (at the time WFTDA D 1 team), and Tokyo Roller Derby. As well as spearheading the adoption of Rolla Skate Club's Short Track Roller Derby ruleset to enable Dubai to play more derby in more places, she's also become part of the trio behind the UAE All-Stars.
With Spinky (president of Abu Dhabi Roller Derby) and Mean Curls, the plan has gone from a discussion over ice-cream to reality.
As Inga and Mean Curls tell it: "In less than two months, we [] created the team, organized weekly practices focusing on Short Track coached by Inga, and played our first international game in Hong Kong as part of Pan Asian Spring Rollers (prompting the self-proclaimed name of the “Get Sh*t Done Team” :D)."
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Dubai and Abu Dhabi also the most populous cities in the UAE (and their eponymous emirates), and fairly closely located, the All-Stars can alternate training between the two easily, helping to build a sense of equal partnership in the national team.
At present, the team is working on helping to develop visibility and interest in Roller Derby - and Roller  skating - in the UAE, where historically there hasn't been much. (At present, all of Dubai and Abu Dhabi's kit comes from abroad via international shipping.)
One aim of this increased visibility is towards developing the skill levels for their member skaters, by providing opportunities for higher level play that would otherwise be inaccessible. 
Inga's contacts with the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers (the Roller Derby collaboration between Beijing, Shanghai, Hong-Kong and Bangkok &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderby.wordpress.com/2017/06/07/east-asian-derbys-new-spring-rollers/"&gt;we've covered previously&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) immediately paid off in this sense. Having played against the Spring Rollers as part of the Women's Roller Derby Japan team at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderby.wordpress.com/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/"&gt;Tomodachi Roller Derby tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Okinawa (2017), she was hoping for opponents to play Short Track derby with.
As it happens, the timing of the Spring Rollers bout against Hong-Kong was too good to pass up: Mean Curls, Spinky, and Inga were able to make the trip to join Pan Asia v. Hong Kong as members of the Spring Rollers team.
(Their team ended up winning too, 159 to HKRD's 127.)
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That bout also helped to build even more contacts: Derby Without Borders' founder Mae Dae has recently relocated to Bangkok, and was present as part of the Hong Kong event. We're promised future collaborations with Derby without Borders, supporting their mission in the Middle East and Asia so watch this space! (Mae themself has also been busy since moving to Bangkok, and we'll be catching up with them in a future article.) 
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27923,"width":561,"height":842} --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Two of UAE All-Stars' skaters (Mean Curls, Spinky) in blue as part of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers team against hosts Hong Kong Roller Derby. Photograph by Teddy Tse" src="https://scottishrollerderby.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/dsc_5798-2.jpg" title="Two of UAE All-Stars' skaters (Mean Curls, Spinky) in blue as part of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers team against hosts Hong Kong Roller Derby. Photograph by Teddy Tse"&gt;Two of UAE All-Stars' skaters (Mean Curls, Spinky) in blue as part of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers team against hosts Hong Kong Roller Derby. Photograph by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teddy.tse.12"&gt;Teddy Tse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At home, they're focusing on Short Track Roller Derby as it makes practice much more accessible: not only is it easier in terms of numbers, the smaller space needed (the Short Track track fits inside a standard basketball court) makes it much easier, and cheaper, to find spaces to practice in. 
With the UAE's regulations limiting other opportunities (public events need licenses, for example), having more options in hosting always helps. 
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, UAE All-Stars aren't limiting themselves to a single ruleset for future games. Inga and Mean Curls emphasised "we are interested in any and all roller derby opportunities for our skaters. We are lucky to live in a place with direct flights to so many cities, making it relatively easy for us to visit other teams as well as to host events in the future."  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, whilst the team has not ruled out applying to join the WFTDA in the future, they're also setting their sites on the most international of competitions. 
"Our ultimate goal is to represent the UAE at the next Roller Derby World Cup," the team told us, adding "Mean Curls is the only current Emirati roller derby skater (that we know of) and will represent us on the Nations Committee".
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>abu dhabi roller derby</category><category>articles</category><category>dubai roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><category>short track roller derby</category><category>uae all-stars roller derby</category><category>uae roller derby all-stars</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/03/20/uae-all-stars-a-national-team-for-the-emirates/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 12:27:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Short Track Worldwide Update (2019 Feb)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/03/01/short-track-worldwide-update-2019-feb/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderby.wordpress.com/2018/10/26/short-track-roller-derby-a-first-scottish-test/"&gt;first article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://rollaskateclub.com/lets-rolla/"&gt;Short Track Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, back in 2018, the new ruleset has continued to spread, in almost all the places in the world where Roller Derby is played.
As such, we thought we’d follow up, just 4 months later, with some of the exciting developments in Short Track worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, as readers of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://whataboutmagazine.com/"&gt;What A Bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; magazine will already know, Short Track Roller Derby has spread further-and-wider than we could have hoped: to Russia, and Dubai, in the United Arab Emirates, already. You should read the full article in WAB &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://whataboutmagazine.com/2019/01/20/what-a-bout-issue-3-winter-2019/"&gt;Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for full details, but look out for several Short Track tournaments in Moscow, and other Russian cities later in the year. Dubai’s interest in Short Track has also led to bigger things which we’ll get to later in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short Track is continuing to enable more teams to play derby, even now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Poland, Gdańsk’s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/551140512034275/"&gt;Chrome Sirens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are playing their first ever public game, thanks to Short Track rules enabling them to put together two competitive teams (and use more accessible venues). This double-header event will be coming to the city in the middle of next month - March 16th!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Americas, Short Track Derby is also taking off: ruleset creators Rolla Skate Club having provided initial impetus with a comprehensive series of trial sessions across Canada and the North-west of the USA. In Latin America, meanwhile, there is interest in Buenos Aires, Argentina, in exploring the ruleset, as it solves several of the challenges of the many teams in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27916,"width":600,"height":426,"linkDestination":"custom"} --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Illinois Valley Vixens Roller Derby during their first public bout under Short Track Rules.(Photo used by permission of Dave Schrader under license. [not covered by site CC license] )" src="https://scottishrollerderby.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/img_6131-crop-1.jpg" title="Illinois Valley Vixens Roller Derby during their first public bout under Short Track Rules.(Photo used by permission of Dave Schrader under license. [not covered by site CC license])"&gt;Illinois Valley Vixens Roller Derby during their first public bout under Short Track Rules.(Photo used by permission of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/korfan/collections/"&gt;Dave Schrader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; under license. [not covered by site CC license] )
&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the USA, though, public bouts have already started, with the ruleset enabling teams to play their first games in years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/IVVRD/"&gt;Illinois Valley Vixens Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, who played their first public bout for 3 years thanks to Short Track back in February, the ruleset has been a revelation. Whilst some venue issues meant that they had to modify the track slightly, the bout was a complete success - despite only using word of mouth and social media for advertising, they managed to fill all the available seating. Speaking for the league, Lemon Squeezer told us : “We now know that a smaller track definitely does not mean less exciting or intense, quite the opposite! I can't remember a time I have heard a crowd this engaged before and the feedback from spectators was that they are looking forward to the next one and bringing friends. We also had several former skaters come to check it out that are now interested in coming back.”. 
I.M.GROOT added, “The fact that all players have to both jam and block really takes you out of your comfort zone. It pushes you to use all the skills you have learned, not just the ones you prefer. Short Track has the ability to really push skaters to be stronger, better and more adaptable in game play.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an even more striking mode, the USA has also brought us the first ever “Short Track” league: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pstrollerderby.com/"&gt;Pittsburgh Short Track Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, founded by a group of skaters who retired from “competitive” Roller Derby, but still wanted to play a friendlier version of the sport. Their league aim, as expressed on their website and Facebook page, “We are a group of friends who wanted to create a safe, stress free environment to get together and skate. Community over competition.” encapsulates the entire point of Short Track as a ruleset and community. (You can find out more about them on social media and their website.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further in the future, there’s also exciting news of potentially the first ever international Short Track Roller Derby Tournament.  The newly created &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/UAERollerDerby/"&gt;UAE All-Stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the United Arab Emirates’ official travel team, are exploding onto the scene, and one of their first public plans is to play Short Track Derby! Formed of skaters from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DubaiRollerDerby/"&gt;Dubai Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ADRollerDerby/"&gt;Abu Dhabi Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the team plan to play all kinds of Derby, but Short Track is definitely a solid component of their goals. [We have more about UAE All-Stars themselves in another new article here, which we’re going to publish soon - and their first ever public game &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/495068457564329/"&gt;will be this weekend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, 2nd March, in Hong Kong, as part of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27917,"width":576,"height":384} --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="UAE Roller Derby All-Stars practising on the Short Track [courtesy of UAE All-Stars]" src="https://scottishrollerderby.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/53180456_272367973677005_4491993895592263680_n-e1551445852446.jpg" title="UAE Roller Derby All-Stars practising on the Short Track [courtesy of UAE All-Stars]"&gt;UAE Roller Derby All-Stars practising on the Short Track [courtesy of UAE All-Stars]
&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the support of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gogogent.be/en/home-default/"&gt;GO-GO Gent Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, who had been investigating hosting an experimental Short Track clinic for several months, UAE All-Stars will be travelling to Belgium on the 1st and 2nd of June. The first day will be a Short Track Roller Derby training workshop, allowing the experienced skaters from Dubai’s testing of the rules (and potentially other skaters who’ve tried Short Track from the rest of Europe) to explain and demonstrate the potential of the ruleset to attendees.  
The second day will be a tournament event: the structure of which is still under development. Teams are welcome to participate from across Europe, and we know that there’s been interest from several regions already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even further in the future, there’s the possibility of Short Track bootcamps in other parts of Europe, including the UK, and other plans afoot about which we can’t speak at this time. Stay tuned for further updates as they occur!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dubai roller derby</category><category>in the news</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><category>polish roller derby</category><category>short format tournaments</category><category>short track roller derby</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/03/01/short-track-worldwide-update-2019-feb/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 13:12:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Guest Post: Roller Derby — Bangkok Style!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/22/guest-post-roller-derby-bangkok-style/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In another guest post, we're bringing you a report on Bangkok Roller Derby's recent bout against Pan-Asian travel team, the Spring Rollers, by Mouth Almighty; Mouth recently moved to Bangkok (after being deeply involved in UK derby), and this was her first experience of the East-Asian implementation of the sport. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, 2 weeks ago I moved from the UK to Bangkok as part of a change of employment. As a former skater with Wolverhampton Honor Rollers and  a former director of UKRDA (United Kingdom Roller Derby Association) back in Britain, I was eager to see what Roller Derby in Bangkok had to offer. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As luck would have it, within my first week of moving to Thailand, Bangkok Roller Derby were hosting an event: "Monsoon Mayhem".&lt;br&gt; So, at 7pm on Saturday 17th of November, I had my very first taste of Roller Derby, Bangkok-style. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Most Roller Derby bouts or events in the UK tend to be set in the morning or mid afternoon, in a local leisure centre or school (or whatever venue a team can manage to find that is big enough to host a game and is willing to allow teams to actually skate).&lt;br&gt;Here, Bangkok Roller Derby have the luxury of an actual Roller Dome and an evening start time (I can see why, as it had been 34°C most of the day, with a huge rainstorm in the afternoon, so the humidity factor meant that it was still about 30 degrees at 7pm). &lt;br&gt;These factors put together surely helped bring what was very close to a capacity crowd to this event, something that I fear very few Roller Derby teams in the UK have the joy of seeing at their events. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby versus Pan-Asian Spring Rollers&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:heading --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27781} --&gt;

&lt;figure class="wp-block-image"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/11/bangkok-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-27781"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/gjsheehan"&gt;Gareth Sheehan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gameplay itself was fast paced and aggressive, not violent, simply aggressive, passionate gameplay. The  girls on track seemed to truly enjoy the fun, frantic pace of the game, as did the people watching it.&lt;br&gt;An injury early on in the first half bought to my attention that first aid here in Bangkok is not at the same level as bouts in the UK. (However, this was a friendly game). A single first-aider dealt with the injured player before she was eventually taken off the track in a wheelchair (temporary, I’m sure!) to rapturous applause from both players and spectators.&lt;br&gt;The game continued at a fast pace, with fast jams but with relatively low scoring from both teams; some heavy blocks and hits but thankfully no more injuries.&lt;br&gt;The second half continued at the same frantic pace, some very fast jammers up against some skilled blocking on both teams. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Noticeable differences between UK and Bangkok Roller Derby included less referees and NSOs (this may have been due to lack of volunteers perhaps &lt;em&gt;[something which affects Roller Derby everywhere - Ed])&lt;/em&gt; but as Bangkok Roller Derby grows, and as roller derby in Asia grows in general, this will surely stop being the case. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27782} --&gt;

&lt;figure class="wp-block-image"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/11/bangkok-2.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-27782"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/gjsheehan"&gt;Gareth Sheehan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Announcing was minimal, but with a team made up of English, American, Canadian, French &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Thai players, and with a truly multicultural audience watching, perhaps announcing would have simply been lost in translation... &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also no music playing during the game, something that as a follower of UK roller derby I have become used to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing Bangkok Roller Derby did that is not the norm in UK (although is becoming more common for the big tournaments) is half time entertainment: three inline skaters (one in a dinosaur costume) dancing and doing tricks, followed by throwing cuddly toys out into the crowd, which the audience loved. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; The game finished and it was evident that the players on track, the spectators and everyone involved had enjoyed a great evening of roller derby&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:separator --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator"&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:separator --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby can be found here: &lt;a href="https://bangkokrollerderby.weebly.com/"&gt;https://bangkokrollerderby.weebly.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Their opponents, the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers, are a travel team composed of members of Beijing Roller Derby, Shanghai Roller Derby, Hong Kong Roller Derby and Bangkok Roller Derby (but are open to other Asian teams). They can be found here: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Pan-Asian-Spring-Rollers-448887468791803/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/Pan-Asian-Spring-Rollers-448887468791803/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>bout reports</category><category>guest posts</category><category>international derby</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/22/guest-post-roller-derby-bangkok-style/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 14:04:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>East Asian Derby's new Spring (Rollers)!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/07/east-asian-derbys-new-spring-rollers/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Spring is the time when new growth happens, how appropriate it is that East Asian Roller Derby is just now bursting into life and catalysed by the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-14040 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/pan-asian.jpg" alt="pan-asian" width="223" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Readers may remember our coverage of Japan's second-ever Roller Derby Tournament, the&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, in Okinawa earlier this year. The &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/02/08/the-tomodachi-cup-teams-pan-asian-spring-rollers/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pan-Asian Spring Rollers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; were one of two "exhibition" teams founded to attend - comprising of skaters from Beijing Roller Derby, Shanghai Roller Derby, Hong Kong Roller Derby (the three Chinese leagues), and Bangkok Roller Derby for Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally, the plan was for them to simply exist for the one tournament - a chance for those 4 leagues to share costs and make a more competitive roster together - but the Spring Rollers have quickly become something more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only a few weeks ago, Shanghai Roller Derby held their first ever public game, enabled by the existence of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers as a team to play against them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a few weeks' time, Hong Kong Roller Derby also hold their first public game, ever, once again enabled by the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pan-Asian Spring Rollers are represented by reps from each of their source teams, and we spoke to their Hong Kong Rep, Willow Whips (who also Captained PASR at Tomodachi), and their Bangkok Rep, Jean Claude van Slam about the new aims of PASR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JC:"We all got on amazingly well [at the Tomodachi Derby Tournament], some of us meeting for the first time just hours before our first game. I think we all felt sad to depart afterwards partly for the awesome experience but also as new found friends.
It was after I chatted with members of Okinawa Roller Derby that the idea came to try and maintain the PASRs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beijing and Bangkok had talked before about the importance of maintaining the relationship between our teams as the key to growing this sport in Asia and so this seemed like the perfect opportunity to harness that enthusiasm and drive this new partnership into something long standing."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WW: "We have been working on a set of regulations and things like that, so the aim is that each team will try and host one event (a training session or a scrim) per year. Bangkok is planning on hosting a boot camp and scrimmage at the beginning of October, which will be open to anyone affiliated with Pan-Asian Roller Derby"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JC: For BRD, it's given members a new motivation for the sport, knowing that all that effort each week of learning and practicing drills has a chance to be put into real action, in addition to attracting new people to our team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the issues for BRD being out further than the rest, is the travel costs. However, one of PASRs conditions for being a team member is to host at least one event per year so this should make for plenty of opportunities to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope that this will also help us to build recognition of the sport in Thailand and encourage more people to join. Just having those opportunities that has already made such a difference [to the team]"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WW: "The [long term] aim is to head back to Japan next year for the [next Japanese] tournament, now that we have played together a few times we will hopefully be even more badass!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JC:"I hope that with the extended reach out to lone players in parts of Asia who don't currently have a home team, the PASR team might encourage new leagues to start in other Asian countries. That's yet to be seen but fingers crossed!!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Willow: "If any teams want to join they just have to be in the region and put forward one representative from the team. If any individual skaters are in the area they are also welcome to sign up and train and play with us!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next fixture in this new East Asian derby calendar is against Hong Kong Roller Derby on the 17th June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-20178" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/hkrd.jpg?w=300" alt="HKRD" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Roller Derby, which started out when founder Buffy SlayHers moved to Hong Kong from the USA in 2013, was inspired by an article listing "Top 5 Reasons HK Needs a Roller Derby Team" after realising that her new destination had no derby at all. As Buffy put it, "So I decided the best way to start was to "recruit " my friend, and roommate at the time, Glenda by having a roomie night and watching, yes, you guessed it, 'Whip It!' Now, before you start hating, and as cliche as it I, I think all of us love 'Whip It!' whether we have accepted the facts or not."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team has had a bumpy ride - despite a huge amount of effort, the original Hong Kong Roller Derby collapsed in 2014, "I'm sure you all know the common difficulties many, if not all derby players face, but being in HK, made it that much harder. From difficulty in securing practice venues, to people moving away, and misunderstandings, our team fell apart and remained that way for over a year and a half."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reformed now, for another go since 2016, the new Hong Kong Roller Derby has managed to grow to a healthy 19 skaters!  Buffy has drawn the following lesson from the two experiences: "It still seems like a dream, but [HKRD] is finally happening and has opened my eyes to why we had failed before. It all comes down to the people and the passion. Without community and support, we are nothing. But now our team is a family, and we realize we won't always agree but we will always have each others' backs and remember that in the end, we all want the same thing."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HKRD's A Team, the Yau Ma Titties, have put a huge amount of effort into organising this first bout (thanks to the previous derby experience of their founder, it's been easier than it might have been).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow the event here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1240708282693458/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1240708282693458/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to join the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers as another Asian team, you can find their Facebook page here: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Pan-Asian-Spring-Rollers-448887468791803/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/Pan-Asian-Spring-Rollers-448887468791803/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  which also links to all of their member leagues, including Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>hong kong roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/07/east-asian-derbys-new-spring-rollers/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 08:37:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tomodachi Cup Teams: Pan-Asian Spring Rollers!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/08/the-tomodachi-cup-teams-pan-asian-spring-rollers/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;Next in our coverage of teams attending the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Okinawa, March 24th to 26th, is one of the entrants into the "B" tier of the tournament.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;The Pan-Asian Spring Rollers are a hybrid team, consisting of members from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.beijingrollerderby.com/"&gt;Beijing Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/shanghairollerderby/"&gt;Shanghai Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hongkongrollerderby.com/"&gt;Hong Kong Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BangkokRollerDerby/"&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, representing the East-Asian derby communities outside Japan. (Several of these teams previously combined forces to stage the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/"&gt;first ever Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; bout in China last year.)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;At the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the Spring Rollers will be competing against the exhibition team Team Women's Roller Derby Japan, and Tokyo Roller Girls' Sushi Rollers.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;Sarah Cason gave us this history of how the team formed.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14040 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/pan-asian.jpg" alt="pan-asian" width="223" height="200"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt;The Pan-Asian Spring Rollers, a fusion of derby teams from Beijing, Shanghai, Hong Kong and Bangkok, merged in November 2016 to form a joint league for the upcoming Tomodachi Derby Tournament in Okinawa, Japan this Spring. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt;As individual teams, all had recieved the invitation to join the tournament as much as a year ago, but the challenges of sustaining a roller derby team outside in this particular region meant that it was seen as nothing more than an extremely beautiful pipe dream.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt;Until, that is,  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Shanghai's Lauryn Kill met one of the Beijing players completely by chance while in Beijing for an unrelated work event. The two of them got talking. The Beijing player mentioned the tournament and that they didn't have enough players to compete, and the idea to form a mixed team was born!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt;Shanghai contacted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Beijing and Hong Kong and put forward the idea of forming a joint team - an idea that both teams immediately got on board with! Beijing suggested bringing Bangkok into the mix, the teams having recently joined forces for Beijing's successful Roller Derby Invitational in partnership with UN Women's HeForShe campaign. Bangkok were keen, and from four small teams, the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers were born!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt;Unity of purpose was what really brought the teams together into a unified whole. Roller derby is still catching on in many parts of Asia and hasn't yet gained the popularity it has in many western countries. For the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; skaters of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers, the tournament is about the game (always!) - the opportunity to scrimmage can be a rare one in places where roller derby is struggling to take hold - but it's also and importantly about raising awareness of our sport in our region, about building thriving relationships with our sister teams, and about working together to promote and develop the thrilling and empowering sport of roller derby across the region.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;We feel that it's only by uniting, sharing skills, knowledge and ideas, and working together to overcome the challenges we face that we can build a self-sustaining and successful roller derby community in our delicious little corner of the globe.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/08/the-tomodachi-cup-teams-pan-asian-spring-rollers/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 09:43:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tomodachi Derby Tournament - The Teams</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, the Asia-Pacific Region saw its first ever Roller Derby Tournament, hosted in Okinawa. Whilst the Japan Open was a huge success, the host leagues were keen to hold another one, with even more direct control from the leagues and skaters themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14076 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tomodachi.png" alt="tomodachi" width="400" height="400"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is the result - another two day tournament, now hosted by the new Japan Derby Tournament Committee, a collective of the involved Japanese leagues. As with the previous Tournament, the Tomodachi also serves a practical benefit to all the teams involved, giving somewhat geographically isolated teams a chance to play those from other areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be bringing you more info with interviews with the attending leagues in the run up to the event on the &lt;strong&gt;24th&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt;, (at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/%E6%B2%96%E7%B8%84%E7%9C%8C%E7%B7%8F%E5%90%88%E9%81%8B%E5%8B%95%E5%85%AC%E5%9C%92/@26.3099785,127.8141462,15.5z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x76c4ab9c228dd0cb!8m2!3d26.3107468!4d127.8213143"&gt;Okinawa Comprehensive Sport Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), but we're starting (as with EuroClash) with an overview of the competitors... (a timetable is available on our technical annex, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/tomodachi2017.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;WFTDA-Sanctioned Division&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14022" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/pacificrollerderby.png" alt="pacificrollerderby" width="200" height="200"&gt;Pacific Roller Derby&lt;/h3&gt;
Pacific Roller Derby are one of the oldest of the cluster of Hawaiian teams, dating from 2008, and a member of WFTDA since 2009! Due to the geographical factor, they mostly play the other Islands teams, especially at the yearly "Battle of the Islands" tournament. Based in the Islands' Capital, Honolulu, Pacific are currently 305th in the WFTDA Rankings (344th by FTS), partly, we suspect, simply due to not having had much opportunity to play non-Hawaiian teams. The Tomodachi will be their first fixtures against non-HI leagues since 2014!
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14024" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/fairbanks_rollergirls.png" alt="fairbanks_rollergirls" width="200" height="240"&gt;Fairbanks Rollergirls&lt;/h3&gt;
Hailing from their namesake in Alaska, Fairbanks Rollergirls are another member of the "Alaskan Derby" set alongside last year's Japan Open competitors, Juneau (who memorably attended with only 6 skaters!). A WFTDA member since 2011, the league has hosted the Alaskan "United We Roll" tournament for the last two years. We rate them at 1137th out of all teams (male and female, A and B) in the World which can be rated, whilst FTS places them 331st out of all WFTDA teams (a much smaller set).
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14034" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/devil_dog_300.png" alt="devil_dog_300" width="200" height="199"&gt;Devil Dog Derby Dames&lt;/h3&gt;
Local Okinawan Derby league, Devil Dog Derby Dames, (868th SRDRank), were a competitor at the Japan Open last year, although failed to defeat the non-Japanese teams in the WFTDA Division. (Their Home Team, competing in the Unsanctioned Division, defeated exhibition team Nippon Senbatsu.) The year before that, DDDD managed a win over fellow Okinawa league Kokeshi, which they'll be looking to repeat this time.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14036" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/kokeshi.png" alt="kokeshi" width="200" height="200"&gt;Kokeshi Roller Dolls&lt;/h3&gt;
The first league in Okinawa, Kokeshi Roller Dolls, (700th SRD Rank) were hosts of the Japan Open last year, as well as organising hosting for the Tomodachi Tournament as part of the Japan Roller Derby Tournament Committee. At the Japan Open, they took a win over Alaska's Juneau Roller Derby; we will see if they managed to repeat the feat against Fairbanks this time around.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14028" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tokyo.jpg" alt="tokyo" width="200" height="200"&gt;Tokyo Roller Girls&lt;/h3&gt;
The first league in "mainland" Japan, Tokyo Roller Girls, (745th SRD Rank) faired as well as the Devil Dog Derby Dames at the last tournament. However, they've had a busy home season since then, with all three of their home teams bouting each other, and recruitment has been strong. (TRG skaters have also been behind much of the activity of Women's Roller Derby Japan, the governing body for the Japanese Women's National Team, including their impressively active outreach in the last year.)
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Men's Division&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14032" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/grd_logo_cmyk.png" alt="grd_logo_cmyk" width="200" height="102"&gt;Glenmore Reservoir Dogs&lt;/h3&gt;
Hailing from Calgary, Canada, Glenmore Reservoir Dogs (Chinook City Men's Roller Derby) are the 17th ranked MRDA team in the world (65th SRD Rank), and are the men's component of Chinook City Roller Derby. Perhaps most recently known on the international stage as hosts of the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup, the league as a whole also regularly host the annual "Flat Track Fever" (women's derby) tournament. Last year, the Reservoir Dogs themselves competed at the Mayday Mayhem (Colorado) and the O-Town Throwdown (Ontario), taking second place at the former.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14038" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/japan-logo-232x300.jpg" alt="japan-logo-232x300" width="193" height="250"&gt;NinJapan Rollers&lt;/h3&gt;
The Japanese Men's National Team, and still the only Men's league in Japan, NinJapan Rollers have fairly frequently competed against the other Japanese teams (especially Tokyo), but have rarely had the chance to play non-National teams from other locations. In the 2016 MRDWC, NinJapan placed 17th, although their performance was very close to that of Puerto Rico, one place above them. The NinJapan Rollers have also (partly due to necessity) actively promoted Roller Derby throughout Japan, and have a comprehensive "off-season" training and recruitment system to build up their pool of skaters.
&lt;h2&gt;Unsanctioned Division&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14026" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/yokosuka.png" alt="yokosuka" width="200" height="189"&gt;Yokosuka Sushi Rollers&lt;/h3&gt;
A Tokyo Roller Girls "Home Team", this is the Sushi Rollers' first appearance as a travel team, let alone their first tournament. Based in and around United States Fleet Activities Yokosuka naval base, the Sushi Rollers were the founding team of Tokyo Roller Girls, and remain one of the strongest in intraleague contests. It remains to be seen how they will fare in their first bouts away from Honshu.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14040" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/pan-asian.jpg" alt="pan-asian" width="223" height="200"&gt;Pan-Asian Spring Rollers&lt;/h3&gt;
The Pan-Asian Spring Rollers are a collaboration between the other (non-Japanese) East Asian Roller Derby leagues, with members from Beijing Roller Derby, Shanghai Roller Girls, Hong Kong Roller Derby and Bangkok Roller Derby. Several of these leagues participated in the first ever Roller Derby bout in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; last year (hosted by Beijing), and so collaboration to attend the Tomodachi seems natural.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-14030" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/teamwrdj-sm.jpg" alt="teamwrdj-sm" width="250" height="154"&gt;Team WRDJ&lt;/h3&gt;
Team "Women's Roller Derby Japan" is a the open-subscription exhibition team, run by the committee for . It comprises skaters from the Neon Roller Monsters (Tokyo Roller Girls' Japanese-nationals-team), Tokyo Three Rollers (Tokyo's Open-To-All/Coed Team), Kokeshi Roller Dolls, Devil Dog Derby Dames, and a single skater from Hawaii's Echo City Knockouts (of Kailua-Kona).&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>beijing roller derby</category><category>devil dog derby dames</category><category>fairbanks rollergirls</category><category>glenmore reservoir dogs</category><category>hong kong roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>kokeshi roller dolls</category><category>ninjapan rollers</category><category>pacific roller derby</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><category>shang-hai rollers</category><category>tokyo roller girls</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>women's roller derby japan</category><category>yokosuka sushi rollers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 08:05:15 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>