<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about parma violents)</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/parma-violents.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:54:39 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Parma Violents vs. Silvery Tayzers</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/26/parma-violents-vs-silvery-tayzers/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Saturday 6th September, FVRG's Parma Violents will take on DRG's Silvery Tayzers in Grangemouth Sports Complex. Doors open at 3:30pm, with the game starting at 4pm.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;The two teams first met in February 2012 in the Parma Violents first public game. Although the Silvery Tayzers took home the victory, the Parma Violents jumped at the chance for a rematch in November 2013, and again for the chance to play them again next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Tickets are available online from &lt;a title="Buy Tickets Online" href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/836544" target="_blank"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt; for £5 (+ admin fee), or £7 on the door. Under 14s go free with a paying adult.  Join FVRG's &lt;a title="FVRG Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1515534441994379/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt; for more information - and details on their ticket give-away competition!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/header.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3632" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/header.jpg" alt="Image courtesy of Fierce Valley Roller Girls" width="614" height="292"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Fierce Valley Roller Girls
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>parma violents</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/26/parma-violents-vs-silvery-tayzers/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 18:50:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Close Encounters of the Thrilled Kind - derby double header</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/26/close-encounters-of-the-thrilled-kind-derby-double-header/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/3xo4jhp-imgur.png"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-3550 aligncenter" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/3xo4jhp-imgur.png?w=300" alt="3xO4jHP - Imgur" width="422" height="163"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow is bracing itself for a close encounter of the ‘thrilled’ kind as some of the grooviest skaters in Scotland and England clash as part of a unique sporting double-header.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city’s first men’s roller derby team – Mean City – will host the special event on August 23 at the ARC sports centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City will be playing Teeside’s Skate Invaders – the first time the two teams have clashed – in an all-male, action-packed contest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space will be a premium as the Invaders beam into Glasgow – hoping they can blast their way to victory against the MCRD troopers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The double bill will also see Glasgow Roller Derby’s Cannie Gingers compete against Fierce Valley Roller Girls’ Parma Violents in an all-female thrill-fest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jim Whyte, Chairman of Mean City Roller Derby (MCRD), said: “We can’t wait for this very special double-header. The skating will be out of this world with four great roller derby leagues going toestop to toestop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Mean City is Glasgow’s first and only men’s roller derby league and has been going from strength to strength since it was formed in 2012. We’re genuinely thrilled to be welcoming three amazing squads to Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Skate Invaders are a great team and a terrific bunch of lads – we can’t wait to line up against them. Mean City features some of the best skaters in Scotland and we will be giving our all to ensure the super summer of sport continues in Glasgow.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby (GRD) – Mean City’s all-female sister league – is renowned throughout the roller derby world. Its A team – the Irn Bruisers – recently stormed America, while its B team – the Maiden Grrders – are also a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such is the strength in depth at GRD that a third travel team has been formed – the Cannie Gingers – who made their competitive debut against Fierce Valley in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jim added: “Fierce Valley had the edge in the first encounter, but Glasgow will be keen to win on home soil. It’s going to be another cracking encounter between two brilliant teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Get your tickets now – just £5 in advance for two amazing full games of roller derby starring four interstellar teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s going to be a great showcase of all that roller derby has to offer – an action-packed afternoon of skating, scoring, skills, thrills and spills.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby has been developing as a league since its formation in 2012. Men’s roller derby is a fledgling off-shoot of the modern day all-female sport of roller derby – with the game rising in popularity with people of all genders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City train regularly in the Glasgow area and new members are always welcome to give the sport a go in a supportive environment. Equipment can be provided – just get in touch in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby"&gt;www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby&lt;/a&gt; to buy tickets for the event and to find out more about joining the revolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cannie gingers</category><category>fvrg</category><category>grd</category><category>mcrd</category><category>parma violents</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/26/close-encounters-of-the-thrilled-kind-derby-double-header/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 22:59:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hinnies Head for Scotland - Newcastle Roller Girls on their Month of Scottish Derby</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/05/27/hinnies-head-for-scotland-newcastle-roller-girls-on-their-month-of-scottish-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Up in Scotland, we're no strangers to &lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.org.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;; they've played most of our established leagues over the last few years. This year, however, they've made slightly more of an impression, scheduling 4 bouts against Scottish leagues all within the month of May!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we approach the last of those dates, which sees Newcastle's B-team (The Whippin' Hinnies) take on &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie&lt;/a&gt;'s B Cannon Belles in Edinburgh on the 31st, we thought we'd have a chat to Newcastle's A and B teams about their experience so far, and some other exciting things that have happened in the last few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/theasaurus-wrecks.jpg"&gt;&lt;img id="i-3456" class="size-full wp-image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/theasaurus-wrecks.jpg?w=615" alt="Theasaurus Wrecks"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big event was always planned to be the one Newcastle hosted, a double-header at their usual venue, the Walker Activity Dome, featuring the Whippin' Hinnies taking on &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee&lt;/a&gt;'s Silvery Tayzers, followed by Newcastle A, the Canny Belters, facing off against &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; B, the Maiden Grrders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hinnies had previously taken on Dundee at the Into The Nitemare organised tournament, Battle of Britain, in November last year. Battling for the title, the Hinnies won with 60 points to Dundee's 51, in an extremely low scoring bout.
Theasaurus Wrecks, Hinnies Captain both for that bout and this year, remembers it fondly: “Battle of Britain was amazing. We were the underdogs, and I always think we perform really well as underdogs. ... we had a fantastic bench who knew the rules very well, and that worked incredibly well to our advantage. We also had a really strong team at the time with a lot of great crossovers [skaters who are on the 20 player pools for both the A and B teams, and thus eligible to roster for either].”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming into the Dundee bout this year, the team composition was a little different, the Hinnies roster having collected newer, less experienced skaters in the interim. In addition, Dundee's Tayzers had already demonstrated a very powerful team for the new year, with an impressive win over &lt;a href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/"&gt;Granite City&lt;/a&gt; at the end of March. So, it should not, perhaps, have been surprising that the first game of the double header went to Dundee Roller Girls, 163 to 131.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That the score was that close was a testament to the Hinnies' grit and determination, “In the first section of the 2nd half, the Hinnies were quite battered and feeling a bit down about it, but we kinda escalated away and picked up 70 pts in 15 minutes or so. So we sort of really brought it back in,” Thea told us, adding, “[it] shows what a psychological game roller derby is as well. Quite often if you start to think that you're losing it, then you kind of lose your psychological game and sort of give up. If you're willing to battle through to the end, then you can bring it back 'round to your favour.” While the Hinnies didn't quite manage that this time around, Dundee certainly felt the need to work hard, “They said to us afterwards that it was one of the best games they'd played in a long time, because they'd felt really challenged by it as well.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/gin-jamming-close-up.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3458" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/gin-jamming-close-up.jpg?w=614" alt="Gin and Sonic, on track." width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Gin and Sonic, on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the second bout of the day was not to happen, as a leak in the roof of the Walker Activity Dome began to let water on to the track during the inter-game break. With the referees ruling the track unsafe as long as water continued to fall, there was no choice but to call off the game. The Belters' Gin and Sonic was not alone in feeling extremely frustrated by the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So, you think when you play an &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;indoor &lt;/span&gt;sport that it will go ahead rain or shine... Our home venue is in many ways the perfect space for roller derby, and it’s not long since it was refurbished, so to say we were gutted when our GRD bout was rained off after a leaky roof issue is a MASSIVE understatement. We have so much love for GRD, they were really understanding (not to mention incredibly patient on the day while we waited to hear if the bout could go ahead safely...) and we’re hoping to reschedule very soon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently Newcastle are in negotiations with Newcastle City Council to resolve their venue issues – either by fixing the roof or getting a new venue – but they are determined not to let it affect their schedule at all. (Their next home fixture, seeing the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/486333931501291/?ref=5"&gt;Belters take on Birmingham Blitz Dames (in a double header with Tyne and Fear v The Inhuman League)&lt;/a&gt; is still on for the 7th of June, in the Centre for Sport, on the West Road, and has been rescheduled to a later time (but the same date) as a result.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Breaking News, added to this document after publication: The cancelled Glasgow Roller Derby bout has been rescheduled for June 28th, and will be hosted by &lt;em&gt;Glasgow&lt;/em&gt; at their usual venue, the ARC, as a replacement to the previously scheduled Glasgow A v Hot Wheels game (which is now cancelled).]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/theasurus-jamming.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3459" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/theasurus-jamming.jpg?w=614" alt="Theasaurus, pushing past the final blocker." width="614" height="614"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Theasaurus, pushing past Dundee's Milky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the loss of their venue is a setback, it didn't affect the next Scottish bout for the Hinnies, as they travelled up to Stirling to play &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' Parma Violents. This was a return bout, as Fierce Valley had travelled down to Newcastle in April 2013, and while a Newcastle win was expected, the Hinnies weren't going to relax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thea noted “the Hinnies, being a B-Team, being dynamic, is always changing, so we had a completely different lineup to the Dundee game. ... I'm one of the few people who's been with the Hinnies all this time, as the Team Captain, so yeah, we had a great opportunity with FVRG that we could try out lots of new players. So we had 1 brand new player, and 3 or 4 players who'd only played 1 or 2 games before, that was a really good learning curve for a lot of the newer people in the team.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And indeed, taking the opportunity to gain experience for the newer skaters still paid off, with the Hinnies pulling out a close (201 to 169) win – less than predicted, but nothing to sneeze at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we look ahead to the final bout in Newcastle's packed Scottish schedule (and it is exciting for multiple reasons), we should note that Scotland is not the &lt;span style="font-weight:bold;"&gt;only &lt;/span&gt;place that Newcastle Roller Girls have been involved with recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/gin-sonic-high-fives.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3460" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/gin-sonic-high-fives.jpg?w=614" alt="Gin and Sonic, taking high-fives post bout." width="614" height="345"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Gin and Sonic, taking high-fives post bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a start, three of the Canny Belters have made the roster for Team Wales Roller Derby, and will be playing for the Valleys in the Blood and Thunder World Cup in December. Gin and Sonic was one of the three, and was happy to talk to us about her choice of Wales over England:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was eligible to try out for both England and Wales. I tried out for England on a bit of a whim and really steeled my resolve to try out for Wales and gave it everything I have. I’m so glad I did as we have a really great team and they make me really proud of my Welsh side. It’s been brilliant sharing the try out process with [fellow Belters] Hit One Purl One and Marie Bayonet as we’ve been each other’s cheerleaders and it’s great having travel buddies for long trips to training! NRG have been so supportive of us and I know we’re going to learn lots from the experience and bring it all back to Newcastle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Belters have been getting skaters onto National teams, the Hinnies have gone the international route, playing their first European away bout against Eindhoven's Rockcity Rollers in January. Winning by a single point, the experience has whetted the Hinnies' appetite for Euroderby, in Thea's words: “That was one of the most Emotional games [she laughs] that I've ever played. It was really close.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While normally it would be the A team that gets into International derby first, in this case it was an existing connection that brought the Hinnies to the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It came about because we had a skater from &lt;a href="http://www.domcitydolls.com/"&gt;Dom City&lt;/a&gt; which is in Utrect. She came over and skated with NRG for three months, and we kind of just built up a really good friendship. So she said that since they were kind of an up and coming league, they would love to have us come over and do some coaching.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanting to get as much our of the trip as possible, the Hinnies found &lt;a href="http://rockcityrollers.nl/"&gt;Rockcity Rollers&lt;/a&gt;, ranked very closely to them, in Eindhoven, and managed to arrange a bout for the dates they were over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thea is still emotional about the event “we'd been travelling for ages, and it was a covered outdoor venue, and it just... it just was so close.
In final jam, we had our jammer, Torville and Scream, up and I saw her calling it off, and I didn't even know if she'd made the points, but she just was absolutely shattered, so she had to call it off and we were all there holding our breath just hoping that she'd picked up the points, and she had, so it was amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that was the first game that my parents had ever seen me play, so they said they kind of got how exciting roller derby could be from that game.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And more international bouts might be on the cards:
“I think it's all about funding and finances. I think I'd really like to play Amsterdam. One Love is really good as well, I would like to play a lot more teams of similar to us in the rankings, cause the games that we've had recently with Scottish teams have all been so challenging, and so exciting, and really pushing us to our limit. And that's really .. when you learn a lot about your team.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Canny Belters, meanwhile, are focussed on the American side of International derby, as Gin and Sonic revealed: “we’re dead proud of our Hinnies flying the NRG flag in Europe earlier this year and the Canny Belters have big aspirations for the next year! We became WFTDA apprentices earlier this year and we’re hoping to graduate as full members very soon. We’ll be focussing on the Northern Series which is a round robin of UKRDA/WFTDA games between Leeds Roller Dolls, Rainy City Roller Girls and Middlesbrough Milk Rollers. Hopefully our first round of WFTDA sanctioned bouts will put us in a good ranking position to go further afield in 2015. We’re itching to go a big international tournament like ARRG and Glasgow!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it's only an hour and a half from Newcastle to Edinburgh, the Belters will surely be discussing how to dominate America with Auld Reekie's Twisted Thistles, as both watch their B team sistren play this coming weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This looks like being a particularly close fought bout, with the rankings very close between the teams. Theasaurus Wrecks agrees, “
[I'm] Really excited. This is going to be the highlight of the year, I think. I think it's going to be the toughest challenge that the Hinnies have had; obviously ARRG are a really strong team, they've got a fantastic foundation, fantastic coaching from their A Team, they're in a really strong position on the table. So I'm really looking forward to us having that real focused challenge, and trying to achieve the best that we can for that. Having a battle - it's going to be very tough.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is not all, as Fierce Valley's junior derby league, the &lt;a href="http://www.fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs&lt;/a&gt;, are making a debut appearance at half-time, with a demonstration scrim. The Cubs are all big derby fans as Thea has already discovered, “I'm really excited to see that! They sent a really nice email to us, asking if we could do a photo with them at the end. I'm looking forward to that one :D”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe she'd sign an autograph or two as well (as the Cubs have been known to collect in the past)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;laughs&lt;/em&gt; Oh, I'm looking forward to it.
I feel like a minor celebrity(!)”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hinnies won't be the only celebrities present, either. Recently, Auld Reekie revealed that (known derby fan) Phill Jupitus will be co-announcing the bout, alongside long-standing ARRG announcer Stephen Tawking.
“I have noticed, that on QI, he's worn Kent Roller Girls t-shirts quite a bit, so I'm hoping that he'll wear ARRG and Newcastle shirts after this bout,” said Thea. We're pretty sure that Phill will end up getting freebie tshirts from all the leagues present after this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to see the Whippin Hinnies take on Auld Reekie Roller Girls on Saturday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;31 May, doors open at 2pm, for skateout at 2:30. Tickets can be bought at
&lt;a href="http://m.bpt.me/event/643612"&gt;http://m.bpt.me/event/643612
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Newcastle Roller Girls' Theasaurus Wrecks, Gin and Sonic, and PR Pretty Skate Machine.
All photographs from Newcastle Roller Girls - photographers please contact me for attribution!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was edited after publication to include details of the rescheduling of the GRD v NRG bout, and to improve cross-linking to league pages.
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>cannon belles</category><category>canny belters</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>interviews</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>nrg</category><category>parma violents</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>whippin hinnies</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/05/27/hinnies-head-for-scotland-newcastle-roller-girls-on-their-month-of-scottish-derby/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 18:55:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Girls vs. Glasgow Roller Derby</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/28/fierce-valley-roller-girls-vs-glasgow-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 15th February, The Peak in Stirling will play host to &lt;a title="FVRG Website" href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' first bout of 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Parma Violents will take on &lt;a title="GRD Website" href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s brand new team, The Cannie Gingers, who will be making their bouting debut. This is an event not to be missed!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 2pm with the first whistle at 2.30pm. Tickets can be bought for £5 (+ booking fee) in advance from &lt;a title="But Bout Tickets from BPT" href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/560142" target="_blank"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt;, or cost £7 on the door. Under 14s go free with a paying adult.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please see &lt;a title="FVRG Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/278718162276368/" target="_blank"&gt;FVRG's Facebook Event &lt;/a&gt;for full details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/poster.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3207" alt="FVRG vs. GRD bout poster" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/poster.jpg" width="614" height="906"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; FVRG vs. GRD bout poster - image courtesy of FVRG&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cannie gingers</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>parma violents</category><category>stirling</category><category>the peak</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/28/fierce-valley-roller-girls-vs-glasgow-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 12:48:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls vs Fierce Valley Roller Girls</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/13/dundee-roller-girls-vs-fierce-valley-roller-girls-2/</link><dc:creator>louisepants</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a busy weekend for Dundee Roller Girls travel team, The Silvery Tayzers. Sunday 17th November sees them take on Fierce Valley Roller Girls travel team, The Parma Violents. It has been over a year and half since these 2 teams met, both having refreshed their rosters and experience since then. Come along to the DISC, Dundee to see who will win in what is sure to be a most exciting bout. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 1.30pm with the bout beginning at 2pm. Tickets are available in advance for the reduced price of £5 (£6 on the door on the day). There will be merchandise from both teams available and beautiful cakes baked by the skaters/refs/NSO's themselves! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is absolutely not to be missed. See you trackside for some Live Action Roller Derby!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/fvrg.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-3036" alt="Image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/fvrg.png?w=650"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>disc</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>parma violents</category><category>roller derby</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/13/dundee-roller-girls-vs-fierce-valley-roller-girls-2/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 16:02:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mad Smacks: Newcastle Roller Girls vs FVRG</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/25/mad-smacks-newcastle-roller-girls-vs-fvrg/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In homage to the remake of Mad Max, &lt;a title="Newcastle Roller Girls on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/newcastlerollergirls" target="_blank"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; are hosting 'Mad Smacks' on Saturday 30th March: a double-header bout  featuring &lt;a title="Fierce Valley Roller Girls on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/FierceValleyRG?fref=ts" target="_blank"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NRG's Whippin' Hinnies will take on FVRG' s Parma Violents in the first bout of the day, from 12:15 pm. Both teams are keen to hold onto their winning streak, but only one will be victorious!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets can be &lt;a title="Buy Tickets Online" href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.org.uk/belters-vs-harlots" target="_blank"&gt;bought online&lt;/a&gt; in advance for £6, or for £7.50 on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit the&lt;a title="'Mad Smacks' Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/494675117242402/" target="_blank"&gt; 'Mad Smacks' Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt; for further details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/mad-smacks.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2370" alt="Mad Smacks Poster" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/mad-smacks.png" width="614" height="225"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>parma violents</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/25/mad-smacks-newcastle-roller-girls-vs-fvrg/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 19:42:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bout Report: Fierce Valley Roller Girls vs Dundee Roller Girls in "Bruise Brothers" </title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/02/27/bout-report-fierce-valley-roller-girls-vs-dundee-roller-girls-in-bruise-brothers/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/02/bruise.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/02/bruise.jpg" alt="" title="bruise" width="614" height="446" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-893"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Laura MacDonald&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head over to &lt;a href="http://aoanla.blogspot.com/2012/02/bout-report-fierce-valley-roller-girls.html"&gt;Ante Ortus A Novus Ars&lt;/a&gt; to read the bout report for the &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girl's&lt;/a&gt; Parma Violents first public bout against &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girl's&lt;/a&gt; Silvery Tayzers.
For another view of the bout,you can read Rochelle Stewart's bout report over on the Fierce Valley Roller Girls &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/news-story.php?id=29"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.This was originally published in The Alloa Advertiser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>drg</category><category>fvrg</category><category>parma violents</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>video</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/02/27/bout-report-fierce-valley-roller-girls-vs-dundee-roller-girls-in-bruise-brothers/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 14:02:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls vs. Fierce Valley Roller Girls</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/02/13/dundee-roller-girls-vs-fierce-valley-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a title="FVRG Website" href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' Parma Violents are preparing to take on &lt;a title="Dundee Roller Girls website" href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' Silvery Tayzers on Saturday 18th February in their first public bout!
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/02/bruisebrothersflyer.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-859" title="Bruise Brothers Flyer" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/02/bruisebrothersflyer.jpg" alt="Bruise Brothers Flyer" width="614" height="868"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'&lt;a title="Bruise Brothers Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/327179873989413/" target="_blank"&gt;Bruise Brothers&lt;/a&gt;' will kick off slightly earlier than usual at 12 noon in The DISC, Dundee. Rest assured, there will be more raffle prizes and cakes than you can shake you tail feather at!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced tickets are &lt;a title="Advanced Tickets for Bruise Brothers" href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/223454" target="_blank"&gt;available online&lt;/a&gt; for £5, or £7 on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>parma violents</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/02/13/dundee-roller-girls-vs-fierce-valley-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 20:01:20 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>