<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about pictures)</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/pictures.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:54:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Mean City Roller Derby: Relaunch 2017</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/17/mean-city-roller-derby-relaunch-2017/</link><dc:creator>meancityrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-19258" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/received_10158754925150594.jpeg?w=300" alt="received_10158754925150594" width="300" height="300"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;Roller derby is a very DIY sport, so people at different levels will always be looking to achieve different goals within the sport. For some, their purpose is to advance as far as their body will allow. For others, it’s a great way to get out a couple of nights per week and let off some steam in a fun, friendly environment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby fall somewhere in the middle, as we're made up of a wide variety of different people and personalities – we have actors, students, scientists and even a Thai masseur! It's our members that make our league special. Although we have lives outside of derby, we'll always be there for each other, both on and off the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we're looking to continue to build upon progress we've made as a league and as a group of friends. Next Saturday&lt;strong&gt;, 20th May 2017&lt;/strong&gt;, will be our first bout of the year and we are hoping to capitalise on the hard work we've put into our training. Not only that, we are rebranding and will be debuting our new logo and team tops for the first time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logo really captures the good humour of the league and the spirit of Glasgow, Mean City's home and stomping ground.  We don't want to give too much away until game day, but we can say the logo is indeed still purple! This has been a long time in the making, but we can proudly say it looks fantastic. A big thank you to our Design Team and to Roller Derby City for our awesome new uniforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are facing tough opposition. Our ladies' team are playing the Granite City Fight Hawks from Aberdeen. We played them up north in &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85548"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and were narrowly defeated, so we will be looking to make the most of the home advantage! Our co-ed/open team will then be playing the Portsmouth Scurvy Wenches who are travelling up to Glasgow for the bout. They are more unknown to us, so should make exciting opponents. We also hear they like a good after party, as do we!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-19259" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/received_10158754874915594.jpeg?w=300" alt="received_10158754874915594" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The action starts at &lt;strong&gt;12pm&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662012,-4.2516905,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8661982!4d-4.2494965"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARC: Health &amp;amp; Fitness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Glasgow Caledonian University, Cowcaddens Road, Glasgow, G4 0BA. Entry is &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; per person/under 14s free,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets available from the Facebook event page here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1288036437909237/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1288036437909237/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>annoucements</category><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>pictures</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/17/mean-city-roller-derby-relaunch-2017/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 14:08:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Scotland Launch New Logo</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/06/12/team-scotland-launch-new-logo/</link><dc:creator>zenrhe</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thursday the 11th of June saw &lt;a title="Team Scotland Wesbsite" href="http://teamscotlandrollerderby.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Team Scotland &lt;/a&gt;announce their new logo to the world on &lt;a title="TS Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Team-Scotland-Roller-Derby/235701999922927" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After many months of deliberation and polls showcasing various themes and designs (A unicorn had been the leading idea in the beginning), they picked one and sent it off to be made into the snazzy form that you now see here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/06/logo.png"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-3475" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/06/logo.png?w=614" alt="logo" width="614" height="503"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This logo will be available on all of there new merch, both via the website shortly and at their games (including their very first one on &lt;a title="TS Event Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/585745674873560/?fref=ts" target="_blank"&gt;July 5th in Glasgow!&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>facebook</category><category>pictures</category><category>team scotland</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/06/12/team-scotland-launch-new-logo/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 15:31:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee and Granite City - A Retrospective.</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/03/23/dundee-and-granite-city-a-retrospective/</link><dc:creator>clinicallywasted</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the 29&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of March 2014 Granite City Roller Girls will face off against Dundee Roller Girls’ Silvery Tayzers. This will be the third time the teams have played each other in the space of 4 years – a period of time that has seen a change in the look, the feel and the integrity of our sport and as such, a change in The Fights and The Tayzers. Clinically Wasted and Milky offer an interesting retrospective into how their leagues have developed in this time, and their aspirations for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City and Dundee were the first younger leagues to spring up in Scotland after the teams on the central belt had become more established. As a result, the leagues formed a symbiotic relationship, assisting each other wherever they could.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;-Roller derby in Dundee has always been close with GCRG. They made the journey week after week to help us with every aspect of derby - from putting us through our minimum skills to helping us structure our league. It's fair to say that we wouldn't be the team we are without the help they gave us in the start, and their continuing support.&lt;/em&gt; (Milky)&lt;em&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;-The relationship between Aberdeen and Dundee goes back along time, before I had even put on a pair of skates myself. The maturing of both leagues has ran side by side, and for a while it almost felt like we had a conjoined league of Dundeen where we would attend each others training and in fact GCRG’s first ever closed door bout featured a few of the Dundee girls.&lt;/em&gt; -(Clinically Wasted)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/935888_10153084748090392_1488004219_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3344" alt="Courtesy of Zenspirations Photography" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/935888_10153084748090392_1488004219_n.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Courtesy of Zenspirations Photography&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Riding off the back of Highland Fling, Dundee hosted their first ever home game in November 2010. Their opponents - GCRG's Northern Fights.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;-A select few of us remember bouting GCRG  - our first home bout as Dundee Destroyers. We didn't have any tactics really, we were just ecstatic to be sharing the track with our big sister league. We didn't take ourselves or the bout too seriously. As newbies we were all still caught up in the novelty of bouting - I think the majority of our time was spent considering uniforms, chants and face paint. Needless to say, GCRG had the edge on the day and took home the win. &lt;/em&gt;(M)&lt;em&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;-We were flying high with all the good intentions and in our fishnets, high socks and pants we were ready to kick butt. Dundee so kindly got somebody to film the occasion so it can eternally be watched. The video always makes me smile, because I remember how much fun we had that game, playing against our sisters. &lt;/em&gt;(CW)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/gcrgvsrk1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3346 " alt="Courtesy of Andrew Leatherbarrow." src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/gcrgvsrk1.jpg" width="614" height="407"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Courtesy of Andrew Leatherbarrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you haven't seen it already, here is a link to the video by Dylan Drummond: &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IPylGsXKJAE" target="_blank"&gt;Northern Fights vs Rippin Kittens 2010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time marched on. Outside of these two league's UKRDA were fighting for recognised sport status, London RollerGirls had joined WFTDA, people were taking knee down starts…remember them? Our sport evolved. And then these sister leagues played again, this time in Aberdeen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;-By our return bout the following year, we were now Dundee Roller Girls. Skating under a new name and colour and with new ambitions and values. The team was much more focused - we'd spent months studying our tactics, rules and honing our skills. The atmosphere for us was a little more tense this time as we were aiming for a win. The bout was hard fought from both sides, but again GCRG just pipped us in the final minutes. It was the best we'd skated as a team and the closest we'd come to victory. We finished proud of ourselves and incredibly proud of our friends in GCRG who had grown so much and who continued to teach and support us.&lt;/em&gt; (M)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- The game was hard, well fought, close and most of all fun. The level of derby and strategy had changed, but that buzz of seeing your friends play well made it all worth while. (CW)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/nfvsst.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3348" alt="Courtesy of Granite City Roller Girls" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/nfvsst.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Courtesy of Granite City Roller Girls&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fast forward to now, in 2014. DRG and GCRG have both had an incredible few seasons. Both teams are serious about progressing our sport and promoting the athleticism and empowerment they've worked so hard to achieve. Each team has changed vastly since they first lined up against each other in 2010; Dundee are in fact a completely different league with only 4 rostered skaters playing from the original line up, and Granite City only having 3 original Fights playing. Despite all the changes the two teams have experienced, they've continued to meet on track throughout the years, together and as opponents, still supporting our derby sisters and always proud of each teams acheivements.
&lt;/strong&gt;
-&lt;em&gt;We've remained each other's biggest fans. For me, I still frantically follow Twitter feeds for away scores as if it were for my own league. Regardless of the outcome of our upcoming bout, there's not a team in the world I'd rather share a track with, and not a team in the world I'd rather drag my battered body to share a pint with afterwards! &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;(&lt;/em&gt;M)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;em&gt;We always love catching up with the Dundee girls, and when we hear of their upcoming games it's as if we are skating with them! Tentatively waiting for scores on twitter and facebook! &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;People have come and gone and attitudes have changed but I know for certain one thing; at the final whistle, we will all hug, we will go grab a beer and we will all party like it’s 2010! (&lt;/em&gt;CW)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Girls play Dundee Roller Girls Saturday 29th of March 2014 at the Beach Leisure Centre in Aberdeen. Doors at 2.00pm for 3.00pm. Free Entry.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/blamming-season.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3347" alt="Courtesy of Granite City Roller Girls." src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/blamming-season.jpg" width="614" height="868"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Courtesy of Granite City Roller Girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>aberdeen</category><category>articles</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>pictures</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>video</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/03/23/dundee-and-granite-city-a-retrospective/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 19:50:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Merry Xmas from GCRG!</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/12/19/merry-xmas-from-gcrg/</link><dc:creator>zenrhe</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/image.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>aberdeen</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>image</category><category>pictures</category><category>xmas</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/12/19/merry-xmas-from-gcrg/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 18:00:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Interview With: the Roller Grrrls team.</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/04/an-interview-with-the-roller-grrrls-team/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps one sign that you've arrived as a sport is having works of fiction made about you. If that's the case, then Roller Derby has certainly made it, through the forthcoming &lt;a href="http://www.rollergrrrls.com/"&gt;Roller Grrrls&lt;/a&gt; comic series, which has had much support and publicity over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the official launch of the Roller Grrrls Sketchbook at &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s Chaos on the Clyde tournament, Gary Erskine, Anna Malady and the rest of the team have had a very busy few months with promotion and touring the various comics events around the world. We caught up with them via email to talk about the project, derby, and comics in general...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/04/an-interview-with-the-roller-grrrls-team/roller-grrrls_banner_reference/" rel="attachment wp-att-1948"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-1948" alt="The Roller Grrrls Sketchbook: Available now!" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/roller-grrrls_banner_reference.jpg?w=161" height="300" width="161"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Roller Grrrls Sketchbook: Available now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gary, you've been doing line-art for comics for about 24 years now; since your start in Marvel + 2000AD, there's quite a lot of the "traditional" SF + superhero work in your back catalogue, but also less conventional work. Do you have a preference for a particular genre, and how do you (and the others) feel about the popular pigeon-holing of comics as “SF+capes”?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Gary Erskine]I love comics as a medium. The genres I work with are just that, and I like working with them all. Each one gives me a new challenge.
Future sci-fi nonsense allows a completely free canvas to design a new world environment and the characters within that (the Irons:Hybrids work for Madefire has a Blade Runner vibe about it) Working on Roller Grrrls offers new challenges, as a contemporary story requires a similar attention to detail since EVERYONE will recognise the settings and people within the story. Another new project I am working on with my former studio colleague Dominic Regan is a horror/western. That also requires an approach and attention to detail to ensure that the setting helps the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did the three of you get into Roller Derby? Obviously, you know Glasgow Roller Derby well, but what was your first encounter?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Anna Malady] I remember seeing reports of Roller Derby in Glasgow from 4 years ago. Unfortunately it took another 2 years for either Gary or I to get to a live Bout. This was courtesy of some friends (Turbulinz and Bruisedog) who posted a Bout poster up on Facebook. I remember being confused for the majority of the time, but still coming away hoarse from shouting. It was exhilarating and just fantastic!
Gary joined me at the afterparty that night and we were hooked by not just the sport but the community spirit, the personalities, individuality, and colour. The whole atmosphere and pure community spirit of the sport gets into your blood and lifts you to believe in yourself. That may come across a bit new age, but for us, and many people we talk to its fact, so I don’t apologise for sounding like a hippy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gary and I then asked Yel to colour our project as Gary had worked with her in the past and we’re both massively impressed with her work. She is a talented colourist who has worked on quite a few projects with Gary including The Irons:Hybrids motion comic published by Madefire. Her colourist credits of note include The Only Good Dalek (BBC books, 2010), Need for Speed; The Run (EA Games/Firebrand, 2011) and she is currently working on the ongoing graphic novel series Hero; 9-5 for Markosia. You can see more of her work at &lt;a href="http://yelzamor.carbonmade.com/projects/"&gt;http://yelzamor.carbonmade.com/projects/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Gary] We were both fans of the sport following it online but were never able to attend a bout due to travelling and convention commitments. Our first bout proved an exhilarating experience and encouraged/convinced both Anna and I that a comic book series about the sport and characters within that would be a similarly exciting project to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anna, how did you get into the comic book scene?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Anna] My first introduction to the whole world of comics was exiting a lift into the lobby of a convention hotel and seeing 4 stormtroopers explaining to 2 firemen how the imperial guard were stuck in the next lift and they needed out to do their guest appearance. The next morning Star Fox (in full costume) was complaining to the bewildered front desk staff that there was no hot water in her room and that afternoon there was a showdown between a squad of Stormtoopers and a bronze Dalek. I mean, how could you not love this scene?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/04/an-interview-with-the-roller-grrrls-team/rollergrrlssplace/" rel="attachment wp-att-1949"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-1949" alt="Probably the most popularly distributed preview from Roller Grrrls." src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/rollergrrlssplace.jpg?w=193" height="300" width="193"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Probably the most popularly distributed preview from Roller Grrrls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are some obvious life models for some of the Roller Grrrls character studies (especially for anyone who knows Glasgow Roller Derby's skaters and announcers), but the majority have no single origin. Roughly, how much of real personalities went into the comic as a whole (as opposed to the other influences, such as Helles Belles)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Anna] Many of the characters are collages of real people. A body build from here, a tattoo from there, a hair style or colour from someone else. A couple of characters are drawn from real people, close friends who got us into Roller Derby in the first place. They know who they are. Being close friends they also know that it’s their image we are borrowing, not their characters or lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important to emphasise is that none of the character traits, personalities or story arcs are from real life. HOWEVER, we’ve been amazed how often we find that fiction has unwittingly reflected someone’s reality. We were seriously worried about it for a while. It seemed that, as we got to know the girls from the awesome Glasgow Roller Derby, and got round to discussing our project with them (often, although not always, after a few drinks at the afterparties) that someone in the team had been through the experiences we were writing about. Then as we got to know the UK Derby community we found out that quite a few girls had experienced a rough journey to get where they are and realised that these are people who
1) aren’t afraid to live a full life, and
2) are in general happy to talk about it and share their experience, especially if by doing so they can help others living through the same challenges.
We realised that of course we were going to come across people with experience of what we’d written. So we stopped worrying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But finally I would like to re-emphasise that the Roller Grrrls are totally fictitious and the situations they find themselves in, and their reactions, are totally made up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Gary] See above!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As roller derby can be a very fast paced game, I guess you do most of your reference work against photography, but some of the panels are from perspectives you can’t have had a reference for (the big “downed skater” view, for example). Can you guys talk a little about the process of constructing a page, and if there are particular challenges for sporting/action vs more sedentary scenes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Gary] There are certain considerations regarding the representation of any fast sport in an illustrated format. With some experience of storyboarding and animatics for game trailers there are visual tricks available to help keep the frantic and exciting energy of roller derby in a static/frozen image. Drawing the characters in layers with a separate background allows me to put on a motion blur for each parallax layer to help show the speed of the foreground figures and the blurring of other team members (and the crowd) in the background.
It is a similar effect to the slow shutter speed on a camera. Forced perspectives and POV shots also help give an immediacy to the action and provide new shots for the bout action. I also particularly want to show shots from 'in pack’ which would be near impossible to do in a real life bout. The comic format allows new opportunities to show some exciting possibilities of how the sport can be seen (in an illustrated format).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another trick we are toying with is to use motion effects and transitions (testing with Powerpoint initially) to create actual movement and subtle animation for a possible Roller Grrrls trailer. If successful then we may well have a digital release with bout action that moves on the page/screen. Watch this space! ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I assume this is the first "wholly self-supported" comic project the three of you have worked on? How's the experience of the indie comic project compare to previous work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Gary]My own previous experience in the industry has always been on the creative side, so this new publishing (and distribution) venture has been both exciting and scary for both of us and fairly new territory.
Having said that we have had a lot of very good (and much appreciated) advice from Jessica Ali of &lt;a href="http://www.insidelinemagazine.co.uk/"&gt;Inside Line&lt;/a&gt; and Vic Croughan of &lt;a href="http://www.leadjammermag.com/"&gt;Lead Jammer&lt;/a&gt; magazines. They have been especially helpful and generous with us and we really couldn't have got to this stage as quickly or comfortably without their help. Jessica was kind enough to recommend the printer to us (possibly the single most important decision for us!) and we can't thank her enough and Vic was offering indispensable advice for InDesign. Without those two key points we would not have our Roller Grrrls Sketchbook printed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's easy to compare Roller Grrrls with other "slice of life" comics, like the Hernandez' &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_and_Rockets_(comics)"&gt;Love and Rockets&lt;/a&gt; (or even &lt;a href="http://www.strangersinparadise.com/"&gt;Strangers in Paradise&lt;/a&gt;, before it got all Gritty). Do you think this is a valid comparison? - I notice that both came from an initially SF setting (albeit pre-design in RG's case) which went away as the concept solidified.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Gary]Roller Grrrls is very definitely inspired by Love and Rockets first and Strangers in Paradise also serves as an influence. There is little else out there that we would consider similar to what we are wanting to do (although some super hero team books do also have 'slice of life' storylines in between the predictable battles and villians) The Helles Belles project was something we wanted to work on a few years ago when we were living in Germany and was an all-female sci-fi adventure that unfortunately turned into Firefly (which we had never seen) The similarities were obvious and added to the work involved to design a new world environment kind of killed the project for us. We both still felt that female teams and characters were desperately under-valued and presented in mainstream books or worse still, shown in over-sexualised forms. I then considered a Rollerball reboot for Rebellion with the girls replacing Jonathan and the Houston team but the initial response from a couple of writers I approached was lukewarm and it stalled again. A casual chat with Mhairi one night about what needed to change with the ensemble story coincided with that fateful invitation to the GRD bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not write the story in a contemporary setting instead and the ideas and references (Love and Rockets/Strangers in Paradise) literally flowed out over dinner. I quickly decided on the name Roller Grrrls as I liked the association with the Riot Grrrls movement and the rest as they say is history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading the little “pocket bio” strips you did to introduce the characters, each of them has a fairly distinctive “trait” - from the cultural barriers of the Hindu student roller girls, and the clear drama of the pregnant “ex” derby girl with the difficult home life through to contrasts between “tame” librarianship and active derby playing. With a large ensemble cast, each with a potentially complex personal plotline, how are you planning on balancing the comic? Are we going to see character-specific issues, or something more interwoven?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Anna]Just as real life is a tangle of relationships and stories this is what we want to do with RG. Obviously it will have to be oversimplified and the time frames will be shortened. There is also an obvious balance to be struck between putting too much into a single issue and not enough.
We obviously think we’ve struck that balance, I guess we’ll really find out when we start to get feedback from the fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Gary] Redacted! ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roller Grrrls Sketchbook is available to buy now, with the Roller Grrrls comic proper due sometime next year. All images in this post are, of course, copyright Roller Grrls&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>pictures</category><category>roller derby</category><category>roller grrrls</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/04/an-interview-with-the-roller-grrrls-team/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 19:56:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls Want You!</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/09/23/dundee-roller-girls-want-you/</link><dc:creator>louisepants</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/09/fresh-meat-2012.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/09/fresh-meat-2012.png?w=487" alt="Image"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's that time again. Yes that's right ladies and gents, Dundee Roller Girls are opening their doors to everyone over the age of 18 to come and try out roller derby. Why not come and check out the fastest growing sport in Scotland? DRG will be hosting 3 open fresh meat nights, which is open to both men and women of all abilities and ages (over 18 only!). Full kit needed will be provided, all you need to do is turn up! The three nights of Fresh Meat kicks off on 26th September, second session 3rd October, ending on 10th October. Session starts at 7pm until 9pm at the DISC, Mains Loan, Dundee. We hope to see all your smiling faces there!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>pictures</category><category>roller derby</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/09/23/dundee-roller-girls-want-you/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 12:33:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bout Report: Glasgow Roller Derby v Stockholm Roller Derby Double Header</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/30/bout-report-glasgow-roller-derby-v-stockholm-roller-derby-double-header/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/grdstock.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/grdstock.jpg" alt="" title="grdstock" width="614" height="274" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1224"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photograph by Sam Skipsey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bout report for the recent GRD double header against Stockholm Roller Derby is up on &lt;a href="http://aoanla.blogspot.co.uk/2012/04/bout-report-glasgow-roller-derby-v.html"&gt;Ante Ortus A Novus Lumen Ars&lt;/a&gt;.All the usual pics and video, as well as a comprehensive report to feast your eyes on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>grd</category><category>irn bruisers</category><category>maiden grrders</category><category>pictures</category><category>video</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/30/bout-report-glasgow-roller-derby-v-stockholm-roller-derby-double-header/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 10:50:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bout Report: ARRG Home Season 2012: Cherry Bombers v The Skatefast Club 7th April 2012 </title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/18/bout-report-arrg-home-season-2012-cherry-bombers-v-the-skatefast-club-7th-april-2012/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/dsc02410.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/dsc02410.jpg" alt="" title="SONY DSC" width="614" height="276" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1122"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photograph by Sam Skipsey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you head over to &lt;a href="http://aoanla.blogspot.co.uk/2012/04/bout-report-arrg-home-season-2012.html"&gt;Ante Ortus A Novus Lumen Ars&lt;/a&gt; you can read the bout report from the most recent installment of the Auld Reekie Roller Girls Home Season.A closely fought match between the &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Cherry-Bombers/274799135908869"&gt;Cherry Bombers&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/theskatefastclub"&gt;Skatefast Club&lt;/a&gt; with all the usual pictures and video to peruse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>bout reports</category><category>cherry bombers</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>pictures</category><category>skatefast club</category><category>video</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/18/bout-report-arrg-home-season-2012-cherry-bombers-v-the-skatefast-club-7th-april-2012/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 21:39:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bout Report: Glasgow Roller Derby v Granite City Roller Girls &amp; Berlin Bombshells </title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/03/20/bout-report-glasgow-roller-derby-v-granite-city-roller-girls-berlin-bombshells/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/03/grd-gcrg.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/03/grd-gcrg.jpg" alt="" title="grd gcrg" width="614" height="429" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-979"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head over to &lt;a href="http://aoanla.blogspot.co.uk/2012/03/bout-report-glasgow-roller-derby-v.html"&gt;Ante Ortus A Novus Lumen Ars&lt;/a&gt; for a fine bout report for the recent &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; double header featuring GRD's Maiden Grrders against &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/GraniteCityRollerGirls"&gt;Granite City Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; and the Irn Bruisers up against the mighty &lt;a href="http://bearcityrollerderby.com/"&gt;Berlin Bombshells&lt;/a&gt;.Plus all the usual pictures and video to peruse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/03/grd-berlin.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/03/grd-berlin.jpg" alt="" title="grd berlin" width="614" height="369" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-978"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All photographs by Sam Skipsey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>grd</category><category>irn bruisers</category><category>maiden grrders</category><category>pictures</category><category>video</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/03/20/bout-report-glasgow-roller-derby-v-granite-city-roller-girls-berlin-bombshells/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 11:31:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bout Report: ARRG Home Season 2012: Leithal Weapons v The Skatefast Club </title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/03/05/bout-report-arrg-home-season-2012-leithal-weapons-v-the-skatefast-club/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/03/lw-v-sfc.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/03/lw-v-sfc.jpg" alt="" title="SONY DSC" width="614" height="398" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-935"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photograph by Aoanla&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find a bout report for the second of &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Arrg&lt;/a&gt;'s Home Season games over at &lt;a href="http://aoanla.blogspot.com/2012/03/bout-report-arrg-home-season-2012.html"&gt;Ante Ortus A Novus Lumen Ars&lt;/a&gt;.All the quality reporting,pics and video you have come to expect from Aoanla.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>bout reports</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>leithal weapons</category><category>pictures</category><category>skatefast club</category><category>video</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/03/05/bout-report-arrg-home-season-2012-leithal-weapons-v-the-skatefast-club/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 14:10:15 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>