<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about pohjola cup)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/pohjola-cup.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Russia at the Pohjola Cup: the Furies feed back</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/24/russia-at-the-pohjola-cup-the-furies-feed-back/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/06/the-pohjola-cup-finland-and-russia-compete/"&gt;reported last year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, this season's Pohjola Cup - the official tournament for the leagues of Northern Finland - has broken new ground by inviting their first competitors from outside Finland itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;St Petersburg's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/rollerderbyrussia/"&gt;White Night Furies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Russia's first Roller Derby team (and currently the only bouting one) have played about half of their scheduled bouts in the tournament now, so we thought we'd catch up with them to see how it has been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Furies' Hulk answered a few of our questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did the Furies get the idea to compete in the Pohjola Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White Night Furies decided to to compete in 2016-2017 Pohjola Cup a year ago. We wanted to take a part in a tournament or Cup, to try our derby and team skills and and to see what we can do if we have one game a month, every month. I found the Pohjola Cup organizer (it wasn't very easy &amp;gt;&amp;lt;) and asked if we can join, despite the fact that we are not from Finland. And we're here :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's fair to say that the tournament has been a tough experience for the Furies so far, as first tournaments often are. How have you been adapting to the experience - what have you learned?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can say that all our bouts there were tough :) Each bout we try to use different combinations of tactics and players and see how it works. Each game we change bench stuff and player's roster - from now we just started participating in serious games and we need to know what and how works. That's why I can say that this Cup is very helpful for us - we're learning new things. Also our first two games were on one day, and we'll have the same experience in April, in Oulu. That can be tough, especially if you drive the whole night and then play :) We've learned to play all together as a team regularly (and of course faced a lot of problems inside the team from this), to play a roster of 12, to have a bench and line up for the first time in our team's life :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At this point, are you hoping to return to the Pohjola Cup in the 2017/18 season?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, we are planning to return to the Pohjola Cup next year, we should climb higher to the first place :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This year is very much the year that the Furies are breaking out and making waves. What else do you have planned for 2017?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plans are huge for this year: we founded a B-team and they will have their first game in May, also all of us will have 3-4 days of awesome practices with a Rose City coach who will come and train Team Russia members in Saint-Petersburg: we'll have a big presentation and couple of newbie practices for girls in Minsk, Belarus. One of our big plans is to visit the Moscow team again and help them with making a team (they are reunited again this year!) and, in September-October we want to play 2-3 bouts and haven't decided yet where, but are thinking about teams in Sweden and Netherlands!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>finnish derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>pohjola cup</category><category>team russia</category><category>tournaments</category><category>white night furies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/24/russia-at-the-pohjola-cup-the-furies-feed-back/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 10:56:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Pohjola Cup: Finland (and Russia) Compete!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/06/the-pohjola-cup-finland-and-russia-compete/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We love the way in which Roller Derby has distributed itself worldwide, and part of this is the formation of many "regional" tournaments which are unfortunately easy for others to miss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these is the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/villipohjolarollerderby/"&gt;Pohjola Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the annual tournament between the various leagues of Northern Finland. This is the third season of the cup, and it has grown each year, from a five team series in 2014 to a seven team invitational extending outside of the confines of Finland itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-9788 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14641920_1295491657167849_7122659968114717430_n.jpg" alt="14641920_1295491657167849_7122659968114717430_n" width="960" height="358"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This season (October 2016 to May 2017) the teams competing are:
&lt;strong&gt;Jyväskylä's&lt;/strong&gt; "Blockbusters"
&lt;strong&gt;Kuopio's&lt;/strong&gt; "Kuopio Roller Derby B"
&lt;strong&gt;Oulu's&lt;/strong&gt; "Shitty Village B-Pol" [Winners in 2014]
&lt;strong&gt;Rovaniemi's&lt;/strong&gt; "Roll-On Derby"
&lt;strong&gt;Seinäjoki's &lt;/strong&gt;"Seinäjoki Roller Derby" [Winners in 2015]
&lt;strong&gt;Ylivieska's&lt;/strong&gt; Riverdale Rollers
and, the first non-Finnish entrants to the Cup,
&lt;strong&gt;St. Petersburg (Russia)'s&lt;/strong&gt; "White Night Furies"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who've not looked at a map of Finland, these teams cover a pretty impressive geographical area, as you can see from the tournament map:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-10976 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/pohjola2016-1.png" alt="pohjola2016-1" width="600" height="800"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cup is one great example of how more local roller derby groups can be essential to improve game opportunities and other collective activities. The Villi Pohjola Roller Derby group, who organise the Cup, are a collective of northern Finnish leagues (not just those competing in the cup itself), and also organise scrimmages and other activities together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with previous iterations, the 2016/7 Pohjola Cup is a round-robin, played over several months - one or two double-header fixtures a month, for a total of 21 bouts. Points are assigned as 2 for a win, 0 for a loss, with defaults counted as a loss for the absent team.
There's then a single-elimination "finals" which takes the top 4 teams to determine the absolute winner for the year. The winner wins the Pohjola "Pölkky" (log), which is gloriously decorated for the occasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-11006" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/20161106_102324.jpg?w=2002" alt="_20161106_102324" width="1001" height="1024"&gt; The Pohjola Cup "Pölkky", which is retained by the champions each year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may be the final year when this is possible, however; the rapid growth of required games in round-robin tournaments with size might cause a change in formats next year, if the Cup continues to grow in membership, especially outside of Finland itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first games of this Cup have &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/85241"&gt;already been played&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, with last year's Champions Seinäjoki taking a convincing 190:121 win against Riverdale, and the Blockbusters a closer 197:146 victory over Shitty Village.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope to bring you more structured updates on the Pohjola Cup as it progresses over the next few months!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Thanks to Villi Pohjola's Heli Hiltunen for the details and photo of the Pölkky. Map of Finland based on OpenStreetMap data which is Creative Commons: Attribution-Share-Alike. &lt;a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/" rel="license"&gt;&lt;img style="border-width:0;" src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/4.0/80x15.png" alt="Creative Commons License"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
This work is licensed under a &lt;a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/" rel="license"&gt; Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt; .]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>pohjola cup</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/06/the-pohjola-cup-finland-and-russia-compete/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 10:27:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>