<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about preston roller girls)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/preston-roller-girls.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>June 11th's Packed Scottish Derby Schedule...</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The weekend of the 11th is another extravaganza for high level Scottish Roller Derby, with both Auld Reekie Roller Girls and Glasgow Roller Derby engaged in multiple bouts across the weekend, and Fierce Valley playing away in the continuing British Champs Tier 3 North fixtures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Glasgow and Fierce Valley playing away, the Scottish home games are happening at Auld Reekie's traditional venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Meadowbank+Sports+Centre/@55.956622,-3.1585026,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4887b86eb150070f:0x6955a8c9b9a10cc5!8m2!3d55.956619!4d-3.1563086"&gt;Meadowbank Stadium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, doors open at &lt;strong&gt;2:20pm Saturday 11th&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-7441" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13235130_10156950736565224_2994993262049877442_o.jpg?w=1024" alt="13235130_10156950736565224_2994993262049877442_o" width="1024" height="385"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heading up &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/350352705088707/"&gt;the double-header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Auld Reekie's All-Stars are taking on Kallio Rolling Rainbow, one of Finland's finest teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After their usual impressive performance at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-big-o-2016-schedule-timezones/"&gt;The Big O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Oregon, Auld Reekie are riding high, ready for another challenge - Kallio are slightly higher ranked than they are (FlatTrackStats &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/79684/rankings"&gt;predicts a win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the Finns, albeit with some uncertainty). This will be a WFTDA Sanctioned bout and contribute to both teams' rankings, so it will be an especially hard-fought contest, as both teams will want to reach Division 1 (or remain in Division 2) of the WFTDA Rankings in order to qualify for Playoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other bout is no less exciting in its own way, marking the debut of ARRG's new 'C'-team, the 'All-Star Rookies'&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/#sup"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as they take on Granite City Roller Girls B, the Fight Hawks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, with a team debut, it's hard to make predictions as to the result of the bout; this will be a contest between Auld Reekie's new skater training and the experience gained by the Fight Hawks over the last year. (Having seen some of ARRG's rookies in "rising stars" bouts in the last few months, however, there's some very impressive performers there...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets on the door will be £8 (just £4 per bout), or £5 online via &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2553305"&gt;BrownPaperTickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Concessions tickets will be just £6 on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Glasgow Roller Derby are apparently the stars of the show down in Oldham, as Rainy City Roller Derby are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://rainycityrollerderby.com/event/euro-weekender/"&gt;hosting a weekend of derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, in which Glasgow feature in 3 out of 4 bouts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a Scotland versus Wales playoff, Glasgow's A team, the Irn Bruisers, will be taking on Tiger Bay Brawlers' A; and their B team, the Maiden Grrders will also be facing off against TBB's B-Bombs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FlatTrackStats predicts an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/7953/7929"&gt;incredibly closely-matched bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; between the A-teams (the result depends on which team you give "home-team advantage" to). The B-teams are almost as close in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/10262/11067"&gt;FTS's predictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, although it looks like their stats very narrowly favour the Welsh team (albeit by only a few percent). With only one exception, match-ups between GRD and TBB have been hard-fought, high-level affairs, so we do anticipate some great derby here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Rainy City Roller Derby are scheduled against simply "Glasgow Roller Derby", which we might guess is the A team... Last time they faced each other, Glasgow came out with a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/59869"&gt;convincing win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;; but Glasgow's significant team changes this year have FTS &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/10262/11067"&gt;predicting a win&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the home team this time around. Glasgow will have to pull out something special to keep the win record on their side...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the rankings of Tiger Bay Brawlers A, and Rainy City Roller Derby, these bouts also fill in a chunk of the higher-level UK matchups missing from British Champs this year. With the results from these games, we'll be publishing an "extended" BC Tier 1 ranking, extrapolating where some of the teams not competing in T1 might have ended up, this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[On the Sunday, Kallio Roller Derby are also featuring in this derby weekend, so presumably there's some exciting train travel in Kallio's Sunday morning schedule...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://britishchamps.com"&gt;British Champs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, after an extended period &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/17/british-champs-at-dundee/"&gt;hosted in Scotland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the Tier 3 North fixtures continue in the North of England, with Hallam Hellcats hosting a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/587023974805101/"&gt;double-header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of bouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7445" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13267947_1010255862421996_6895825634478283487_n.jpg" alt="13267947_1010255862421996_6895825634478283487_n" width="530" height="750"&gt; Hallam's bout poster was also available as a limited edition physical print! (Design by Ed Syder) &lt;a href="http://edsyder.tumblr.com/"&gt;http://edsyder.tumblr.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hosts will be taking on Preston Roller Girls, while Scotland will be represented by Fierce Valley Roller Girls taking on Manchester Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FVRG will be hard pressed to defeat currently unbeaten Manchester, but a loss will keep them at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/womens-tables-2016/"&gt;bottom of the table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and in danger of relegation. Meanwhile, Hallam and Preston will be fighting it out to avoid the second-from-bottom spot in the table - there's not much to call between them, but FTS believes that home-team advantage gives the hosts &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/25963/8972"&gt;a slight edge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="sup"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;the Auld Reekie current team naming scheme is a bit confusing - the A team are simply "All-Stars", whilst the B team append "Reserves" and the C team "Rookies". This makes it a bit hard to unambiguously form acronyms for the two, but we're working on this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>auldreekierollergirls</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>fvrg</category><category>gcrd</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>hallam hellcats roller derby</category><category>kallio rolling rainbow</category><category>manchester roller derby</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/02/june-11ths-packed-scottish-derby-schedule/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 11:04:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Skaters on track for New Town Cherry Popper</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/09/new-skaters-on-track-for-new-town-cherry-popper/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;March 19th&lt;/strong&gt; sees the Livingston area's &lt;strong&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; host a one of roller derby's traditions - a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1048868645164481/"&gt;cherry popper bout&lt;/a&gt;, showcasing new skaters from a mix of leagues. The bout will be held in New Town's current bouting venue, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/DSZTrnU8cYo"&gt;Blackburn Community Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6395" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/412387_204493976333497_2093997456_o.jpg?w=600" alt="412387_204493976333497_2093997456_o" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skaters from Auld Reekie Roller Girls, Bairn City Rollers, Lothian Derby Dolls, Doonhame Derby Dolls, Ayrshire Roller Derby, Fair City Rollers and Preston Roller Girls will join host New Town's own new skaters on track in two exhibition teams: The Morello Mashers (skating in hot pink) and the Women of Mass Destruction (skating in sapphire).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an ideal opportunity to see the potential of new roller derby skaters as they play their first bout in public. It's particularly exciting to see skaters from some of Scotland's leagues who are not publicly bouting yet, as this is a preview of perhaps what we might expect from Ayrshire, Doonhame and Fair City when they enter public bouts as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a slightly later game than we normally have in Scotland, with doors opening at &lt;strong&gt;4:45pm&lt;/strong&gt;, for a 5:15pm start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are available online from &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2521813"&gt;brownpapertickets&lt;/a&gt; for just &lt;strong&gt;£4&lt;/strong&gt;. Under 14s are free. Tickets will also be available on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>cherry poppers</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/09/new-skaters-on-track-for-new-town-cherry-popper/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 21:19:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs 2016 opens for Scotland</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/02/16/british-champs-2016-opens-for-scotland/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the second year of the nationwide &lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com"&gt;British Championship&lt;/a&gt;s started last week, a quirk of scheduling means that all of Scotland's teams have their first games &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, there are no less than three double-header events for British Champs this weekend featuring Scottish teams, and two of them are being hosted up in Scotland itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Auld Reekie Roller Girls, Voodoo Roller Dollies and New Town Roller Girls all having left British Champs for various reasons after the 2015 Season, there are currently 4 Scottish leagues still competing in the schedules, all of whom play this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working up the tiers, then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;Saturday&lt;/strong&gt;, Aberdeen's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.granitecityrollerderby.co.uk/"&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are hosting the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/199093520445006/"&gt;first fixture&lt;/a&gt; of the Tier 4 North Division, in their usual venue, the Beach Leisure Centre. The double header will see Blackpool Roller Derby League take on Halifax Bruising Banditas; followed by hosts Granite City taking on Durham Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-5755 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/12525411_10154612912394012_7934633322794908992_o.jpg?w=212" alt="12525411_10154612912394012_7934633322794908992_o" width="212" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;FlatTrackStats&lt;/a&gt; predicts a win for GCRD over Durham; however, the Halifax/Blackpool bout should be extremely close, potentially coming down to the final jam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GCRD are hosting at the &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Beach+Leisure+Centre/@57.1556049,-2.0820887,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x48840e4028217933:0x30c6b9176815da5b"&gt;Beach Leisure Centre&lt;/a&gt;. Doors open at 12:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Down in &lt;strong&gt;Preston&lt;/strong&gt;, both &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/dundeerollergirls/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; will be competing in the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1755123161386637/"&gt;first fixture&lt;/a&gt; in T3 North on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday&lt;/strong&gt;. FVRG will lead the schedule, taking on Hull's Angels Roller Dames; Dundee Roller Girls follow, taking on hosts Preston Roller Girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FTS's predictions here are that H.A.R.D. should triumph over Fierce Valley, while hosts Preston should lose, albeit narrowly, against Dundee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-5743 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/brit-champs-t3-gameday-1-768x768.jpg?w=300" alt="Brit-Champs-T3-Gameday-1-768x768" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This event will be held in Preston's usual venue, &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Preston's+College/@53.7849145,-2.7022612,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x487b721b0a2e51eb:0x9868b02f36edca68"&gt;Preston's College&lt;/a&gt;. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;midday&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; will be hosting the&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/events-calendar/2016/2/21/british-roller-derby-championships-double-header"&gt; first games&lt;/a&gt; of the T1 "Premier" Division, on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday&lt;/strong&gt;! While Glasgow won the T1 Division last year, they're also one of the few teams from T1 returning from the last time: this first fixture sees them facing Newcastle Roller Girls (who promoted from T2 last year) and also facing London Rollergirls B, who are new to the Championships. Glasgow will be keen to prove that they're capable of defending their title against new challengers, while Newcastle will be equally keen to show that they deserve their promotion from Tier 2, and the Brawl Saints will want to make their mark as incomers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5761" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/12646940_10156610083540389_6438710273192564289_n.jpg" alt="12646940_10156610083540389_6438710273192564289_n" width="960" height="303"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking to FlatTrackStats, it expects Glasgow to take an easy win against Newcastle, but a more challenging one against London's Brawl Saints. With the London bout second, it could be even closer than FTS expects; the statistics don't take into account the possibility that one team might be more tired after playing previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow are hosting this event at their regular venue, the &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662183,-4.2519236,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7"&gt;ARC Health and Fitness&lt;/a&gt; at Glasgow Caledonian University. Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;12:45pm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>blackpool roller derby</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>durham roller derby</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>halifax bruising banditas</category><category>hull's angels roller derby</category><category>london rollergirls</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/02/16/british-champs-2016-opens-for-scotland/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 17:04:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Coach Trip to Preston!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/04/04/coach-trip-to-preston/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 26th April, &lt;a title="FVRG Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/FierceValleyRG?fref=ts" target="_blank"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; will be heading to Lancashire to take on &lt;a title="https://www.facebook.com/prestonrollers?fref=ts" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/04/04/coach-trip-to-preston/Preston%20Roller%20Girls%20Facebook%20Page" target="_blank"&gt;Preston Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; - and they want you to join them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two teams last met in February 2013 at The Peak in Stirling. Although Fierce Valley took the win in ‘Love Hurts’, it was a tough bout and came right down to the last jam. Both teams have come up against some stiff opposition over the past year – with both celebrating wins and losses – so it's all to play for in this year’s ‘Block Stock and Two Smokin’ Jammers’!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to cheer on the Parma Violents in their next bout, there are still seats available in their hired bus.  The return journey costs £18 per person. The coach will leave from the main car park in &lt;a title="Grangemouth Sports Complex" href="http://www.falkirkcommunitytrust.org/venues/grangemouth-sports-complex/" target="_blank"&gt;Grangemouth Sports Complex&lt;/a&gt; at 8am sharp on Saturday 26th April, then after the action-packed bout, the coach will leave Preston to head back home at 9pm. The travel time is approx. 3 hours 20 minutes each way, plus a rest stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reserve your seat on FVRG's Coach Trip, please email &lt;a title="Email FVRG" href="mailto:%20BoutManagement@fvrg.co.uk"&gt;BoutManagement@fvrg.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; with your name and contact details. Seats will be reserved on a first-come, first-served basis. Payment will be taken on the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a title="Preston vs FVRG Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/623798847687043/?ref=5" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event &lt;/a&gt;for full details on the event; tickets can be bought in advance online for £4.50 from &lt;a title="But Tickets Online" href="http://prg.bigcartel.com/product/block-stock-and-two-smokin-jammers-prg-vs-fvrg-26-04-14" target="_blank"&gt;Big Cartel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/04/coach-trip-3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3369" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/04/coach-trip-3.jpg" alt="Coach Trip 3" width="550" height="310"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/04/04/coach-trip-to-preston/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 19:11:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Love Hurts: FVRG vs Preston Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/28/fvrg-vs-preston-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first bout of &lt;a title="Fierce Valley Roller Girls on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/FierceValleyRG" target="_blank"&gt;FVRG&lt;/a&gt;'s 2013 season will see the Parma Violents take on &lt;a title="Preston Roller Girls on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/prestonrollers" target="_blank"&gt;Preston Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;! This will take place on Saturday 16th February, at The Peak Sports Village in Stirling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The home team are setting themselves a challenge to make this event even bigger and better than their last visit to The Peak. Even though their previous bout clashed with pretty much every other Scottish Roller Derby team, Fierce Valley packed out the main hall in the sports centre and attracted lots of attention from the gym-goers and staff alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 2pm, for a 2:30pm start. Tickets cost £5 in advance online via &lt;a title="Buy tickets from Brown Paper Tickets UK" href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/312786" target="_blank"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt;, or £7 on the door. Under 14s are welcome to attend for free when accompanied by a paying adult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full details of the event can be found on the &lt;a title="FVRG vs Preston Roller Girls Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/114944845342095/?ref=22" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/love-hurts-small.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2106" alt="Love Hurts Poster, designed by SeenGus" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/love-hurts-small.jpg" width="614" height="867"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Love Hurts Poster, designed by SeenGus&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>preston roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/28/fvrg-vs-preston-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 23:09:09 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>