<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about re:act)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/react.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Open and Junior Derby for Refugee Action in Grangemouth</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/01/open-and-junior-derby-for-refugee-action-in-grangemouth/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we approach the Christmas season, we've said only recently, people's thoughts turn to charity and giving. This means that we get to advertise a lot more events which support great causes, as well as providing fantastic Roller Derby!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Glasgow Roller Derby's charity event this weekend, there's a chance to even more people on the &lt;strong&gt;10th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;December&lt;/strong&gt;, as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Grangemouth+Sports+Complex/@56.0117322,-3.7230771,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x488879aaeb85b4ed:0x204ad804f85c6304!8m2!3d56.0117322!4d-3.7208831"&gt;Grangemouth Sports Complex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; hosts a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/633601170145402/"&gt;charity event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in support of Re-Act Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.re-act.scot/f-a-q/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Re-Act Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;is a humanitarian aid project devoted to providing assistance to refugees from war-torn (and other areas in crisis) regions - particularly towards the large refugee camps which have emerged in areas such as Calais.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be a double-header event, with Scotland's first Junior League, Fierce Valley Roller Cubs playing an intraleague (their first since their first ever away bout, a few months ago) at the top of the schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be followed by a Co-ed/Open invitational bout, currently featuring skaters from Fierce Valley Roller Girls, Bairn City Rollers, Mean City Roller Derby, Glasgow Men's Roller Derby, Auld Reekie Roller Girls and Granite City Roller Derby. (Many of these leagues are also providing officials to allow both bouts to take place, and Glasgow Roller Derby are providing the head ref in Candy Moho.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as the on-track action, we're promised an array of stalls, with Sweets Jewellery, and Face Painting by Cinders already signed up, and potentially more to announce, as well as the traditional cake and baking stall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this is a Charity event, there will be &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; required entrance fee - but donations to the event charity are encouraged. These can be monetary, but they can also be in the form of useful items - for example, winter clothing for adults in small and medium sizes, waterproofs and sturdy footwear suitable for being outdoors in, tents, sleeping bags and/or blankets.
Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;2:30pm.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="_5wd4 _1nc7 direction_ltr"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="_5wd4 _1nc7 direction_ltr"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>charity</category><category>re:act</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/01/open-and-junior-derby-for-refugee-action-in-grangemouth/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 11:28:36 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>