<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about review of the year)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/review-of-the-year.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>2016 in Review</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst on a general level, 2016 has been labelled a bad year (perhaps unfairly - it's been a mixed bag, it's just that the negatives have been big and prominent, and the positives less so), for Roller Derby, in Scotland and World wide, it's been pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're capping off the year by talking about the things that happened in the past 12 months, first in Scotland (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/1"&gt;page 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and secondly across the World (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/2"&gt;page 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), before rounding up our hopes for 2017 (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/3"&gt;page 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Scotland&lt;/h3&gt;
Scottish Roller Derby continued to Grow: several new leagues popped up, which we recently brought to you [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/06/scotlands-newest-coed-league-inverclyde-roller-derby/"&gt;Inverclyde Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/13/scotlands-newest-northernmost-league-orkney-viqueens/"&gt;Orkney ViQueens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/15/west-lothians-newest-league-west-lothian-roller-derby/"&gt;West Lothian Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/09/glasgow-mens-roller-derby/"&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/30/glasgows-new-inclusive-junior-derby-resistance-roller-derby/"&gt;Resistance Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] and others continued to grow.
Ayrshire Roller Derby had their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/08/16/ayshire-roller-derby-hit-the-track/"&gt;first public bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (against Lothian Derby Dolls) as did &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/12/granite-city-brawlers-debut-home-game/"&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and GMRD, and Helgin Roller Derby  and the renewed Fair City Rollers have scheduled their (joint) first bout for next year (if we were to bet, we'd expect Doonhame Roller Derby to be the next to be bout-ready).
Scotland's only bouting junior derby team, Fierce Valley Roller Cubs, also played their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/07/cubs-take-on-new-opposition/"&gt;first ever interleague bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, against a mixed team from Sheffield and Newcastle.
Even the larger leagues continued to expand, with Auld Reekie Roller Girls' ASTROs founded this year, and taking the number of ARRG travel teams to 3. As our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/19/yearrgly-review-2016/"&gt;Auld Reekie review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; shows, the whole league had a pretty good year, with the All-Stars qualifying for WFTDA Division 2 playoffs (after an impressive performance at The Big O in the USA), and sensibly declining in favour of working on longer term goals.
&lt;p&gt;Further north, both Dundee Roller Girls and Granite City Roller Derby had very good years as well. Both leagues' A-teams performed impressively in their Divisions at British Champs (Granite City qualifying for promotion to Tier 3 from Tier 4, and Dundee just missing out on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/17/british-champs-at-dundee/"&gt;the promotion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to Tier 2 at the Tier-3 playoffs). Whilst Dundee has withdrawn from Champs to focus on their national and international game (especially after playing their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/08/dundees-international-debut/"&gt;first international away&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, in Tenerife, just scant weeks ago), Granite City will indeed be in Tier 3 of Champs next year, alongside Auld Reekie's Reserves! The two leagues' B-teams also had very good years, with Dundee's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/16/a-chat-with-bonnie-colliders-captains-khilleesi-and-g-wrecks/"&gt;Bonnie Colliders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; winning basically every bout they played until ARRG's ASTROs late in the year, and GCRD's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/21/granite-citys-hawks-flock-to-the-arrgmageddon/"&gt;Fight Hawks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; playing three times as much derby as they did in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Central Belt, Bairn City Rollers' Skelpies managed a few bouts, despite many of them also making Power of Scotland, which prevented them taking fixtures in the first half of the year!. Alongside GMRD, they'll be joining the British Champs Men's T3 in 2017, and we expect good things of them. Meanwhile, BCR's &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/12/bairn-city-belters-captain-and-vice-interview-2016/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central Belters&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;continued their own upward rise in the rankings - a win against the newly-reformed Furness Firecrackers sealing that trend for the year, and setting the Belters the challenge of maintaining expectations in 2017 (the problem with upward growth is that people start expecting it to never stop!). The open-gender Belter Skelpers had a much quieter year, taking on just Mean City's coed-team and then hosting Granite City Brawlers and friends for BCR's 4th Anniversary event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Mean City, they were also extremely busy this year, hosting a vast range of events, including &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/24/powers-of-two-at-mean-city/"&gt;double-headers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; supporting Power of Scotland. With the growth of coed leagues in Scotland (several of our newer non-bouting leagues are open), hopefully Mean City will have an even busier year next year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the Scottish Men's National Team, Power of Scotland also had a very big year, representing well at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/30/mrdwc2016-rankings-and-statistics/"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Calgary, placing a creditable 10th, just below the tournament's surprise unseeded upset of Mexico. Several members of the 2016 team are also now involved with Team Scotland Roller Derby, who will be hoping (along with PoS) to represent the nation strongly in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not to say that there weren't some wobbles in Scottish Derby: due to an unfortunate series of retirements, Glasgow Roller Derby has spent the season with a very different roster to 2015, resulting in the 2015 British Champs Champions placing near the bottom of the Premier Division in 2016.  They'll be aiming to pull back their WFTDA ranking position over 2017... although they've retired from British Champs to focus their team on this goal.   Similarly, a series of transfers and other movements lead to Fierce Valley Roller Girls performing less well than they would have liked in the Champs Tier 3, resulting in potential relegation to Tier 4 in 2017. (Despite this, both FVRG and GRD have been drivers of many Scottish events in the past year - Fierce Valley hosting a pair of massive &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/18/the-team-who-sur5ed-fierce-valley-host-harry-potter-themed-open-event/"&gt;Sur5al&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; tournaments and hosting an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/23/international-roller-derby-in-the-forth-valley/"&gt;international&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; against Zurich, and Glasgow hosting &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/28/glasgow-roller-derby-close-the-year-with-festive-charity/"&gt;Charity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; events and playing &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/01/glasgow-at-europes-first-wftda-division-1-tournament/"&gt;all&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/25/glasgow-cross-the-irish-sea-dublin-v-irn-bruisers/"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Europe themselves, as well as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/29/international-derby-at-glasgow-and-edinburgh/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Berlin, and playing a big part in Vagine Regime UK.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another growing trend in Scotland (and the UK) this year was "cherry popper" or "rookie" bouts, with almost every league in Scotland hosting at least one such event this year, including Livingston's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/09/new-skaters-on-track-for-new-town-cherry-popper/"&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we shouldn't just talk about the Leagues themselves. Scottish Referees and NSOs also continued to represent at the highest levels of the sport, with Dundee's Righteous Oxide particularly visible at international level events like MRDWC and ; but many other referees like , and NSOs (many of whom were nominated in the TDTM Listener awards) travelled huge distances and devoted much time to supporting the sport.
Scottish photographers were also supporting international events this year, with Dave McAleavy and Laura MacDonald being both ubiquitous at Scottish games, but also travelling to Tenerife in Dave's case, and to the Men's World Cup in Laura's. (As the two are, between them, the photographers for the two national teams, we expect even more travel in their future.)
Our Announcers didn't do too badly either, with Helliverence near-ubiquitous across UK events, Bairn City's man of many names Graeme "Archie" McPhail supporting MEC [and announcing two tournaments in Scotland without a break in each],  MRDWC media director Chasing Katy appearing at several events, but especially MEC, and Granite City's sMACklemore doing both MEC and  Track Head Announcing at MRDWC itself. The latter two also helped to push on the Scottish contributions to Roller Derby media, with the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://tdtmpodcast.wordpress.com/"&gt;Talk Derby To Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; podcast [also hosted by King Crazy] going from strength to strength over the year (especially with their excellent coverage of tournament-level events), culminating in a rather huge Listener Awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(For us at the Scottish Roller Derby Blog, it's also been a good year - we've expanded our coverage again, introduced our own rankings, and even managed to expand into some new fields of video and audio interviews. We also &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/category/mrdwc2016/"&gt;covered&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the Men's Roller Derby World Cup in more depth than we have any previous event. In order to handle this, we &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/"&gt;launched our own annex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to the blog, which hosts links to content which doesn't work well with Wordpress.
We also managed to hit more then 1500 likes on our Facebook page just a few days ago, which was our own goal for 2016!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to Scotland (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/1"&gt;page 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) , forward to "The Future" (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/3"&gt;page 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;UK and Europe&lt;/h3&gt;
Obviously one of the most exciting developments of 2016 was the announcement of so much International Derby coming to Europe in the next two years. Both World Cups will be in Europe - the Men's in Barcelona and the Women's in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/05/a-rainy-day-for-international-roller-derby/"&gt;Greater Manchester&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - in 2018; but before that, one MRDA playoff and the Championship itself will be in Europe as well.
With so many Europe-wide international tournaments already happening in Europe (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/"&gt;ERDT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/27/a-quick-analysis-of-road-to-tbc/"&gt;The Road to...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, SKOD, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/17/first-time-tournament-announcing-or-how-chasing-katy-survived-mec-2o16/"&gt;MEC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/01/glasgow-at-europes-first-wftda-division-1-tournament/"&gt;European Smackdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and so on... with Newcastle's EuroClash joining the set in 2017), this was almost inevitable at some point, but no-one expected everything but WFTDA to happen at once.
&lt;p&gt;Another positive development in the UK was the coming together of Coaches at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/03/uks-first-coaching-summit-derby-stance/"&gt;Derby Stance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Coaching Summit (followed by the Summit at the Ramps, which brought together skaters from multiple disciplines) organised by Rule 56 and the Female Coaching Network. We're very much in favour of people working together to progress the community...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...which is also why we were cheered by the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/19/by-their-powers-combined-they-are-leeds-roller-derby/"&gt;announcement very recently&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that Leeds Roller Derby had formed from fusion of Hot Wheel and Leeds Roller Dolls. We'd love to report on more "collaborations" rather than the politics which leads to splits in Roller Derby, and hope this can be a trend for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Roller Derby media also had some growth in the UK as well, with two new podcasts - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hellyeahrollerderby.com/"&gt;Hell Yeah! Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Croydon and elsewhere] and the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://goodarrows.libsyn.com/podcast"&gt;Good Arrows Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Nottingham Roller Derby] both launching this year, with good content already!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;International&lt;/h3&gt;
Internationally, the most exciting places for Roller Derby are always where growth and development is still raring ahead.
&lt;p&gt;So, in East Asia, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/"&gt;Japan Open Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was possibly the most significant event of the year - the first ever international tournament in the region, hosted in Okinawa and with attendees from the Pacific Region, Australiasia and beyond (Alaska and Copenhagen!). We're very excited to see what the sequel (now managed directly by a consortium of the Japanese leagues) tournament - the Tomodachi in March 2017 - manages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also in East Asia, after literally years of development, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/"&gt;first ever public bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in China happened, with Beijing Roller Derby hosting a mixed team from the rest of the Asian leagues. This was also a great example of the still-political purpose of Roller Derby, as the event was in promotion of the UN HeForShe project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growth has also continued in other regions, with Latin America now hosting a huge number of teams (although their terminology for leagues and teams differs from the USA and Europe), including 3 now in WFTDA (as full members, with more Apprentices). Across Europe and the Middle East, increasing number of countries are growing not just one, but multiple teams - and in the more established countries we've seen huge growth in national level tournaments (the French Nationale is a mighty thing), and other regular events (for ex. the Finnish &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/06/the-pohjola-cup-finland-and-russia-compete/"&gt;Pohjola Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; now trans-national as it includes Russia's White Night Furies this year).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of National Teams representation, 2016 has seen continued growth in both the Men's and Women's parts of the sport - MRDWC 2016 saw a massive surge in teams attending, filling out Europe and Latin America [Colombia having a last-minute technical hitch which prevented this being even more impressive]; and there are already at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/22/new-nations-in-the-world-cup/"&gt;least 5 new Nations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the 2018 Roller Derby World Cup in Manchester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we were very pleased that WFTDA has started adopting positive policies such as releasing the (alpha) of their new bout stats management tool, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/19/bouttime-open-source-what-is-it-and-why-is-it-relevant-to-roller-derby-and-wftda/"&gt;bouttime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, as an open-source project, truly for the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And International Derby Media has also continued to grow, with the startling appearance of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://thederbyapex.com/@thederbyapex"&gt;The Derby Apex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; earlier this year, and their meteoric rise to popularity. We're sure we'll see more good things from them in 2017 and beyond. (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.derbycentral.net/"&gt;Derby Central&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, of course, continued to do great work, covering all of the international things above, and many more.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to Scotland (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/1"&gt;page 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and back to the World (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/2"&gt;page 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The Future&lt;/h3&gt;
So, what would we like to see in 2017?
&lt;h4&gt;National Teams leveraging PR to promote growth in their "home" nations.&lt;/h4&gt;
Whilst Teams Korea, Philippines and West Indies are all representing their nations, none of them have any leagues &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; those nations to draw skaters from. With all three declaring their intent to use their existence to promote the sport, we'd love to see this bear fruit. (Korea has a league, but like most leagues in East Asia [except Kamikaze Badass in Tokyo, and Tokyo Roller Girls' Neon Roller Monsters team] it is almost entirely composed of non-nationals.)
&lt;h4&gt;The Derby Apex's "Stat Rataissance" actually happening.&lt;/h4&gt;
One of The Apex's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://thederbyapex.com/our-10-favourite-things-from-the-2016-wftda-season-d516ae8284e4#.jmhiwv3pm"&gt;high points&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of the year has been the improved availability of stats for WFTDA bouts, alongside the promotion of bouttime. We're a little more skeptical of this as a global phenomenon - Roller Derby is not just WFTDA teams [in fact, they're still a minority, especially if you include the fact that only A teams count for WFTDA member leagues], and stats availability for the sport as a whole is still relatively poor, despite the best efforts of Flat Track Stats and others. We'd like to see this happen, though, and still have some hope. (Our own effort in this regard - the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; rating system - is still very much dependant on FTS's own records, which are themselves dependant on both the site's few volunteers and the Roller Derby community itself.)
&lt;h4&gt;Increased openness, transparency and collaboration.&lt;/h4&gt;
One reason why stats are an issue feeds into this next wish: Roller Derby still has problems with openness and transparency. The bouttime release was definitely a positive step from WFTDA, but we think that most Derby bodies (international and national) could improve on their transparency (the MRDA gets points for having a public forum!) and communication. Alongside this, we'd also like to see positive elements of collaboration continue to grow - more things like Derby Stance, more mergers of leagues to make stronger bodies, and generally more "derby spirit".
&lt;h4&gt;A WFTDA Playoff outside North America (and a non-US team winning Champs).&lt;/h4&gt;
As The Apex noted, WFTDA is now the only major entity with "international" contests not to have some component held outside North America. It would be great to see some movement on this, especially with the increasing number of ranked European teams at D2 and even D1 level. (We'd also love to see a non-US team win the WFTDA Championships - Victorian have come ever so close twice now [and they've beaten Rose on neutral ground this year], so 2017 could still be it.)
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what would you like to see in 2017 - from us, or from Roller Derby? Let us know via our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/scottish.rollerderby/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; page, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/scotrollerderby"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or just email (scottishrollerderbyATgmailDOTcom)!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>articles</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>international derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>review of the year</category><category>team scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 14:21:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Voodoo and Hades in 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/12/voodoo-and-hades-in-2015/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2015 was a particularly packed year for the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Voodoo-Roller-Dollies-571771319549241/"&gt;Voodoo Roller Dollies&lt;/a&gt;. As well as participating in &lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/category/women-local/local-north/"&gt;British Championships Tier 4 North&lt;/a&gt;, they also managed to both host and attend several tournaments, and fly across Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, before the Tier 4 fixtures even started, Voodoo had already hosted their own mini-tournament, taking on fellow Tier 4 competitors, New Town Roller Girls, and Glasgow Roller Derby's Cannie Gingers in the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/144431299060564/"&gt;Highland Rampage&lt;/a&gt; in Edinburgh's Jack Kane Centre.  While the Cannies emerged victorious, VRD took the win against New Town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VRD also managed to sneak in a battle of the Zombie themed teams, playing Tournai, Belgium's Rolling Zombie Dolls away, and North Wales Roller Derby's Zom Bs at home, before British Champs started in April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5609" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/01/11024650_10100359068288294_1208772091011200554_n.jpg" alt="11024650_10100359068288294_1208772091011200554_n" width="960" height="640"&gt; Voodoo Roller Dollies take on New Town for the first time in 2015 (Credit: &lt;a href="http://lauramacd.co.uk"&gt;Laura MacDonald&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In between Champs fixtures, Voodoo even took a side trip to Ireland, successfully taking on Belfast City Rockets on the way to a rematch against the East Coast Cyclones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Voodoo failed to earn promotion in British Champs, they also avoided relegation, defeating New Town a second time to stay off the bottom of the table. (VRD are also one of quite a few teams not returning to British Champs in 2016, so that they can concentrate on the rest of their bouting fixtures.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voodoo indulged their love of sur5al in November, sending a team to the Blackpool Roller-Coasters' Sur5al 2015 Mini Tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the Dollies capped off the year by hosting their &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/908423505918913/"&gt;second mini tournament&lt;/a&gt; of 2015, with returning Cannie Gingers also taking on Lucerne's Hellveticats in the triple header in Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HadesRollerBoys/"&gt;Hades Roller Boys&lt;/a&gt; were not letting their sisters in Voodoo have all the fun. At the same time as changing their Facebook page, the Boys started their year in March taking on Bristol's Vice Quads away for a loss, and Cornwall's Scrumpy Old Men for a win the very next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hades followed this up by taking on the impressive Tyne and Fear B in May (as part of a double-header, featuring Newcastle v Brussels), and facing off against Portsmouth's Scurvy Dogs (also as part of a double header, featuring Portsmouth Roller Wenches v Norfolk Brawds) in July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hades also love sur5al, and they competed well in both Glasgow Roller Derby's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1128420117173784/"&gt;tournament&lt;/a&gt; in June, and Leeds Roller Dolls' &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1658884867657678/"&gt;Rolling Dead&lt;/a&gt; in October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5612" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/01/12362692_1012007705529392_4768291942966720645_o.jpg" alt="12362692_1012007705529392_4768291942966720645_o" width="2048" height="1365"&gt; Hades take on De Ronnys in the BEARDI final! (Credit: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/orelkichigaiphotography/"&gt;Orel Kichigai&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important event in Hades' 2015 must be their attendance at the alternative men's European tournament, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BEARDi-1456637027957678/"&gt;B.E.A.R.D.I.&lt;/a&gt; As the only Scottish team attending, Hades had a lot of weight on their shoulders, and they excelled, defeating all comers to make it to the final against Germany's De Ronnys. After a very physical bout, Hades emerged triumphant as 2016 B.E.A.R.D.I. champions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Hades and Voodoo also found the time to fully combine their powers, with &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HoodooCoedRollerDerby/"&gt;HooDoo Co-ed Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; making their track debut against the "Beach Brawl All Stars" exhibition team. We expect more fixtures for HooDoo this year, as Co-ed roller derby continues to grow in Scotland!&lt;/p&gt;
Finally, 2015 saw the end of an era as two of Voodoo and Hades' founders, Raven and Pete, moved on to other geographical locations. (Raven's last ever bout was also the last bout of the year.)
&lt;p&gt;We'll finish on this message from the current Voodoo Roller Dollies team:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;We would like to say Thank you to Raven and Pete for their contribution to the team and wish them well for the future.
2015 was a very busy year for us and we managed to do more than we even thought we could manage. We are looking forward to 2016 and the opportunities and potential it holds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>hades roller boys</category><category>hoodoo roller derby</category><category>review of the year</category><category>voodoo roller dollies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/12/voodoo-and-hades-in-2015/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 16:11:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow Roller Derby - 2015 in Review</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/04/glasgow-roller-derby-2015-in-review/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's fair to say that &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; had a packed year in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the launch of &lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/"&gt;British Championship&lt;/a&gt;s last year, GRD A, the Irn Bruisers, had a full set of fixtures in the first half of the year just dealing with the Premier Tier bouts. This busy schedule didn't affect the Bruisers' performance, however, and they managed to top their tier (and therefore become crowned the strongest team in British Champs) with an unbroken win record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow, the Bruisers also found time to make it over to Berlin to take on the Berlin Bombshells in April, which chalked up their only loss for the first half of the year, in a hard fought game for both teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, their extraordinary performance in Champs, especially their 226 point win over Tiger Bay Brawlers, and 116 pt margin against Auld Reekie, was sufficient to place GRD A at 24th in the WFTDA world rankings, and win them a place in the &lt;a href="https://wftda.com/tournaments/2015/jacksonville"&gt;WFTDA Division 1&lt;/a&gt; playoffs in Jacksonville. (Glasgow are currently only the second UK league, after London, to make Division 1 Playoffs.) It also got Glasgow to be &lt;a href="https://wftda.com/featured-league/glasgow-roller-derby"&gt;WFTDA Featured League&lt;/a&gt; for July!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all this excitement, GRD B, the Maiden Grrders, weren't sitting around doing nothing. In March, the Grrders flew over to Nantes to participate in &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/60735"&gt;West Track Story II&lt;/a&gt;I, facing hosts Nantes Derby Girls along with Amsterdam, Bear City B (Inglorious Bombshells) and Kallio B (Kinapori Fistfunkers). After some close games against Amsterdam and Berlin, the Maidens placed a creditable middle of the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April, Glasgow also took on Team Metal Legs as part of Mean City Roller Derby's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1609824055906168/"&gt;double header&lt;/a&gt;, with a mash-up team containing A and B team skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow C, the Cannie Gingers, also had a successful first half of the year, taking on Voodoo Roller Dollies and New Town Roller Girls in February's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/144431299060564/"&gt;Highland Rampage&lt;/a&gt;, and winning with 100 and 200 pt margins respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On to the second half of the year, and Glasgow doubled down on fundraising to get the Irn Bruisers over to America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arriving in Jacksonville, seeded 7th, Glasgow A played a strong game against first opponents, Charlottesville, before being outlasted by them for a relatively close loss. Unfortunately, Tampa Bay then took a strong win against the Bruisers; thankfully, GRD recovered from their loss to take a convincing final bout against Pike's Peak, finishing their first ever Division 1 Playoffs with a 1-2 win-loss ratio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With everything else on pause a bit for playoffs, the Maidens and the Gingers had a quieter second half of the year. The Maidens took on Auld Reekie B and Manchester for convincing wins, and then Finland's Tampere and (rematching) Kinapori for losses. The Gingers took on Bairn City Rollers' Central Belters in July, and also attended a second Voodoo hosted tournament, beating the hosts again, and demolishing Luzern's Hellveticats in their first "European" match-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all of this excitement, there wasn't enough room in the year for a full Home Teams tournament in 2015, so the bouting year was capped by a single-day &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1507855322868655/"&gt;Home Teams Extravaganza&lt;/a&gt;, which the Bad Omens won fairly convincingly.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;As for 2016:&lt;/h5&gt;
Glasgow Roller Derby are one of the few Premier Tier leagues returning for a second year in British Champs, and no-doubt they'll be aiming to retain the championship, and return to the USA for a more successful Division 1 Playoffs. In aid of this second aim, the Irn Bruisers are attending the first ever WFTDA European Division 1 Tournament, the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/551420871678799/"&gt;European Smackdown&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;The first bout of the year, however, will also be GRD's first bout in a new venue: &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/glasgow-roller-derby-vs-vagine-regime-uk-double-header-tickets-20064045099"&gt;Glasgow's A and B teams taking on Vagine Regime UK's A and B&lt;/a&gt; rosters in the Lagoon Centre, Paisley. After the closure of the Kelvin Hall International Sports Arena left GRD with only the small confines of the ARC in Glasgow Caledonian University, they've been looking for a more expansive venue, and the Lagoon Centre will hopefully meet their requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/04/glasgow-roller-derby-2015-in-review/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 11:25:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2015 was ARRGmazing!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/31/2015-was-arrgmazing/</link><dc:creator>jennifergelignite</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/arrg-banner.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5399"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-5399 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/arrg-banner.jpg?w=300" alt="ARRG-Banner" width="837" height="187"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a comedy gig with a famous guy (remember Dylan Moran back in January!).
The Reserves took on the Oxbridge double.
The All Stars came second in the first ever British Championships!
And we hosted THE best Champs day in May!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The All Stars took on Glasgow in June again, a month that also featured an excellent family fun day in Portobello!
We had a Hunger Games themed Bootcamp in July! Those May the Quads be Ever in your Favour tops were a popular choice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the Fringe, the All Star Reserves took on Glasgows Maiden Grrders, and then we held an awesome All Star Expo with skaters from across Scotland and Northern England!
Throughout the year we held some Taster Days and Fresh Meat intakes!
And of course the year has culminated in the Home Season and All Star Reserves season!
We've also said some sad goodbyes, but welcomed many awesome members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Home Season 2015 was won by THE LEITHAL WEAPONS!! In a very closely fought game against The Skatefast Club, with the score being extremely close throughout. Congratulations to the Cherry Bombers for taking the victory in the third place game against our guests, The Rolling Bones - what a win!
Thank you to ALL of everyone who helped at the Home Season, whether you skated, officiated, announced, helped as a member of the game crew, EVERYONE. THANKS!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also got the FIRST Certified officials in Scotland! Which is pretty huge! And we had official reps at some of the biggest tournaments/games around Europe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our All Star Reserves came back from an excellent trip to Copenhagen at the start of November!
They played both Copenhagen Roller Derby and Malmo's Crime City, in the one day! They did amazing for being pitted against such tough teams! So many giants. Hipster hostels. Team hang outs. Christmas. I think we can say it was still a successful trip!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now the Reserves have a couple more games in the new year! In January they will be taking on Dresden Roller Derby at home, and we can’t wait! And then another in March!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new rosters have also been announced, and the All Stars themselves have started training in time for, yes, THE BIG O! This is a fantastic opportunity and an amazing tournament. SO many amazing teams will also be there! Even the other ARRG (Arch Rival Roller Girls). And whether you can make it over to Portland (we wish), or can cheer and support from here, there is SUCH EXCITEMENT.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>leithal weapons</category><category>maiden grrders</category><category>review of the year</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/31/2015-was-arrgmazing/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 13:45:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-bouting Leagues Roundup of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/30/non-bouting-leagues-roundup-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year has seen another uptick in the number of new leagues in Scotland, with both &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HelginRollerDerby"&gt;Helgin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/WeeCRD"&gt;Wee County Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; joining the ranks of &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/InvernessCityRollerDerby/"&gt;Inverness City&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/FairCityRollers/"&gt;Fair City&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Ayrshire-Roller-Derby-Official-618921518215712/"&gt;Ayrshire&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DoonhameDerbyDolls"&gt;Doonhame Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; as leagues making the journey towards their first public bout. As traditional, we're covering all of these leagues together in a Review of the Year, as usually bouts are a big part of what the bouting leagues cover about in their own articles. Since we have so many non-bouting leagues this year, however, we're splitting this article over several pages for readability - click the links at the bottom of each page to move between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every league forms its own relationships with the wider derby community when starting out, but some of our non-bouting leagues have developed particularly close ties.
Inverness City Roller Derby were very happy that Helgin Roller Derby started up nearby in Elgin, and the two have been combining resources:
"Helgin are fantastic and are growing so fast.
We try to go through as often as possible to coach them and help them with anything they may need help with and they often come through to us for a session and with such a big turn out at these sessions it boosts team morale."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5376" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/pudz.jpg" alt="PuDz" width="960" height="540"&gt; Power of Scotland's PudZ, selfie with combined Inverness and Helgin skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helgin are equally happy with the relationship, as they benefit from ICRD's experience and numbers. "All of our skaters rave about Nat from ICRD’s sessions for days afterwards – she really works us hard and we learn a lot! […] We’re looking to link up with ICRD at least once a month in 2016, so that we can all get a bit more contact and pack skills practice – something that can prove difficult if you’ve got a session with low numbers."
Of course, Helgin have also been keeping up their connections with the team to the East of them, and Granite City have been as supportive as they were at Helgin's founding, even donating kit and support for their fresh meat sessions. The Brawlermen also donated Power of Scotland's PudZ for a training session, "Our session with PudZ from Power of Scotland was brilliant – it was our first proper session where we got to practice game tactics and we learned so much!", which also included ICRD, "we had PudZ from POS run a session on walls and pack work which was also tremendously good fun."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, at the south end of the country, Dumfries' Doonhame Derby Dolls made the fortuitious discovery of nearby Carlisle's &lt;a href="http://www.bordercityrollers.com/"&gt;Border City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;, who are newly founded this year. The two leagues have quickly become quite attached, as Doonhame noted: "We only recently discovered that Carlisle had a team on the go through Facebook, one of our girls is from the area and she never even knew haha! This is now the closest team to us! We got in touch and done our own first ever guest coaching with 3 of our girls travelling down to their training night and they couldn't have been more welcoming, they're a great bunch of guys as we expected and they were so pleased to learn and understand where to go from where they'd got to. Georgie and Chloe Holmes helped start is up and have done well starting from scratch. We have kept in touch and they have been along to support us at games in Newcastle and Glasgow, making wee banners and being total fangirls which is amazing (it's usually us fangirling others!). "
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h6&gt;RECRUITMENT AND TRAINING&lt;/h6&gt;
All of the non-bouting leagues have been focussing on the three most important things for any newer league: recruiting skaters, training them to pass mins, and raising money to support all of this.
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, &lt;em&gt;Helgin&lt;/em&gt; held several successful fresh meats this year, recruiting 19 since we &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/23/helgin-roller-derby-scotlands-northernmost-league/"&gt;interviewed them last&lt;/a&gt;, and have also gained some transfers from other leagues "We’ve gained another few regular skaters, including some skaters formerly of Granite City Roller Derby, New Town Roller Girls and Belfast City Rockets, and we’ve now got enough people training on a regular basis to be looking to put a team together". They also have a tremendously organised public training plan, as anyone can see from the regular updates on their Facebook page, "This started back when we were chopping and changing venues a lot, as we were still trying to find permanent training locations, and we needed to keep people informed of where the sessions were. Many people commented that they liked knowing what was coming up, so we just kept it going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We like to be organised, and have a progressive training plan so that we can see the development of our Fresh Meat – sometimes sessions go to plan, sometimes you’ve got an odd number of people there and the ‘paired work’ session plan goes out the window! Slowly but surely we’re working it all out, and we hope to get our next batch of Fresh Meat minimum skills passed much quicker."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They've also been doing quite well at fundraising, having entered multiple grant shortlists, and also "doing rather well with community fundraising, and held another successful pub quiz at the end of August, keeping us afloat for a bit, and we’re looking to put on another at the end of January or beginning of February, to boost funds for 2016."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inverness&lt;/em&gt;, being one of the more established leagues in this article, has been growing a little more slowly, "We've had a few intakes but the struggle to find new members in Inverness is ongoing, we've lowered the age limit to 16 to try grow the team a little, we've got a few new(ish) faces and everyone is coming on leaps and bounds, and we should fingers crossed have them all mins passed just after the new year."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perth's&lt;em&gt; Fair City Rollers&lt;/em&gt; have had an interesting year, given that we reported last year that they were aiming to bout in 2015. Instead, this year has been one of introspection and consolidation. "Over the past year we've redefined ourselves as a team; who we are, what we do and where we're headed.  Our direction has become more bout focused and we've started to work towards becoming an actual bouting team again.
Over the past year we've worked on aligning focus and skills, and recruitment.  We're currently about halfway through our training programme of the new skaters we recruited in September, and are aiming to bout in 2016"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-5372" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/11880588_901492176606579_4883872526247151434_n.jpg?w=300" alt="11880588_901492176606579_4883872526247151434_n" width="300" height="300"&gt; The Wee-County Golden Gauntlet logo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clackmannanshire's &lt;em&gt;Wee Country Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt; have been attempting to retain the momentum from their initial launch (which we interviewed them about &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/29/a-wee-chat-with-wee-county-roller-derby/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), partly by launching their distinctive gauntlet logo,
We really wanted our logo to describe the fight we have for derby, and our community spirit rolled into one. Its our take on the clackmannshire logo of the gauntlet, with 'Look Aboot Ye' as a tag line. It works as a double meaning, having to be aware at all times who and what is around you on track.
There was a real buzz around the team in the beginning, it was great: lots of attention and press coverage. We had a strong initial recruitment and kept a steady flow of interest, with word of mouth travelling fast. It has been a challenge to form a solid basis for the team, but we have a great foundation of members now. Its been a tough year, of trial and error and lots of personal growth. We were overwhelmed by the support and commitment of the members we do have, as they get stuck in and really help to make our team a family.
Looking at how far we've come and comparing it to how far we have to go to allow us to have our debut bout is quite a step, but were confident that we have the determination and the strong mind set to make it happen."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5381" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/11050639_820246781416517_7188774811881300574_n.jpg" alt="11050639_820246781416517_7188774811881300574_n" width="540" height="960"&gt; Coach Graeme Gow keeping a watchful eye on the paceline at Ayrshire Roller Derby (Credit: Sally Wilkes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ayrshire Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt;, meanwhile, have enough mins-passed skaters that they're starting to attend scrims and the like. "ARD have had an excellent year. We were joined by coach Graham Gow of Power of Scotland and Mean City fame. Our team may be small at the moment but it is growing all the time! Our mins passed players are regularly participating in open scrims and learning all they can. We would really like to thank all  the local teams that have helped and supported us this last few months." In addition, ARD have been at a whole host of fundraising and publicity-related engagements, including a stall at their local Christmas Fair. They've also had enthusiastic spectating presence at many bouts this year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, to the south, &lt;em&gt;Doonhame&lt;/em&gt; have been growing strong,
"Recruitment was a challenge to start, with maybe 6-10 people showing up at the start of the year, we then took a break from 'Fresh Meat' open nights and 're-evaluated our training / introduction methods. We then went on to having 2 of our most successful openers in Sept and October with a full house (of 30odd) both nights, and around half of that number dedicating and joining the team! Its the keeping them excited and committed that's the harder bit. We try to encourage everyone to the best of their ability and push those wishing to be pushed, but at a pace that's comfortable with them. We have been very lucky to be able to have a lot of amazing players come along and guest coach for us. To be able to have such a high profile skater like Stefanie Mainey come and guest at our bootcamp in May 2015 was amazing! She was brilliant  and really put us through our paces on the track and giving us some great insights! We love learning new stuff and stretching our mindsets."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5368" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/received_10153711888193956.jpeg" alt="received_10153711888193956" width="600" height="339"&gt; Doonhame's 7 cherry popping skaters at Bristol Roller Derby's event. (Credit: Andy Jardine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Ayrshire, Doonhame have a strong core of mins-passed skaters now, but they've been seeking out public cherry-popper bouts as well as scrims. Most notably, they even managed to appear on film in their first ever appearance (at Bristol Roller Derby's Summer Double Header): "There was 7 of us that popped our cherries in Bristol. It wasn't just any normal cherry popper though, we were filmed by the BBC 'See, hear' programme to promote the abilitly to skate with deaf / hoh players. What a rush! It was so nerve racking, exciting and hundreds of miles away from home, but we did it!
After we got the taste, we actively started to look for cherry poppers, charity games, closed scrimms, anything to let us get out there to play. Its really difficult, frustrating, when you have a handful of players passed skills, gagging to play, but not enough players yet for a full team! Which leads to all of these brilliant events opening up their doors to us, where you learn just how special roller derby is. This has meant us travelling to Edinburgh, Dundee and Newcastle for scrimms and bouts to join other teams. The friendships and camaraderie throughout playing with other teams would be the highlight of travelling, and of course gaining the experience and playing along side some awesome derby gals. "
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h6&gt;PLANS FOR NEXT YEAR&lt;/h6&gt;
We asked each of the leagues about their plans for next year, and it looks like most of them have the same aim in mind: getting on track for their first public bout!
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doonhame&lt;/em&gt;: "All in all I think 2016 is going to be amazing for DDD as we are pushing our girls hard to try and bag a full team line up to finally play as a proper DDD full team. Until then though the girls that have passed will be playing in mixed scrim and bouts when they can and it's great we're always thought of to take part. 2016 will just be Onwards and upwards for DDD. Watch this space!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ayrshire&lt;/em&gt;: "We reckon we will be putting a team together at the beginning of next year and we REALLY cant wait to get stuck into playing!
I feel like it will be next year's [update] that has all the exciting stuff in it!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fair City&lt;/em&gt;: "[We] are hoping to pop our collective team cherry at the start of March 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, within the year of the restructure, we'll be back on track and competing against other teams.  Exciting times for the FCR!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wee County&lt;/em&gt;: "For next year we're hitting training and promotion head on, really pushing ourselves to the limits i know we can achieve. New and improved training programmes will be put in place to fully structurise the fresh meat members, also one for the more advanced skaters.
Were looking to get into the community in a big way, and doing our bit for local charities.
Our goal for 2016 is to integrate roller derby into the Wee County in a big way, so as always, look aboot ye."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Helgin&lt;/em&gt;: "Well, fingers crossed, we get all of our current skaters mins passed in early 2016, and then we’re going on the road to join some boot camps and open scrims to get a bit more experience in game play.  This, along with regular training with ICRD will hopefully have us bout-ready by the end of the year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re planning to hold three more Fresh Meat intakes – probably around February, May and September to keep our skater numbers up, and probably a similar number of fundraisers to keep us going financially. We’re also hoping to get our Business Plan finished over the Festive period (since our training venues are closed and we can’t skate :() and will be able to widen the net of the funds we can apply to, so that we can get scrim vests, more hire kit, more people first aid trained, and even cover our hall hire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve also been in discussions with Moray Sports Centre (a new state-of-the-art sports centre planned to be built on the southern boundary of Elgin) and things are looking hopeful that we may well have a new home in the future – one large enough to host bouts!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inverness&lt;/em&gt;: "We are looking forward to 2016 and having a team ready to start playing after all these years, we will be frequenting Dundee's open scrims with everyone learning to nso's for a couple of turns and then scrimming when mins passed, also we will have a regular session every month with Helgin to keep building on pack skills and game play.  Fingers crossed that later in 2016 Icrd will hit the track as a team!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all goes to the plans above, it's quite possible that next year, there will be no non-bouting leagues roundup, as there'd only be one or two leagues left to cover in it! As always, it's an exciting time with the growth of Scottish derby, and 2016 might see the next big wave of leagues entering the bouting world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>helgin roller derby</category><category>inverness city roller derby</category><category>review of the year</category><category>wee county roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/30/non-bouting-leagues-roundup-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 12:29:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lothian Derby Dolls round up of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/26/lothian-derby-dolls-round-up-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls have been kind enough to send us this update on their year&lt;/em&gt;:
&lt;p&gt;2015 has been a busy year on and off skates for &lt;a href="http://lothianderbydolls.com/"&gt;Lothian Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year the Dolls have been really focusing on progressing our new skaters into the team, building on the skills the experienced skaters already have and being involved in helping the wider roller derby community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dolls are very proud to have 6 skaters bouting in our team who have come through the LDD fresh meat programme this year and one referee passing his refereeing tests to be officiating regularly. With all the excitement and skills of the last fresh meat who graduated in December, we are going to have even more skaters hot on the Dolls’ heels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LDD skated in three public bouts against the Central Belters in May, GCRD ‘B’ team, the Fight Hawks in September and New Town Roller Girls in October. LDD put together the Dolly Mixtures to play against DRG ‘B’ team in September with skaters from the Central Belters, Doonhame Derby Dolls, Voodoo Dollies and Mean City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5314" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/fb_img_1450951138669.jpg" alt="FB_IMG_1450951138669" width="1080" height="720"&gt; LDD taking on Granite City B, the Fight Hawks (Photo: Laura MacDonald)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also had a wonderful year of being out in the derby community more, which has helped us build strong ties with teams such as BCR's Central Belters and Capital City Roller Derby. LDD have been happy to have some co-ed experience with CCRD and enjoy our new found partnership. The Dolls have also been busy this last year taking part individually, guest skating, refereeing, NSO-ing and helping out with other teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our events team have been busy organising all our fundraising events as well as bouts, scrims and meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LDD are always looking to skate on different floors and were delighted to be given the opportunity to skate at Transgression Park, our local skate park. LDD and TP are working on a partnership, so watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LDD were lucky enough to welcome [London Rollergirls + Team England coach and Southern Discomfort skater] Ballistic Whistle for a training session which all our Dolls got so much from, with some finding themselves a little star-struck.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A word from our 2015 Captain &lt;strong&gt;Psycho&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; In 2015, what was your LDD highlight?
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Being nominated as captain for the Doll Stars for 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
 How do you feel about how far LDD has come?
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;The team has improved massively over the years since the start but more so in the last year due to the commitment of the league members.&lt;/p&gt;
 Your personal proudest moment of 2015?
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Seeing 5 of the last fresh meat to go on and play their first game and receiving my award for the most inspirational Doll. I was totally gobsmacked.&lt;/p&gt;
 What are you hopes for 2016?
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;To see the creation of the 2nd LDD team, the Rising Stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
LDD has only been so successful due to the strength and commitment of all the Dolls who are involved in LDD. LDD has had some of our skaters get injured and we have missed them on the track, but because of their commitment we have not missed their presence, especially when they are shouting at us all while coaching or organising social events, so we can all laugh together.
&lt;p&gt;LDD are also excited to welcome two more LDD babies to our team in 2016 and can’t wait to meet them both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LDD have come so far in the last year and we have no plans to slow down in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love and Shoves, Lothian Derby Dolls!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>lothian derby dolls</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/26/lothian-derby-dolls-round-up-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 10:15:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City Brawlermen - A Roundup of 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/31/granite-city-brawlermen-a-roundup-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I had a little chat with the wonderful Orion Packs (aka Edd Chandler) at the Granite City Brawlermen have made this year&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has recruitment for the Brawlermen gone in 2014? There has been quite a few new members, have you had to separate training?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had 2 recruitment sessions in 2014 and are looking to hold our next one in the spring of 2015 (likely some time in April)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite a couple of our members moving away, our membership has almost doubled since our first intake all those months ago!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We train for 2 hours on a Sunday at the moment. Skaters from other leagues are welcome (pay to skate rates would apply), all we ask is that they contact us in advance so that our coaches can have the final say.  For now, all levels of skater attend this session and we cover as much as we can either as a whole or in separate groups&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/brawlermen.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4484 size-full" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/brawlermen.jpg" alt="brawlermen" width="604" height="731"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Granite City Brawlermen official logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen is quite far away from other men's leagues, how much opportunity have you had to scrimmage?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of our skaters have been to Dundee for their open scrims and we'd like to thank the folks at DRG for hosting and inviting us down.  Some have also visited Grangemouth on a couple of occasions to take part in the open Power of Scotland training sessions and 2 took part in the Team Scotland bootcamp prior to the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few of us have been lucky enough to take part in coed scrims with Granite City Roller Girls.  The girls know that scrimmaging opportunities for us are limited so they invited our mins passed skaters along.  In return, we brought as many members as possible with us to support with NSO'ing etc.  We can't thank GCRG enough for all their support so far. The experience gained by taking part in those sessions is invaluable to our progress as a league&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about the Brawlermen's plans for 2015, so many people are eager to hear if you have any bouts planned&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don't have any bout plans for 2015 as our main aim is getting our current crop through their minimums and into scrimmages if possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our main focus is getting our skaters through their minimum skills assessments and scrimmaging whenever/wherever they can.  We also want to grow awareness of roller derby as a whole in the north east AND we will be helping with the organisation of the new Scottish Men's Roller Derby League with the overall aim being to eventually take part!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're always looking for new ways to grow and progress so although you may not see us on track, we can guarantee that 2015 will be another year of positive growth and development for GCB.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/31/granite-city-brawlermen-a-roundup-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:00:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City Roller Girls - A Roundup of 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/30/granite-city-roller-girls-a-roundup-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I transferred to Granite City Rollergirls in February 2014 and have been lucky enough to spend a fun filled (almost) year with the league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a busy year for GCRG! We have had a few changes to the league, some friends left for pastures new, some returned and we got some amazingly talented new teammates and referees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been many promotion opportunities for us including the Discover Aberdeen dolphins and live demonstrations in the Bon Accord Centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/gcrg.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4487" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/gcrg.png" alt="Granite City Roller Girls  official logo" width="335" height="151"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Granite City Roller Girls official logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our final game of 2014 against Bedforshire's Rebellion Roller Derby was a fantastic game to watch. The team really pulled together and used every skill that they had been working on and ended our bouting year on a high with a win of 184 to 155.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the whole league will agree that one of our highlights of 2014 was cheering our wee hearts out for Jill Stephen (Fight Cub), Jill Simpson (Rock n Riot), and Carolyn Mackenzie (Clinically Wasted) when they represented GCRG in Team Scotland at the Blood and Thunder Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended 2014 with an annual Skateroonie where fights, refs and newbies got together to play games, eat food and more importantly, play tug of war (the girls took victory ). This was followed a few days later with a league night out to end 2014 appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My own highlight for 2014 was playing my debut game as a Northern Fight against Hull. There was a great atmosphere and I was super proud to represent the Fights for the first time. Any occasion where we get together whether to skate or just have a nice time is always a highlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10571952_10154540553565160_2015222088721681186_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4479" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10571952_10154540553565160_2015222088721681186_o.jpg" alt="Photo credit: Caroline Allison" width="614" height="461"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photo credit: Caroline Allison&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a mentor for our fresh meat I have the luxury of seeing our newbies turn from timid wee lambs into confident team mates. The structure of fresh meat training has changed so you can really see the progress from one week to the next. I'm so excited to see what the future holds for our newbs! They will be taking part in their first team scrimmage in January and I for one will be beaming with pride...and just a wee warning that I shall probably cry proud little tears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year promises to be an exciting whirlwind for GCRG as we will be taking part in British Championships Heartland series! Some of our eagle eyed readers may have seem the recent announcement of GCRG's B team. There is so much to come and I'm excited!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I spoke to GCRG's captain for 2015, Mental, about what the roller derby community can expect from GCRG next year;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"From the start of 2015 we have entered the British Championships, these are very exciting times for GCRG. For me personally I've got big boots to fill but I believe if you put in 100% you get 100%. I can see a more focussed, determined and stronger team for 2015"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10460596_10203580393204655_5761820161661248642_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4480 size-full" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10460596_10203580393204655_5761820161661248642_o.jpg" alt="Photo credit : Andy Morris" width="614" height="410"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Photo credit: Andy Morris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/30/granite-city-roller-girls-a-roundup-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow Roller Derby:  Round-Up of 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/29/glasgow-roller-derby-round-up-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>paingrrl666</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img id="featured-image" class=" aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/grd-logo.jpg?w=300" alt="Featured image" width="166" height="166"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby have had quite possibly our busiest year to date, and are already working hard on plans to make 2015 even better if possible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;2014 saw GRD firmly establish our C team, the Cannie Gingers, and fully integrate them into Scottish Roller Derby with 4 amazing bouts spread throughout the year.   Our B Team, the Maiden Grrders, trained hard, culminating in a super win against London’s Batter C Power.  And our super A Team, the Irn Bruisers, took America by storm at Spring Roll, as well as capturing home wins against Middlesborough and Dublin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img id="featured-image" class=" aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/maidens.jpg?w=300" alt="Featured image"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;Our 4 home teams battled throughout the year, culminating in the Bad Omens recapturing the winners trophy for Home Team Season 2014.  And many of our skaters represented at mixed games and tournaments across the UK.  This included 8 of our skaters playing for Vagine Regime UK throughout the year; 9 of our skaters representing their home countries at the World Cup in Dallas; as well as skaters representing at Sur5al, Skate of Ages and various other mixed charity games.  We love the enthusiasm and passion our skaters demonstrate for roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img id="featured-image" class=" aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/world-cup.jpg?w=300" alt="Featured image"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;Our fundraising and events teams have been hard at work raising funds and events to allow GRD to do what we do best.  Successes included our awesome GoFundMe t-shirt campaign, with fantastic custom artwork by Gary Erskine.  There was also an American-themed fundraising bout, which saw our mini-bruisers defeat mini-America.  Lots of good fun!  And none of this could be possible without our wonderful PR committee, who spread the good word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;Our skaters have also been hard at work off track, with some amazing league accomplishments.  Mistress Malicious, co-founder of Glasgow Roller Derby and UKRDA, organised the first UK-ROC in October 2014.  This was a huge success, bringing together skaters from across the UK to attend workshops and learn from the most experienced skaters in the world about roller derby infrastructure.  2 of our skaters were also involved in the UKRDA’s development of a fully inclusive Transgender Policy and Guidance, which has been voted in as operational for every member league in the UK.  And our WFTDA reps have been hard at work, with tireless Bruisers captain and WFTDA rep Rogue Runner assisting in strategic development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;What next for GRD?  We plan to train even harder, and play even harder.  Each of our travel teams has their own goals in sight, and as a league we plan to get even stronger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;We will be kicking the year off with a fantastically diverse fundraising bout on Sat 31&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; Jan at the Arc, showcasing a mixed Glasgow team playing against the highly skilled Vagine Regime UK.  The bout will be followed by a drag party, where everyone is encouraged to leave the confines of socially constructed gender behind and just have a jolly good time exploring gender expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;Our Bruisers will be competing in Tier 1 of the British Championships, showcasing UK derby at its best.  Our Maiden Grrders will be hosting a B-level Scottish tournament, and our Cannie Gingers will be appearing in the Highland Rampage tournament.  Invites are flooding in for each of our teams to skate, and our games schedule is looking very exciting!  We shall also be announcing new team captains for each team, as well as looking to optimise on our events schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img id="featured-image" class=" aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/bruisers.jpg?w=300" alt="Featured image"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;If this sounds like something you want to get in on, then Glasgow Roller Derby are holding a new intake on Sunday, January 11&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; 2015 – and we would love to see you there! If you are interested in signing up and changing your life, sign up at recruiting@glasgowrollerderby.com. Find out more on our &lt;a title="GRD Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/645457582240839/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 in review</category><category>an interview with...</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/29/glasgow-roller-derby-round-up-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 11:56:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls: Roundup of 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/28/dundee-roller-girls-roundup-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We caught up with &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee&lt;/a&gt;'s Julia "Crown Julez" Wright to get the story of the league's 2014:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/735097_492237780841642_237571758_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4501" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/735097_492237780841642_237571758_n.jpg?w=300" alt="Dundee Roller Girls logo." width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Dundee Roller Girls logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girls' Silvery Tayzers started the year with their first game against old rivals Granite City Roller Girls Northern Fights in Aberdeen. The Tayzers had never beaten GCRG in their previous games but after an almighty comeback by GCRG in the second half the Tayzers finally came out winners with a 182 – 83 victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What followed was a hectic season with the Tayzers playing more games both home and away than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An away win against Newcastle’s Whippin Hinnies (131 -163), was closely followed by home defeat to Hulls Angels Roller Dames in the most dramatic of overtime jam finishes. Furness Firecrackers were the next team to make the trip to Dundee and were defeated 178 – 157 in a thrilling match-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May saw one of the most exciting developments in DRG history, with the launch of our Home Teams Season. Assisted by the Big Lottery Fund, DRG were awarded £2000 to develop the Home Teams brand. Sticking close to Dundee’s Jute, Jam and Journalism history, three teams were created; The Jutes of Hazzard, Jammin’ Dodgers and the Press Gangsters. After a summer season of Home Teams games, the Jutes and Press Gangsters fought it out for the trophy with the Press Gangsters triumphing in the final 163 - 108.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10628596_10100312218540564_7362283630468818259_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-4500" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10628596_10100312218540564_7362283630468818259_n.jpg?w=614" alt="Dundee's Rising Stars, post Bairn City bout (Photo: Laura MacDonald)" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Dundee's Rising Stars, post Bairn City bout (Photo: Laura MacDonald)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late summer also saw the first game for DRG’s B team with the Rising Stars defeating Durham Roller Derby by a single point in nail-biting game (172 – 171). The Silvery Tayzers were also in action on this double-header day being defeated by a hard-hitting Roller Derby Leicester team (107 – 228).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second double header pitted the Rising Stars against Team White and the Tayzers playing Halifax’s Bruising Banditas, with both teams securing victories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The autumn began with the Tayzers playing two away games to FVRG and their furthest away trip to Swansea. Both games ended in defeat for the Tayzers but they left with a great deal of experience gained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tayzers final game of the season was another against an old rival; Glasgow Roller Derby’s Maiden Grrders, a team the Tayzers had yet to record a win against. After a brilliant match-up between the two teams, the Tayzers managed to pull off a memorable victory defeating the Maidens 181 -143.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;November held the final games for the Rising Stars who were trying to maintain their 100% record in their debut season. Two victories against Voodoo Roller Dollies and Bairn City’s Central Belters saw the Rising Stars achieve this record and with it brought the end of a memorable season for DRG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five of DRG headed off to Dallas in December for the Blood and Thunder Roller Derby World Cup in Dallas, Texas. Representing the league were; Milky (Team Scotland Skater), Jill Antonic (Team Scotland Manager), Righteous Oxide (member of referee crew), Crazily InSanne (Team Netherlands Skater) and Twiggy Ramirez (Volunteer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2014 was a fantastic season for DRG with some tense victories, heart-breaking losses and masses of experience gained. With the development of the British Championships, DRG are looking forward to 2015 with a positive outlook and great expectations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 in review</category><category>articles</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/28/dundee-roller-girls-roundup-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 09:33:37 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>