<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about roller derby world cup 2011)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/roller-derby-world-cup-2011.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 08:59:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>An Interview With... outgoing Team England Coach, Ballistic Whistle!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/10/an-interview-with-outgoing-team-england-coach-ballistic-whistle/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of people were surprised to hear that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamenglandrollerderby/"&gt;Team England Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s Ballistic Whistle announce that he did not intend to reapply for the role in the current round of recruitment. (The applications for the Team England (Women's) coaching and management roles are currently being voted on.) Considering his contributions to Roller Derby, both in the National teams, and also ongoing with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://londonrollergirls.com/"&gt;London Rollergirls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.southerndiscomfort.co.uk/"&gt;Southern Discomfort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, we thought it was a good idea to catch up with him and talk about, well, him.
(This interview is also undertaken in collaboration with the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UK Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, as part of our National Teams series.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/10/an-interview-with-outgoing-team-england-coach-ballistic-whistle/9012365607_0dd177bdf1_k/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-7241"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-7241" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/9012365607_0dd177bdf1_k.jpg?w=700" alt="Ballistic Whistle (London Rollergirls v Rat City) (Photo: Eric Von Flickr)" width="700" height="467"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Ballistic Whistle (London Rollergirls v Rat City) (Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/31756530@N08/9012365607"&gt;Steve Messerer&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Despite the wide range of your involvement in Roller Derby, you're probably best known as the Coach and Bench Manager of London Roller Girls, who pretty much were the vanguard of Europe's entry into the top levels of Roller Derby. Did you feel responsible, in a way, for representing the UK or Europe in the early days of LRG going across to the States (and is it more of a relief that other teams are now increasingly high level)?&lt;/strong&gt;
I don't feel that was ever a specific goal or aim of ours. From a really early stage we had aspirations of travelling to the States to play high level derby. That benchmark over the years has continued to be pushed on and on to test how far we can go. Through our first tour of the States, and the first visit of American teams to our shores it was quite evident just how much support we were receiving from the UK and Europe. Feeling that during our Stateside trips has always been amazing for us and serves as quite an emotional motivator when away from home. If we have had an impact on how enthusiastic other players and teams are for playing the sport then we've definitely achieved one of our aims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Literally everyone we've spoken to before this interview has mentioned specifically that you're a nice guy (and you parodied this in your appearance in the LRG Fort Wayne's World promo videos [which sadly seem to have mostly disappeared from the internet]). Do you think this surprises people?&lt;/strong&gt;
Haha, that's nice of you to say. I guess I try my best not to irk people on purpose, but I definitely have my foibles and personality clashes just like anyone else. I guess what I find most interesting is how people will formulate an idea of you without ever having met you, purely by how they would expect a person in my position to be. I'll often meet someone for the first time and there will be a period of trying to balance out the shockwaves in our interactions as a result of how they expect me to behave. I'd really love to not have to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As well as coaching and bench managing, you also find the time to play on track, with Southern Discomfort (as well as another signing we'll get to next…). How does your time on track contribute to your coaching decisions (and which would you rather be known as: a great coach, or a great skater)?&lt;/strong&gt;
I took some time off during the 2015 season to try and rehabilitate a back injury. It was during this season that there was a major swing towards formation defense. I realised after a number of months that I was lacking empathy for the difficulty our players had working against this formation. Some of the minor adjustments I was asking our players to make, were actually majorly difficult. Getting back into playing has helped me incredibly to understand what is possible and where the difficulties lie in the modern game. I also get the opportunity to jump in with Brawling from time to time, which I find incredibly helpful to understand what it feels like being inside of the on track action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I roll all of these experiences into my coaching; I guess that answers your parenthesised question. I have no doubt that I love coaching more than playing. I feel like seeing my friends achieve amazing things is much more rewarding for me than achieving them myself. The great thing about fighting to see your team-mates reach their goals, is that you generally achieve yours as a result!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And you recently made the roster for the Team Australia (&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/WizardsofAusDerby/"&gt;Wizards of Aus&lt;/a&gt;) who will be competing at the &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; in Calgary. How did you make the decision to represent your birth nation in the World Cup, and how does it feel to be on the team?&lt;/strong&gt;
Um, actually, it's not my birth nation. I was born in Denmark to a Danish father and Belgian mother. I arrived in Australia on my 2nd birthday and remained there until age 25. But, if you were to ask me what I considered my nationality it would be Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the first World Cup, I had the amazing opportunity to participate with so many of my great derby friends for Team England. Being a part of that team was a fantastic experience, but it wasn't until I was selected for the Australia team that I truly understood what the other players on that English team felt during that first World Cup. In hindsight, I felt incredibly guilty for taking that feeling from someone during the first World Cup, and I feel that is the special thing about that event. Playing for your nation is something that can call on something deeper. At all World Cups I have attended, both male and female, hearing the Australian national anthem has been a...tricky...moment for me emotionally. At this next World Cup, I am going to be so happy to be able to belt out the anthem without any mixed feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You've been Team England Coach for two World Cups, and London Roller Girls coach for 5 years. While both positions are top-level coaching positions, are there more differences than might be apparent?&lt;/strong&gt;
Absolutely. There's no substitute for working with the same team week in week out. You can definitely deliver the most effective change in strategy and refine what you do on track on multiple occasions over a shorter period of time. With both teams you are dealing with a group of incredibly talented skaters, but with Team England it was much more of a situation of building cohesion. Nailing down defaults and making sure, as much as possible, everyone is on the same page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the England team, there was the tricky balance of trying not to be just Brawling + friends, but really appreciate that there are different ways to play. World Cups comprise a number of nations from the extreme fledgling derby countries to the most seasoned. We had always set our sights on taking on the most seasoned. Hopefully in coming World Cup cycles, there will be more English players in other teams who have more of that high-level derby play and will be ready to take on the best countries in the world. With limited training sessions, it becomes a lot more sink or swim when put into that intensely hot cauldron of competition, and so it is all about looking for the players who can take that pressure and really excel. Without the experience of that level, it comes so much more down to personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recently, you announced that you would not be applying for the role of Team England Head Coach this time around. Can we talk a bit about your reasons for this, and your feelings about the decision?&lt;/strong&gt;
The 2015 season was one that definitely took a toll on me. Brawling, at the beginning of the season, had set ourselves what we thought was the ultimate goal (incidentally, we have since understood that the Hydra is not the ultimate goal). Having an amazing season and falling short at the critical time definitely hit me with my first proper feeling of derby burnout in the 9 1/2 years I've been in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we've set our sights even higher than the goals we set last year and I understand what that is going to take from me on a personal level. I also feel that this time around, we are blessed with a number of candidates that could really use this as a springboard to get that experience of that new level. I obviously have mixed feelings about it. Watching England at the World Cup is going to be tough as I'll be wanting the best for all my friends on that team, but will have zero input on helping them achieve that. I'll be waving the 3 Lions flag regardless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, what have been the high and low points in your 6 years as TE Head Coach?&lt;/strong&gt;
Again, it's only 5 years really as the lead up to that first World Cup happened in the same year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lows have always been any time we needed to make some kind of cut to the squad, whether that be to the charter that would go to an event or the roster of 14 that would play. I've been tasked with making these decisions countless times during my life as a coach, but it never gets easy telling talented players that they aren't going to have the opportunity, this time, to do what they love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As bad as those moments are, they are eclipsed by the highs, and I feel like one of the biggest highs was our final against the USA at the 2014 World Cup. Prior to the game I had pored over and re-written my pre-game speech so many times I thought I had written the perfect speech. I got in there and saw all of those players looking at me to hear the message I had for them at that point. Prior to a game where getting all of the 1 percenters right mattered. I threw everything I had written out the window and just spoke from the heart. Anyone in that room will be able to tell you that the message was pretty simple. Regardless of its simplicity, I feel like it resonated with the players, and really struck a chord. In spite of the result, it was one of those games where we just felt like we were playing on point, executing our strategies so well. It all felt so streamlined and precise, against potentially the toughest group of individual skaters you could ever face on track. For it to culminate in one of my derby idols - Kamikaze Kitten - taking us over the 100 point mark in the final jam, I couldn't have asked for a better written story. For me, that game illustrated what Roller Derby (and playing team sport for that matter) is truly all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Given your experience in the role, do you have any advice to pass on to your successor as Head Coach?&lt;/strong&gt;
I feel like there are a lot of coaches out there who work with a top down decision making structure. The coach will dictate the direction and decisions the team makes, sometimes opening the floor to the players for input. When working with some of the best players to ever play the sport, it would be remiss of any coach not to leverage that knowledge and experience. Every single player that played for Team England has a wealth of experience, has an incredibly active derby brain. It's so important to keep those brains ticking over and thinking at a high level, rather than trying to stifle them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with both Brawling and England has shown me that when you are dealing with these incredibly talented groups of players, you are just one equally important part of the team, rather than the single decision making point. Having said that, there definitely comes a point whereby the players need to focus on playing and the decisions need to be directed. The closer to game time this is, the more important it becomes for the coach to take responsibility for decision making. So, rather than a top down, triangle type shape, I think of it more of an hourglass decision making shape. The active brains in the team will feed their ideas into the team's leadership or management, and the leadership with all of this great information will compile it and disseminate a directed decision to the team to execute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, coaching a high level national team at a World Cup is something that not many people the world over will ever be able to say they did with their life. It's exhilarating, and the more you put into it, the greater the reward will be. Don't fuck it up!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team england roller derby</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/10/an-interview-with-outgoing-team-england-coach-ballistic-whistle/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 09:16:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Scotland Tryouts, a Reminder</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/04/team-scotland-tryouts-a-reminder/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Team Scotland, the Women's National Team, is up and running and ready for skaters to try out to represent their country at the 2014 World Cup in Dallas, Texas (and potentially other events).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/08/ts-logo.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/08/ts-logo.gif?w=614" alt="TS-Logo" width="614" height="652" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-89"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to try out, there are two sessions being held:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session 1&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sunday 24th November&lt;/em&gt; – Grangemouth Sports Complex, Abbots Road, Grangemouth, FK3 8JB – &lt;strong&gt;13:00 – 16:30&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session 2&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Saturday 7th December&lt;/em&gt; – Dundee International Sports Complex, Mains Loan, Dundee, DD4 7AA – &lt;strong&gt;13:00 -16:00&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[googlemaps https://maps.google.co.uk/maps/ms?msa=0&amp;amp;msid=201904390601748355049.0004ea576c1ab0811ec82&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=56.243952,-3.3402&amp;amp;spn=0.464629,0.762546&amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;output=embed&amp;amp;w=425&amp;amp;h=350]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are unable to attend either session, then tryout by video submission will be possible. Contact Team Scotland via &lt;a href="mailto:teamscotlandrd@gmail.com"&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or their &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Team-Scotland-Roller-Derby/235701999922927"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; to arrange this.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tryouts will be part drills part scrimmage and will be filmed for selection purposes. Those attending are asked to bring both a black and white scrim shirt, without league/team logos on it. This is a UKRDA guideline on tryout kit, to ensure impartiality on behalf of the selectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eligibility for tryouts is dependant on possession of a British Passport. You are eligible to try out for Team Scotland in particular if you, or at least one parent or grandparent, were born in Scotland, or you are a current resident in Scotland with 4 or more years' residency. There are no requirements on membership of particular teams. Full details are available here: &lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk/?p=567"&gt;http://ukrda.org.uk/?p=567&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>tryouts</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/04/team-scotland-tryouts-a-reminder/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 10:44:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Applications for Team Scotland (and Team Wales) Coaching reopened!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/07/25/applications-for-team-scotland-and-team-wales-coaching-reopened/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This morning, UKRDA announced that they were reopening applications for several of the National Team Coaching positions. If you think you can coach Team Scotland (or Team Wales) to success in the 2014 World Cup, and other endeavours, then apply before the 31st of August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full press release is reproduced below, with all the information and links you need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applications for Scotland &amp;amp; Wales National Team Coaching Positions OPEN until 31 August 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UKRDA are pleased to announce we are re-opening applications for various positions in the Scotland and Wales Women’s Coaching Teams. UKRDA is currently processing Round 1 of applications which closed on 30 July, however we did not receive any applicants for the following positions and so are proceeding with Round 2 and accepting new applications for all of the following positions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· Team Scotland Head Coach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· Scotland Line-up Manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· Wales Head Coach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· Wales Assistant Coach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· Wales Line-up Manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month Blood &amp;amp; Thunder announced that the second Roller Derby World Cup is to be held in Dallas, Texas in December 2014. At UKRDA we are very excited about being appointed by BRSF to help get the official UK National teams up &amp;amp; running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step in making this happen is to appoint a Coaching Committee for each team. UKRDA will then work collaboratively with Coaching Committee’s to help develop and run fair &amp;amp; transparent skater try outs and get team coaching sessions up and running. Although the day-to-day running of the teams will be in the hands of the Coaching Committees and skaters themselves, UKRDA will be on hand at every turn to offer support, guidance and oversight ensuring everything is running fairly and according to plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re looking for enthusiastic, committed and passionate people to join the Coaching Committee’s and work with us to ensure Team England, Team Scotland and Team Wales are the best they can be; to represent UK Roller Derby in style next December. Applicants' need a lot of drive, experience, knowledge of cutting edge roller derby, and the leadership &amp;amp; communication skills to coach your team to success.
Come on UK Roller Derby... let’s smash last time’s results!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Round 2 will be open for applications between 22 July 2013 – 30 August 2013. Applicants need to return the application form linked below along with three letters of recommendation. Letters of recommendation can be from skaters/coaches &amp;amp; leagues and must be from least two separate league sources. Applicants for coaching positions can be any nationality and be affiliated to any team, UKRDA members or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply for one of these positions, please fill in this application form: &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/n4yefkr41018r0k/National%20Team%20Coaching%20Application.docx"&gt;https://www.dropbox.com/s/n4yefkr41018r0k/National%20Team%20Coaching%20Application.docx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For details on the selection procedure for National Team Coaches please see: &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/6qp1c5ar4tr0q2j/UK%20National%20Roller%20Derby%20Squads%20-%20Selection%20Process%20v1.0.pdf"&gt;https://www.dropbox.com/s/6qp1c5ar4tr0q2j/UK%20National%20Roller%20Derby%20Squads%20-%20Selection%20Process%20v1.0.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For details on the Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup see: http://rollerderbyworldcup.com/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The selection timelines are detailed below:
22 Jul - Round 2 applications open&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;31 Aug- Deadline for applications&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 Sept- Initial sift complete &amp;amp; invitation to submit statement of intent to all successful applicants&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23 Sept- Deadline for statements of intent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29 Sept- Deadline for UKRDA member vote for successful applicants&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;30 Sept- Deadline for responding to all applicants&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 Oct- Press Release announcing appointment of National Team Coaches&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><category>team scotland</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/07/25/applications-for-team-scotland-and-team-wales-coaching-reopened/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 10:23:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A chat with Brim Stone</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/02/28/a-chat-with-brim-stone/</link><dc:creator>pandacatkaty</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/02/img2012-x22.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-912" title="IMG2012-X2" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/02/img2012-x22.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="278"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was given the assignment to speak to Brim Stone I was so excited. But I knew I had to suppress my inner fangirl to take care of the job at hand. However, I couldn't help but gush a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brim, known to her intimates as Kayla Wilkins, skated as part of Team Canada during the 2011 World Cup and also skates for CN Power, the Toronto Roller Derby travel team, and Gore-Gore Rollergirls, Toronto's home team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just starting her sixth year in derby, Brim admitted that she had "never understood the appeal of team sports" before giving roller derby a chance, although she did take part in horseback riding when she was younger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On track, her favoured position is Pivot, and aside from concussion, she has managed to avoid any serious injuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asking someone who has come so far and achieved so much for a list of their derby idols might seem a bit ridiculous, but everyone looks up to someone and Brim was no exception. "Bonnie Thunders and Joy Collision are at the top of my list right now, but I have so many!  There are so many great skaters out there."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making the cut for Team Canada was no easy task. Brim explained that multiple tryouts were held across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"There was a fitness component (push ups, sit ups, agility test, beep test, etc.), a derby skills component, and a mark given for scrimmaging.  Coach Pauly made a long-list at each tryout, and then chose a team of 20 from that list."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After surviving the gruelling "audition" process, Brim said she was "shocked" to make the team. "I wanted to make the team so badly, and I was so honoured to be put on the roster to represent my country."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She added: "It [making Team Canada] wasn't always a goal - I wasn't very competitive when I started derby - so it was something that developed over time.  I had thought about what an amazing opportunity that would be before the World Cup though, so when it became a possibility I wanted to put everything I had into the tryouts."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And once at the World Cup, Brim Stone was keen to get stuck in, although she didn't get to play against everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I wanted to play against all of the teams!  I really didn't have a lot of knowledge of what the other teams would be like, so I was looking forward to that challenge.  I have to admit that I did really want to play against the USA, but I wasn't chosen for that particular roster.  That was ok though, in a team sport the team always has to come first to be successful, and sometimes the best thing you can do as a player is to be the best cheerleader for your team!  And now I've got a better idea of what skills I need to work on to be a better skater in the future."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite her preference for playing Pivot, Brim found herself on track jamming a lot during the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"So, my personal best moment was a jamming moment for sure - I took hip off of my team mate Windigo's shirt, and swung into the inside track, on one leg, and managed to save it and skate out of the front of the pack!  It was so fun!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And cheering her all the way into the final was her support system, which included her parents, who travelled from their home two and a half hours north of Toronto, an aunt and uncle who flew in from Alberta, Brim's derby-playing partner, and some of her team-mates from Toronto Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what did Brim think that first time she heard the Canadian national anthem played?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"It was great - after 5 years of playing derby, I now associate the national anthem with 'go' time!  It was especially important hearing it at an international event."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the World Cup, Brim left with a lot of lessons learned, but cites one as the top of the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The most significant was the importance of bringing the international derby community together in one place.  Incredible!  Every country can learn so much from Team USA - how they operate on and off the track - and I think that will push us all to move the sport forward much faster."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the competition wasn't just all business, and Brim shared her favourite part of the experience, off-skates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"For me it was all of the support and encouragement I received from my ToRD league mates.  That was what was driving me to do the best that I could do on the track because I wanted to make them proud."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Brim told me when I asked if she was aiming for total victory at the next World Cup: "Iam always aiming for total victory!!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photo used with kind permission of Sean Murphy. For more of his images, visit his website at &lt;a href="http://www.womenofderby.com"&gt;www.womenofderby.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>brim stone</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><category>team canada</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/02/28/a-chat-with-brim-stone/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 21:15:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Interview With Lily Lethal</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/02/24/an-interview-with-lily-lethal/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/02/scotland-usa-23.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/02/scotland-usa-23.jpg" alt="" title="Scotland-USA-23" width="614" height="421" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-888"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photograph by&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://boutday.com/"&gt;Dave McAleavy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Scottish Roller Derby blog presents an interview with one of Team Scotland's Co-Captains,Lily Lethal of Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does it feel to have been chosen as Co Captain of your national squad at the first Roller Derby World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being selected to play for my National team was really enough of a personal achievement to be honest. If I hadn't been selected as co Captain then that would have been fine,but I didn't take the role on half heartedly. When Crazylegs from Auld Reekie was up for the other Co Captain position, it kind of put me at ease. Despite being in different leagues, we know each other well and my previous experiences with her have always been positive ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your World Cup highlights,both personally and for the team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose on of the highlights for the team was beating Argentina and Brazil in the same day! Knuckles our bench manager said, "now that wouldn't ever happen in football". The team relished the chance to play against most of our Derby heroes in Team America and skating past and seeing Scotch Corner and all our fans that had travelled was fantastic support. The free lasagna and tampons were great too! as was the general atmosphere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you think that the team's performance reflects the 11th place position?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think, that in true Scottish style, we got a difficult first group. The teams were seeded on point differential so unfortunately that put us with Australia in our first seeded bout. They ended up being fourth overall, it was a difficult game and it was our third of the day. If we had been selected in a different group, things may have been different but we were happy with 11th Place. I think New Zealand came 8th and they only beat us by 13 points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How difficult was it for you and your Co-Captain,Crazylegs,to select teams for the opponents you faced during the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team selection was hard. it's hard enough having to do it once or twice a month but 6 times in 36 hours! In between that we had to deliver both disappointing and good news to our skaters with regards to whether they were skating or not. It's human nature to be disappointed with non-selection for whatever reason but in this instance, you didn't really have time to dwell or get over it! Then, we had line ups to write and strategy to discuss...it was a relentless week of hard work, but we both came away from this experience knowing that we did pick the right teams for the bouts we played. In future events like this, i would probably consider only taking 16 skaters instead of the 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Was being Co-Captain what you expected?..and will you put yourself up for re-election when the time comes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think that being Captain was exactly what i expected. It was hard work and i don't think that i would put myself up for reselection. I think it's a role that needs to be taken up by someone with a lot of Captaining and Derby life experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hindsight is a wonderful thing,is there anything more Team Scotland could have done to prepare for the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This job would have been easier if the team had the time for more practices and bouts together. This is why i feel the team should reselect skaters and Captains as soon as our term is over in march and regularly practice. To be a good Captain, i think you need a lot of respect and trust from your team it's hard to get that when you skate for a different league and are usually seen as the opposition. This needs to be worked on regularly and practice is the only way to do it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you take from your own experience of the World Cup to improve as a skater and what lessons can be learned for the team as a whole?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all came back with our own individual goals on how we can improve ourselves and this no doubt will be passed on to our individual leagues. Roller Derby is progressing at such a fast rate that things are changing constantly and you have to be in the loop .You have to constantly evolve or you get left behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With the European Cup cancelled, are there any other international bouting plans?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Scotland had hoped to play Team Ireland in March but it doesn't look like this is happening now. I don't know if any other national teams are free on the 17th March? but with the Euro cup cancelled, there are no plans at yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Roller Girls have a busy season with upcoming bouts against Berlin,Stockholm and Paris.What else are the Glasgow Roller Girls up to this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as for Glasgow Roller Derby as we are now known......well....watch this space!
We have a BIG year ahead of us! changes all round. We as a league are heavily focused on being a constantly evolving sport! The correct image that allows us to be taken seriously as athletes is so important! We have gone through a rough patch and lost and gained some fantastic skaters. It takes time to gel as a team and this is now happening at an alarming rate! Glasgow Roller Derby are going to be a force to be reckoned with this year! We hope that our European Games will help to spread the word and with our own tournament taking place in August, it would be the icing on the cake for us to come out top and with our full WFTDA membership around the corner?...
Onwards and upwards....
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>grd</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><category>team scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/02/24/an-interview-with-lily-lethal/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:04:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Scotland MVP-Marla Mayhem</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/01/10/team-scotland-mvp-marla-mayhem/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is guest post from Bryan McWilliam aka Flyin’ Bryan Killman,Bryan is the manager of&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.torontorollerderby.com/chicksahoy.php"&gt;Chicks Ahoy!&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;of Toronto Roller Derby and a freelance journalist from Toronto. He has covered roller derby for&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.gearupforsports.com/"&gt;Gear Up For Sports&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;and his writing portfolio can be viewed at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://bryanmcwilliam.com/"&gt;Bryan McWilliam.com&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;Last December, Blood and Thunder Magazine hosted the first-ever Roller Derby World Cup, in conjunction with Toronto Roller Derby at The Bunker in Toronto, Canada. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tournament had several exciting moments, from the overall dominance by USA, to host country Canada playing to a silver medal.  The event also featured a bout where 500 points was scored by one team and the rare appearance of a “ghost jam,” which occurred during the Ireland/Finland bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Scotland added some astounding moments of their own into the mix, having played one of the hardest hitting bouts of the weekend against New Zealand, adding their rendition of “Flower of Scotland” to the opening ceremony and scoring a thirty point jam of their own, courtesy of jammer Marshall Lawless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, what could arguably have been the most exciting moment of the tournament came upon its conclusion. A most valuable player award was handed out to one member of each team for their outstanding performance over the course of the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An impressive list of skaters from around the world such as Iron Wench for Canada, Francey Pants for France, Swede Hurt for Sweden, Shortstop for Australia and Joy Collision for USA earned the honour for their teams. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Lisa Donati a.k.a Marla Mayhem, a member of Team Scotland who also plays for Glasgow Roller Girls, was announced as the MVP for her nation she had a look of wonder on her face when she ran up to accept her award and pose with the other MVP’s for the press photos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps Marla was surprised by the announcement, but with the kind of tournament she had against some of the top skaters in the world, the award should have been expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marla showed no fear from the jammer position as she fought through tough packs and took bodily damage over the course of the three days. She scored a large majority of her team’s points along with fellow jammers Lawless, Blazin Phoenix and Clinically Wasted and the tournament decided that her effort and “never say die” attitude was worthy of the MVP honour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/marla-3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/marla-3.jpg" alt="" title="Marla 3" width="614" height="470" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-760"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting back from the World Cup, getting over the loss of her voice, working through a mountain of work from her two businesses and spending time with her two pre-schoolers she managed to answer some questions for Scottish Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bryan Mcwilliam&lt;/strong&gt;:  How did it feel playing in the first ever World Cup?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marla Mayhem&lt;/strong&gt;: A great honour and amazing experience. I feel hugely inspired to do better having skated with the world’s greatest skaters, especially so many in a short space of time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BM&lt;/strong&gt;: Did you enjoy Toronto? How do you think Blood and Thunder and Toronto Roller Derby did hosting the event? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MM&lt;/strong&gt;: Toronto was great. I’m a fan of cities built on a grid system; it’s clean and from what I experienced, most efficient. Fortunately, I managed to squeeze in some sights too, once I recovered from our post cup celebrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blood and Thunder have got off to a great start laying the foundations for future World Cup events. The tournament ran to schedule, B&amp;amp;T were great hosts, always available, &amp;amp; willing to help. Having the opportunity to get injuries dealt with on site with Dr Rick was a godsend and definitely a requisite for all future tournaments. I met some amazing people and hope I have the opportunity and good health to be up for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BM&lt;/strong&gt;: What were some of your personal in-game highlights? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MM&lt;/strong&gt;: Well, skating with athletes at the top of their game wasn’t too shabby. New Zealand was tight and that’s my kind of game. USA was crazy and brilliant together, it’s the only footage I’ve seen and I had to watch myself through my cringing fingers – those women really are something. Each game had its own merits and delivered its own highlights for different reasons, but when Team Scotland delivered what we were aspiring to, it couldn’t get any better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BM&lt;/strong&gt;: Did you think you would win the MVP for Team Scotland? Why do you think you were chosen? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MM&lt;/strong&gt;: Not at all, especially as our first day was so challenging. It’s difficult to comprehend that you’re doing okay when you’re taking such a battering and defeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BM&lt;/strong&gt;: If you could give your MVP award to any one of your team-mates who would it be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MM&lt;/strong&gt;: I think I’d need to share it with Wild Oates, Marshall Lawless &amp;amp; Mistress Malicious. Malicious knows tactics and play like no-one else. I love watching her thought process filter from brain to skate – as ever, it was in top form in Toronto. Oates and Lawless have been training like devils and it really shows; every time I see them they get fitter, stronger and up the challenge for the opposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BM&lt;/strong&gt;: What does the future hold for Marla Mayhem in life, in derby and in any other interesting aspects?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MM&lt;/strong&gt;: Ah, life. I’m shifting the whole focus of my life, work and derby this year. I am intending to make 3 training sessions this year, 2011 I was lucky to make 1 or 2. We have a great season lined up - Berlin, Paris, Malmo, and Rainy City - and I’d like to bring my best to the Glasgow Roller Girls’ Irn Bruisers. I have 2 young daughters whom I’ll be mainly hanging out with until August when they start nursery and primary school, a bit of skating with them hopefully. I have 2 businesses, one of which I will be stepping back from, the second of which, I launched last year ,&lt;a href="http://www.psychopants.com/"&gt;Psycho Pants&lt;/a&gt;, and will be putting my energies into progressing that to the next phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off-skates training I try to build into normal life, for example cycling with the girls in a trailer in the back, running to the shops, squats in the garden, etc. I loathe wasteful time, like sitting on a bus or in the car when I could cycle, walk, do something rather than nothing. Other than that, random things I’d like to do is explore the old, disused underground network in Glasgow, it’ll be freaking scary, but good scary. I’d also like to try trapeze and to design a font.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future seems bright and busy for Marla Mayhem as she looks to bring her success from the World Cup to her home team in Glasgow. If she keeps up the type of play she did in December she will definitely be a skater to watch for as the Glasgow Roller Girls season begins in 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Many thanks to Bryan for this interview and to&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://boutday.com/"&gt;Dave McAleavy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;for kindly supplying the photo of Marla Mayhem.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/01/10/team-scotland-mvp-marla-mayhem/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 12:55:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Interview with Tarce</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/01/09/an-interview-with-tarce/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/s720x720/380795_2578899805857_1655254998_2388672_820374595_n.jpg" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-764  " title="Tarce in action at the Roller Derby World Cup in December" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/380795_2578899805857_1655254998_2388672_820374595_n.jpg" alt="Tarce in action at the Roller Derby World Cup in December" width="614" height="403"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The skaters always seem to be the stars of the Roller Derby show, but realistically, a live bout would dissolve into chaos if we didn't have Team Line Up Managers, Bench Managers and Non-Skating Officials (NSOs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tarce, a skater with Glasgow Roller Girls, unexpectedly found herself positioned as Line-Up Manager for Team Scotland only a few weeks before the World Cup kicked off! The person in this role is a vital part of any team as they take the time to understand each skater's strengths and weaknesses, and can make clear decisions on which skaters will play together per jam, and how to recover when players are sent to the penalty box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We catch up with Tarce to hear how she found the World Cup experience and just what the job entails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you become involved with Roller Derby?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was back in February 2010 when I got a message about the Glasgow Film Festival on Facebook. The message also contained a part about a roller derby bout that Saturday between Glasgow Roller Girls and London Rockin' Rollers. Now I’d never heard of roller derby before but something about women on skates possibly hitting each other somehow drew my interest! I decided to go along by myself to check it out and as soon as I entered the room I knew I was in the right place for me! So this was where the cool people hung out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went along to the after party too and got talking to one of the refs (who I’d met before through our mutual tattooist) and him and his lovely wife talked me into coming along to the next newbie intake, which just happened to be that same Tuesday! I also remember talking to a rather drunk Marla Mayhem of GRG and the Fabulous Mighty Mighty Bash of LRR and thinking these were women I could definitely get along with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plucked up the courage to go along to newbies that very Tuesday and managed not to break anything or embarrass myself too much .. and I’ve been hooked ever since!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you get involved in Line-Up in general, and what made you sign-up for the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haha now here comes the funny part! When I did the line up managing for Team Scotland’s first game against New Zealand at the World Cup, that only the second time I had ever done it! To say I was slightly nervous would be a small understatement; I’d much rather have been skating at that point that much I knew!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in February last year, Viper, our head of league training at GRG at the time, was in the first stages of trying to organise a national team for Scotland and she was desperate for people to help out. To play to my strengths, I volunteered to administer the Team Scotland forum as I sit in front of a computer all day at work and I’d done that sort of thing before anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To cut a long story short, before I knew it I was Chairperson of Team Scotland and I was off to Toronto in a few weeks! It was at that late stage that the person we had in the role told us that due to family commitments she would be unable to attend theWorld Cup. My one previous time doing line-ups (TS vs Northern Allstars) had filled the captains with enough confidence that they asked me to do it again for Team Scotland – the crazy fools! Well, I was going to be there anyway and I knew all the skaters, whats the worst that could happen?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What makes a good Line-Up Manager?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well you definitely need to remain calm and focussed in the eye of the storm! Exuding an air of confidence and that you know what you’re doing are very important too (even if you are actually bricking it inside!). You have to make instant decisions and stick to them. Stay focussed on whats happening on track and in the penalty bin and listen to what the bench manager is shouting at you too. You have to be able to be firm with the skaters as well as they will either be giving you puppy dog eyes to go on next, moaning that they want to go on with their best buddy or crying cos they ain't getting played enough! It’s a tough job! You’ve also got to keep an eye on them, especially the jammers, to see how tired they are and if they maybe need to sit off for a couple to get their breath back. Its definitely not a job to take on if you want to get a good view of the bout, that’s for sure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you prepare for the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I realised that I was going to be the one doing the job, I made sure I went along to all the training sessions and watched and got to know all the skaters that weren’t from my own league. I needed to familiarise myself with the roles they played when skating; who only blocked, who would jam and block, who was confident pivoting, etc. I’d have liked to have been able to perform the role at more bouts or even scrimmage sessions but unfortunately there just wasn’t the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also spoke to Knuckles, our bench manager and got as much information and tips from him as possible. He does an amazing job and it was great working with him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has the experience changed how you would manage Line-Up in future?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to do it ever again! Haha. Seriously though, I did gain a lot of confidence in the role by being thrown in at the deep end; it is full on and it is stressful but at the end of the day as long as you get enough skaters on track you’ve done your job! Lol. If I do it again in future I wont worry so much about trying to stick to the written line-ups provided by the captains; after that first person goes to the penalty bin you can basically throw them out the window. Just stick to the general ethos in your head of what they want and just go with what feels and looks right to you at the time. I think trying to work to that bit of paper definitely made things more stressful. So I guess the lesson to learn is: know your skaters well, know their strengths and weaknesses and know the tactics that the captains are playing to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think the World Cup has done for Roller Derby in Scotland?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's really given skaters new enthusiasm and motivation! Something new to aim for; who wouldn’t want to make it on to their country’s national team! We showed this year that Scotland is definitely a force to be reckoned with and basically anything is possible for us. Roller derby is going to keep on growing exponentially from here, its going to be huge and Scotland has a chance to be a big name in the sport. We have some amazing new skaters coming through who have a real hunger to do well. I see great things ahead for us! This first World Cup for a bit of an experiment really but it totally worked! I cannot wait to see what the next one will look like... it's going to be immense! Watch out USA, Scotland is coming for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any advice for anyone considering becoming a Line-Up Manager for their local league?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All those non-skating roles are vitally important to the sport as a whole; if we didn’t have people to fill bench and NSO roles then we couldn’t play, simple as! All leagues need those people that are dedicated to the sport and want to do their bit even if it doesn’t involve skating. And the skaters are hugely thankful that they come along and do what they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come along as often as you can for scrimmage sessions especially. Get to know everyone and feel part of the team. Know the rules inside and out and watch as much roller derby as you can – just like being a skater really! Practice makes perfect, the more you do it the more confident you will get. I don’t think there are any big secrets to it, it's just about being level headed, sensible and logical really. And if the skaters know they can rely on you they will love you forever!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><category>team scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/01/09/an-interview-with-tarce/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 20:21:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Interview With Ballistic Whistle</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/01/09/an-interview-with-ballistic-whistle/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In another World Cup interview,we talk to Ballistic Whistle,Head Coach of Team England &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/ballisticwhistle-2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/ballisticwhistle-2.jpg" alt="" title="BallisticWhistle-2" width="614" height="434" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-756"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo of Ballistic Whistle by &lt;a href="http://boutday.com/"&gt;Dave McAleavy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the World Cup,Team England placed a well deserved third,how does it feel to have represented your country and managed a squad of skaters to such an amazing achievment?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, technically I haven't represented my country....being Australian and all. I did take a sick joy from writing myself into what my countrymen would consider the wrong side of that classic sporting rivalry though. However, I do feel that English derby is truly where my heart lies. Having invested so much time and effort into the sport in this country it was emotional to have the opportunity to lead a team of excellent skaters at an event which saw sickening amounts of national pride. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From the streamed footage everything seemed to run very well,what were your impressions of the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought it was really well produced for a first event of its kind. Obviously there were some elements that I would've preferred were different - for example the pillars in the middle of the track - but given the scale of the event I thought Black Dahlia did an amazing job of pulling together something that no-one, up until now, had decided to brave attempting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your World Cup highlights? Both personally and for the Team&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My actual highlight from the world cup can't go in print so I'll just say that I loved the New Zealand Haka as well as watching the USA v USA bout. The thing that really sticks with me was just seeing so many different countries representing their brand of derby. It was great to watch. That, and being able to coach some fantastic skaters that I don't normally get the opportunity to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team England drew a varied group with Ireland and Argentina,interestingly, Team Ireland featured some skaters from The London Roller Girls,given that those skaters are well versed in the way you work,how did that affect your tactics for that bout?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, for whatever reason Team Ireland chose not to play those skaters in our game against them. We had the luxury of being able to observe the Ireland team before we played them so had an idea of how they were going to set themselves out. Having said that, they certainly played a style we weren't expecting and made our opening game really tough which, given points differential was vital to the knockout phases, put a little extra pressure on us for the remaining group game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A sizeable chunk of the Team England squad had played in the Eastern Region Playoffs as part of the London Roller Girls team where you were also Coach,how much of an edge do you think that experience gave you over most of the other teams in the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting better by playing better teams is one of the hard and fast derby truths that LRG swears by, so having the opportunity to go to Regionals just made those participating players stronger, both physically and mentally. I can imagine that a lot of the players at the cup would never have felt the experience of being involved in such a large-scale, high-profile event such as that, so having players who were able to put all that to one side and focus on the job at hand was quite advantageous to us&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Argentina were one of the unknowns in the competition,how impressed were you with them and the newer,less established teams?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was almost impossible for us to do research on many of the unknown teams. Footage doesn't exist and you only really find some snippets of the one or two "stars" playing with their own league. Argentina and Brazil were especially exciting to watch during the cup as they were essentially representing the newest frontier of derby (out of the teams at the cup anyway). I was incredibly impressed with how well Finland did and am just sad that I didn't have more free time to catch more of their games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking back at England's World Cup bout scores,it seems that you sailed through almost every match,however,scores rarely reflect how hard fought a bout was,who among your opponents gave you the hardest bouts?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Canada game was the toughest by far. We never really got into the game and were working hard just to stay within touching distance. We got off to a terrible start against Australia, but just needed to take a breath, have a chat, and we were able to regain control of that one. For me, the most unexpectedly tough game we played was against Ireland. Not because it was our first bout of the tournament, not because it was played at 9:30am on a Friday, but because Ireland played a really strong, disciplined game. They gave us a fight right from the start and pretty much made us re-evaluate our tournament game plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think of the European Cup that has recently been announced?,can we expect to see Team England there?,or do you have any other international bout plans?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the idea of a Euro Cup. I think whoever takes responsibility for organising it is going to have to deal with headaches Blood &amp;amp; Thunder avoided, now that the teams are established and have a voice. Something that Dahlia started catching more and more as the prep for the World Cup went on. I would hate for a Euro Cup to happen without Team England there. The team took the festive season off, but we're going to be discussing how we want to move the forward in 2012. Obviously a lot of the players have hectic derby schedules already, so working out how we can fit it in is going to be somewhat tricky. As for other international bouts, there are some things that are being discussed, but I can't divulge anything at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 will be an exciting time for Roller Derby here.There are new full WFTDA and apprentice leagues all over Europe and the Track Queens competition coming up for them later in the year,plus the European Cup.All of which can only improve the standard of the sport right across the board.How do you see the future of Derby in Europe?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have fingers crossed that WFTDA will consider formalising the European Region in terms of the existing Big5 tournaments. It's going to be tough to work out how a Region with such a small number of teams and such a diverse ability level will fit into their tournament structure though. That's a task I don't envy. I'm hoping that the Euro Cup will give an opportunity to some other European Countries to establish their national teams as well. The Track Queens tournament is really exciting as well. I realise there have been localised tournaments such as Tattoo Freeze and Highland Fling, but I'm hoping this can be the spiritual continuation of Roll Brittania wihich is now so long overdue. 2011 saw me witness European teams playing strategies that were less than 3 months old at the time. That many of the established teams have reached that point means their progress should accelerate even more rapidly in 2012. Exciting stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Many thanks to Ballistic Whistle for taking the time to do this interview&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/01/09/an-interview-with-ballistic-whistle/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 14:07:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Roller Derby World Cup 2011-Photography Round Up</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/12/24/roller-derby-world-cup-2011-photography-round-up/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just in case you haven't quite had your fill of World Cup pictures,here is a round up of some of the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kicking off with the official Team Scotland photographer,&lt;a href="http://boutday.com/"&gt;Dave McAleavy&lt;/a&gt;
As you might expect,lots of shots of Team Scotland in action and all of the superb quality that marks all Dave's work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.girlsofderby.com/"&gt;Sean Murphy&lt;/a&gt; is head photographer for the Renegade Derby Dames,Alliston,Ontario and has an impressive array of galleries,covering not only the World Cup,but also a range of bouts that feature some of the top names in American and Canadian Roller Derby.It's a superb site and he has a great beard!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.roller-derby-on-film.co.uk/"&gt;Jason Ruffell&lt;/a&gt; has some excellent World Cup work on show,including some of Team Scotland and Team England.Plus an archive of top English bouts that goes back to 2009.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gregrussellphotography.com/derbyworldcup"&gt;Greg Russell&lt;/a&gt; has some amazing work,split into days rather than bouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorado based &lt;a href="http://www.wickedshamrockphotography.com/"&gt;Wicked Shamrock Photography&lt;/a&gt; has a lot of quality work covering Team Ireland,click,'Roller Derby' then 'Special Events'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Finland photographer &lt;a href="http://punkmarko.com/2011/12/12/roller-derby-world-cup-done/"&gt;Marko Niemelä&lt;/a&gt; has an excellent gallery on his national team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note&lt;/strong&gt;:All images on these sites are the property of their respective photographers,permission must be obtained before reproducing these images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>in the news</category><category>pictures</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><category>team scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/12/24/roller-derby-world-cup-2011-photography-round-up/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 13:39:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An interview with Crazylegs.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/12/20/an-interview-with-crazylegs/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;All the skaters in Team Scotland are important, of course, but Co-Captains Lily Lethal and Crazylegs were responsible for leading the rest to victory in Toronto. We caught up with Crazylegs to talk about the challenges of competing in the world's first international Roller Derby World Cup, and of the future for Team Scotland.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/12/me-and-shenita-stretcher.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-711" title="CrazyLegs AND SHENITA STRETCHER!" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/12/me-and-shenita-stretcher.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="431"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Although we’ve talked about this before the World Cup, it’s worth revisiting now: how did you prepare for the world’s first international Roller Derby competition?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I went to as many training sessions as physically possible - both with my league (the Auld Reekie Roller Girls) and with Team Scotland, and sometimes with the lovely GRG.  I also did a more intense off skates cross training regime to get fitter to be able to handle more than one game per day.  I had no idea what kind of intensity to expect or how many games we would be faced with in Toronto.  Team Scotland organised as many practice dates together as we possibly could in the lead up to the Tournament, we had an advantage in being geographically close with our team mates, but because of other commitments – individual league bouts and practices to plan around, we didn’t manage to hold as many as we would have wanted.We also did some research on the teams/skaters who were listed to take part in the World Cup – stalking if you like, and tried to keep a lot of our focus on bringing Scotland onto the world stage for derby in a good light.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In pretty much all of your bouts, Team Scotland did better in the second period; in fact, you only lost the second period against Team USA and Team Australia (which isn’t bad company to be in). &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team England shared a similar property of having a sudden revival after their initial start, thanks to Ballistic Whistle calling a time-out and restrategising; is Team Scotland’s approach similar, or does Knuckles just incredibly inspirational in his half-time speeches?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting to note this trend for second period come backs!  In a tournament situation, it’s almost certainly linked in some part to the warm up and preparation – we had less time generally to warm up and get our heads into the game than in a usual bout situation, something we’ve learned from and will certainly plan for next time. In my mind the Germany game stood out as the most significant in terms of performance difference per half and this was due to a distinct tactical change we made in our game at half time.  In saying that, Knuckles always does give a good half time booster chat – in fact he’s possibly the most positive and encouraging person I have ever met!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While meeting all of the national teams was obviously a major part of the tournament, everyone really wanted to lose to the USA. How did it feel playing the best roller derby players in the world? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long did it take to switch from being star-struck to trying to hip-check Suzy Hotrod?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The USA game was all about the enjoyment and learning from madly talented skaters. We had a goal to minimise the amount of points they scored which is hilarious to think of now.  I was really focussed on the game, so no time to be star struck.  It's all a bit of a blur with random faces you know appearing and you think 'oh God that's Bonnie Thunders sailing past me!'  I had no idea I had knocked Suzy Hotrod over until I saw my Facebook page that night.  It was amazing the amount of sheer control they had over us – it was like they were playing in slow motion Matrix style and we were just madly reacting to everything and keeping going like duracell bunnies.  I have never expended so much energy in a bout before – I loved how our skaters kept getting back up and never gave up pushing, all with huge grins on faces.   I did notice Sexy Slaydie’s rear end holding me back on more than one occasion though, and after the game blurted out ‘I love you’ to her, like a geek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/12/me-and-suzy.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-712" title="Crazylegs and Suzy Hotrod" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/12/me-and-suzy.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="212"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Scotland ended up placing 11th in the rankings. How do you feel that ranking reflects the team’s performance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m happy with 11,  It’s my fave number!   In truth – I am very proud of the whole team for playing with such heart, and our management team for organising us so well.  I think unless we’re looking at first, second, third or fourth place - which we will be for next time ;-) - it really doesn’t matter too much where you come.  We got to play some of the best teams from places furthest away from Scotland and I’m pleased about that. We have all come back with so much new knowledge and of course there are some key area’s I would like us to focus on for any future TS endeavours, but I’ll be keeping that to myself for now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going on from the World Cup, clearly you will have picked up lots of contacts and tips from the rest of the international roller derby players present, in addition to getting a better feel for how Team Scotland plays. What do you think Team Scotland will be working in before their next appearance; and what tips did you pick up from the rest of roller derby?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being Co-Captain meant my time between bouts was focussed on the next bout, helping to re-write line ups, team rosters and making sure the team were happy and the occasional power nap/toilet dash! I didn’t get as much chance to ‘internationally network’ as I would have liked to; but I did get a chance to catch up with some familiar faces from past bouts, which was lovely.   We were given some great advice from the TORD coach, and I know a lot of our skaters did manage to get some good advice/chats and bonding in, so we’ll be making sure we utilise everything we can in building an improved team for future games/tourneys. One area is of course more integration and practice between skaters from the different leagues involved and being fast to adapt our strategy when required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s not much of a secret that at least some of Team Scotland are already thinking about further bouts against national teams post-World Cup, especially since you didn’t get to play all of the European teams during the tournament itself. Do you have any particular team you’d like to play that you missed during the Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it happens, there is already some secret squirrel planning underway looking at future bouts, so hopefully something will be arranged.  I would jump at the chance to play any of the teams we didn’t manage to play against.  Ireland looked really good and would be an interesting match up I think, and I really wanted a chance to play against Sweden…but then France did so well too…oh so many to choose from. Hopefully we can play them all one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being from there originally, would you have tried out for a Team Wales if one had existed in time for the World Cup? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Now you’re wedded to Team Scotland by the team selection rules, how would you feel about a Team Wales participating in the next World Cup?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good question! It would have been a difficult decision, but ultimately I skate for a Scottish league and my home is here now – so even though my immediate family are still mostly based in Wales I would have had to choose Scotland (sorry mum).  I've so much respect for skaters that I've played with and against from Scottish leagues and geographically it makes more sense for me to be involved with planning, practices and bouts for Scottish Roller Derby. It was a real shame that Wales was not able to represent this time – I know there are some amazing skaters emerging in Wales already, and I would be so excited to see a Welsh team in future tournaments.  I would definitely be their biggest supporter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, in the medium term for Team Scotland, what would you like to see happening? There’s been talk of a European Cup in the next year or two, for example, or just more international bouts in general?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A European Cup would be awesome in the interim – the more time we can spend playing with the best skaters from countries outside of Scotland, the faster we will learn, improve and hopefully close the gap between us and the USA!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, how do you feel about the next World Cup, in two or three years? Will you be trying out for the national team again?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Well I’m no ‘spring chicken’ at 38, but I do think that with careful training and looking after myself, I have a few good derby years in me yet! I’d love to be able to try out for another World Cup or European Tournament; it was the best experience ever, hands down.  But in saying that, there are so many talented new skaters springing up all over Scotland, that it may be time for some new blood take my place? I’ll definitely fight them for it though ha-ha.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><category>team scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/12/20/an-interview-with-crazylegs/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2011 19:47:04 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>