<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about roller derby world cup 2014)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/roller-derby-world-cup-2014.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Road to TBC: Lessons from ERDT and the last World Cup!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Blood &amp;amp; Thunder still have yet to formally announce the location and date for the 2017 Women's Roller Derby World Cup, by the end of November we will have already seen two of the "lead up" events for next year's tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is the the already complete &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://euroderbytournament.eu/"&gt;European Roller Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, held in Mons, Belgium. The second will be Team Wales Roller Derby's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1224163900948144/"&gt;"The Road To TBC"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, scheduled for the &lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;27th&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;November&lt;/strong&gt; 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the two tournaments, we will get a good look at most of Europe's competitors in the Third World Cup, albeit at an early stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attending the European Roller Derby Tournament were &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Denmark&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Switzerland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Portugal&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Italy&lt;/strong&gt; and new team &lt;strong&gt;Iceland&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Road To TBC will bring you &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt; again, with the addition of &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Sweden&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;West Indies&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; all showing their national team debuts at the event!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what can we predict, if anything, about The Road to TBC from what has come &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we can look at ERDT. Whilst only 50% of the lineup overlaps between ERDT and TRtT, we can judge some expectations about absolute strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the now-traditional Bayesian inferred strength charts from ERDT, with the top four teams also singled out in separate highlights [as usual, these charts are relative to the winner - in this case, France - and so they are not directly represented]. We've marked vertical lines to show the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/"&gt;performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (also relative to France) in the Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Women's World Cup 2014, for those teams who attended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="8997,9001,8998,8999,9000" type="slideshow" link="file"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is pretty clear, whilst Spain is just about separate from the top three, although closely competitive with Wales and Belgium; the distributions for Belgium and Wales are almost indistinguishable. While France was indisputably the strongest team at ERDT, it's reasonable to suggest that the tournament also showed that Belgium and Wales are almost identical in strength. (Wales was the victim of one of the classic problems with single elimination tournaments, being relegated to the consolation brackets by an early encounter with the eventual Champions, and achieved Third as their highest possible relegation place.)
It's also possible to see that, assuming France is still relatively similar in strength, that Wales, Spain and Portugal have all noticeably improved in strength from 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/2/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over the page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we'll talk about the teams at The Road to TBC in more detail...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we can expect the hosts to be strong competitors in November... but what about their challengers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9075" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14448951_1432178393465450_4812609206374398804_n.jpg?w=600" alt="14448951_1432178393465450_4812609206374398804_n" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/"&gt;back at the last World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Sweden&lt;/em&gt; was one of the strongest teams in the tournament, reflecting the strength of Scandinavian Roller Derby even back then. Since then, Swedish roller derby has gone from strength to strength, with both Stockholm Roller Derby and Crime City Rollers in WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs this year!
A quick count of their recently published training team for 2016/17 [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamswedenrollerderby/photos/a.517256094957689.143365.224501220899846/1432139023469387/?type=1&amp;amp;theater"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] suggests that at least &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt; of the skaters from 2014 are returning as possible rosters (as several skaters were recorded under their legal names for the 2014 roster, and under their skatenames here, it's a little tricky to be 100% certain).
We expect, on the balance of this, and the general health of Swedish derby, for Sweden to be a contender for the top spot at The Road to TBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3901" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamfrance.png?w=570" alt="TeamFrance" width="285" height="300"&gt; Team France logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team France&lt;/em&gt; were a top 8 team for us in 2014 (although they narrowly missed the actual final 8 at the tournament itself. We see at least 12 skaters from 2014 in the 2016 roster so far, which is about an average rate of returns in Europe. Almost 50% of the roster is drawn from Paris and Toulouse (with the rest mostly from the other strong French leagues), and both teams have experienced strong growth since 2014. Paris Rollergirls, in particular, have rocketed up the WFTDA rankings in the last two years, currently at #77 in the World.
We would consider France to be one of our three contenders for 2nd place, with chance at taking on Sweden for the top spot too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Belgium&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Wales&lt;/em&gt;, as we mentioned above, statistically drew at ERDT. At the 2014 World Cup, Belgium was the stronger team, by some distance, so this represents a particular improvement on Wales's part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9087" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/1957831_642788809139747_4859931912064326634_o.jpg?w=600" alt="1957831_642788809139747_4859931912064326634_o" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the composition of 2016 &lt;em&gt;Team Wales&lt;/em&gt; is quite different to that in 2014, with only a handful of skaters shared betwen the two rosters. What is still true, however, is the dominance of Tiger Bay Brawlers and Swansea City Roller Derby in the training team, making up 18 of the 30 spots. Both teams have have exceptional years, with Swansea City particularly excelling at British Champs (where they defeated all comers in promotion to Tier 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3897" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teambelgium.jpg?w=582" alt="TeamBelgium" width="291" height="300"&gt; Team Belgium logo: Anouk Paepen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Belgium&lt;/em&gt;, meanwhile have at least 14 skaters returning from the strong 2014 roster in 2016. Belgian Roller Derby has always been pretty strong, on the basis of Gent Go-Go Rollergirls and One Love Roller Dolls amongst their many teams. However, we've not seen, perhaps, the explosive performance increase that, for example, Scandinavia has. We'd say that Team Belgium is, indeed, about as strong as it was in 2014.
We expect Wales to be keen on taking on Belgium on their home turf, and cautiously predict a win for the hosts on this basis. Overall rankings are hard to predict, but there are some particularly strong teams competing in The Road to TBC, and we wonder if the battle here will be for 4th place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3842" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamspain.jpg?w=600" alt="Team Spain logo -" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2014, &lt;em&gt;Spain&lt;/em&gt; have clearly come on in leaps and bounds.
The 2014 Team Spain consisted almost entirely of skaters from Barcelona and Tenerife, along with a few from outside Spain. The 2016 Training Team contains 13 skaters from 2014, but a huge number of new faces. We expect that Barcelona and Tenerife will still be strongly represented, however, and note that both leagues have significantly improved their rankings in the last 2 years (Tenerife has a steadily increasing ranking on Flat Track Stats, with no drops at all over that period!). We'd say that Spain have a good chance of placing well, assuming no surprises - although the general strength of teams at The Road to TBC is also higher than ERDT, so another 4th place is unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3773" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamwestindies.jpg?w=424" alt="Team West Indies Logo" width="212" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team West Indies&lt;/em&gt; was new to the Roller Derby scene in 2014, and also had the aim of trying to promote the sport back in the West Indies itself, with all of the skaters being from leagues outside of the islands (and many from the UK). Two years later, it seems that they're planning even greater things - but there's no official roster published for the team to date. We gather that Birmingham Blitz Dames and London Rockin' Rollers are still the core of the UK branch of the team, however, and both teams have had strong years - the Blitz Dames in particular benefitting from a change of coaching style which has improved their performance. While we rated West Indies as a little weaker than Spain and Wales in 2014, we wouldn't rule out surprising things from the team after 2 more years to build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4007" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/team-ireland.jpg?w=600" alt="team ireland" width="300" height="300"&gt; Team France logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Ireland Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt; did pretty well at the 2014 World Cup - in fact, on some metrics, we considered them competitive with France! The 2016 iteration is totally unknown, however - they're literally recruiting and selecting as we write this. On the basis of the performance of Dublin Roller Derby (who recently had a US trip and came back even stronger), we wouldn't rule the new Team Ireland out of a top 3 spot in this tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9080" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14390622_1111812092237414_410042907831655880_n.png?w=600" alt="14390622_1111812092237414_410042907831655880_n" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we come to our local team: &lt;em&gt;Team Scotland&lt;/em&gt;!
Scotland performed very creditably in the 2014 World Cup, placing around 10/11th place by our calculations. In 2014, the Scotland team was strongly dominated by Glasgow Roller Derby and Auld Reekie Roller Girls, with only a few skaters from Granite City, 1 from Dundee, and 1 each from Seaside Sirens and London Rollergirls.
This time around, due to both changes at Glasgow, and the strong growth in strength at Dundee and Granite City, we have a more rounded mix of representation in the training team (5 skaters from Dundee, and one from Fierce Valley!); as well as more skaters from outside Scotland itself, with 2 from Wirral, 2 from Newcastle and 1 each from Hallam, Leicester, London Rockin' Rollers!
We're not sure how the team roster for Team Scotland has been selected for The Road to TBC, but we've seen the team in practice, and they look pretty cohesive already. We'd tip Scotland for a chance at upsetting Ireland's dreams of a Top 3 spot, if anyone does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the only way to actually see if we're right is to make your way to Cardiff for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1224163900948144/"&gt;The Road to TBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; itself. Ticket sales are open for the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;27th November,&lt;/strong&gt; and sales are going fast, we believe!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>european roller derby tournament</category><category>international derby</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>statistics</category><category>team belgium</category><category>team france</category><category>team ireland</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team spain</category><category>team sweden</category><category>team wales</category><category>team west indies</category><category>the road to tbc</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 10:36:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Interview With... outgoing Team England Coach, Ballistic Whistle!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/10/an-interview-with-outgoing-team-england-coach-ballistic-whistle/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of people were surprised to hear that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamenglandrollerderby/"&gt;Team England Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s Ballistic Whistle announce that he did not intend to reapply for the role in the current round of recruitment. (The applications for the Team England (Women's) coaching and management roles are currently being voted on.) Considering his contributions to Roller Derby, both in the National teams, and also ongoing with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://londonrollergirls.com/"&gt;London Rollergirls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.southerndiscomfort.co.uk/"&gt;Southern Discomfort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, we thought it was a good idea to catch up with him and talk about, well, him.
(This interview is also undertaken in collaboration with the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UK Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, as part of our National Teams series.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/10/an-interview-with-outgoing-team-england-coach-ballistic-whistle/9012365607_0dd177bdf1_k/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-7241"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-7241" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/9012365607_0dd177bdf1_k.jpg?w=700" alt="Ballistic Whistle (London Rollergirls v Rat City) (Photo: Eric Von Flickr)" width="700" height="467"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Ballistic Whistle (London Rollergirls v Rat City) (Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/31756530@N08/9012365607"&gt;Steve Messerer&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Despite the wide range of your involvement in Roller Derby, you're probably best known as the Coach and Bench Manager of London Roller Girls, who pretty much were the vanguard of Europe's entry into the top levels of Roller Derby. Did you feel responsible, in a way, for representing the UK or Europe in the early days of LRG going across to the States (and is it more of a relief that other teams are now increasingly high level)?&lt;/strong&gt;
I don't feel that was ever a specific goal or aim of ours. From a really early stage we had aspirations of travelling to the States to play high level derby. That benchmark over the years has continued to be pushed on and on to test how far we can go. Through our first tour of the States, and the first visit of American teams to our shores it was quite evident just how much support we were receiving from the UK and Europe. Feeling that during our Stateside trips has always been amazing for us and serves as quite an emotional motivator when away from home. If we have had an impact on how enthusiastic other players and teams are for playing the sport then we've definitely achieved one of our aims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Literally everyone we've spoken to before this interview has mentioned specifically that you're a nice guy (and you parodied this in your appearance in the LRG Fort Wayne's World promo videos [which sadly seem to have mostly disappeared from the internet]). Do you think this surprises people?&lt;/strong&gt;
Haha, that's nice of you to say. I guess I try my best not to irk people on purpose, but I definitely have my foibles and personality clashes just like anyone else. I guess what I find most interesting is how people will formulate an idea of you without ever having met you, purely by how they would expect a person in my position to be. I'll often meet someone for the first time and there will be a period of trying to balance out the shockwaves in our interactions as a result of how they expect me to behave. I'd really love to not have to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As well as coaching and bench managing, you also find the time to play on track, with Southern Discomfort (as well as another signing we'll get to next…). How does your time on track contribute to your coaching decisions (and which would you rather be known as: a great coach, or a great skater)?&lt;/strong&gt;
I took some time off during the 2015 season to try and rehabilitate a back injury. It was during this season that there was a major swing towards formation defense. I realised after a number of months that I was lacking empathy for the difficulty our players had working against this formation. Some of the minor adjustments I was asking our players to make, were actually majorly difficult. Getting back into playing has helped me incredibly to understand what is possible and where the difficulties lie in the modern game. I also get the opportunity to jump in with Brawling from time to time, which I find incredibly helpful to understand what it feels like being inside of the on track action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I roll all of these experiences into my coaching; I guess that answers your parenthesised question. I have no doubt that I love coaching more than playing. I feel like seeing my friends achieve amazing things is much more rewarding for me than achieving them myself. The great thing about fighting to see your team-mates reach their goals, is that you generally achieve yours as a result!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And you recently made the roster for the Team Australia (&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/WizardsofAusDerby/"&gt;Wizards of Aus&lt;/a&gt;) who will be competing at the &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; in Calgary. How did you make the decision to represent your birth nation in the World Cup, and how does it feel to be on the team?&lt;/strong&gt;
Um, actually, it's not my birth nation. I was born in Denmark to a Danish father and Belgian mother. I arrived in Australia on my 2nd birthday and remained there until age 25. But, if you were to ask me what I considered my nationality it would be Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the first World Cup, I had the amazing opportunity to participate with so many of my great derby friends for Team England. Being a part of that team was a fantastic experience, but it wasn't until I was selected for the Australia team that I truly understood what the other players on that English team felt during that first World Cup. In hindsight, I felt incredibly guilty for taking that feeling from someone during the first World Cup, and I feel that is the special thing about that event. Playing for your nation is something that can call on something deeper. At all World Cups I have attended, both male and female, hearing the Australian national anthem has been a...tricky...moment for me emotionally. At this next World Cup, I am going to be so happy to be able to belt out the anthem without any mixed feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You've been Team England Coach for two World Cups, and London Roller Girls coach for 5 years. While both positions are top-level coaching positions, are there more differences than might be apparent?&lt;/strong&gt;
Absolutely. There's no substitute for working with the same team week in week out. You can definitely deliver the most effective change in strategy and refine what you do on track on multiple occasions over a shorter period of time. With both teams you are dealing with a group of incredibly talented skaters, but with Team England it was much more of a situation of building cohesion. Nailing down defaults and making sure, as much as possible, everyone is on the same page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the England team, there was the tricky balance of trying not to be just Brawling + friends, but really appreciate that there are different ways to play. World Cups comprise a number of nations from the extreme fledgling derby countries to the most seasoned. We had always set our sights on taking on the most seasoned. Hopefully in coming World Cup cycles, there will be more English players in other teams who have more of that high-level derby play and will be ready to take on the best countries in the world. With limited training sessions, it becomes a lot more sink or swim when put into that intensely hot cauldron of competition, and so it is all about looking for the players who can take that pressure and really excel. Without the experience of that level, it comes so much more down to personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recently, you announced that you would not be applying for the role of Team England Head Coach this time around. Can we talk a bit about your reasons for this, and your feelings about the decision?&lt;/strong&gt;
The 2015 season was one that definitely took a toll on me. Brawling, at the beginning of the season, had set ourselves what we thought was the ultimate goal (incidentally, we have since understood that the Hydra is not the ultimate goal). Having an amazing season and falling short at the critical time definitely hit me with my first proper feeling of derby burnout in the 9 1/2 years I've been in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we've set our sights even higher than the goals we set last year and I understand what that is going to take from me on a personal level. I also feel that this time around, we are blessed with a number of candidates that could really use this as a springboard to get that experience of that new level. I obviously have mixed feelings about it. Watching England at the World Cup is going to be tough as I'll be wanting the best for all my friends on that team, but will have zero input on helping them achieve that. I'll be waving the 3 Lions flag regardless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, what have been the high and low points in your 6 years as TE Head Coach?&lt;/strong&gt;
Again, it's only 5 years really as the lead up to that first World Cup happened in the same year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lows have always been any time we needed to make some kind of cut to the squad, whether that be to the charter that would go to an event or the roster of 14 that would play. I've been tasked with making these decisions countless times during my life as a coach, but it never gets easy telling talented players that they aren't going to have the opportunity, this time, to do what they love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As bad as those moments are, they are eclipsed by the highs, and I feel like one of the biggest highs was our final against the USA at the 2014 World Cup. Prior to the game I had pored over and re-written my pre-game speech so many times I thought I had written the perfect speech. I got in there and saw all of those players looking at me to hear the message I had for them at that point. Prior to a game where getting all of the 1 percenters right mattered. I threw everything I had written out the window and just spoke from the heart. Anyone in that room will be able to tell you that the message was pretty simple. Regardless of its simplicity, I feel like it resonated with the players, and really struck a chord. In spite of the result, it was one of those games where we just felt like we were playing on point, executing our strategies so well. It all felt so streamlined and precise, against potentially the toughest group of individual skaters you could ever face on track. For it to culminate in one of my derby idols - Kamikaze Kitten - taking us over the 100 point mark in the final jam, I couldn't have asked for a better written story. For me, that game illustrated what Roller Derby (and playing team sport for that matter) is truly all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Given your experience in the role, do you have any advice to pass on to your successor as Head Coach?&lt;/strong&gt;
I feel like there are a lot of coaches out there who work with a top down decision making structure. The coach will dictate the direction and decisions the team makes, sometimes opening the floor to the players for input. When working with some of the best players to ever play the sport, it would be remiss of any coach not to leverage that knowledge and experience. Every single player that played for Team England has a wealth of experience, has an incredibly active derby brain. It's so important to keep those brains ticking over and thinking at a high level, rather than trying to stifle them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with both Brawling and England has shown me that when you are dealing with these incredibly talented groups of players, you are just one equally important part of the team, rather than the single decision making point. Having said that, there definitely comes a point whereby the players need to focus on playing and the decisions need to be directed. The closer to game time this is, the more important it becomes for the coach to take responsibility for decision making. So, rather than a top down, triangle type shape, I think of it more of an hourglass decision making shape. The active brains in the team will feed their ideas into the team's leadership or management, and the leadership with all of this great information will compile it and disseminate a directed decision to the team to execute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, coaching a high level national team at a World Cup is something that not many people the world over will ever be able to say they did with their life. It's exhilarating, and the more you put into it, the greater the reward will be. Don't fuck it up!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team england roller derby</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/10/an-interview-with-outgoing-team-england-coach-ballistic-whistle/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 09:16:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pride, passion and no regrets … except perhaps the kangaroo!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/01/25/pride-passion-and-no-regrets-except-perhaps-the-kangaroo/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that the derby dust has settled on the 2014 Blood and Thunder World Cup – and a new year of our sport is already underway – it’s a good time to look back and reflect on a stellar set of performances from Team Scotland in Dallas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flat-track facts are two wins, a narrow loss and a Davina and Goliath-like performance against one of the best teams on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/1559577_10204841834359734_5493801035271240774_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4535 " src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/1559577_10204841834359734_5493801035271240774_n.jpg?w=300" alt="1559577_10204841834359734_5493801035271240774_n" width="380" height="253"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Pic by Dave McAleavy
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;But that doesn’t begin to tell the story of just how sensational the Team Scotland players were – on and off the track – flying the flag for their country and impressing everyone who saw the blue belles rock their stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
Team Scotland kicked off the tournament with a terrific win over Team Mexico (207-45) and then – within hours – narrowly lost to Team Finland (126-78).
&lt;p&gt;The following day, Team Scotland turned on the thrusters to beat Team Colombia (230-53), but they knew they had a daunting task ahead – with the mighty Team Australia in their path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, the Aussies beat Scotland 464-35, but the scoreline doesn’t reflect the skill, stamina and heart that was poured into the game by all the players, coaching staff and supporters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRD spoke to Team Scotland’s Captain Fantastic – Lianne Parry – on her memories of the World Cup, Kangaroogate and what’s next for Caledonian derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How was the World Cup for you, Captain?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great experience! The tournament was huge this time and the venue was brilliant. The whole weekend had a completely different feeling to the last - bigger and a lot more hectic, but I loved seeing the new teams involved, and the semi-final and finals games were really inspiring to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS started strongly against Mexico, played well against Finland and beat Colombia convincingly. Are you pleased with how Scotland played?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course! It was a huge deal for us to face up against unknown teams like Mexico and Colombia - it's hard to describe how different a team’s style can be outside of Europe; it's always a good experience to be exposed to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Finland game was one that a lot of the team enjoyed playing most, even though it was the most heartbreaking to lose! It felt like we could definitely have taken the win - we brought it to within a few points - but ultimately they played a really strong game and held it together better at the end. It felt like how playing roller derby should feel all of the time - I wish that game could have lasted two hours instead of 40 minutes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your thoughts on the Australia game? They are an excellent side, but Scotland gave as good as they got – especially second half. What were the differences between the teams in the end?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thoughts on the Australia game at the time were that it was probably going to feel as challenging as when we faced Team USA in 2011. I'm not sure all of the team were really fully prepared for just how tough it was going to be though, and in the first half I think we definitely struggled mentally in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The style of play was nothing like I'd come up against before, they are quite simply, just really really flipping good at roller derby! Strong, focused, technically excellent, amazing at forcing penalties on their opponents, and they use their whole bodies way more intelligently than I've ever encountered in another team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was difficult to get a handle on how to block them, or do effective offence against their walls, and it probably took us until half-time to really get a grip on that a little! But what an opportunity - so much stuff to figure out and learn from that game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights on and off track?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gahd too many to mention - on track definitely Australia - every jam I played against them - even if it was totally frustrating. Off track mostly food-related (giant steaks) in Dallas, Kangaroogate (being caught by the Dallas police hot footing it up the road with the Team Australia mascot), failing at the human knot game with the whole team but laughing so hard we forgot to be nervous, making up the stupid team awards at the end and just spending time with the best people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any regrets? Perhaps if Scotland had got a better draw…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously - who bloody regrets anything from such an amazing experience! You do it, you try your best, you learn, you grow, you move on. We've started to gather feedback, stats and footage ready to start preparing for the next challenge. We've loads to work on and loads to change up, so I'm raring to get started. The way it worked out, we got to play Australia and I think I learned more from that game than any other game I've played in the last two years so I'm happy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does playing for your country compare to league? Is it tricky when you don’t know the players as well or did find you all worked well together?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, I guess playing for your country feels like it has way more pressure attached to it - you don't want to let a whole nation down and it seems like the whole world is watching. With your own league you just know each other so well, you know that even if you act like a complete tit by accident, they will still love you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess it can be tricky on mixed teams - skaters from different leagues often have different 'defaults' on track, different cultural norms and are used to different ways of managing their teams - especially decision-making both on and off track - there is quite a lot to try to navigate through, but as you know the derby scene in Scotland is really closely knit so we all know each other fairly well, and there is a lot of respect and support between the leagues. I think the team gelled so well both on and off track this past year, that it won't take much work at all to really build on it and see fast improvements. It takes a big event like this to boost you to the next level sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How proud were you of your team? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So - even though this was the second time Team Scotland has played in a World Cup tournament, the team this time was mostly made up of skaters who hadn't played last time; some of whom have never been to the US or outside of Europe to play derby before, and a couple of whom were cheering Team Scotland on as spectators last time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They all seriously just took it in their stride, prepared well, stepped up to the challenge, gave so much positivity and energy to each game - even (especially!) when not on the game roster. I'm mostly proud of the sportswomanship the team showed, both to each other and to the teams we played. Even though there were difficult moments, decisions and disappointments, there were also huge smiles, happy tears, so much laughter in the changing room and lots of sweat (and a bit of facial bleeding too).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where will Captain Parry and Team Scotland go from here?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the drawing board! A wee break to let everyone re-focus on their own league challenges and then we'll start up a new training programme. Look out for some changes to the team leadership structure, it's always good to breathe new life and ideas into a team and we'll definitely be looking to open up some extra team roster spots to ensure we keep providing opportunities to skaters across Scotland. So - watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>an interview with...</category><category>in the news</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/01/25/pride-passion-and-no-regrets-except-perhaps-the-kangaroo/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 18:29:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Roller Derby International Rankings for 2014: An Analysis</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the back of &lt;a title="Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup – the Wrap Up." href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/12/blood-thunder-world-cup-the-wrap-up/"&gt;our attempts&lt;/a&gt; at a more neutral ranking scheme for the World Cup national teams, and some subsequent conversation on the Rollerderby subreddit and Twitter, we've made a few tweaks to our ranking algorithm, and fed it the games from &lt;a href="http://euroderbytournament.eu/"&gt;European Roller Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://rollinnews.com/post/derbyscores-27th-october-2014"&gt;Road To Dallas&lt;/a&gt; as well as the World Cup games it had before.
[Technical notes: we've been persuaded that the topological sorting constraint is overly aggressive in asserting groupings from the initial ground truth, which adds some inflexible structure to the sort, so instead we iterate the inference rankings to self-consistency and sort on the relative strengths in the self-consistent inference matrix, using the final inferences only. Code for this has been added to the &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/ranking-chain-inference/"&gt;repository &lt;/a&gt;here. ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hear that there was some controversy on our previous rankings being published, although none of the teams have actually contacted us to make any comment. (The only actual direct comments we've had have been from people expressing interest in the statistical methods used, which were chosen to be neutral. In fact, this article was written partly on the request of a number of people to see what the inclusion of additional datasets did to our ranking calculations.) We, of course, welcome any criticism of our methods and discussion of the results of our analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to allay any possible sense of bias being present in what was designed as a neutral computational statistical ranking, we have also calculated the least squares rankings for the National Teams from the same data set (plus the Italy v Switzerland result from the same timeframe), with both score difference and log(score ratio)&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; rankings. In this, we follow &lt;a href="http://www.masseyratings.com/theory/massey97.pdf"&gt;Massey&lt;/a&gt;, considering that least squares rankings are generally held to be amongst the most accurate ranking methods for predictive sports ranking.&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Technical notes: The approach used for least squares ranking was to form the usual matrix of games from Massey, but rescaling scores on the 40 minute bouts by 60/40 to estimate the score difference in a full game. For score ratios, this was not necessary, as ratios are scale-invariant measures (which is the reason we decided to use them for our metric), but we do provide the same capping of blowouts as if the zero-scoring team really scored 1/2 a point as we do in our own measure. In the National Teams dataset, this only affects the Sweden-Japan game: altering the game to give a single point to Japan instead does not affect the final placement of Sweden by the ranking, although it does adjust their predicted power. We prepared data using python scripts for processing in GNU Octave for the least squares fit; the scripts used are also available in the same repository as our ranking code.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our modified iterative ranking predicts the following ranking of teams, with the old algorithm by the side of it for comparison and the Least Squares ranks in addition&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;. We've colour coded the teams by their divergence from the official B&amp;amp;T World Cup rankings for interest (&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;Black&lt;/span&gt; is the same as B&amp;amp;T, &lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;Green&lt;/span&gt; is higher ranked than B&amp;amp;T, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;Red&lt;/span&gt; is lower ranked than B&amp;amp;T).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Topological Sort (old model)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Iterative consistency (new model)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Least Squares Rank with respect to Score Difference
(Power is expected score diff)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Least Squares Rank with respect to Score Ratio
(Power is expected score ratio)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;1. USA&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 2. England&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 3. Australia&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 4. Canada&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 5. Finland&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;6. Sweden&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;7. Scotland&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;8. Argentina&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;9. Ireland&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;10. France&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;11. Germany&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;12. NewZealand&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;13. Belgium&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;14. Norway&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;15. Netherlands&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;16. WestIndies&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;17. Wales&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;18. Denmark&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;19. Colombia&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;20. Spain&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;21. Greece&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;22. Brazil&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;23. Chile&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;24. Italy&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;25. Mexico&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;26. Portugal&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;27. SouthAfrica&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;28. Japan&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;29. PuertoRico&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;30. Switzerland&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;1. USA&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 2. England&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 3. Australia&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;4. Sweden&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;5. Canada&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;6. NewZealand&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;7. Finland&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;8. France&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;9. Ireland&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;10. Germany&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;11. Scotland&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;12. Argentina&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;13. Netherlands&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;14. Belgium&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;15. Spain&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;16. Norway&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;17. Wales&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;18. Chile&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;19. Denmark&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;20. WestIndies&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;21. Colombia&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;22. Greece&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;23. Brazil&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;24. SouthAfrica&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;25. Portugal&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;26. PuertoRico&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;27. Mexico&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;28. Switzerland&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;29. Italy&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;30. Japan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;1. USA 0.0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 2. England -191.00&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 3. Australia -213.273&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 4. Canada -294.666&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;5. Sweden -380.901&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;6. Finland -460.143&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;7. NewZealand -465.461&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;8. France -539.895&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;9. Germany -554.373&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt; 10. Scotland -567.636&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;11. Argentina -570.828&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;12. Ireland -572.967&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;13. Belgium -721.009&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;14. Norway -729.422&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;15. Spain -743.184&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt; 16. Chile -744.361&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;17. Wales -748.199&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;18. Denmark -752.251&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;19. Netherlands -759.382&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;20. Colombia -768.326&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;21. WestIndies -788.968&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;22. Mexico -870.077&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;23. Greece -886.9503&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;24. Portugal -887.2898&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;25. SouthAfrica -893.530&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;26. Brazil -895.490&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;27. PuertoRico -944.083&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;28. Switzerland -955.1116&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt; 29. Italy -975.691&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt; 30. Japan -1062.202&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;1. USA 1.0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 2. England 0.3009&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 3. Australia 0.2700&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;4. Sweden 0.1516&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;5. Canada 0.1317&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;6. NewZealand 0.06539&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;7. Finland 0.05634&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;8. France 0.04562&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;9. Ireland 0.04243&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;10. Germany 0.04091&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt; 11. Scotland 0.03381&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;12. Argentina 0.03077&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;13. Belgium 0.01542&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;14. Netherlands 0.01384&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;15. Norway 0.01355&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;16. Chile 0.01341&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;17. Wales 0.01295&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;18. Denmark 0.01169&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;19. Spain 0.01157&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;20. WestIndies 0.01128&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;21. Colombia 0.009998&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;22. Greece 0.006950&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;23. Brazil 0.005783&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;24. Portugal 0.005648&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;25. SouthAfrica 0.005354&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;26. Mexico 0.005206&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;27. PuertoRico 0.005150&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;28. Switzerland 0.004456&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;29. Italy 0.003946&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;30. Japan 0.001298&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
All rankings show that there are groupings of teams with extremely close strength (for example (Canada,Sweden), (Scotland, Ireland, Argentina) and (England, Australia) ), but there are elements of disagreement in precise ranking.
&lt;p&gt;We also see that it is still unambiguous that Germany was unfairly relegated from the Top 16 due to poor group selection in the World Cup (another three big upward movers that we missed before are Spain,  Greece and Chile, with Spain looking like another possible-Top-16). We're particularly impressed by the performance of Greece, as they had very little practice time before the World Cup itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The "amount of divergence" from the B&amp;amp;T tournament ranking increases as we move away from the top ranks, which is &lt;a href="https://www.cerge-ei.cz/pdf/wp/Wp252.pdf"&gt;precisely as expected&lt;/a&gt; for a single-elimination tournament ranking. (The case of Wales, which is incongruous in being ranked precisely as B&amp;amp;T does for all of the rankings, is probably due to it being a pivot point, on the edge of the Top16 ranking. As our rankings are all tournament-neutral, there's a tendency for teams to shuffle ranking relative to the tournament, pivoting around the tournament boundaries. We also see this around the Top 8 boundary, with more fuzz due to the higher concordance with the B&amp;amp;T rankings in general. That is: this apparent structure is a reflection of the tournament structure itself, rather than the ranking methods here, which are structureless except for the Topological Sort.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, the pure ratio based models (our new model and log(ratio) least squares) agree with high correlation for the majority of the table, with the ranks around the 15th to 19th positions showing the worst concordance. As both methods are global optimisation schemes, we'd expect them to agree substantially on the rankings, given the same metric; the least squares method has the advantage of executing substantially more quickly! The topological sort has the highest rank disagreement with the other models, although it agrees with some general properties of the ordering (it is the only sort to agree generally with some of the B&amp;amp;T Cup ranking properties, as it tends to lower the rank of teams who played less games, a property enforced on some teams by the tournament structure itself). The linear score difference least squares is also surprisingly congruent with the ratio-based metrics, outside of a few anomalies like the lower placement of the Netherlands, and it does tend to uprank and downrank the same teams as the ratio methods, relative to the B&amp;amp;T tournament ranks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pattern of up and down ranked teams in the 8-16 rank positions, with substantial agreement across all of the three latter rankings, is largely consequence of the "score difference from last bout" ranking chosen by B&amp;amp;T. As we mentioned in other comments, there are issues with such a ranking mechanism, as score-difference is only a measure of the &lt;em&gt;relative&lt;/em&gt; skill difference between two teams, not an &lt;em&gt;absolute&lt;/em&gt; measure. As the difference in skill in the top 8 is unambiguously large, the score difference for 8-16 rank teams can be dominated by which of the Top 8 teams they played, rather than the actual difference in skill within the 8-16 rank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the basis of this comparison, and for additional interest, we also calculated Least Squares rankings for the Men's National Teams who attended the Men's Roller Derby World Cup 2014. Again, we've colour coded for alterations relative to the official tournament rankings; as the MRDWC2014 allowed draws for 7th and 11th places, we've half-coloured teams which are ranked in the "7,8"th places or "11,12"th places when MRDWC2014 assigned them to the drawn 7th and 11th positions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rank with respect to Score Difference(Power is expected score difference)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rank with respect to Score Ratio(Power is expected score ratio)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;1. USA 0.0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 2. England -160.067&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 3. Canada -196.457&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 4. France -288.076&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 5. Australia -414.936&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 6. Wales -425.478&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;7. Argentina -490.412&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;8. Finland -566.641&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;9. Scotland -573.354&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;10. Ireland -576.750&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;11. Belgium -676.660&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;12. Germ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;any -723.834&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;13. Netherlands -738.020&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;14. Sweden -788.960&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 15. Japan -905.176&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;1. USA 1.0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 2. England 0.273&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 3. Canada 0.267&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 4. France 0.132&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 5. Australia 0.0664&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; 6. Wales 0.0531&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;7. Argentina 0.0394&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;8. Scotl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;and 0.0271&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;9. Ireland 0.0236&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;10. Finland 0.0147&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;11. Belgium 0.0136&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;12. Nether&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;lands 0.00898&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;13. Germany 0.00791&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;14. Japan 0.00630&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;15. Sweden 0.00491&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
As can be seen, despite being a single-elimination tournament, with relatively unknown team rankings, MRDWC2014 did remarkably well at ranking its teams compared with post-hoc statistical methods - even the differences in ranking are almost all 1 position shifts! This is partly because the tournament was half as big, of course, which makes ranking geometrically easier. It was also, however, because the tournament design was explicitly constructed with proper ranking in mind (this can be seen in the refusal to separate the drawn 7th, 11th positions on the principle that the paired teams never played each other, and so there is no ground truth to separate them), which helped to ameliorate the deficiencies of the single-elimination format. (Splitting the difference between the two least squares methods would seem to suggest that Ireland/Scotland/Finland deserve a three way tie for 8th place, and Germany/Netherlands should be tied for 12th rather than 11th, but these are small divergences from the tournament ranking.) This ranking, of course, does not include any other games outside the MRDWC2014, and so should only be considered representative of the state of the teams at that time.
&lt;p&gt;Returning to the Women's National Teams, our main conclusion is that we would really like to see Canada play Sweden at some point in the near future (and Finland take on Sweden in a rematch). In general, we'd like to promote the use of fairer ranking schemes, and more thought in planning large tournaments in order to encourage the fairer ranking of those competing. The example of MRDWC2014 shows that it is quite possible to manage a tournament, with care, to maximise the neutrality of the contest, whilst still admitting other constraints (such as getting teams from different geographical locations to play each other).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;We have to use log(score ratio) for a least squares regression to make the measure linear. This issue with the linearity requirement was one reason we didn't adopt a least squares method for our initial inference model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;For example, &lt;a href="http://www.math.duke.edu/~idrayer/2012REU.pdf"&gt;Sports Rankings REU Final Report 2012&lt;/a&gt; notes that least squares minimisation provides the most accurate predictive rankings for Basketball and Football out of all of the (non-simulational) methods they compare, and the &lt;a href="http://www.mathaware.org/mam/2010/essays/ChartierBracketology.pdf"&gt;Bracketology review&lt;/a&gt; of College Basketball rankings and this &lt;a href="http://www.science.uva.nl/onderwijs/honours-ai/201314/Sport_Rating_Systems.pdf"&gt;comprehensive analysis of ranking predictive systems&lt;/a&gt; across many sports also show that "Massey"/least squares methods have good predictive power. Even in a comparison of &lt;a href="http://www.few.vu.nl/~zszlavik/papers/IJAPR.pdf"&gt;football team prediction&lt;/a&gt;, where home-team advantage is not modelled by simple Massey predictions, it is still one of the best "simple" models tested. This is unsurprising&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;, as least squares regression is one of the most tested means of statistical modelling of (linear) functions in modern science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;Of course, least squares methods, like our inference scheme, assume that "superiority at a game" is a transitive condition, which is not necessarily true in sports (you can imagine a team whose tactics are simply ill-suited to an opponent of similar ability). However, the real world performance tests of the method suggest that transitivity does hold strongly enough in many sports for least squares methods to provide good metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com"&gt;FlatTrackStats&lt;/a&gt; uses &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elo_rating_system"&gt;Elo&lt;/a&gt; ranking methods instead, which do not assume transitivity, and have similar performance properties to Massey least squares rankings (the &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/about/algorithm/detailed"&gt;FTS algorithm&lt;/a&gt; uses a normalised score difference method, slightly different to our pure ratio, to determine team strength, for the same "scale-invariance" property that we value&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;, and also apply a non-Gaussian error estimator). Elo rankings tend to perform better with lots of contests between players, as the estimator works by "transferring" points from a losing team to a winning one. This also means that it scales better with huge numbers of contests - it's a good choice for FTS to use, given the size of their bout database. Global estimator methods, like linear least squares, are better suited to tournament style prediction, however, where the number of contest pairs is small compared to the total space, and the games are all played in a relatively short timeframe (and there's no home-field advantage). The supplied python scripts also generate a ranking based on the FTS normalised score difference using least squares optimisation, so the interested reader can generate the pseudo FTS ranking themselves. We don't publish it here to avoid filling the table with too many very similar results (the rankings produced are generally half-way between the score difference and pure ratio least squares rankings, with the only significant deviation being a particularly low estimated ranking for Portugal, which we don't really understand).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;Direct evidence in favour of scale-invariant ratio measures like log(ratio) and FTS style "normalised score difference" comes from the Men's Roller Derby World Cup. Belgium and Japan faced each other twice during the tournament, once in the group stage and once in a full length bout, as did Germany and Ireland. Computing the ratio of scores and the normalised difference of scores for both bouts produces estimated relative strengths for the two teams which match very well (almost perfectly for Germany/Ireland, and within 20% for Belgium/Japan, where we would expect a higher disparity due to Japan's own rapid skill development). Computing the score difference does much more poorly (off by 100%+ in both cases)!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>articles</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>statistics</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 13:48:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blood &amp; Thunder World Cup - the Wrap Up.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/12/blood-thunder-world-cup-the-wrap-up/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, as you read this, you'll all know that, while Team USA once again took 1st Place in a roller derby tournament, they were forced to work hard for it by both 2nd place England and 3rd place Australia (Australia's record low score differential against USA only being beaten by England's own score differential against the Americans hours later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike many of the commentators, we at the blog were elated but unsurprised by England and Australia's performance. England had previously beaten Canada this year (at &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/43950"&gt;Super Brawl of Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; ) rather convincingly, and there was no particular reason to believe they couldn't repeat the performance a second time. Australia's team this year was looking exceptionally strong as well, with much more participation from Victorian Roller Derby, who are by far the strongest of the Australian leagues, with impressive performances in the USA this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've done some post-facto analysis of the scores across the World Cup, and we've convinced ourselves that the available evidence supports the result of the tournament in placing England in 2nd (although we'd love to see Australia play England just to eliminate any doubt).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full technical description of the process we adopted is &lt;a href="http://aoanla.wordpress.com/2014/12/12/ranking-the-bt-world-cup-2014/"&gt;over here&lt;/a&gt; on the author's occasional personal Wordpress to save space here. Associated with this is &lt;a href="http://aoanla.wordpress.com/2014/12/12/a-poor-system/"&gt;another essay&lt;/a&gt; explaining just why the Group+Single-elimination tournament structure chosen by the Cup has these ranking problems, and why, in particular, Germany is so horribly done by in the official B&amp;amp;T rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After our extensive statistical analysis, however, we are happy to pronounce our Global Power ranking as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;England&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Australia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canada&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sweden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scotland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Argentina&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NewZealand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Belgium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ireland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;France&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colombia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Germany&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Denmark&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greece&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brazil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Norway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WestIndies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Netherlands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Italy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portugal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mexico&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SouthAfrica&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switzerland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PuertoRico&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Japan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note that this is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to say that the Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup rankings are &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt; - they are simply the rankings of how teams performed &lt;em&gt;in the World Cup&lt;/em&gt;. Our ranking is an attempt to rank the National Teams in terms of how relatively good they are globally, which is not the same thing.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team scotland</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/12/blood-thunder-world-cup-the-wrap-up/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 20:34:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Roller Derby World Cup - Day 3 Review</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/07/roller-derby-world-cup-day-3-review/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 3 of the second ever Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup was devoted to the first stage of the Elimination round, along with the completion of the Consolation bouts for those teams not finishing in the top of their group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, due to the pairing of Group #1 seeds against Group #2 seeds in the Elimination bracket, it has to be said that the closest and most exciting bouts of the day were mostly in the Consolation round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While they seemed less certain in the first period, Team Japan pulled out easily the best performance of their tournament in the second period of their Consolation bout against Mexico, really showing how much they've developed as a team over the past few days (even if both teams had an overflowing penalty board by the end of the game...).  Switzerland v Italy was a very close to-and-fro game, especially in the first period. Once again, accumulated penalties told on both teams, and Italy pulled ahead for the win in Period 2. And Denmark v Portugal once again repeated the same story - a close first period, with Denmark turning on the gas in the second to secure a convincing win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over in the Elimination bouts, Norway, West Indies and Brasil all had predictably crushing bouts against the probable top three in the tournament; USA, England and Canada. Brasil managed to score an impressive 75 points against Canada, however, showing what a great team they've become since the 2011 Cup!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweden, New Zealand, Finland and Argentina had less easy groups to win, but triumphed over Ireland, Netherlands, Belgium, France in the end. Of these, the Argentina v France bout was the only truly close bout of the Top 16 playoffs, with the result completely unpredictable during the first period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rankings going into the Final 8 being determined by score difference in the previous single bout, this close Argentina win rather sealed their fate, as the #8 Seed must play #1, the dominant USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over to Scotland, however, where our team was unlucky enough to be drawn against Australia, #4 placed team from 2011, and probable #3 or #4 place contestors in this tournament. It was a difficult first period for Scotland, with some incredible displays of blocking and jamming on track; however, Australia managed to control the lead jammer position for the entire first period, preventing Scotland's excellence from doing anything other than limiting Aussie scoring. In the very last jam of the period, a star pass to Kerr during a leadless jam, allowed a literal last-second score, putting a single point on the board for Scotland!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejuvenated by breaking their duck, Scotland returned to the 2nd Period determined to mix it up. Liston, jamming for the first time in the game (tournament?), picked up the first lead jammer call for Scotland during the opening (power) jam and the first grand slam pass seconds later. This was the start of a much more confident play by Scotland, with Gow taking a natural lead jammer call soon after, although being forced to call after a single scoring pass after a block knocked her face first into the concrete floor (this also put her out of action in the line-up while she was checked out by the medics). A few power jams for both teams (including a couple of jams where both Scotland and Australia's jammers headed to the box simultaneously), and the Australian blocking mostly told, despite sterling blocking by Maclean, Davis, Liston, Parry (until she fouled out), Cider, Kerr, Simpson and Skinner in particular on the Scottish team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, a scrappy final jam featuring more alternating jammer penalties, brought the score to 464-35 for a deserved Australia win, but a hard fought one against Scotland's resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the quarter final, then, the drawing of high seeds against low continued to produce some predictable blowouts, with USA destroying Argentina just like they destroyed everyone else in the tournament, and England taking a very convincing win over Sweden. Being closer to the middle of the seeds, the Canada - Finland and Australia - New Zealand bouts were slightly less one sided, with Finland standing up pretty well to the #3 seed and taking home 145 pts to Canada's 290.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USA will play #4 seed Australia today, before number #2 and #3 seeds England and Canada duke it out. The winners will go through to the Final, while the losers will play for 3rd place in a last minute change to the schedule (check our&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/10/bloodthunder-world-cup-timings-uk/"&gt; UK timetable&lt;/a&gt; for the accurate timings).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, a brief digression for a slightly controversial statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blood and Thunder's official "Knockout standings" (which are based on the score differentials only for the Group of 16 bouts, as far as we can tell) are [taken from their Facebook page]:
OFFICIAL KNOCKOUT ROUND STANDINGS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team USA Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team England Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Canada B&amp;amp;T World Cup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Australia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team New Zealand Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Finland (Roller Derby)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Sweden Rollerderby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selección Argentina de Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team France Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Ireland Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Belgium Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Netherlands - Women's Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Scotland Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roller Derby Brasil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team West Indies - Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Norway Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, the Top 8 rankings may change based on the games still to play (although we at the Blog believe that England &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; have a strong chance to beat Canada to 2nd place).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's more problematic is that the placements in the bottom 8, including Scotland, are apparently based only on a single score differential, so teams like Norway, Scotland, West Indies and Brasil are penalised by taking on the eventual number 1-4 seeds in their only rank-contributing bout.
We at the Blog disagree strongly with this ranking approach, as it can be shown to underrank those 4 teams - the highest rank Scotland could expect would be 12, under this approach, which they have been assigned.
In the particular case of Scotland, it rankles more, however, as, if we compare the results of Scotland v Finland in the group stage (126-78 for Finland, a 2/3 length bout), and the results of Belgium v Finland in the Elimination stage (383:124 for Finland), it is very clear that Scotland should be ranked above Belgium. Based on other pairwise score-comparison considerations, we believe that Scotland's "true" rank in the tournament is probably &lt;strong&gt;10th&lt;/strong&gt;, narrowly ranked just above Ireland (who Scotland beat not long ago at the Road to Dallas tournament). We believe Norway is strongly penalised by their matching against USA as well, and think their rank should also be at least 2 higher than it actually is in the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full score table for the day is below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SATURDAY, DECEMBER 6, 2014
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(FULL 60 MINUTE BOUTS)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 1 (ROLL-LINE TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 2 (BLOOD &amp;amp; THUNDER TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 3 (TBD TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 7-1 (&lt;strong&gt;Canada 581&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 2-2 (Brazil 75)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 3-1 (&lt;strong&gt;Sweden 303&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 6-2 (Ireland 133)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 3 ( Japan 114) VS. 4 (&lt;strong&gt;Mexico 278&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 1-1 (&lt;strong&gt;NZ 356&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 8-2 (Netherlands 91)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 8-1 (&lt;strong&gt;USA 854&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 1-2 (Norway 6)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 2 ( Switzerland 136) VS. 5 (&lt;strong&gt;Italy 193&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 2-1 (France 162) VS. GR 7-2 (&lt;strong&gt;Argentina 205&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 4-1 (&lt;strong&gt;Finland 383&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 5-2 (Belgium 124)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 3 (&lt;strong&gt;Wales 395&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. 6 (Puerto Rico 75)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 5-1 (&lt;strong&gt;Australia 464&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 4-2 (Scotland 35)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 6-1 (&lt;strong&gt;England 708&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 3-2 (West Indies 31)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 2 (Portugal 135) VS. 7 (&lt;strong&gt;Denmark 245&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TEAM 1 (&lt;strong&gt;USA&lt;/strong&gt; 569) VS. TEAM 8 (Argentina 14)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TEAM 3 (&lt;strong&gt;Canada&lt;/strong&gt; 290) VS. TEAM 6 (Finland 145)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 1 (Chile 116) VS. 8 (&lt;strong&gt;Germany&lt;/strong&gt;330)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;01:00AM(SUN)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TEAM 3 (&lt;strong&gt;England&lt;/strong&gt; 278) VS. TEAM 7 (Sweden 72)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TEAM 4 (&lt;strong&gt;Australia&lt;/strong&gt; 284) VS. TEAM 5 (New Zealand 56)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;01:10AM(SUN)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 7 (&lt;strong&gt;Denmark&lt;/strong&gt; 332) VS. 8 (Puerto Rico 169)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>articles</category><category>blood and thunder world cup 2014</category><category>bout reports</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/07/roller-derby-world-cup-day-3-review/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 09:05:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Roller Derby World Cup Day 2 - Review</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/06/roller-derby-world-cup-day-2-review/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a second exciting day of Group bouts, here's what our table looked like:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NEW ZEALAND 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FRANCE 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SWEDEN 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FINLAND 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AUSTRALIA 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ENGLAND 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CANADA 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;USA 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NORWAY 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SWITZERLAND 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WEST INDIES 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SCOTLAND 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ITALY 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GERMANY 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DENMARK 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PUERTO RICO 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SOUTH AFRICA 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BRAZIL 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;JAPAN 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COLOMBIA 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BELGIUM 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SPAIN 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ARGENTINA 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;THE NETHERLANDS 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WALES 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PORTUGAL 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CHILE 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MEXICO 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GREECE 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;IRELAND 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
As a correction from yesterday, it appears that the labelling on the official schedule confused us: any team not in the top 2 in their group pass through to the Consolation round, with one game each (except those in Group 7 and 8 who get two games, as there's only one of them for each Group, and they got less Group games in total). Our UK and Japan time schedules are now updated to reflect that fact.
&lt;p&gt;So, on to the Derby: As is often the case for the second round of groups, most of the really tight games were in the second day. That said, we started with Finland, Australia and England getting the blow-outs that we expected against Mexico, Greece and Ireland (not to say the latter are poor teams, but the former are really exceptional).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fighting it out for the second place in their group brought grit to the Switzerland v Brasil bout, with Brasil just pulling out the edge in an exciting bout (one for the archives if you missed it). While West Indies won both their bouts (against Japan and Chile) to put themselves into the second position in Group 3, neither of their opponents disgraced themselves, with Japan showing how much they'd learned just in the previous day of play, and Chile holding on until the very last jam!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On to Scotland:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned yesterday, Scotland needed to beat Colombia in order to make it through to the Elimination round. While Colombia had periods of control on the track, taking lead jammer mostly when Scotland had a blocker deficit on track, and both teams suffered some penalty issues (there were jams for both teams where they had to cope with having only a single blocker on track), Scotland's excellent pack work, lead by Maclean, Skinner, Parry, Cider, and Davis and Kerr, told in the end ('Splat' Kerr developed a particular skill for knocking Colombian jammers out of attempted apex jumps). Despite a tired O'Carroll and her Colombian opponent spending the second-last jam taking two trips to the penalty box each, in general the Scottish jamming was also excellent, with Gow, Rogue, Hyndman and O'Carroll all able to trust their blockers, and get on with dedicating their skill to scoring. In the end, the balance of jammer penalties, and the superior track control when there was no pack deficit against them, told in Scotland's favour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scotland will play the mighty Australia on Track 1 at 9pm UK time today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belgium, Netherlands, Ireland and England, the other teams in the tournament featuring Scottish skaters, also made it through to the Elimination stage. Belgium, Netherlands and Ireland, being 2nd in their groups, face tough 1st Group place opponents today in Finland, New Zealand, Sweden, while England, having easily taken their 1st Group place, have the West Indies as their first opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Match ups in the second stage of the elimination are to be decided by the overall score difference after the first round, so even a close game could make all the difference (for the winner) for a better draw in the Quarter Final later on in the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the final Group bouts, the schedule managed to sneak in a few more special games: the first two Consolation bouts, with Colombia triumphing over Greece, and Spain taking their first win of the tournament over South Africa. We suspect that many of the viewers were tuned into the Vagine Regime Expo bout on Track 3, however, where PanGina pulled ahead from a close half time score versus Queerope to take a commanding win in the second period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day concluded with another Expo of top skill, the Team USA "Stars and Stripes" bout, where Stars took the close win against Stripes 134:129.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRIDAY, DECEMBER 5, 2014  (40 MINUTE BOUTS)
&lt;/strong&gt;CONSOLATION BOUTS ARE FULL 60 MINUTE BOUTS
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 1 (ROLL-LINE TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 2 (BLOOD &amp;amp; THUNDER TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 3 (TBD TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FINLAND&lt;/strong&gt; (312) VS. MEXICO (38)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AUSTRALIA&lt;/strong&gt; (449) VS. GREECE (17)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENGLAND&lt;/strong&gt; (329) VS. IRELAND (50)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:20PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NORWAY (219)&lt;/strong&gt; VS. SOUTH AFRICA (80)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SWITZERLAND (108) VS. &lt;strong&gt;BRAZIL &lt;/strong&gt;(120)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:30PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WEST INDIES&lt;/strong&gt; (235) VS. JAPAN (70)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:40PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NEW ZEALAND&lt;/strong&gt; (250) VS. WALES (60)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRANCE&lt;/strong&gt; (310) VS. PORTUGAL (36)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:50PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SWEDEN&lt;/strong&gt; (296) VS. CHILE (39)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCOTLAND&lt;/strong&gt; (230) VS. COLOMBIA (53)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ITALY (86)VS. &lt;strong&gt;BELGIUM &lt;/strong&gt;(273)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GERMANY&lt;/strong&gt; (216) VS. SPAIN (70)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8:20PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DENMARK (85) VS. &lt;strong&gt;ARGENTINA &lt;/strong&gt;(202)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PUERTO RICO (154) VS. &lt;strong&gt;NETHERLANDS &lt;/strong&gt;(209)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8:30PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WEST INDIES&lt;/strong&gt; (104) VS. CHILE (100)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 4 (&lt;strong&gt;Colombia 305&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. 5 (Greece 136)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 6 (South Africa 143) VS. 1 (&lt;strong&gt;Spain 227&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;VAGINE REGIME EXPO BOUT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;00:00 (MIDNIGHT)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TEAM USA STARS VS. STRIPES EXPO&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>blood and thunder world cup 2014</category><category>bout reports</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/06/roller-derby-world-cup-day-2-review/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2014 07:57:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blood and Thunder World Cup Day 1 Review</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/05/blood-and-thunder-world-cup-day-1-review/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, that was exciting. 27 games in the placement groups, lead to the scores in the groups now sitting as below (assuming one point for each win):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BRACKET STRUCTURE COURTESY OF THE WOMENS FLAT TRACK DERBY ASSOCIATION (DAY 1)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NEW ZEALAND 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FRANCE 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SWEDEN 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FINLAND 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AUSTRALIA 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ENGLAND 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CANADA 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;USA 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NORWAY 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SWITZERLAND 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WEST INDIES 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SCOTLAND 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ITALY 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GERMANY 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DENMARK 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PUERTO RICO 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SOUTH AFRICA 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BRAZIL 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;JAPAN 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COLOMBIA 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BELGIUM 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SPAIN 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ARGENTINA 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;THE NETHERLANDS 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WALES 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PORTUGAL 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CHILE 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MEXICO 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GREECE 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;IRELAND 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
While &lt;a href="http://www.derbycentral.net/2014/12/2014-roller-derby-world-cup-central/"&gt;Derby Central&lt;/a&gt; is working hard on a more complete review of the day, we'll try to summarise a bit before we talk about Scotland.
&lt;p&gt;We believe that the structure for the tournament is that the 4th-placed team in any group will drop out after the group rounds, the 3rd position will take the Consolation position with the same number as their group, and the 1st and 2nd positions will enter the Elimination rounds to play for ranking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, New Zealand, France, Sweden, Finland, Australia, Ireland, Canada and the USA are all safely through to the Elimination rounds already, as 2pts would already place them all at 1st or 2nd place in their group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South Africa, Switzerland, Mexico, Italy are probably already "out" after losing both their games, with only a tough game left today, although Switzerland have a chance at winning their game v Brazil and bringing their group to a points-difference call; West Indies and Japan will play to see which of them gets into the Consolation round for their group today, as will Germany &amp;amp; Spain, Denmark &amp;amp; Argentina, Puerto Rico &amp;amp; The Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Scotland in particular, they played two bouts on Thursday:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some brilliant play against Mexico, Team Scotland picked up their important first win, displaying good control of the track for the entire 40 minute game. Beautiful jamming from Jenny "Attackbar" Gow, Marshall Lawless and Rogue Runner in particular, with Mexico's jammers overwhelmed by the usual solid play by "Crazylegs" Parry, Ciderella, (Steph) Skinner Alive, "Splat" Kerr, and Grace "Mona" Maclean on the blocking side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finland proved a tougher test for Scotland, as they were always going to be. Nevertheless, the scores after the first half were within 15 points of each other, and it looked like Scotland were still within reach of a win. After Finland's Mia, jamming, gave away 3 power jams in a row, it looked even more achievable, despite some very hard blocking from Finland making it hard for any of Scotland's talented jammers to pick up points. However, some excellent performances from Finland's star jammer, SuperMaria, and a little penalty trouble, kept Finland's lead ahead, resulting in a Scotland loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 1 pt in the group, Scotland will enter the Consolation round if they fail to defeat Colombia today at 7pm. Given Finland's performance against the Colombians, however, it seems most likely that Scotland will prevail, gaining the 2nd point in the group to place them into the Elimination round as the 2nd place seed from Group 4. (This makes them very likely to play Australia as their first opponent!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of Team Scotland, but still involving Scottish Players: Auld Reekie's Lilo &amp;amp; Stitches contributed strongly to Belgium's jamming line up (under the first part of her birth surname, deBuyl), and Sarah McMillan and Chemikill Hazard were big parts of Ireland's lineups. Jen Sykes, who spent some time down in London, still counts as a Scottish skater now she's up in Glasgow again, and she did her usual sterling work as part of the mighty English team, and Crazily Insanne at least got to play against the USA as part of Team Netherlands (although of course, no-one is going to &lt;em&gt;defeat&lt;/em&gt; team USA!). Scottish referee Righteous Oxide was also spotted officiating several of the bouts, and Granite City's smacklemore was in evidence commentating (including on the Scotland/Finland game).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our full score matrix from Day One is below (&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/33509"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt; are also tracking scores as usual):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THURSDAY, DECEMBER 4, 2014  (40 MINUTE BOUTS)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 1 (ROLL-LINE TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 2 (BLOOD &amp;amp; THUNDER TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 3 (TBD TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NEW ZEALAND&lt;/strong&gt; (218) VS. NORWAY (59)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AUSTRALIA&lt;/strong&gt; (513) VS ITALY (5)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CANADA&lt;/strong&gt; (290) VS. ARGENTINA (50)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:20PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SOUTH AFRICA (97) VS. &lt;strong&gt;WALES &lt;/strong&gt;(200)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BELGIUM&lt;/strong&gt;  (174) VS. GREECE (96)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:30PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;USA&lt;/strong&gt; (505) VS. NETHERLANDS (15)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:40PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRANCE&lt;/strong&gt; (369) VS. SWITZERLAND (27)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENGLAND&lt;/strong&gt; (272) VS. GERMANY (31)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:50PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FINLAND&lt;/strong&gt; (248) VS. COLOMBIA (32)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BRAZIL&lt;/strong&gt; (167) VS. PORTUGAL (144)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SPAIN (74) VS. &lt;strong&gt;IRELAND &lt;/strong&gt;(203)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCOTLAND&lt;/strong&gt; (207) VS. MEXICO (45)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8:20PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SWEDEN&lt;/strong&gt; (319) VS. WEST INDIES (41)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CANADA&lt;/strong&gt; (301) VS. DENMARK (23)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8:30PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AUSTRALIA&lt;/strong&gt; (349)VS. BELGIUM (24)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9:40PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;JAPAN (53) VS. &lt;strong&gt;CHILE&lt;/strong&gt; (296)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;USA&lt;/strong&gt; (637) VS. PUERTO RICO (3)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9:50PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ITALY (82) VS. &lt;strong&gt;GREECE &lt;/strong&gt;(125)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FINLAND&lt;/strong&gt; (126) VS. SCOTLAND (78)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NEW ZEALAND (315)&lt;/strong&gt; VS. SOUTH AFRICA (15)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENGLAND&lt;/strong&gt; (290) VS. SPAIN (20)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;00:20AM(FRI)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COLOMBIA&lt;/strong&gt; (163) VS. MEXICO (75)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NORWAY&lt;/strong&gt; (150) VS. WALES (105)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;00:30AM(FRI)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GERMANY (129) VS. &lt;strong&gt;IRELAND&lt;/strong&gt; (142)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;01:40AM(FRI)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRANCE&lt;/strong&gt; (315) VS. BRAZIL (14)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SWEDEN&lt;/strong&gt; (459) VS. JAPAN (0)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;01:50AM(FRI)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SWITZERLAND (132) VS. &lt;strong&gt;PORTUGAL&lt;/strong&gt; (139)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>articles</category><category>bout reports</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/05/blood-and-thunder-world-cup-day-1-review/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 12:40:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interviews: Roundup of Roundups</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/14/world-cup-interviews-roundup-of-roundups/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you missed any of our interviews with each of the 30 teams heading for the &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;Blood and Thunder (Women's) Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; in just 2 weeks, here's the links to the round up posts (each of which links to the associated interviews).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interviews: The Americas" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/03/world-cup-interviews-the-americas/"&gt;North and Central America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interviews: South America" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/13/world-cup-interviews-south-america/"&gt;South America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interviews: Northern Europe" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/06/world-cup-interviews-northern-europe/"&gt;Northern Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup 2014: Southern Europe Round-up" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/28/world-cup-2014-southern-europe-round-up/"&gt;Southern Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interviews: Scandinavia" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/27/world-cup-interviews-uk-ireland/"&gt;Scandinavia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup 2014: Africa and Asia-Pacific Round-up" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/22/world-cup-2014-africa-and-asia-pacific-round-up/"&gt;Africa and Asia-Pacific&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interviews: UK and Ireland" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/20/world-cup-interviews-uk-and-ireland/"&gt;United Kingdom and Ireland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and, of course, from earlier today, the &lt;a title="The World Cup: SRDB picks!" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/14/the-world-cup-srdb-picks/"&gt;Blog team's own picks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have also made schedules for the &lt;a title="Blood&amp;amp;Thunder World Cup timings (UK)" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/10/bloodthunder-world-cup-timings-uk/"&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup Timings (Japan)" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/10/blood-thunder-world-cup-timings-japan/"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt; timezones, to help you with the &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com/schedule/"&gt;official schedule&lt;/a&gt; timings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a bit of a break before the World Cup itself, next week we'll be starting some ongoing content on the future of roller derby in various directions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>articles</category><category>blood and thunder world cup 2014</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/14/world-cup-interviews-roundup-of-roundups/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 15:27:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The World Cup: SRDB picks!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/14/the-world-cup-srdb-picks/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spending the last month and a half covering all of the 30 teams heading to the &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup &lt;/a&gt;in less than a month has left all of us at the Blog with anticipation to see what'll happen in Dallas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, with 30 teams, playing up to 3 bouts at a time, everyone will have to make choices as to what to watch and what to miss (at least, until the archives). So, we've spent a bit of time discussing and reflecting, to present to you our personal picks as to the match ups and teams to especially watch, whether you're lucky enough to make it to Texas in person, or are just catching the streams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aoanla&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For their enthusiasm and determination to make it to the World Cup despite their late start, &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Japan [ローラーデービーのワールドカップ：日本のチーム]" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/15/world-cup-interview-team-japan-%e3%83%ad%e3%83%bc%e3%83%a9%e3%83%bc%e3%83%87%e3%83%bc%e3%83%93%e3%83%bc%e3%81%ae%e3%83%af%e3%83%bc%e3%83%ab%e3%83%89%e3%82%ab%e3%83%83%e3%83%97%ef%bc%9a%e6%97%a5/"&gt;Team Japan&lt;/a&gt; deserve a whole host of cheering fans in Dallas. Like the Ninjapan Rollers at MRDWC, I expect them to capture everyone's hearts. (Given &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team West Indies" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/17/world-cup-interview-team-west-indies/"&gt;Team West Indies&lt;/a&gt;' popularity in the UK, they may have a fight for that, however...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Spain" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/23/world-cup-interview-team-spain/"&gt;Team Spain&lt;/a&gt; deserve support just for the travel they've already incurred before even getting to the World Cup. Hopefully the combined forces of Tenerife and Barcelona combine to upset their group a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams Brazil and &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Argentina" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/09/world-cup-interview-team-argentina/"&gt;Argentina&lt;/a&gt; will be interesting to watch, showing off the striking and rapid development of South American derby - which had only just begun at the time of the first World Cup in 2011. I think they may well go very far (and the other South American and Central American teams will also be worth a watch).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Australia" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/18/world-cup-interview-team-australia/"&gt;Australia&lt;/a&gt;, England, Canada and &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team New Zealand" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/19/world-cup-interview-team-new-zealand/"&gt;New Zealand&lt;/a&gt; may be duking it out for the Silver and Bronze medals - although the draw looks like favouring England or Canada for Silver, unless there's an upset earlier in the brackets. Australia could easily upset England or Canada for Bronze, however...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caley&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm really excited to see &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Wales" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/15/world-cup-interview-team-wales/"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt; make their World Cup debut, they feature so many strong skaters that I've seen representing their individual teams and I can't wait to see how they play together! Obviously I can't wait to see &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Scotland" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/16/world-cup-interview-team-scotland/"&gt;Team Scotland&lt;/a&gt; play, especially my team mates Jill Simpson, Carolyn Mackenzie and Jill Stephen and my old Glasgow team mates...I'm at risk of just listing the entire team I'm that excited! I saw a few of their games and they're a fierce team. &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Germany" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/01/world-cup-interview-team-germany/"&gt;Team Germany&lt;/a&gt; are also a favourite of mine, especially after seeing some of the members representing Berlin at Champs. I'm also excited about seeing &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team England" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/17/world-cup-interview-team-england/"&gt;Team England&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Ireland" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/14/world-cup-interview-team-ireland/"&gt;Team Ireland&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Belgium" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/30/world-cup-interview-team-belgium/"&gt;Team Belgium&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Sweden" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/24/world-cup-interview-team-sweden/"&gt;Team Sweden&lt;/a&gt;...basically any team with somebody I know on the roster. It's oddly liberating to fangirl over your pal, mentor, that amazing skater who once looked at you on track and you fell over...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be watching for &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Brasil" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/07/world-cup-interview-team-brasil/"&gt;Team Brazil&lt;/a&gt;, they played in the Roller Derby World Cup in 2011 and some of the team members made their bouting debut during the tournament. They had a fantastic attitude in 2011 and I'm looking forward to seeing how they've grown as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I adore watching teams who are geographically far apart play each other! That's one of the glorious things about gathering all these national teams together. Anything can and will happen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am rather excited about December!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My ‘ones to watch’ are &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Denmark" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/22/world-cup-interview-team-denmark/"&gt;Team Denmark&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Norway" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/21/world-cup-interview-team-norway/"&gt;Team Norway&lt;/a&gt;. Although both are newcomers to the World Cup tournament in 2014, they have both been competing in tournaments in the lead up to Dallas to really learn how to to play as a team. Having played against some of Team Norway when Oslo Roller Derby came to Stirling last year, I’m particularly keen to see Torture and Eda take to the track and give them my support from my armchair!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m also really excited to see &lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Canada" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/30/world-cup-interview-team-canada/"&gt;Team Canada&lt;/a&gt; play again. They fought tirelessly in the 2011 World Cup to come in second place to Team USA - and I’m positive they’ll put up an even stronger fight this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, Team Scotland. There are a lot of new faces on the 2014 roster, but all have definitely earned their sport on the team. I’m particularly looking forward to watching Skinner Alive and Admiral Attackbar from Auld Reekie Roller Girls play. I’m always left exhausted just watching these two skaters, so I’m sure they’ll impress and inspire the many others watching them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>articles</category><category>blood and thunder world cup 2014</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/14/the-world-cup-srdb-picks/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 13:13:34 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>