<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about roller derby world cup calgary 2016)</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/roller-derby-world-cup-calgary-2016.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:54:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Puerto Rico Men's Roller Derby</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/10/mrdwc-2016-team-review-puerto-rico-mens-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Completing our first week of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; team profiles, we have one of the teams new to the Cup: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamPuertoRicoMensRD/"&gt;Puerto Rico Men's Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7699" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/12794452_1968058606751881_850918363325886616_n.png" alt="12794452_1968058606751881_850918363325886616_n" width="526" height="690"&gt; The Team Puerto Rico logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teampuertoricorollerderby/"&gt;Women's Team Puerto Rico&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; attended the &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/33509"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup&lt;/a&gt; in 2014, there was not quite enough interest in Men's Derby for a similar team to form for MRDWC2014. This time around, Team Puerto Rico Men's Roller Derby has been pulled together from Puerto Rican nationals from around the world, as is increasingly the case for "new" National Teams from the smaller nations. There are some great teams providing skaters for Puerto Rico, but as always team cohesion will be the most important factor for a geographically distributed team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Puerto Rico is in &lt;strong&gt;Group Blue&lt;/strong&gt;, with returning teams Belgium, France, Netherlands and Australia. Belgium and Netherlands finished in the lower half of the table last time around; France and Australia did well enough to get through to the placement knockout, placing 4th and 5th in the tournament. With just two teams from each group going through to the knockout with a chance at 1st place, Team Puerto Rico is likely to miss out on the chance at higher rankings - but there's a lot of newer teams in this tournament, and they could place well in the lower half of the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James "Disaster Chief" Wargacki was kind enough to answer some questions for us on the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Puerto Rico are new to the Men's World Cup. What are your aims in the tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;
Our primary goal is proudly represent the island and culture of our families, which have had a particularly unique experience in contributing to the patchwork of the United States. In doing so, we hope that this will spark increased interest in the sport to encourage more Puerto Rican, as well as other Latino, men to put on skates and participate as competitors on the island, in the United States and throughout the Caribbean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;Your Group is full of strong teams, including Australia's Wizards of Aus and Team France (who were 5th and 4th place in 2014). Which teams are you most looking forward to playing (or seeing play)?&lt;/strong&gt;
A: We are looking forward to facing all of the teams in our group. We wish to neither overlook any team, nor subordinate ourselves to others' past performances. We respect the effort that each team has exerted to make it out to the tournament, and hope to bring our best to each game, as we expect from those lace up against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's the level of interest in roller derby in Puerto Rico?&lt;/strong&gt;
Currently, the ladies have several leagues on the island (i.e. Enchanted Island, Rumtown, Wicked Island), along with a team that represented in Dallas, TX at the 2014 World Cup. No men's teams have been formed, as of yet, but we hope that will change in the very near. Male participation in roller derby in Puerto Rico is, at this time, are gentleman serving as referees, along with the handful of skaters attending the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I guess that, like Women's Puerto Rico, you've recruited from Puerto Ricans across the world?&lt;/strong&gt;
We have. A couple of skaters and one of our bench coaches are living in Puerto Rico right now. We also have skaters from New York, New Jersey, Florida, and Arizona. Most of us here in the US still have friends and family living in Puerto Rico as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This year, MRDWC are promoting the lead up to the Cup with the "Road to Calgary" tag. In the spirit of this, what bouts and training have you been doing since the last selection?&lt;/strong&gt;
Due to our geographic limitations, those who get to practice regularly together are in the same league, such as the New York Shock Exchange. When the opportunity presents itself, some individual members have been able to travel and skate in practices and scrimmages with other teammates. This has proven valuable to give skaters the opportunity to become familiar with each other, prior to converging on Calgary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After the last World Cup, several nations saw increased awareness and interest in Roller Derby. What are your hopes for Roller Derby in Puerto Rico?&lt;/strong&gt;
We’re hoping to not only increase awareness about the sport but to also inspire others to give roller derby a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Puerto Rico's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/27/mens-roller-derby-world-cupschedule-timezone-adjusted/"&gt;first bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is against France, the likely Group winners, at 10am Calgary-local-time on Thursday on Track 2, followed by Belgium at 1pm on Track 1. [The official MRDWC schedule is located here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/"&gt;http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Team Puerto Rico roster is:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Samy Franco&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;CoAcH BoOm&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Bustelo, Angel (BUS-TELL-O)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Rivera, Hector&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;11&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;PapiChuleta (PAH-PEE CHU-LEY-TAH)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;18&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Madera (MA-DAY-RAH)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;24&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Flecha (fe-LAY-CHA)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;68&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Rosario, John&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;93&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Tio Danny (TEE-OH DAN-E)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;117&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Disaster Chief&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;275&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Martinez, Angel Andres (MAR-TEEN-EZ&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;414&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Ti-MAN (Tee-MAN)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;5280&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;David Miles Rios (Ree-Ohss)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Bench&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Officer Pain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Bench&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Pirate Booty&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Bench&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Revelyn Sin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>roller derby world cup calgary 2016</category><category>team puerto rico</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/10/mrdwc-2016-team-review-puerto-rico-mens-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 11:02:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>After Action Report: The Power of Scotland Bootcamp, April 2016</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/07/after-action-report-the-power-of-scotland-bootcamp-april-2016/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland"&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; continue on their road to Calgary, they gave the Scottish Roller Derby Community a chance to step into their world last weekend and share their skills, drills and only a few minor spills by hosting a fundraising bootcamp in Dundee. Keen to see exactly what the guys could offer, I snapped up a ticket as soon as they went on sale, and I'm fairly certain that I wasn't only person who was excited to see exactly what was on offer as there was a tremendous turn out.
Unless you have been living under a derby-proof rock, you will be very aware of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/15/power-of-scotland-fundraising-for-calgary/"&gt;amazing efforts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from the whole squad to ensure they arrive in Calgary ready to take on the other participating nations. They've raised money any way they could, from bungee jumping, beard shaving, scrimmage, coaching and selling merchandise at games across the country and now bootcamping (it's a word now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1460057323219.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="wp-1460057323219" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1460057323219.jpg" alt="image" width="1200" height="800"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Photo: &lt;a href="http://lauramacd.co.uk/roller-derby-photography/"&gt;Laura MacDonald&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I am so excited by this bootcamp and possibly why I was asked to write this was my enthusiasm for the fantastic planning and flow of the whole day. These guys didn't throw this together overnight. They even had print-outs! I mean who doesn't love a bit of literature to look back on?! The whole squad pulled together and they really delivered.
The first part of the day was led by the wonderful Nuke. Now, Nuke is a lovely bloke and a fabulous skater to watch and I was very keen on learning from him. Leading the day with agility and footwork he put us through our paces and he stripped everything back to basics - I learned loads. I've skated since 2011/2012 and I had no idea that since mins I had forgotten how to step without my wheels rolling (Don't make me do mins again). The highlight, however, may have been Nuke's tartan leggings &amp;lt;3
Next up we had the lovely Blockbeard with his jamming skills session. Despite the name, everything he went through was very easily transferable to blockers. He broke the session down into evasive, attack and “Blammer” techniques - he really didn't hold back. His session led on from Nuke's agility session perfectly by incorporating the control and agility we had just learned. With an added technique on moving blocker twice your size with just a wee nudge. Thanks Pal!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two solid hours of skating and it was time for lunch and an audience with Optimus Grime, Power of Scotlands very own Viking looking, hard hitting, softy. Those who know Grime, know that he has a background in bodybuilding. Who better to take us through a strength and conditioning seminar with bonus print-outs (I think he has surplus and may as well share). Highlighting some of the confusing things about weight training for performance and making it so easily understood was an incredible addition to the bootcamp. I already mentioned how much I loved the format and this for me was a very welcome aspect to incorporate in. Most people think that just skating will get you where you need to be, but Grime makes sure you know exactly how a little weight training will help improve your game even further, also talking a little about nutrition and the right things to eat pre and post-game/training. The chair demonstrations were also absolutely fabulous. [Editor's note: Optimus Grime's accompanying Mental Strength presentation was cut from the bootcamp due to time, but we have managed to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/07/guest-post-mental-strength-with-power-of-scotlands-optimus-grime/"&gt;publish a copy here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1460057344653.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="wp-1460057344653" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1460057344653.jpg" alt="image" width="1200" height="675"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Skate Plisken and attentive bootcampers. (Photo: &lt;a href="http://lauramacd.co.uk/roller-derby-photography/"&gt;Laura MacDonald&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fuelled up and ready to get back on skates our final session before the mixed scrim was led by Skate Plisken. This session was on effective offence. Plisken took us through a few offence techniques that we have all seen performed by the POS guys recently at scrims and they were most definitely effective. Including the beautifully named “Sausage” technique; I sincerely hope no sausages were offended ( HA!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day wasn't quite over yet; there was still a scrimmage to be had. We had 1 hour to test out everything we had learned over the course of the day with 2 members of POS being gifted to either side as Bench and LUM. Prior to the scrim Nuke and Plisken, who were LUM and Bench for Team White, sat us down and went over basic Scrim strategy. This was excellent; not only were newer skaters getting the chance to scrim but there was also time to talk about strategy, which we all know doesn't come easily. I'm not sure I can express my love for this bootcamp any more than I already have without sounding like a raving loon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout every session the boys were on hand to observe, advise and sometimes join in. The day was full of laughs and smiles but no one was holding back. Those who attended skated hard and gave it everything they could. Absorbing all of this information, everyone was eager to take it back to their home leagues and try it out - myself included. I had such a huge buzz from whole day and have been internalising everything I learned since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1460057355236.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="wp-1460057355236" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1460057355236.jpg" alt="image" width="1200" height="800"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Righteous Oxide drills the referees in their parallel bootcamp. (Photo: &lt;a href="http://lauramacd.co.uk/roller-derby-photography/"&gt;Laura MacDonald&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there was a whole separate side to the bootcamp that I cannot forget to mention, even though I wasn't a part of this side of things I know just how valuable it is to the derby community.
Up in the balcony of the hall there were both a Ref and NSO school going on. Led by Righteous Oxide (Dundee Roller Girls) and Fairy Nuff (Auld Reekie Roller Girls) the Refs were in excellent hands to advance through their Refereeing career, with sessions on positions, communication, and Head Referee responsibilities. It must have been amazing because they did a brilliant job during the scrim.
The NSO section was Hosted by Alix ( Dundee Roller Girls) and Peggy Krueger ( Auld Reekie Roller Girls) with sessions on NSO positions, communication, people management and Head NSO responsibilities. From what I hear it was amazing and everyone thoroughly enjoyed it.
It is absolutely imperative to the sport that we have Refs and officials available and the fact that POS were able to accommodate absolutely everyone was truly amazing. Skill levels did not matter to these lads, everyone had a place and they made it a complete success. I think I can speak for everyone when I say thank-you, POS for hosting such a fabulous bootcamp, for sharing your knowledge, kindness and to wish you all the best of Luck in Calgary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gie It Laldy!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bootcamps</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>reviews</category><category>roller derby world cup calgary 2016</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/07/after-action-report-the-power-of-scotland-bootcamp-april-2016/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 19:43:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Getting to Know Power of Scotland</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/27/getting-to-know-power-of-scotland/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend will see Birmingham host the 4 Nations Roller Derby Tournament. This weekend's extravaganza will feature Team England, Team Wales, Team France and Team Scotland.  I managed to wangle an opportunity to speak to 3 members of Team Scotland's Power of Scotland; Andy Morris, Skate Plissken  and Chris Mathieson, mainly I wanted to be nosy about how the Power Scotland have been preparing for the Wold Cup in Calgary. Since starting this blog piece, I have been informed that Plissken and Chris Mathieson have been voted in as the captains of Power of Scotland,  huge well done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/received_10156211484200587.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full" title="received_10156211484200587.jpeg" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/received_10156211484200587.jpeg" alt="image"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left to right: Mathieson , Plissken and Morris (photo credit Nikki Morris)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in the style of many tv hosts, I kicked off by asking a bit more about the individual skater, their history with sport and team affiliation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up was Plissken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long have you been skating for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come January, 3 years, with no real prior skating experience…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which team do you currently skate for? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nottingham Rolled Derby’s Super Smash Brollers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have a history in any other sports? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I grew up playing rugby, then moved on to American football for a little while when at uni…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up was Chris Mathieson, also known as Pudz and 'that guy who scored the first points in Power of Scotland vs Team USA in the 2014 Mens Roller Derby World Cup'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long have you been skating for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been skating since July 2011, so just under four and a half years&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which team do you currently skate for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City Brawlermen from Aberdeen and Power of Scotland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have a history in any other sports?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to play football as a kid but I wasn’t great at it, other than that a little bit of street hockey when I was 10 but I sprained my ankle once and never put on a pair of skates again until I tried roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And my last victim for interrogation was Andy Morris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long have you been skating for? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the Brawlermen started in November 2013, I did my first scrim in December 2014 after the Womens World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which team do you currently skate for? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City Brawlermen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have a history in any other sports? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played Rugby at school, I snowboard, Surf, Cycling, Motorbikes I’m a petrolhead!
Pre Selection&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So then I wanted to learn more about the selection process for Power of Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When did you first try out for Team Scotland and did you try out more than once?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plissken&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were 2 try out selection dates; I could only make one as SSB were playing a game on the other, so I went up in May having no idea what to expect. A little nervous to say the least! But after 4 hours of skate drills, derby drills and an hour scrim I felt good about how I had performed… followed by the news I had made the 30-strong selection squad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathieson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attended both tryouts in April and May 2015, and then we had to wait a month or so for the decision. It felt like forever between tryout and selection which is understandable as the quality in Scottish roller derby has increased so much since the last tournament in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After making the 30 we had to train as a team for the next 4 months in the run up to a selection bout hosted by the lovely Dundee Roller Girls. The 30 played against each other in this game showcasing the best talent in Scottish men’s derby. It was a high pressure game but with a score tied until the last jam it showed how well the teams were split which made it even more exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week later we found out if we had made the squad going to Calgary. I found out the news just as I was flying to London for a weekend away so a fair few celebration drinks were had and maybe even a wee visit to Double Threat Skates to get sized up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Was there a long wait before you knew about being on the top 20 squad? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The email for the final 20 came through a week after the PoS vs PoS game, that was the longest week ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plissken&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I had made the selection squad I knew I had to work hard, so I went to the 4x training sessions and 1x Scotland v Scotland (two teams made up of the selection squads) and took everything I could from each session, going back to my home league with something to work on. We were told in the first week of November if we had made the final 20, news I was very relieved and excited to hear. Now we have our final 20 we are working towards what we can take to the world cup and showing the world we the Power of Scotland can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then went on to discuss how selection for the Mens' Roller Derby World Cup had impacted their training regimes. I've seen various skater training videos (and some montages) going around on social media, so I wondered if this was typical behaviour and the guys did not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you changed your training regime since being selected?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plissken&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely! There was no way I was going to meet other world class teams without stepping up my game. I joined a gym (not been in years), started eating better, and am currently well on the way to quitting smoking! At the gym I have been working on strength training, HIIT training (if you don’t know it, check it out) and over all endurance. This is to help strength, balance, speed and recovery time between jams. I’ve cut out take-outs, pop (well, mostly ;) can’t beat a pre-game irn-bru) and snacks (and I tell you, you don’t want them as much as you think you do!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attended the gym on the run up to the PoS vs PoS game and pre tryouts quite a lot and since then I’ve taken it easy, come January I’ll be back to 5 -6 days a week. My diet hasn’t really changed a huge amount, I eat a lot of protein otherwise I don’t have the energy levels to play my best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathieson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been focused on making the Calgary squad for the last year, so have been hitting the gym since January, including some 5am sessions. There have been a few blips in the training regime and diet along the way but since making the 20 I’m back properly at the gym in preparation for 4 Nations. I also cut McDonald’s out which used to be my standard post game/training meal, which is tough seeing as there’s at least 4 between Grangemouth and Aberdeen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then wanted to find out more about Team Scotland training.  The roster for Power of Scotland features skaters from Scotland and England and as small as the UK is, so it can't be easy gathering everyone together for training. Team Scotland training takes place once a month in Grangemouth Leisure Centre, from 2016 this will increase to twice a month in the run up to the Mens Roller Derby World Cup.
I wondered if this regular travel necessitated taking time off of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plissken&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a 700mile round trip for me but I generally don’t take time off.  It’s travel up, train for 4 hrs, travel back down, all within about 30 hours...and the rest!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathieson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve been training monthly pre final selection but are ramping it up to twice a month in the new year. We train in Grangemouth which is about a 5 hour round trip from Aberdeen. It’s a long journey which I’ve sadly gotten used to and am currently looking into the options of a timeshare there with Momo. No time off work, but maybe just a little tired the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve been training once a month but from January onwards its every two weeks. I think there will always be things getting in the way of training even more so for the guys down south, cost has a large factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking a team of 20 plus bench and lineup and management is expensive no matter where you go but Canada is pretty far away and flights are not cheap. Next I quizzed the chaps on what they are doing in order to raise funds for this amazing opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathieson filled me in on Power of Scotland's fundraising activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a few fundraising events on at the moment, there are 3 skaters fighting it out to raise the most money to avoid losing their beards, craft fayres and some guest coaching sessions all over the country. I’ve just been up to Elgin training Helgin Roller Derby and Inverness City Roller Derby, which was a pleasure, giving some of them their first experience in wall and pack work drills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a general fundraising page, which if anyone has a few pennies to spare to help the team it would be greatly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;http://gogetfunding.com/allpowernobull/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are proud again to have our uniforms sponsored by MP Locums. MP Locums place Hospital Doctors and GPs into locum work matching your experience and qualifications to your professional goals and ambitions. As a preferred supplier to NHS Scotland they have a variety of locum positions short and long term available throughout Scot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/fb_img_1448576822432.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full" title="FB_IMG_1448576822432.jpg" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/fb_img_1448576822432.jpg" alt="image"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally we got onto the subject that so many of us as looking forward to, the Mens Roller Derby World Cup 2016. The Men's Roller Derby World Cup 2016 in Calgary will be a first time for Morris and Plissken with Mathieson making his second appearance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What part of the World Cup are you most looking forward to? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The atmosphere at the last one was incredible, I can’t wait for that excitement again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plissken&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, challenging myself against other national skaters, I know it’s not going to be easy but how good is it going to feel if I can get lead on Johnathan R? We can all dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathieson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than going to Canada, which is number 2 on the list of countries I’d love to visit, I’m looking forward to the challenge of our group stage. It’s been described as the ‘Group of Death’ but I think we can come out of it strong and it will make for some exciting games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which Team are you most excited to play against?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathieson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m looking forward to us playing the USA again. Last time we managed to score 40 points against them which was a big deal and I think with the team we have this year we will show them how far Scottish roller derby has progressed since then. Goal – first blood!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plissken&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USA, that’s the dream but I’m sure its everyone on the team has the dream to be selected for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you could be in any other bracket, which bracket would you choose and why? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plissken&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t! we have a great set of teams to play, and we have the 6 teams instead of 5 so we get loads of games to play, plus I get to go against the giants, Team USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think I would chose any of the other brackets, the bracket we are in will be the one to watch ☺&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathieson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d go into the Orange group so that we could play against Argentina, they were the heroes of the tournament last time, El Pibe &amp;lt;3!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be Mathieson's second time representing Power of Scotland in the Men's Roller Derby World Cup. I wanted to find out if this had had an impact on his 2016 training regime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You played in the World Cup in 2014, are you doing anything different this time to prepare?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last tournament was one of the best weekends of my life but on the lead up to it I was studying for my professional exams so I had to juggle the two with derby sometimes taking a back seat. This time around though this is my main focus and I’ll be putting everything I’ve got into it, attending as much training and scrimmage as possible. I’ve watched the footage of myself in the last world cup and although I scored the first points against USA it’s a horrible jam to watch, so many falls. But watching it back gives me the drive to do better this time round, upping my game and upping my fitness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally I asked for their predictions for the World Cup...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathieson
Scotland to lift the trophy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plissken
There’s going to be a lot of talent, so I predict a lot of cheering (please!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USA for the win, Canada/England for second and third and I think Scotland defiantly have the potential to better the last world cup position, it’s a very strong team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge thank you to Mathieson, Morris and Plissken for taking the time to answer my many, many questions.
Wishing Power of Scotland all the luck!!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>4nations</category><category>articles</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>roller derby world cup calgary 2016</category><category>super smash brollers</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/27/getting-to-know-power-of-scotland/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 11:48:04 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>