<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about roller derby tenerife)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/roller-derby-tenerife.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 08:59:33 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Tenerife Roller Derby bringing the heat to Winter tournaments...</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/15/tenerife-roller-derby-bringing-the-heat-to-winter-tournaments/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teneriferollerderby/"&gt;Tenerife Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are hosting one of the last tournaments of the year, as they host Dundee Roller Girls and Malmö's Crime City for a sunny Winter's triple header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've already talked to Dundee (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/08/dundees-international-debut/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and Crime City (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/04/crime-city-b-gear-up-for-tenerife/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), so it's time to catch up with the hosts to talk about their year, and their preparations. Speaking to us was Mercromina Tenerife's Co-Captain and also Co-Captain of the current Team Spain (as Mercedes)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-12850 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/mercedes_look.jpg" alt="mercedes_look" width="2048" height="1367"&gt; Mercromina, centre, blocking against Las Palmas earlier this year (Photo: Javier Velasco)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tenerife have had a good year this year, with a good performance in the first Spanish National Tournament (second place to Madrid!), and only one loss outside that (to the very strong Paris B). Are you pleased with your team's performance, and what have you been taking from it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;This past year has been a very important year for us. It might sound strange, but we've lost some games and that has made us get out of our comfort zone and realize how hard one has to work to stay on top. We had never lost against a Spanish team before the final against Madrid this year (in which they played an amazing game and totally deserved the win), so we are convinced that a team needs to lose games sometimes to grow stronger. Of course, that kind of thought comes a bit later, in that moment you just want to win everything. So, in general, I am very pleased with our performance last year at the National Championship, especially if you take into account that we hadn't played any game for a complete year.&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tenerife Roller Derby is also a big part of Team Spain 2018, just as it was a big part of the 2014 team. (And you're co-Captain of Team Spain at the moment!) In 2014, that causes a lot of flights to be needed for practice! How does it feel to be back on Team Spain, and how are the team balancing membership of the National Team with Tenerife's own ambitions?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;I am honoured to have been co-captaining both teams, Tenerife Roller Derby and Team Spain, this year. It is a big responsibility but also a very challenging and exciting work to do, very rewarding.&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;They're both two teams that I love and in which I have enjoyed a great number of games. Living so far away makes it always difficult to attend all practices and participate in the tournaments so not everyone is able to do it and some of us have to do a big economic effort, but, at least in my case, I can say that it's worth it.&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;This year the World Cup will take place in Manchester, so it will be much cheaper than last time, that's great news.&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;Nevertheless, this tournament will be my last one, since I'm retiring from derby after 6 very intense and engaged years, so I'll follow the adventures of my beloved Team Spain mates from a bit further away and the ones from my home team a bit closer.&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recently, it seems that Tenerife have really been excited by international roller derby, inviting a lot of teams from outside Spain for mini-tournaments. What lead to this decision to have these mini-tournaments, and does it help to be a nice warm sunny country when Europe is in Winter when inviting teams?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;We have always been very interested in playing international games. In fact, we've done at home more international than national games (Finland, Scotland, Portugal, Germany, England, France, Sweden are some of the countries that have visited us). This season we are organizing the games in this mini-tournament form so we can offer the teams two games in a row. That's always a good point for visiting teams, having the chance to play two games in one trip.&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;It's not easy to bring teams to the island, because of the long distances and the cost of the trip, but, of course, being an incredibly beautiful and sunny island is always something that encourages them to come. Lots of teams use the chance to stay a few more days here and have some holidays together. I can't imagine a better team bonding acitivity. &lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your next tournament features two teams from much further North in Europe (everyone is further north than Tenerife, but …!) - Dundee and Malmö - but this isn't the first time you've played Scottish, or Swedish, teams. How are you preparing for the tournament - and do you have any advice for the visiting teams?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;We are training really hard for this and the other tournaments to come. We've had a lot of important members of the team leaving us recently but we are also lucky enough to always have new talented and motivated skaters with us, so we are currently focusing on maintaining the level that we've achieved in the last years and doing a good transition to our new skaters squad.&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With both National Championships, and these tournaments, Tenerife Roller Derby must have even more exciting things lined up for next year? What can you tell us of the future plans?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br class="gmail_msg"&gt;Our future plans for this season include some more tournaments at home, but also travelling to play tournaments abroad. That is a really exciting thing for us, since we haven't been able to travel to play a tournament yet, except for the National Championships last summer. So we're really looking forward to it. Our plan is to keep growing and try to be the best team in Spain, although we're very pleased that derby is growing in our country and more and more teams are raising their level, we've always supported our other national teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tenerife's Torneo Triangular Roller Derby is on this 17th December, starting at 2pm , at the Pabellón de deportes Pancho Camurria. Event page is here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1790180551249253/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1790180551249253/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>malmo crime city rollers</category><category>roller derby tenerife</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/15/tenerife-roller-derby-bringing-the-heat-to-winter-tournaments/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 20:15:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee's International Début!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/08/dundees-international-debut/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;Ahead of Tenerife Roller Derby's big &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Torneo Triangular&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; later on this month &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;(Read our interview with Crime City B's captain &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;Darling Ripper &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/04/crime-city-b-gear-up-for-tenerife/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt; we managed to catch up with Dundee Roller Girls co captains of The Silvery Tayzers, Liston (L) and Mayhem (M), to see how the league is preparing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="12259,12260" type="rectangular"]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;So before we look forward to your tournament, we should talk about how the season has gone for you guys? You worked your way to Second place in the British Championship in T3 North, which sent you off to the play offs weekend in Newark! How was that for the team?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;L: &lt;/b&gt;The team have been incredible all season. as always, living in a tiny uni city, we've had a big turnover of Tayzer skaters though the season but everyone takes it in their stride (lol pun), and we've welcomed some incredible new additions to our roster. Playoffs were surreal - we didn't expect to perform so well against Swansea and for a moment panicked we'd have to go to teir 2 haha. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;M: &lt;/b&gt;This season has made us so proud of our team, they always go into a game with a positive attitude and a focus on performing to the best of our abilities. We went into playoffs with a view to keep our scoring differential to a minimum and just like every other game our team came together and smashed expectations! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;We've covered a little bit about the Tenerife Tournament in our previous interview with Crime City, how did you guys get involved with that? This is the first international away game for you guys isn't it?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;L: &lt;/b&gt;We'd been approached by Tenerife last year but at the time British Champs had wiped us all out and the league had no travel funds. So we kept in touch and organised a game for this year as far in advance as possible! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;M: &lt;/b&gt;This was organised mainly through Milky &lt;em&gt;(Liston #07)&lt;/em&gt; and Ellin &lt;em&gt;(Seaton #102)&lt;/em&gt;, keeping lines of communication with other leagues open. We're so excited to have been invited over, it's a great step forward for DRG as a league!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;How are you guys as a league preparing for all of this then, it's not just the skaters that are going as your officials are working towards this tournament as well! How is everyone getting ready to skate in the blistering heat of “winter” in the Canaries going?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;L: &lt;/b&gt;Our officials are always so busy, right until the end of the year. They've been all over lately - Cardiff, Helsinki, Newcastle. Obviously all good prep for the sun! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;I think the Tayzers are prepping by bulk buying sunscreen. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M: &lt;/strong&gt;We are a very lucky league to have so many dedicated officials - they work tirelessly to develop their own skills and bring them back to DRG, like Milks said they've been doing a great deal of travelling lately so they're probably better prepared then the team! Most other leagues are now going into their off-season but we've asked our skaters to keep up the focus and training for this upcoming tournament, it has extended our season quite a bit but we were happy to do it. &lt;b&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you all set yourselves personal goals or do you have a league goal with this tournament in mind?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;L: &lt;/b&gt;We're going into this tournament with the same league and team goals as always - to do our best and have an awesome time. We've got a very short roster against some incredible teams, so this'll be amazing learning to take forward for the season ahead. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;M: &lt;/b&gt; Yup our league wide goal is to enjoy every game as much as you can and perform to the best of our ability. If we can come out of a game having supported each other and gained new learning focuses we've always won!! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;And just to round off, what are the plans for next year? I believe there are a few changes coming to DRG next season, possibly with a hint at more international teams?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/b&gt;We're hoping to graduate from WFTDA Apprentice status to full members next year, so hopefully we'll get a few more trips away to sunnier climates! Or colder. We're not picky...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#1d2129;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Cambria, serif;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M: &lt;/strong&gt;Yes yes next season all focuses are on WFTDA, it'll be a great learning curve for our little league and we hope it will really help us develop. We're all buzzing for our leagues future and yes hopefully some more trips!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fund raise for their travel Dundee Roller Girls are hosting a gofund me:  &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gofundme.com/drg-tenerife-tour"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/drg-tenerife-tour&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;and along with donations towards their cause, DRG are offering their training experience to leagues, from jammers to blockers, officials, league maintenance and structure to game planning and everything in between! Anything you want help with: DRG are willing to come!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tenerife Triple Header will be on &lt;strong&gt;December 17th&lt;/strong&gt;, from&lt;strong&gt; 14:00&lt;/strong&gt; (WET, which is the same as GMT) in P&lt;strong&gt;ancho Camurria Sports Centre, Santa Cruz, Tenerife&lt;/strong&gt;. You can read more at the event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1790180551249253/" target="_blank"&gt;Torneo Triangular&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep up to date on Dundee's travels by following their snapchat: wearethedrg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>european roller derby tournament</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby tenerife</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/08/dundees-international-debut/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 21:55:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Crime City (B) gear up for Tenerife.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/04/crime-city-b-gear-up-for-tenerife/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst now most of the big events are finally dying down as leagues head into their winter off-season (sometimes reluctantly), there's still some sunny climes where tournaments are yet to come.
In particular, Tenerife Roller Derby have been on a bit of a tournament kick recently, and are topping their previous three-team international tournament (against Paris and Royal Windsor) with a possibly even more international one, by distance, as Dundee Roller Girls and Malmö's Crime City (B) both fly down to the Canaries to take in a bit of sun, and a lot of Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this interview, we caught up with Darling Ripper, of Crime City B, to see how the Swedish team are feeling about skating in 20º Celcius heat in December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11938" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/darling-ripper1.jpg" alt="darling-ripper1" width="2048" height="1366"&gt; Crime City B, Darling Ripper middle (visible 6 on arm) Photo: Helena Mettävainio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crime City B have had a very good year to date - you have won all 5 of your games, mostly by quite big margins.In particular, you seem to have made a big jump in performance, to judge from your rematch against Copenhagen and Berlin! In 2015, you lost in quite a close game to Copenhagen, in 2016, you won extremely convincingly; and while you've won against the Inglorious Bombshells twice, you increased your lead this year. Can you say how the year has been from your perspective, and if the team has been doing particular thing to improve this strongly?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DR: It has been a really great year for us and we are very proud of our own development! It's always hard to know exactly why we have improved this much, but I think it's due to the fact that our charter has been rather stable for the last year so we've become a really close-knit team and we have so much fun playing together as well! It also helps having such great coaches from our A and B team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In fact, Swedish (and Finnish, so maybe "Scandinavian" &lt;img class="_1ift _2560 img" src="https://www.facebook.com/images/emoji.php/v6/z4c/1/16/1f642.png" alt="🙂"&gt; ) Roller Derby has been doing exceptionally well in recent years. Do you have any thoughts about what Sweden is doing well, in general?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DR: Haha, I don't know what Sweden is doing in general, maybe wrestling polar bears? But I think the Scandinavian teams are quite good at helping each other out and we play and practice together in different ways so maybe that's why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tenerife will be the furthest Crime City B have travelled for a bout since you've existed. Do long trips feel different than short ones - and how are you expecting to deal with the much warmer climate? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DR: Traveling is always exhausting, but we are really excited to go to Tenerife and look forward to get away from the cold here in Crime City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flat Track Stats puts you as the favourite to win this tournament too, with Dundee Roller Girls and Tenerife both roughly equally rated. What's the teams' goal for this final tournament of the year? (Are you aiming to win, or do you have personal goals, or other goals here?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DR: Our aim for the tournament is to have fun and play our best game. We expect a hard competition from both teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, with this year going so well, what's next for Crime City B next year? Will you be aiming at higher level opponents - Flat Track Stats thinks that you're on a level with, say Nantes or Auld Reekie - and our own ratings put you a little higher, and in contention with the next tier of French teams, maybe Newcastle Roller Girls…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DR: We will have to wait and see what next year will bring us! But it would be fun to play those higher-ranked teams you mention. As a B team, it can sometimes be a bit hard to find competition at your level, seeing how we are not a WFTDA team and therefore can't play Sanctioned bouts. I hope more higher-ranked teams will be interested in playing us now that we have shown that we can put up a good fight!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tenerife Triple Header will be on &lt;strong&gt;December 17th&lt;/strong&gt;, from 14:00 (WET, which is the same as GMT) in Pancho Camurria Sports Centre, Santa Cruz, Tenerife. There's no event page at present, but we will add more information as we have it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girls are raising money to fund their attendance here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gofundme.com/drg-tenerife-tour"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/drg-tenerife-tour&lt;/a&gt; . &lt;/strong&gt;We will add funding links for other teams if we are made aware of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>international</category><category>malmo crime city rollers</category><category>roller derby tenerife</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/04/crime-city-b-gear-up-for-tenerife/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 10:50:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A chat with... Bonnie Colliders Captains Khilleesi and G-Wrecks</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/16/a-chat-with-bonnie-colliders-captains-khilleesi-and-g-wrecks/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So... Dundee's B Team, the Bonnie Colliders, have had a pretty exciting year to date, which is about to get only more exciting with their first appearance in tournament - Auld Reekie's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/535844416618826/"&gt;ARRGmageddon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the weekend of the &lt;strong&gt;26th November&lt;/strong&gt;.
We had a chat with Bonnie Colliders Co-Captains Khilleesi and G-Wrecks about the upcoming challenge - and also Dundee A's upcoming trip to Tenerife in December (as both skaters are also on the A roster).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be able to listen along here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[soundcloud url="https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/293033096" params="auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true" width="100%" height="450" iframe="true" /]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>arrgmageddon</category><category>articles</category><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby tenerife</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/16/a-chat-with-bonnie-colliders-captains-khilleesi-and-g-wrecks/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 11:51:59 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>