<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:34:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>BCR's Central Belters are back on track in 2018</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/30/bcrs-central-belters-are-back-on-track-in-2018/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt;'&lt;/a&gt; Central Belters are back on track and ready to kick some ass for the first time in 2018. On August 18th, they will be taking on Granite City's Fight Hawks at Grangemouth Sports Complex.
&lt;p&gt;This is the Belters' first game since early 2017 and sees a few changes to their team. Whilst some skaters have moved on or retired, the Belters have also had some new faces join their squad, including a couple of familiar faces that used to play elsewhere in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fight Hawks had a great year in 2017, winning all five of the games they played. Now in 2018 they already have 3 games under their belt, the most recent a close bout against Dundee Roller Derby's Bonnie Colliders last weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the details can be found over on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/1767150326733129/"&gt;event page here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/1767150326733129/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone wp-image-27087 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/beltvhawk.jpg?w=700" alt="Wolves vs Hawks" width="700" height="394"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2018 upcoming bout</category><category>bairn</category><category>bcr</category><category>central belters</category><category>fight hawks</category><category>gcrd</category><category>grangemouth</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>granite city</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/30/bcrs-central-belters-are-back-on-track-in-2018/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 12:29:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mean City meets Madchester as Chaos Engine rev up for Glasgow double-header</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/04/05/mean-city-meets-madchester-as-chaos-engine-rev-up-for-glasgow-double-header/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mean City will m&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/11022582_615074245295666_657576044010520377_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4599 alignright" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/11022582_615074245295666_657576044010520377_o.jpg?w=300" alt="11022582_615074245295666_657576044010520377_o" width="442" height="175"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;eet Madchester later this month when Glasgow hosts a colourful clash of skates, songs and sporting rivalry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow’s own Mean City Roller Derby will welcome Manchester Roller Derby’s Chaos Engine to the town for a showdown soundtracked by everyone from Oasis and The Stone Roses to New Order and The Smiths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will Mean City be feeling ‘Supersonic’ with their ‘Wonderwalls’ or will the Chaos Engine skaters be ‘Made of Stone’? We’ll find out on Saturday April 25 at the ARC sportscentre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a very special occasion as Mean City will be joining forces with friends Glasgow Roller Derby to host a double-header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also on the bill will be Glasgow Roller Derby’s Cannie Gingers who will be playing Team Metal Legs – a select squad made up of skaters who have suffered and subsequently overcome breaks during the derby career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means fans will be treated to two full games for the price of one – an all-male game and an all-female game – showcasing some of the silkiest skills and high-octane thrills that this wonderful sport has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alan Muir, Chair of Mean City Roller Derby, said: “I hope as many people as possible come along to the ARC on April 25 – it’s a great opportunity to get to know this wonderful sport, enjoy some groovy tunes and meet some of Scotland’s friendliest skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There’s no ‘Definitely Maybe’ about it – April 25 is going to be a fantastic celebration of spills, thrills and derby-aches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Get your ticket now – we’ll sell you a full seat, but you’ll be perched on the edge of it when these four teams take to the track.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alan added: “We can’t wait to welcome Manchester Roller Derby’s Chaos Engine to town – they are great league and a fantastic group of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And we’re delighted to be hosting a double-header as our good friends at Glasgow Roller Derby take on the magnificent Team Metal Legs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Come along with all the family – there will be refreshments, merchandise and more on the day too. To quote The Stone Roses - it's ‘What the World is Waiting For’!”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Mean City Roller Derby vs Manchester’s Chaos Engine and Glasgow Roller Derby v Team Metal Legs takes place on Saturday April 25 – from 11.30am at the ARC sportscentre, Glasgow Caledonian University, Cowcaddens Road, Glasgow, G4 0BA.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tickets cost £6 in advance - £7.50 on the door.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby"&gt;facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby&lt;/a&gt; for more information on the event and on how to join the revolution at the West of Scotland’s only co-ed roller derby league.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>in the news</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/04/05/mean-city-meets-madchester-as-chaos-engine-rev-up-for-glasgow-double-header/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 16:30:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bairn City Rollers-Roller Derby Taster Session</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/06/23/bairn-city-rollers-roller-derby-taster-session/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/06/10374880_584126878369815_5876659374843654954_n.png"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/06/10374880_584126878369815_5876659374843654954_n.png" alt="10374880_584126878369815_5876659374843654954_n" width="614" height="226" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3507"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://derbygeek.co.uk/"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; are holding a Roller Derby taster Session. If you fancy going along to see what all the fuss is around one of the fastest growing sports in the world, then contact BCR at the email address on the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/872422139449893/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; event page.
The event takes place at The Mariner Centre, Falkirk on Thursday the 26th of June at 8:30pm. Cost is £5 and kit is available to try. Please ensure you email BCR to register your interest in advance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bcr</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>roller derby</category><category>taster session</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/06/23/bairn-city-rollers-roller-derby-taster-session/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 00:20:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MADE In Scotland, from Jammers.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/11/made-in-scotland-from-jammers/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a tendency, especially outside the USA, to use "roller derby" as a shorthand for "WFTDA-rules roller derby". However, not only has roller derby existed long before WFTDA, or the 2001 revival that lead to its formation in 2005-2006, but it has had, and continues to have, multiple representations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from banked-track derby (which differs from WFTDA in more than just the banked track itself), and RollerGame Japan (a highly kinetic, Japanese interpretation of roller derby which has been intermittently popular there since the early 90s), there are two significant flat-track derby interpretations beyond the WFTDA rules that dominate the sport currently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of them, USARS, is the ruleset sponsored by the USA's Roller Sports body. It has just released its 2014 rules revision, and down in Birmingham the Crash Test Brummies have tested it out in the first ever USARS scrim in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other is the Modern Athletic Derby Endeavour (MADE) rules set. MADE is a project started by skaters who wanted to play a version of derby closer to the 60s/70s derby of Jerry Seltzer's era than the WFTDA rules at the time (2008 to 2009). MADE has rules for both banked and flat-track derby and the MADE organisation allows male, female and co-ed registrations. As USARS is also consciously influenced by earlier versions of derby, this means that MADE, USARS and 70s derby have quite a lot in common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, the role of Pivot, and the definition of Lead Jammer, are more dynamic in the three rulesets mentioned, compared to WFTDA rules. Once the opposing team has Lead Jammer, the Pivot is eligible to break out to become Active Scorer, replacing the Jammer for that jam; this also limits early power jams, as the Pivot can replace their Jammer as Scorer at any time before that Jammer scores their first point. In addition, "Lead Jammer" status is owned by the Jammer currently in the Lead, not the first Jammer to break through the pack; catching up with and passing the first jammer out to immediately call the jam is a viable tactic (even returning from a power jam).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, and other rules differences across the set, make MADE (and USARS) a faster-paced game than WFTDA skaters might be used to. (Of course, pace is not everything in a game by any means, but MADE aficionados in the USA are certainly vocal about their versions' spectator-friendly thrills.) The MADE and USARS rules are also considerably shorter than the point-by-point accuracy of the WFTDA ruleset - MADE2014 comes to 6, and USARS2014 to 14 pages (including ref signals), compared to the 50-60 page lengths of recent WFTDA rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/img_0097-2-copy.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3273" alt="Pivots on scoring passes: not something you see in WFTDA-derby ;) (Photo: Laura MacDonald)" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/img_0097-2-copy.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Pivots on scoring passes: not something you see in WFTDA-derby ;) (Photo: Laura MacDonald)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Scottish connection comes into this via Bairn City Rollers' Liz Thrilla, who experienced MADE firsthand on her return to Kansas at the tail end of 2013. Enthused by the pacier feel of MADE derby, she decided to give Scotland a taste of the rules, in the interest of promoting a different side to the sport. The MADE In Scotland group is the result of her efforts, and is hoped to result not just in an all-Scottish coed exhibition bout at the end of the year, but also an International bout in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These things start smaller, however, so MADE In Scotland has arranged a series of taster/training sessions to allow the WFTDA-rules community to experience the different ruleset and form their own opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unavoidable clashes with Fierce Valley Roller Girls scrims and Power of Scotland training limited attendance to the first session, held in the Mariners' Centre, Camelon on Saturday 8th. Nevertheless, enough interested parties attended to allow demonstration pack work and drills within the MADE ruleset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the slightly larger MADE track, and the faster pace of the game, all of the skating attendees found the experience more tiring than they were used to, however they also uniformly seemed enthused by the experience. Raven, of Into The Nitemare, was enthused enough to promise to bring the entire Voodoo Roller Dollies to the next session, and the the doodle poll to arrange the date for that has been filled in by several people who did not attend the first session. (At the time of writing, the most popular date seems likely to be the 1st of March).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This correspondent certainly found the pace of the demonstration to be notably higher than that in most WFTDA bouts; however, it should be borne in mind that this was not a full scrim. The full test of how the rules play out will come with a higher turn-out, allowing a fuller experience of a game. That said, I can certainly understand why MADE-fans love their version of the game as much as they appear to.
Of course, we will continue to follow and report on this exciting project as it progresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/img_0263-2-copy.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3272" alt="The happy attendees of MADE In Scotland's inaugral session (Photo: Laura MacDonald)" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/img_0263-2-copy.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The happy attendees of MADE In Scotland's inaugral session (Photo: Laura MacDonald)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MADE In Scotland Project has a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ScottishMADE"&gt;Facebook Page&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Scottish_MADE"&gt;Twitter Feed&lt;/a&gt;. The Doodle Poll for the next taster/practice session is here: &lt;a href="http://doodle.com/7vgbtgck8ix3na2h"&gt;http://doodle.com/7vgbtgck8ix3na2h&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MADE organisation has a &lt;a href="http://www.skatemade.org/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, where the 6 page rules document can be downloaded, and an official magazine, &lt;a href="http://viciouscirclemag.com/"&gt;Vicious Circle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>made</category><category>made in scotland</category><category>roller derby</category><category>usars</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/11/made-in-scotland-from-jammers/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 21:59:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Talking Derby To Us: Podcasts come to Scotland</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/05/talking-derby-to-us-podcasts-come-to-scotland/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of ways that Roller Derby has been discussed and promoted online and off, from League Websites, through blogs like us, and bigger entities like &lt;a href="http://derbynewsnetwork.com"&gt;Derby News Network&lt;/a&gt;, the derby magazines (the UK's own &lt;a href="http://www.leadjammermag.com/"&gt;Lead Jammer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.insidelinemagazine.co.uk/"&gt;Inside Line&lt;/a&gt; amongst them), and YouTube/Vimeo/etc videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podcasts, on the other hand, are a somewhat rarer breed, much to the sadness of everyone who wants to listen to people talk about Derby on their daily commute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/talkderbytome.png"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-3241" alt="No, really, Talk to Them. They're Listening." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/talkderbytome.png?w=614" width="614" height="81"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The folk up in Aberdeen are well aware of this, however, and have their most talkative member, sMACklemore, (otherwise known with his announcing hat on for Granite City Roller Girls) on the case. He'll be hosting the new derby fortnightly podcast "&lt;strong&gt;Talk Derby To Me&lt;/strong&gt;" starting this very month, with an array of guests from around derby, thanks to the magic of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Episode 1 is due for release around the &lt;strong&gt;11th of February&lt;/strong&gt;, and will feature:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GCRG Vice Captain (and Team Scotland Training Team member) Rock'n Riot,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GCRG Ref (and Scottish Roller Derby Blog contributor) Buffy Boiler,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also GCRG Ref (and holder of longest name in derby) Tessington World of Adventures,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;along with a "mystery guest" from a location "within the UK".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact with the team is currently via their Facebook page here: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/talkderby"&gt;www.facebook.com/talkderby&lt;/a&gt; where they'd welcome anecdotes about your derby Fresh Meat days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: The podcast discussed in this article is now available at &lt;a href="http://www.mixcloud.com/talkderbytome/talk-derby-to-me-episode-1/"&gt;http://www.mixcloud.com/talkderbytome/talk-derby-to-me-episode-1/&lt;/a&gt; and at &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/talkderbytome/"&gt;https://soundcloud.com/talkderbytome/&lt;/a&gt;, the latter of which also allows mp3 downloads.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>aberdeen</category><category>articles</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>podcasts</category><category>roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/05/talking-derby-to-us-podcasts-come-to-scotland/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 13:40:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls vs Fierce Valley Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/13/dundee-roller-girls-vs-fierce-valley-roller-girls-2/</link><dc:creator>louisepants</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a busy weekend for Dundee Roller Girls travel team, The Silvery Tayzers. Sunday 17th November sees them take on Fierce Valley Roller Girls travel team, The Parma Violents. It has been over a year and half since these 2 teams met, both having refreshed their rosters and experience since then. Come along to the DISC, Dundee to see who will win in what is sure to be a most exciting bout. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 1.30pm with the bout beginning at 2pm. Tickets are available in advance for the reduced price of £5 (£6 on the door on the day). There will be merchandise from both teams available and beautiful cakes baked by the skaters/refs/NSO's themselves! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is absolutely not to be missed. See you trackside for some Live Action Roller Derby!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/fvrg.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-3036" alt="Image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/fvrg.png?w=650"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>disc</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>parma violents</category><category>roller derby</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/13/dundee-roller-girls-vs-fierce-valley-roller-girls-2/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 16:02:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bairn City Rollers presents “Blockémon”</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/07/18/bairn-city-rollers-presents-blockemon/</link><dc:creator>graememcphail</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Derby fans, we choose YOU! On Sunday 28th July &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; will evolve to present another double-header of action with Blockémon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For round one, our lovely Central Belters will be hoping the &lt;a href="http://www.furnessfirecrackers.co.uk/"&gt;Furness Firecrackers&lt;/a&gt; don’t prove too hot to handle in what promises to be a searing battle between two great teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, the temperatures will reach fever-pitch as it will be time for round two where the Skelpies will be looking to quell the flames of &lt;a href="http://www.furnessfirecrackers.co.uk/mensteam.php"&gt;Barrow Infernos&lt;/a&gt;. If you can stand the heat you’ll be in for a treat, this one might get a little hot!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skelpies, Infernos and Firecrackers . . .  all the elements are due to collide at the height of summer in an explosion of fun. Come on down and join us, you’ll have a (poké)ball!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/blockemon.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-2837 aligncenter" alt="blockemon" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/blockemon.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="868"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The action kicks off 1:30pm at The Peak in Stirling, tickets are moving fast with only a week to go so make sure you grab some while you can.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/553247878047614/"&gt;Facebook event&lt;/a&gt; to keep up to date with the latest information.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Purchase tickets for Scrape Fear &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/419967"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>central belters</category><category>firecrackers</category><category>inferno</category><category>roller derby</category><category>skelpies</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/07/18/bairn-city-rollers-presents-blockemon/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 21:47:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bairn City Rollers - Fresh Meat information!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/06/25/bairn-city-rollers-fresh-meat-information/</link><dc:creator>graememcphail</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's the lifeblood of any Roller Derby league. The entry point for all beginners. Our apprenticeship. But for those looking in from the outside, thinking of dipping their toes in the off-axis oval waters of derby, there can still be a lot of question marks over what Fresh Meat actually is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our next Fresh Meat taster session on the horizon, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; took a look at some of the more frequent queries from those looking to join Fresh Meat – be it with our league or elsewhere :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/06/fm-poster.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2722 aligncenter" alt="fm poster" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/06/fm-poster.jpg" width="452" height="565"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"I'd love to give it a go, but I can barely skate..."&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a problem. Fresh Meat courses will teach you skating from the basics (and we mean &lt;em&gt;the basics&lt;/em&gt;) upwards, so your existing skating ability is irrelevant. One of the first things you will be taught is how to fall safely, so whatever other obstacles you encounter from there you can be confident in not getting hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"It sounds fun, but I don't really know the sport..."&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't worry, you're not alone there. Many skaters now at bouting level knew little or nothing about derby when they first tried out Fresh Meat, so it's nothing to be concerned about. One of our skaters believed it to be "something like rugby but on skates", while another saw "an elaborate game of tag". Indeed your own writer was, somewhat embarrassingly, originally under the impression that it was in fact a worked sport like pro-wrestling (even after I started training I still had lingering thoughts that maybe they would smarten me up to it after a couple weeks...).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"I don't have all the equipment..."&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can bring the enthusiasm, we can bring pretty much all the rest. At BCR we can provide skates and pads in more or less every size for those wanting to give Fresh Meat a go - all you require to bring is your own mouthguard (we don't share &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt;!) - and most other leagues will have similar set-ups for beginners to give it a try before looking at investing in their own gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"What will I get out of it?"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A whole new world of fun! Polling some fellow Bairn City Rollers on the matter, here are some of the responses: "Getting my cardio back", "Having a second family", "Confidence", "The most fun ever!". Your writer now tends to mentally arrange his life's timeline by Before Derby and After Derby, such is the scale of changes it makes! It truly is a sport like no other, you'll never know how you lived without it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"I'm not sure if I want to be getting hit..."&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's an understandable concern, especially if you are starting out with little skate experience, but chances are by the time you've reached that level (and there will be plenty fun training to be had before you get there) your confidence in falling safely and recovering will be such that it won't be an issue any more. Even then, if it's really not going to be your thing then there are plenty other fun and rewarding branches of derby you can go into such as NSO-ing and refereeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"But what if roller derby takes over my life?"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, this one may well happen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So go on, give it a go! Find out which leagues are closest to you and get in touch. It's a friendly sport that is big on sharing a family ethos, if one league might not be suitable for you they'll be sure to point you in the direction of another one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers taster session for our next Fresh Meat class will be on the 21st of July. If you are interested then &lt;a href="mailto:bairncityrollers@gmail.com"&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; for further information or drop by our &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers"&gt; Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>roller derby</category><category>skating</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/06/25/bairn-city-rollers-fresh-meat-information/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 21:02:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lets hear it for the boys!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/08/lets-hear-it-for-the-boys/</link><dc:creator>thejammingpony</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A female perspective on Merby and CO-ED Roller Derby.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until the past couple of years Roller Derby has been a sport ‘rolled’ out on a predominantly female playing field. There have always been men around, be it in an official capacity or those of the infamous derby widow - ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However those who wished to play on a competitive level have taken the proverbial bull by the horns with Merby leagues are popping up all over the UK. Scotland in Particular has no less than 4 up and coming all male leagues. Their collective bouting team the Jakey Bites have been established for over a year now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arrival of Men’s Roller Derby has been met with mixed reaction on roller derby scene, some embracing it fully and others feeling a little put out that the male specimen are perhaps trying to steal our feminine thunder………God can’t they let us have anything!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being part of a league who have taken to Integrating with open arms, I have had a fantastic opportunity to skate and compete with the some of the Jakey Bites in the past year, skating in the Uk’s first ever CO-ED derby bout with The Jakey Tayzers last September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result I have become a keen supporter for CO-ED and men’s roller derby. The thought of this might seem a bit overwhelming for some but I believe it can make you a more rounded and skilled skater in the long run. I have skated for 2 years now, predominantly in all female training and bout situations and I thought I would take this opportunity to answer some of the questions or allay some of the fears people might have about Male and Co-Ed roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;DO THEY HIT HARDER?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate to emasculate anyone here but the answer to this is not really. I have found that taking a hit from a guy is no different from being hit by the girls. The fact that they don’t really have hips takes a bit of getting used to but the impact of the hit isn't as scary as it might seem.  Put it this way, if you have ever been hit by Cider from Auld Reekie then you have nothing to worry about and are fully prepared…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;ARE THEIR TACTICS DIFFERENT?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever we first started training for the CO – ED bout this was definitely one of our questions, in all honesty we thought for some reason they were going to be all offence and no discipline (not sure why, guess we were stereotyping). This wasn't the case at all; for the most part their tactics are exactly the same as what we are doing on the female side of things. They are definitely very skilled and know their stuff; I didn't find it any different from skating with my female team mates. They have had to adjust to the new rule set exactly the same as we have. From watching various Merby bouts last year there really wasn't much difference in the tactics played and there certainly wasn't any less glitter surprisingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;IS IT AWKWARD?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we all know, roller derby can be a very 'handsy' sport, it is full contact and I suppose it would be normal to wonder if it gets a bit awkward when playing CO-ED. This one is really in the eyes of the beholder to be honest, I personally haven’t ever felt awkward or anything likes that whilst skating. Whether that comes from knowing them quite well or from being in the zone on track I’m not sure but it certainly has never been an issue. You know the bond you have with your team mates on track, well that bond is completely possible in CO-ED as well and it is a pretty gratifying experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;ARE THEY BETTER THAN US?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer to this hangs on the word better; it’s not so much a case of better as different. Roller derby caters for differences; it’s one of the most appealing aspects of the sport which is known for celebrating individuality. In some cases they may be a little stronger and taller than us but……being a big player or a hard hitter isn't the be all and end all if you are smaller and faster. In truth they are as varied and unique as we are on the female side of things. Tall, small, fast, strong, hard-hitting, positional and/or agile everyone has strength it's just finding out how they compliment each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;ARE THEY JUST A BUNCH OF “LADS?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cracking dirty jokes and messing around? As for the dirty jokes I know some female skaters who could make them blush……….But in all seriousness the answer here is no. They are 100% dedicated to the sport and the progression of their regional leagues, the passion they have for the sport is no less than we have in the female leagues and the drive they have shown in starting from scratch has been nothing short of impressive. As a female skater they have always been nothing less than welcoming and supportive of me and since skating with them I have seen a real improvement in certain areas of my skating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a personal perspective I am fully in support of Merby in the UK. I would urge everyone to support their local Merby league alongside their local derby league, Capital City in Edinburgh, Mean City in Glasgow, The Skelpies in the Central Belt and The Tayminators in Tayside. I have had the pleasure of knowing people from most of these teams and can tell you they are a cracking bunch of guys, we should be proud to have them as a part of the Scottish Roller Derby scene. I hope to see a lot more CO-ED action in the future with my Jakey Tayzers. The Skelpies League, Bairn City are already establishing a Co -Ed league so it is onward and upward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to make up your own mind or have a male friend you’d like to wrangle into taking up the sport, the Jakey Bites (Comprising of members from 3 out of 4 of the aforementioned teams) have a bout coming up against The South Wales Silures on April the 6&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; in Grangemouth. Check their Facebook page for event details and ticket sales. The venue only holds 100 so buy in advance to avoid disappointment. Bairn City men’s team will also be playing South Wales the day after on the 7&lt;sup&gt;th &lt;/sup&gt;at the same venue, for more details and ticket sales check their Facebook pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.facebook.com/events/122071404642449/      (SKELPIES VS. SILURES)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.facebook.com/events/432929060108875/     (JAKEYS VS. SILURES)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a title="Jakeys VS. Silures" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/522492_342652352503139_928642489_n.png"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-2291 aligncenter" alt="522492_342652352503139_928642489_n" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/522492_342652352503139_928642489_n.png" width="506" height="567"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/10889_619537551396047_724006372_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-2292 aligncenter" alt="10889_619537551396047_724006372_n" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/10889_619537551396047_724006372_n.jpg?w=211" width="506" height="567"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>image</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>merby</category><category>roller derby</category><category>the jakey bites</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>the tayminators</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/08/lets-hear-it-for-the-boys/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 16:57:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Interview With: the Roller Grrrls team.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/04/an-interview-with-the-roller-grrrls-team/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps one sign that you've arrived as a sport is having works of fiction made about you. If that's the case, then Roller Derby has certainly made it, through the forthcoming &lt;a href="http://www.rollergrrrls.com/"&gt;Roller Grrrls&lt;/a&gt; comic series, which has had much support and publicity over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the official launch of the Roller Grrrls Sketchbook at &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s Chaos on the Clyde tournament, Gary Erskine, Anna Malady and the rest of the team have had a very busy few months with promotion and touring the various comics events around the world. We caught up with them via email to talk about the project, derby, and comics in general...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/04/an-interview-with-the-roller-grrrls-team/roller-grrrls_banner_reference/" rel="attachment wp-att-1948"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-1948" alt="The Roller Grrrls Sketchbook: Available now!" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/roller-grrrls_banner_reference.jpg?w=161" height="300" width="161"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Roller Grrrls Sketchbook: Available now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gary, you've been doing line-art for comics for about 24 years now; since your start in Marvel + 2000AD, there's quite a lot of the "traditional" SF + superhero work in your back catalogue, but also less conventional work. Do you have a preference for a particular genre, and how do you (and the others) feel about the popular pigeon-holing of comics as “SF+capes”?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Gary Erskine]I love comics as a medium. The genres I work with are just that, and I like working with them all. Each one gives me a new challenge.
Future sci-fi nonsense allows a completely free canvas to design a new world environment and the characters within that (the Irons:Hybrids work for Madefire has a Blade Runner vibe about it) Working on Roller Grrrls offers new challenges, as a contemporary story requires a similar attention to detail since EVERYONE will recognise the settings and people within the story. Another new project I am working on with my former studio colleague Dominic Regan is a horror/western. That also requires an approach and attention to detail to ensure that the setting helps the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did the three of you get into Roller Derby? Obviously, you know Glasgow Roller Derby well, but what was your first encounter?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Anna Malady] I remember seeing reports of Roller Derby in Glasgow from 4 years ago. Unfortunately it took another 2 years for either Gary or I to get to a live Bout. This was courtesy of some friends (Turbulinz and Bruisedog) who posted a Bout poster up on Facebook. I remember being confused for the majority of the time, but still coming away hoarse from shouting. It was exhilarating and just fantastic!
Gary joined me at the afterparty that night and we were hooked by not just the sport but the community spirit, the personalities, individuality, and colour. The whole atmosphere and pure community spirit of the sport gets into your blood and lifts you to believe in yourself. That may come across a bit new age, but for us, and many people we talk to its fact, so I don’t apologise for sounding like a hippy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gary and I then asked Yel to colour our project as Gary had worked with her in the past and we’re both massively impressed with her work. She is a talented colourist who has worked on quite a few projects with Gary including The Irons:Hybrids motion comic published by Madefire. Her colourist credits of note include The Only Good Dalek (BBC books, 2010), Need for Speed; The Run (EA Games/Firebrand, 2011) and she is currently working on the ongoing graphic novel series Hero; 9-5 for Markosia. You can see more of her work at &lt;a href="http://yelzamor.carbonmade.com/projects/"&gt;http://yelzamor.carbonmade.com/projects/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Gary] We were both fans of the sport following it online but were never able to attend a bout due to travelling and convention commitments. Our first bout proved an exhilarating experience and encouraged/convinced both Anna and I that a comic book series about the sport and characters within that would be a similarly exciting project to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anna, how did you get into the comic book scene?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Anna] My first introduction to the whole world of comics was exiting a lift into the lobby of a convention hotel and seeing 4 stormtroopers explaining to 2 firemen how the imperial guard were stuck in the next lift and they needed out to do their guest appearance. The next morning Star Fox (in full costume) was complaining to the bewildered front desk staff that there was no hot water in her room and that afternoon there was a showdown between a squad of Stormtoopers and a bronze Dalek. I mean, how could you not love this scene?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/04/an-interview-with-the-roller-grrrls-team/rollergrrlssplace/" rel="attachment wp-att-1949"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-1949" alt="Probably the most popularly distributed preview from Roller Grrrls." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/12/rollergrrlssplace.jpg?w=193" height="300" width="193"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Probably the most popularly distributed preview from Roller Grrrls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are some obvious life models for some of the Roller Grrrls character studies (especially for anyone who knows Glasgow Roller Derby's skaters and announcers), but the majority have no single origin. Roughly, how much of real personalities went into the comic as a whole (as opposed to the other influences, such as Helles Belles)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Anna] Many of the characters are collages of real people. A body build from here, a tattoo from there, a hair style or colour from someone else. A couple of characters are drawn from real people, close friends who got us into Roller Derby in the first place. They know who they are. Being close friends they also know that it’s their image we are borrowing, not their characters or lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important to emphasise is that none of the character traits, personalities or story arcs are from real life. HOWEVER, we’ve been amazed how often we find that fiction has unwittingly reflected someone’s reality. We were seriously worried about it for a while. It seemed that, as we got to know the girls from the awesome Glasgow Roller Derby, and got round to discussing our project with them (often, although not always, after a few drinks at the afterparties) that someone in the team had been through the experiences we were writing about. Then as we got to know the UK Derby community we found out that quite a few girls had experienced a rough journey to get where they are and realised that these are people who
1) aren’t afraid to live a full life, and
2) are in general happy to talk about it and share their experience, especially if by doing so they can help others living through the same challenges.
We realised that of course we were going to come across people with experience of what we’d written. So we stopped worrying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But finally I would like to re-emphasise that the Roller Grrrls are totally fictitious and the situations they find themselves in, and their reactions, are totally made up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Gary] See above!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As roller derby can be a very fast paced game, I guess you do most of your reference work against photography, but some of the panels are from perspectives you can’t have had a reference for (the big “downed skater” view, for example). Can you guys talk a little about the process of constructing a page, and if there are particular challenges for sporting/action vs more sedentary scenes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Gary] There are certain considerations regarding the representation of any fast sport in an illustrated format. With some experience of storyboarding and animatics for game trailers there are visual tricks available to help keep the frantic and exciting energy of roller derby in a static/frozen image. Drawing the characters in layers with a separate background allows me to put on a motion blur for each parallax layer to help show the speed of the foreground figures and the blurring of other team members (and the crowd) in the background.
It is a similar effect to the slow shutter speed on a camera. Forced perspectives and POV shots also help give an immediacy to the action and provide new shots for the bout action. I also particularly want to show shots from 'in pack’ which would be near impossible to do in a real life bout. The comic format allows new opportunities to show some exciting possibilities of how the sport can be seen (in an illustrated format).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another trick we are toying with is to use motion effects and transitions (testing with Powerpoint initially) to create actual movement and subtle animation for a possible Roller Grrrls trailer. If successful then we may well have a digital release with bout action that moves on the page/screen. Watch this space! ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I assume this is the first "wholly self-supported" comic project the three of you have worked on? How's the experience of the indie comic project compare to previous work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Gary]My own previous experience in the industry has always been on the creative side, so this new publishing (and distribution) venture has been both exciting and scary for both of us and fairly new territory.
Having said that we have had a lot of very good (and much appreciated) advice from Jessica Ali of &lt;a href="http://www.insidelinemagazine.co.uk/"&gt;Inside Line&lt;/a&gt; and Vic Croughan of &lt;a href="http://www.leadjammermag.com/"&gt;Lead Jammer&lt;/a&gt; magazines. They have been especially helpful and generous with us and we really couldn't have got to this stage as quickly or comfortably without their help. Jessica was kind enough to recommend the printer to us (possibly the single most important decision for us!) and we can't thank her enough and Vic was offering indispensable advice for InDesign. Without those two key points we would not have our Roller Grrrls Sketchbook printed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's easy to compare Roller Grrrls with other "slice of life" comics, like the Hernandez' &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_and_Rockets_(comics)"&gt;Love and Rockets&lt;/a&gt; (or even &lt;a href="http://www.strangersinparadise.com/"&gt;Strangers in Paradise&lt;/a&gt;, before it got all Gritty). Do you think this is a valid comparison? - I notice that both came from an initially SF setting (albeit pre-design in RG's case) which went away as the concept solidified.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Gary]Roller Grrrls is very definitely inspired by Love and Rockets first and Strangers in Paradise also serves as an influence. There is little else out there that we would consider similar to what we are wanting to do (although some super hero team books do also have 'slice of life' storylines in between the predictable battles and villians) The Helles Belles project was something we wanted to work on a few years ago when we were living in Germany and was an all-female sci-fi adventure that unfortunately turned into Firefly (which we had never seen) The similarities were obvious and added to the work involved to design a new world environment kind of killed the project for us. We both still felt that female teams and characters were desperately under-valued and presented in mainstream books or worse still, shown in over-sexualised forms. I then considered a Rollerball reboot for Rebellion with the girls replacing Jonathan and the Houston team but the initial response from a couple of writers I approached was lukewarm and it stalled again. A casual chat with Mhairi one night about what needed to change with the ensemble story coincided with that fateful invitation to the GRD bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not write the story in a contemporary setting instead and the ideas and references (Love and Rockets/Strangers in Paradise) literally flowed out over dinner. I quickly decided on the name Roller Grrrls as I liked the association with the Riot Grrrls movement and the rest as they say is history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading the little “pocket bio” strips you did to introduce the characters, each of them has a fairly distinctive “trait” - from the cultural barriers of the Hindu student roller girls, and the clear drama of the pregnant “ex” derby girl with the difficult home life through to contrasts between “tame” librarianship and active derby playing. With a large ensemble cast, each with a potentially complex personal plotline, how are you planning on balancing the comic? Are we going to see character-specific issues, or something more interwoven?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Anna]Just as real life is a tangle of relationships and stories this is what we want to do with RG. Obviously it will have to be oversimplified and the time frames will be shortened. There is also an obvious balance to be struck between putting too much into a single issue and not enough.
We obviously think we’ve struck that balance, I guess we’ll really find out when we start to get feedback from the fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Gary] Redacted! ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roller Grrrls Sketchbook is available to buy now, with the Roller Grrrls comic proper due sometime next year. All images in this post are, of course, copyright Roller Grrls&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>pictures</category><category>roller derby</category><category>roller grrrls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/12/04/an-interview-with-the-roller-grrrls-team/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 19:56:35 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>