<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about roller derby bootcamp)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/roller-derby-bootcamp.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Dundee's Beginner Bootcamp Bonanza</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/16/dundees-beginner-bootcamp-bonanza/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-20568" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/bootcamp-banner-blog.png" alt="Skate Tay Victory!" width="727" height="315"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girls are hosting their first ever bootcamp on the &lt;strong&gt;first of July&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;Manhattan Works, Dundee! &lt;/strong&gt;Open to all, this bootcamp is welcoming pre mins skaters as well as recently passed individuals looking to cement their derby skillz! This event boasts four hours (&lt;strong&gt;11am - 3pm) &lt;/strong&gt;of minimal contact training, with on skates tickets selling out on day 1 - &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;spectator tickets are left for a mere £10 a head!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breaking the day down into sections: the five DRG coaches are Goldginger #77, G-Wrecks #713, Hubs #88, Landsborough #792 and Liston #07! Attendees can look forward to the following lessons:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;♥ Wall work with Hubs and G-Wrecks! ♥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter  wp-image-20812" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/walls.png?w=300" alt="walls" width="446" height="336"&gt; &lt;em&gt;"We can't wait to get started on our block for the bootcamp! Sharing skating skills with newer skaters and encouraging everyone, no matter their skating levels, to engage with the core skills needed to further roller derby in Scotland is something we both really want to be a part of! It's really the best way to start the summer!!"&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;♥ Jammer work with Landborough and Goldginger ♥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter wp-image-20811" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/jammers.png" alt="jammers" width="437" height="336"&gt; &lt;em&gt;"Our league has really benefited from specific jammer drills and discussions on how to approach the Star. Being able to share our experiences not only on a skills level but also a coaching level is a really exciting prospect! We'll work you hard but it'll be worth it!"&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;♥ Footwork with Liston ♥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-16584" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/laura-liston.png" alt="Laura Liston" width="271" height="355"&gt; &lt;em&gt;"The building blocks for good wall work always starts with footwork! Lateral movement, recaptures and even jammer work relies on skaters having a strong base of footwork! I'm hoping to break down some of the more daunting skills for skaters to work on before bringing them into the wall! If you're stronger as one, you're stronger together."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to on skates tickets selling out on the first day, the DRG have added extra off skates spectator tickets to allow more to attend! Spectators will be welcomed in discussions of skills and drills throughout the day, to ask questions to any of the coaches as well as take notes, pictures and videos. As this bootcamp is aimed at post/pre mins, the coaches are hoping that skaters will take their newly polished skills back to their leagues to extend the learning process around Scotland (and further afield!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information please visit the event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1852866768310688/?ref=br_rs" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
Link for off skates tickets (£10) can be found: &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2932707" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coaching</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>roller derby bootcamp</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/16/dundees-beginner-bootcamp-bonanza/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 09:00:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow Roller Derby:  Next Level Bootcamp &amp; Guest Coaching Available</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/02/02/glasgow-roller-derby-next-level-bootcamp-guest-coaching-available/</link><dc:creator>paingrrl666</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img id="featured-image" class=" aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/getattachment.jpg" alt="Featured image" width="273" height="163"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby had an exciting year last year, and now we are looking to share our learning with other leagues!
We have lots on offer, both for leagues and for individual skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sat 21st March, we are hosting our ‘Next Level Bootcamp.  This is a fully co-ed bootcamp, which is aimed at two levels – people wishing to learn basic skills for passing minimums (stops/stride/laterals), and then people who have passed minimum skills and are aiming to become bout ready (agility, edge work, hockey stops etc).   The bootcamp is being offered at the super reasonable price of £25 on-skates, and £15 off-skates.  We will also have our very special Roller Grrls t-shirts available for sale which are unavailable for general purchase, as well as a range of other Grd merch.  You can book a place on the bootcamp &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/787419911313296/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also available to leagues who would like some guest coaching, and have developed a training menu which will cater for league at any level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have coaches available to cover sessions such as:-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;all levels of skills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;all levels of strategy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nutrition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;off skates fitness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mental conditioning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;league morale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;team building&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;scrimmage/bout footage reviewing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to take advantage of this opportunity, please contact &lt;a href="mailto:interleagueliaison@glasgowrollerderby.com"&gt;interleagueliaison@glasgowrollerderby.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to meeting you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/grd.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4565 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/grd.jpg?w=300" alt="grd" width="310" height="119"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>grd</category><category>roller derby bootcamp</category><category>roller derby bootcamps</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/02/02/glasgow-roller-derby-next-level-bootcamp-guest-coaching-available/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 15:57:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Doonhame Derby Dolls: Dollfest</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/14/doonhame-derby-dolls-dollfest-2/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/dollfest.png"&gt;&lt;img src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/dollfest.png" alt="Image courtesy of Doonhame Derby Dolls" width="614" height="877" class="size-full wp-image-3572"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Doonhame Derby Dolls
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.doonhamederbydolls.co.uk/"&gt;Doonhame Derby Dolls&lt;/a&gt; present Dollfest, a series of events over the weekend of 15/16/17 August. 
For DDD members there are open forum discussions and a boot-camp featuring guest coaches from &lt;a href="http://windsorrollergirls.com/"&gt;Royal Windsor Rollergirls&lt;/a&gt;. 
For non members, a chance to meet the guest coaches, and find out about volunteering with the Doonhame Derby Dolls in a more social setting, with live music and dj's.
&lt;a href="http://www.doonhamederbydolls.co.uk/index.php/ct-menu-item-3"&gt;Contact the Dolls&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>doonhame derby dolls</category><category>roller derby bootcamp</category><category>roller derby bootcamps</category><category>royal windsor rollergirls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/14/doonhame-derby-dolls-dollfest-2/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 23:15:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>School of ARRG Knocks:Beginner and Intermediate Bootcamp</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/09/04/school-of-arrg-knocksbeginner-and-intermediate-bootcamp/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/09/arrgknocks.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/09/arrgknocks.jpg" alt="" title="arrgknocks" width="608" height="430" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1684"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls have released ticket prices and details on their upcoming boot camp, the School Of ARRG Knocks on Saturday the 6th of October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day will feature...
two tracks running sessions for different levels with coaches from Auld Reekie Roller Girls' All Star Travel Team.
off skates strategy, skate maintenance, fitness and league structure sessions.
a day-long referee bootcamp with WFTDA certified official and Head Referee of Leeds Roller Dolls, Boris Snarloff.
a graduation scrimmage.
an amazing not-to-be-missed afterparty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limited tickets are available &lt;a href="http://schoolofarrgknocks.eventbrite.com/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and prices are as follows:
Skater Ticket (Minimums passed skater)£35.00  &lt;br&gt;
Referee Ticket £25.00
Off Skates Referee/NSO Ticket £10.00
Off Skates Skater Ticket £10.00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>roller derby bootcamp</category><category>roller derby bootcamps</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/09/04/school-of-arrg-knocksbeginner-and-intermediate-bootcamp/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 01:14:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Tale Of Two Bootcamps</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/07/27/a-tale-of-two-bootcamps/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are two upcoming bootcamps to mark in your diaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/07/newbielogo4.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/07/newbielogo4.gif" alt="" title="newbielogo4" width="614" height="790" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1562"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up is Glasgow Roller Derby's &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/415060935206862/"&gt;Harder Better Faster Stronger&lt;/a&gt; on Saturday the 11th of August.A day dedicated to the skills new skaters need to pass their minimums.You can register your interest &lt;a href="http://regonline.activeeurope.com/Register/Checkin.aspx?EventID=1120768"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
Please note that all attending skaters must bring their own kit in addition to both black and coloured shirts with name and number.
You can read SRD's own Chasing Katy's thoughts on attending a previous GRD Bootcamp &lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/15/newbie-bootcamps-how-they-can-help-skaters-grow-and-improve/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/07/arrgknocks.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/07/arrgknocks.jpg" alt="" title="arrgknocks" width="608" height="430" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1563"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next is the Auld Reekie Roller Girls' event, School Of ARRG Knocks on Saturday the 6th of October.This one is for minimums passed skaters only,on and off skates training,strategy and a whole lot more.
More details nearer the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>grd</category><category>roller derby bootcamp</category><category>roller derby bootcamps</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/07/27/a-tale-of-two-bootcamps/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 21:13:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Newbie bootcamps...how they can help skaters grow and improve</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/15/newbie-bootcamps-how-they-can-help-skaters-grow-and-improve/</link><dc:creator>pandacatkaty</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/skates1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1094" title="skates" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/04/skates1.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="720"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, I, and around 50 other skaters from leagues around the country, took part in the Glasgow Roller Derby newbie bootcamp. Afterwards, tired and sore, I lay in a bath and reflected on the day. And for me, it was a boost of not just my skills, but also my confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first heard about GRD's bootcamp, designed to help newbies pass their minimums, I was excited. I'd been stuck in a bit of a skating plateau, and felt this was what would clear the mental block and get me through my tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the closer it came to April 7, the more nervous I got. I had never really skated with people from other leagues, what if they were miles better than I was, what if I looked like an idiot, what if I couldn't keep up with what we were doing, OH MY GOD I'M SKATING IN FRONT OF PEOPLE FROM GRD, WHO ARE AWESOME!! My brain was turning me into a ball of panic and anxiety, and I was powerless to stop it. Nightmare!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, a couple of nights before, I voiced my fears to a member of my league, who told me to "do what you could, take breaks when you need to, but get back up and keep going". This simple sentence worked wonders, and on the day it kept resonating in my brain. It was not about other people, I just had to do the best I could and learn as much as I could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the day, the nerves continued as I approach ARC. But inside, I saw the many other girls who had made the trip to Glasgow and realised that many, if not all, were probably feeling the same way I was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After filling in waivers, we were called on track for a group warm up. I will admit, I wasn't at my best. The nerves, coupled with an unknown floor (it was my first time skating at ARC) and new wheels (I had borrowed some slim wheels to try out) had me unsteady on my feet. But I got used to it and managed to keep up with the knee falls, stops and baseball slides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, much to my relief, we were allowed to pick whether we went into a basic, or more advanced group. The relief was, we got to pick ourselves, based on how we felt about our capabilities. Had the coaches singled me out and put me in a group I didn't think matched my abilities, I would have been mortified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it was down to business. Throughout the day, we covered laterals, a lot of hitting (lateral hits, close hits), positional blocking, keeping your feet moving (having Viper up your ass screaming "FEET! FEET! FEET!" as you made your way between two pacelines was a daunting experience), transitions and much more. At every step, there were a number of GRD skaters helping, talking you through it, giving demonstrations and advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a hardcore day, that pushed me to my limit. And as I said earlier, by the end of it I was sore, knackered and incredibly smelly. All I wanted after was a bath, a meal and my bed (which is pretty much how the rest of my evening went).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the thing...It was probably the best thing I could have done for my skills and confidence. Yes, there were times I had to come off track and stretch my leg (which had been giving me a bit of bother earlier in the week) but I remembered what I was told, took the time and then got back on track. And yes, there are some things that I didn't manage to master and will need to continued to work on. But I got to meet some new people, see how other skaters were developing (and yes, for every skater that was ahead of me, skills-wise, there was one who wasn't as advanced as I was), and I got to learn and practice skills that I will use on-track for as long as I do derby. I was taught by some of the best skaters in Scotland, and actually got praise from them!! I broke through that wall that was stopping me from improving, by staying in the game and not letting either my brain or my physical limitations defeat me (although I did have to stop about 20 minutes from the end when my leg decided that it had had enough). I also got advice on nutrition, equipment and being a newbie going through the process of passing minimums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that I've got a long way to go, but this bootcamp has shown me that I can do it...if I can skate for nearly seven hours and not pass out, suffer serious injury or die, I can get passed my minimums and hopefully become a pretty kick-ass skater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again to Glasgow Roller Derby and to newbies out there....the next time you see a newbie bootcamp, sign up. You won't regret it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>roller derby bootcamp</category><category>roller derby bootcamps</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/04/15/newbie-bootcamps-how-they-can-help-skaters-grow-and-improve/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 11:51:49 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>