<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about roller derby world cup)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/roller-derby-world-cup.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:34:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Team Scotland Events: Fundraiser coming to a close!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/06/team-scotland-events-fundraiser-coming-to-a-close/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While over on Facebook, we've been regularly sharing info about the preparations for the various National Teams heading for the two Roller Derby World Cups next year... we've been saving a blog post for the Scottish National teams, starting with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Team-Scotland-Roller-Derby-235701999922927/"&gt;Team Scotland Roller Derby.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13779 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/scotland.png" alt="scotland" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In common with many of the teams heading for the 3rd Roller Derby World Cup in Trafford, England, Team Scotland are &lt;a href="https://www.crowdfunder.co.uk/team-scotland-roller-derby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;raising money&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to support their attendance. (Being a National Team has all the costs you would expect, from training venues, equipment, travel and accommodation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a special consideration this time around, &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; of the funds raised by TS will be donated to the charity &lt;strong&gt;Mind&lt;/strong&gt;, in support of mental health - and if you feel like you need a more tangible personal benefit for donating, all donations above &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; are eligible for Team Scotland branded merch, with donations above &lt;strong&gt;£75&lt;/strong&gt; enabling you to sponsor a specific Team Scotland Rostered Skater (who will wear a sponsors patch provided, during the World Cup).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have just until the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; to donate to the fundraiser, and help it reach its goal of just £2000, so please consider donating!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donation link is here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.crowdfunder.co.uk/team-scotland-roller-derby/"&gt;https://www.crowdfunder.co.uk/team-scotland-roller-derby/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in competing with Team Scotland, as well as supporting them, there's also the opportunity still to sign up as part of the mash-up team who will get to scrim against TS at their November training session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up in the Manhattan Works venue (Dundee Roller Girls' training venue), you will get to play with the best skaters that Scotland has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's still time to sign up here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/111479986185051/?"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/111479986185051/?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, if you'd like to help Team Scotland, rather than compete against them, applications are now open for the position of "Team Sports Therapist" attending the team for their training sessions, and competition, including the World Cup itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apply here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScwqegWr0F1-lAoO0hrXqrFLDx-fi1ueSwz7K9wZP4D3HugcA/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScwqegWr0F1-lAoO0hrXqrFLDx-fi1ueSwz7K9wZP4D3HugcA/viewform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on in the Year, Team Scotland will be making appearances at a few other events, so stay tuned to see how you can catch them on track before the World Cup!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>crowdfunding</category><category>fundraising</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/06/team-scotland-events-fundraiser-coming-to-a-close/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 14:13:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Upcoming National Teams Bouts</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/12/upcoming-national-teams-bouts/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With both World Cups now less than a year away - the&lt;a href="http://www.rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;in February, and the &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in April, there's an increasing number of National Teams related fixtures being announced, as all the teams get in some practice, some visibility, and some fundraising opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's easy to miss what's happening, so maybe it helps to keep them all in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the events we're aware of (and do please let us know if we've missed anything!)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Women's National Teams&lt;/h3&gt;
15th July: Equipe de &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt; play an exhibition bout hosted by Les Passeuses Dâmes [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1394914887229155/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;p&gt;15th July: Team &lt;strong&gt;Portugal&lt;/strong&gt; have an open training session for Portuguese skaters [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1887307271583565/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16 July: at least some of Team &lt;strong&gt;Germany&lt;/strong&gt; are at Euro Derby Con participating in events [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/596116850567901/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22 July: Team &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; Roller Derby turn up to play London Rollergirls B, the Brawl Saints as part of a double header in London [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/431163560596192/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29 July: Team &lt;strong&gt;Korea&lt;/strong&gt; and Team &lt;strong&gt;Philippines&lt;/strong&gt; make their world debuts at Rollercon, playing against each other on Saturday! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/143735569514656/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29 July: Team &lt;strong&gt;South Africa&lt;/strong&gt; have their final round of tryouts! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1932492993665870/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5-6 August: Team &lt;strong&gt;England&lt;/strong&gt; host Team &lt;strong&gt;Sweden&lt;/strong&gt;, Team &lt;strong&gt;Finland&lt;/strong&gt; and Team &lt;strong&gt;Canada&lt;/strong&gt; for a weekend round-robin event, in Nottingham! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1883460565201595/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5-6 August: &lt;strong&gt;Aotearoa&lt;/strong&gt; Roller Derby (Team &lt;strong&gt;New Zealand&lt;/strong&gt;) play a black v white scrim, followed by a bootcamp run by their coach, Mick Swagger. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/147390622507530/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 August: Team &lt;strong&gt;England&lt;/strong&gt; will also be scrimming with an open subscription team after that round-robin [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/203298956860930/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 August, 20th August: Team&lt;strong&gt; West Indies&lt;/strong&gt; scrim against all comers in two open subscription bouts in Bedford (6th) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1962826457294629/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;] and Birmingham (20th) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/738090882982520/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 September: Team &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; will be taking on a scrimmage against an open subscription team [Applications open] [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1874512536208906/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23 September: Équipe de &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt; Feminine host a fixture against 2 undisclosed National Teams, in Tourcoing, France [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/276715376142982/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 October: Team &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt; host Team Italy and Team Netherlands for a triple header [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/298561590623060/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;Austria&lt;/strong&gt; are hosting Team Germany and Team Switzerland for a triple header [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/138743263531937/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; are playing an undisclosed team in Dublin [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/666484320215767/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; are again scrimmaging with an open subscription team (applications open) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/111479986185051/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;England&lt;/strong&gt; take on an undisclosed team in Peterborough. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/105377736693871/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2-3 December: Team &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt; welcomes undisclosed opponents to the Road to Manchester tournament! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/222986121542528/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Men's National Teams&lt;/h3&gt;
(Some time during this period, Team &lt;strong&gt;Finland&lt;/strong&gt; are planning... something.)
&lt;p&gt;15 July: Team &lt;strong&gt;New Zealand&lt;/strong&gt; have their tryouts in Kawerau [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/287594671647468/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23 July: Team &lt;strong&gt;England's&lt;/strong&gt; Stage 1 Tryouts (open submission) happen in Nottingham [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1409006599141670/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5-6 August: Team &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt; host the Torneo Barcelona City... but aren't playing in it? [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1906063339640738/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 October: Team &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt; have a mysterious event [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/246263629227122/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18-19 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;Netherlands&lt;/strong&gt; hosts &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Italy&lt;/strong&gt; in a "Road to Barcelona" event. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/259318537912275/?"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18-19 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;Germany&lt;/strong&gt; hosts undisclosed opponents in a... "Road to Barcelona" event [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/482556138758766/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;England&lt;/strong&gt; take on an undisclosed team in Peterborough (double header with Women's team above) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/105377736693871/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2018</category><category>team scotland</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/12/upcoming-national-teams-bouts/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 16:08:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Poland: New to the World Cup 2018</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/09/team-poland-new-to-the-world-cup-2018/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Returning to our series on the 11 teams new to the Roller Derby World Cup 2018 in Manchester, and we're staying in Europe for this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poland, despite having one of the largest populations in Central Europe, has only recently developed a significant Roller Derby population. We talked to one of Team Poland's organisers, Ewa Kaczyńska, about the formation of the National Team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-19856" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/screen-shot-2017-06-02-at-15-34-22.png?w=300" alt="Screen Shot 2017-06-02 at 15.34.22" width="300" height="188"&gt; The Polish Flag (standing in for Team Poland's logo)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Roller Derby having only come to Poland in 2013 - the first league in Poznań quickly followed by Warsaw, then Wrocław, Szczecin and Gdańsk - there was little possibility to compete in the 2014 World Cup. Since then, Polish Derby has grown considerably, to the point of holding their first &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1232048456872900/"&gt;Derby Sevens tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; this year, as well as hosting one of Scald Eagle &amp;amp; Lady Trample's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1852698681626181/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WinTourOpe bootcamp&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; dates. Whilst not all the leagues are huge at the moment (there's a preference for mixed team events and scrims to cover the numbers for the smaller teams), Polish derby is still growing and in a strong position in the Central European vanguard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is often the case, inline skating is more popular in Poland than Quads, although, Ewa notes: "[interest in quad skates] is growing, here is a better access to quads in shops. However, not that much luck with roller derby related skate shops, as there are just 3 or 4 with limited offerings." It's perhaps the growth of Chicks in Bowls, which also has a Polish branch, which is helping to drive this interest, helping out Roller derby with the cross-over, as it does elsewhere. "Yes, they definitely [help]. It's good that girls are taking over the skateparks!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more derby related help, the community surrounding has been supportive, with bootcamps and shared bouts popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Thanks to skaters from all over the World we are able to organize bootcamps led by experienced coaches," Ewa told us. "That is so much different from learning from the book - as we did at first! 'Roller Derby 101: The Fresh Meat Training Manual ' was our first derby bible... Now, we get a lot of help and support from Czech and German teams - I guess it's just the thing with neighbours! &lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We also get  lots of help from Polish (and other) skaters from all over the World.&lt;/span&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the intent to participate applications opened for the 2018 World Cup,  Poland were actually the last team to sign up, as Ewa notes: "There’s been a discussion about founding Polish National Roller Derby Team going on since November 2016 in Poland. [...]No decisions were made until the very last moment before the registration period ended. We formed a Founding Committee and acted!
I think [the decision] was just about not letting people miss the opportunity to represent Poland."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ewa also had personal reasons for pushing for the decision to commit, "I believe that sometimes people need to be pushed a bit. Sometimes no decisions are made simply because of the lack of courage, or ability to take responsibility for one's actions. I started derby three years ago and I started it to compete later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;At first I thought that Polish skaters are not yet ready to compete on such level as World Cup. Since last November, we had numerous discussions with more experienced skaters. We got a lot of encouragement and support and then it suddenly became clear to us: t&lt;/span&gt;hings like forming a National Team need to be done to push things further, to make teams grow, to create opportunities for development. We cannot just sit doing nothing!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the last-minute decision, Poland's size and population have immediately produced results, with more than 50 skaters registered to try out or otherwise be involved, with around 50% from the existing Polish teams, and the rest from across the World. Poland has many nationals, and descendants of nationals, spread across the world - in Europe and in the USA - and many of them feel just as much pride for their country as those who live there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"After we decided to found Team Poland we got a massive response from other parts of the World, which is just amazing; [...] it is truly touching when we get messages from people that 'want to do it for their Grandpa', although we would [also] love Team Poland to have lots of Polish girls living in Poland!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for all National Teams, and especially the newer ones, Team Poland are driven by more than simply patriotism. With National teams comes the chance of better visibility for Roller Derby as well - and a chance to combat myths and prejudice. "What really pushed us to form TP is a bigger picture," explains Ewa. "We know that all the teams went the same way at the beginning: rented vintage skates, no proper protection, no coaches, no places to skate. Also most of people think about roller derby as of 'rugby on quads' or an aggressive sport for punk girls with piercings and tattoos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely, we do have them, but taking a part in such a big event could be an eye opener for people here! We would love them to acknowledge this sport as an athletic discipline, not only for 'outcasts'..."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And part of growing that athletic image is, of course, better training. As we discussed with &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/26/team-austria-new-to-the-world-cup/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Austria&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the advantage of  National Teams is also in the sharing of experience and skills, and Ewa agrees. "We all think that apart from World Cup, the following months will let us all benefit from the joined training sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a big step for Polish roller derby, that's for sure!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no Team Poland website or Facebook page yet - interested people should email the team at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:team.Poland.roller.derby@gmail.com"&gt;team.Poland.roller.derby@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;or&lt;strong&gt; message Ewa Kaczyńska on Facebook.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2018</category><category>team poland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/09/team-poland-new-to-the-world-cup-2018/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 15:25:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Romania: new to the World Cup</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/10/team-romania-new-to-the-world-cup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Next in our series of articles covering new teams in the 2018 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the smallest attendees. Representing Eastern Europe along with Team Russia, it's Team Romania!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20282" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/romania.jpg" alt="Romania" width="800" height="800"&gt; Team Romania Logo: by Libby Odai and &lt;span class=""&gt;Alina Usurelu&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;As with much of Eastern Europe, the spread of Roller Derby in Romania has been very slow: in fact, there are currently no leagues in the country, even in the capital Bucharest. Team Romania, then, is necessarily formed from expats and descendants of citizens - with the intent to promote the sport in the country itself as a result.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Exe QT, one of Team Romania's founders, is perhaps typical. "I've lived in Sweden since I was 4, so I'm pretty much Swedish," she told us, "even though I go back to Romania once every couple of years and obviously still speak Romanian with my mum, relatives etc..."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;A skater for Gothenburg Roller Derby, Exe QT first thought of the possibility of Romanian entry for the World Cup because of a chance meeting at a London Rollergirls bootcamp. London Brawling's AnDrac is herself of Romanian ancestry, and meeting someone so well known in the sport set a "seed" in her brain. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;All it took for it to sprout was hearing that there were other eligible skaters... and it started to look very possible indeed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Despite there not being any skaters in Romania itself, the team takes the representation of their country seriously. "I believe it's a huge thing to get to represent your nation, in any situation," says Exe QT. "I am proud of my heritage, even though in my daily life, no-one would think about that I'm basically a first generation 'immigrant'." &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;And this patriotism is something echoed by fellow Team Romania member Tenacious (of Kent Roller Girls), for whom representation is really important: “to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; represent Romania, myself, a woman, to the world it's fantastic! We have always had great females taking part in many different sports, females that I have always looked up to with a lot of respect and admiration. I would like to show that Team Romania can be diverse and supportive of all genders of people!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;AnDrac, who has joined the Team Romania roster herself, told us, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"I am finally starting to feel quite excited about a potential Team Romania in the next World Cup as there is no roller derby in Romania yet. Hopefully we will be able to find a few more players to field a team.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;It will be an experience for all of us as we won't really have the time to train together like the more established teams but we would have paved the path for the future Romanians that play or will play Roller Derby around the world. Exciting times ahead!"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;As with many of the newer teams, the aim for Team Romania this time around is simply to represent. Exe QT notes, "For the Cup, I'm hoping that we could all go there and have fun! No-one should be upset if we lose games, and we could all celebrate being able to skate for our birth nation, enjoying the ambience, meeting new friends.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;If we would win a few games that would be awesome.  But I don't want to put too much pressure on everyone, because we will be a team that barely would have practiced together, and that is a big disadvantage!"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;And in the future, maybe Roller Derby will come to Bucharest itself! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Exe QT: "It would be great if we could find some people in Romania who'd be interested in starting up a team, but as we both know, it requires not only a lot of time and energy, but also money. Where should they practice, how do they get equipment etc etc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;I'd love to go there for a week and coach derby, like a full week's program on and off skates, so that they could start up (I coach my league, and I really love it)"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Even for the National Team itself, experienced skaters from Romania are welcome, as Tenacious notes, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;“I know Romanians are big on skating, inline especially. We can find a way of getting a team together, coaching them, even from the distance, if there's anyone interested in putting themselves forward!”&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Team Romania are still recruiting for players, and looking for coaches and support staff of all kinds, so if you would like to skate with them, apply at their Facebook page here: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/RollerDerbyTeamRomania/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;https://www.facebook.com/RollerDerbyTeamRomania/&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="_4tdt _ua1"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international</category><category>international derby</category><category>new national teams</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2018</category><category>team romania</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/10/team-romania-new-to-the-world-cup/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 10:20:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Austria: New to the World Cup</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/26/team-austria-new-to-the-world-cup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've previously covered the first sets of new teams to appear before the 2018 World Cup in two articles - 5 of them in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/22/new-nations-in-the-world-cup/"&gt;this roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; last year, and Team Iran &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/02/representing-the-middle-east-the-effort-to-build-team-iran/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there are even more teams arriving on the scene for what will be the largest World Cup ever... and we're catching up with the rest of them in this series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first subject is a Nation which is surprising, perhaps, for its previous absence: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/rollerderbyteamaustria/"&gt;Austria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-17819" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/teamaustria.png" alt="TeamAustria" width="1378" height="1378"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Whilst neighbouring Germany was one of the first European nations to gain Roller Derby leagues, and Team Germany having attended both previous World Cups, Derby in Austria has developed more slowly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;For many years, the capital Vienna was the site of the only league in the country, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.viennarollerderby.org/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Vienna Roller Derby&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;, founded in 2011 (as Vienna Rollergirls). Vienna, whilst an active league, was not even a WFTDA member at the time of the 2014 World Cup, and so a Team Austria simply wasn't on the cards then...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Team Austria's rep KnockOut Nora explains, "Even Vienna wasn't ready when the last World Cup came up (and it was 2014, its really such a long time ago already). And I think, no-one in Austria had even thought of the possibility of participating."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"Austria's just really slow when it comes to Derby, I think. Especially when you compare it to Germany, say, they have a Championship [the Bundesliga], there's 40 teams or more. Or if you compare it to France... &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;In Austria, I think it's really quite a different situation, because we're just, even now, four teams." &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Only much more recently, three more leagues, in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/linzrollerderby/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Linz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; (to the North) in 2015; and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/fearlessbruisers/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Innsbruck&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; (to the East) and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/dustcityrollers/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Graz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; (to the South), in 2016, have formed, but the Roller Derby scene in Austria is very much still developing.  As with the Czech Republic, Poland and further East, it seems like it's more difficult to sell the game in Central and Eastern Europe.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;This is a problem which Nora has also been thinking about: "Yeah, actually, I really don't know what it is - I started derby in the Netherlands originally, I skated there for 3 months, and, especially if I compare it to the Netherlands; there's also so many teams there, I think they're better connected; the people were so much more willing to travel, and everything was just closer. "&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"But I think in general, Austria might be a little slow with new things, and especially when it comes to derby, I mean, a sport for women and then people are kind of suspicious because there's no balls involved(!). I wish it were different! But I think things are really starting to change now - with the three newer teams, they're really really motivated, and I mean there's been so many [new] girls within the last one and a half years, so I think it's also maybe changing at the moment with Derby in Austria."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"And I also see the World Cup, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;participation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; in the World Cup, as maybe a turning point ... to also make it more 'official' in Austria maybe. Because it's also something that people know, and that they can relate to a World Cup - it makes our sport sound more Official to some people." &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"If I compare it to Vienna: the team is going on for more than 5 years now, we fill out every game, we have a huge fan crowd and we have an A and B team, Fearleaders, it's quite a thing already... and it's still really hard to get funding, and to get venues which are not city owned. And perhaps with National teams this will change, and they'll take it more seriously, and think 'this is a real sport, they play it in other nations, and other cities'... and I think that this is also what this Team means to me, actually, that it might create visibility for Roller Derby in Austria."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Especially with this World Cup projected to be the biggest yet, with (not yet confirmed) comfortably more teams attending than the 2014 World Cup, itself large with 30. It's hard to discount the relevance of a sporting event with quite so many nations involved...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"Yeah, it's a big thing, and that's also something you can tell the people when you're applying for funding - this is really happening, it's a real thing, there's 40 nations coming, and it creates a little bit more seriousness to the sport then."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;To take part can also be a difficult thing in itself. The announcement that the 2018 Roller Derby World Cup would be held in Manchester was a catalyst for the formation of Team Austria. Whilst there was a chance that the Cup would be held far away for a third time running, there was no point in trying to form the team - why recruit if you won't be able to afford to travel?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"As soon as the decision was made that it would be in Manchester, I think this is the point where the people involved in planning - 12 people - we all knew that we could really make it happen.. and then we started to plan &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;for real&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Before then, it was always more like 'let's see what happens', because I think many people wouldn't have been able to afford flying to Australia, or South Africa, or South America... or anywhere except Europe! It would have been quite a financial disaster for most of my team!"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Team Austria have yet to hold their tryouts, and are hoping that when they do, they will be able to represent all of Austria, and Austrians outside the country as well.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"So, the thing is we haven't had our tryouts yet. The tryouts will take place in June - we are still looking for Skaters. Everything is still quite vague, we're 10-12 people who are planning in Vienna, and we're at the moment organising everything connected to the National Team. It's only Vienna skaters at the moment - the other leagues are busy with hosting their first bouts. We really hope that all of the leagues in Austria will be involved in the planning in the next few months."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"We will have two skaters from Munich coming to assess, along with our bench coach. We'll have a practice roster soon after tryouts, I think mid-of-July or something like that, and then the idea is that we practice together once a month until October/November, and then we will have our final roster cuts to 20 skaters."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;As with a lot of teams, especially this time around, the training team serves a dual purpose, and one which will hopefully benefit the newer teams contributing skaters.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"The training roster is also to make it more inclusive, and to give people the chance to practice together, and to learn, and to really make the National Team a chance to help roller derby grow. And because, in Austria, the levels of the teams are actually still quite different, just because of age."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;This kind of "community growth" effect from National Teams is perhaps one of the more socially important aspects of National organisation - and one which doesn't get as much press as it might do.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"The people that are working on it now have been doing so since the announcement in December. But long before that, I've been to several EROC conferences, in 2013, and 2014, and since then I've been involved with other people from other national teams, and with the Roller Derby Nations Committee (for which I am the Austrian representative). So, I've been involved in that way, but the real planning part began in December, and I think for many people it got more real - we said, we have to decide right now, do we want this, because we don't have a lot of time, so we have to do this right now, or never."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;With Team Austria one of the newest teams at the World Cup, its aims are a naturally different from those nations turning for a third time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"I haven't actually thought about it [pauses]. It's not that easy - I can only speak for myself, but I think for many people it's the idea of having a National Team. Everyone I know who's into Derby watched the World Cup, and it's so fascinating to see all these people play. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;And I think that many people, were then like 'ahh, I wish I could be there as well'."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"So I think the biggest motivation is to just actually be there for the first time, and also of course to play great games as a team which has grown within the last months of training. And maybe also to prove to ourselves, that while it took us a while to show up, that we did get there!"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Not, of course, that Austria will be content to simply 'participate' once they've arrived...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"For us, judging from the people I know that applied, for the tryouts already, they are rather competitive, so I think once they are there, they will also want to win! We’re not sure what the final tournament will look like, but we’ll definitely be there to show Austria off well."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"But also I think that we will have quite some fans coming  - also because it is in Europe, it will be so much easier for friends and fans to come along!"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"I think that this also helps Derby grow in Europe as a whole - to have fans travel there. Sport is so much about fan culture as well, and this might also grow and become a bigger, more cohesive thing because people can actually go and see the World Cup."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;"Not in a far away place, where you can still stream it, but it's not the same as being there, it's still kind of unreal."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Team Austria will be making things more real from their tryouts in July. You can find out more about Team Austria, and how to apply for those tryouts, at their Facebook page here:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/rollerderbyteamaustria/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;https://www.facebook.com/rollerderbyteamaustria/&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>new national teams</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2018</category><category>team austria</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/26/team-austria-new-to-the-world-cup/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 15:04:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Representing the Middle East: The effort to build Team Iran</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/02/representing-the-middle-east-the-effort-to-build-team-iran/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[NB: on request of the skaters involved, this article has been edited to remove some identifying details]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late last year, we reported on the five new &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/22/new-nations-in-the-world-cup/"&gt;National Teams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; representing for the 2018 Roller Derby World Cup. With increased representation in Asia, Europe and the Pacific, there are only a few regions in the world without any representatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this does not mean that there are not efforts afoot to build representation in those few untouched places... starting with the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-15537 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/teamiran.jpg" alt="teamiran" width="960" height="720"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nascent &lt;strong&gt;Team Iran&lt;/strong&gt; is actively recruiting Iranian skaters from around the world in a bid to represent their country on the International stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carmen masterminded the initial planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I was the scoreboard operator at the roller derby game in Zürich." she relates. "There I saw a skater who was jamming for Team Gothenburg. After the game I asked them, how it comes that they have a Persian Derby name... we found out we are both Persian and we'd both love to see our nation at the World Cup."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's often the case that National Team efforts only get started with the realisation that you're not the only person of your nationality who actually plays Roller Derby... and that it might actually be possible to find enough compatriots to form a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, recruitment has been ongoing, the issue always being to identify and raise visibility so that those interested even know you exist. Maz told us about how she found out, "A stranger messaged me on Facebook to ask if I was Iranian and if I would be interested in joining the Team Iran that she was trying to put together. I jumped at the opportunity, as being Iranian is a part of who I am. Getting the chance to represent Iranian women, and show the world who we are will be great. Having the opportunity to promote derby even more in the World, and the Middle East is also a defo plus for me!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the recent&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/18/menas-first-ever-public-interleague-abu-dhabi-v-cairollers/"&gt; CaiRollers/Abu Dhabi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; bout representing the first ever Middle East/North Africa bout in roller derby history, it does seem like the time is right for at least one Middle Eastern Roller Derby team to exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, as with many National Teams, Team Iran will be formed from both expatriots and Iranian nationals (in fact, many of its founders are distributed across Europe, the USA and beyond).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jazmyn, also a Team Iran member, echoes this kind of internationalism in Team Iran: &lt;span class="s1"&gt;"That's kind of what this group has been about - finding each other in the big wide world. I don't think many of us have met very many Middle Eastern people playing roller derby so we've had to be really hands-on in recruiting. We have made a huge effort to get the word out and build our numbers to NINE skaters who are based all over the world, e.g. Australia, New Zealand, UK, Sweden and the USA. For me it is very cool and special to be preparing to come together with so many other Persian women in this context. They are a great bunch and I am very excited to skate with them at the World Cup."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other half of internationalism is engagement with the rest of the world, of course. By bringing the spirit of roller derby into any national team, you also create the opportunity for more bridges and more engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five Foot Furby, who skates for The Hague, Netherlands' Parliament of Pain, seems to agree that outreach is another important driver for a Team Iran to exist. "I see this as an opportunity to show another side of Iranian people, " she told us. "A lot of Iranian people have emigrated to other countries and have a different lifestyle and mentality than some people would expect, I hope this team can show a new perspective of Iranian people."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're eligible to skate for Team Iran - under Roller Derby Nations Committee rules, this means you need to either: have been born in Iran, or acquired Iranian nationality by marriage or naturalisation, or have at least one parent or grandparent with Iranian Nationality, or have lived in Iran for the last 5 years continuously at the point of the World Cup [1 February 2018] - and would like to help this team become a reality, please contact the Team Iran Facebook Group here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Team-Iran-Roller-Derby-600268706834097/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/Team-Iran-Roller-Derby-600268706834097/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team iran roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/02/representing-the-middle-east-the-effort-to-build-team-iran/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 09:32:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Seeing in the New: National Teams in Dundee.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/10/seeing-in-the-new-national-teams-in-dundee/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend sees a double-dose of National Teams action for those in Scotland, as Dundee hosts a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1382676465099043/"&gt;combined event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with Team Scotland Roller Derby and Power of Scotland both on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14736 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/02/tspostb.jpg" alt="tspostb" width="1071" height="400"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, the Training Team for Team Scotland will be holding a Black v White bout, competing against themselves as part of the selection process for the new Team Scotland. After playing as two teams last weekend in Belgium (and winning both games), all of the skaters will be at their best, and bringing you (by definition), the highest level roller derby in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the Power of Scotland roster from the 2016 Men's World Cup will be playing their swansong bout, against Team Belgium Men's Roller Derby. Symbolically, this is their passing of the torch to the new Power of Scotland training team, who are currently undergoing the selection process after their tryouts in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the close connection between the National Teams, we were delighted to be able to talk with Rosie Peacock (PoS 2016 LUM/Assistant Coach, TS 2017/8 Head Coach) and Laura "Milky" Liston (PoS 2016 Coach, member of TS 2017/8 Training Team) about things. Between them, the two were selected to Captain the Team Scotland rosters in Belgium, so they have a great feel for the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First question, then: How did it feel to be selected as a Captain for the bouts last weekend?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rosie:&lt;/em&gt; So, Milky captained both in the end because I had too much caffeine and got super radge... Me and Milks were the only two who were nominated, but it was good the team trusted us to do the thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura&lt;/em&gt;: It was lovely knowing some of the team had nominated us, and it was such an amazing opportunity to Captain the squad, but yeah, we were the two nominated haha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, following up on that: Team Scotland won both their games, with both rosters against Belgium. How do you feel the games went - what are you happiest about, and is there anything you might work on?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rosie&lt;/em&gt;: I think outer defence side walls are really tight and fluid and adaptive; I'd love to work more on our offer credit and jammer pairings, but that's something we can't progress too much further until we have our final squad and definitely establish roles...
I need to keep my temper and not drink red bull when pmsing 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura&lt;/em&gt;: I really loved some of the bonds and partnerships we starting building on track, which I think were really apparent throughout the day. I'm looking forward to seeing how they develop in the final squad. Both of the games brought different challenges so it was great to see how we adapted to the change in gameplay style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And moving to this weekend: obviously we can't talk too much about selection itself, but clearly everyone there is hoping to make the final selection - do you see changes in both your own performance (and gelling) and your teammates already at this point?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura&lt;/em&gt;: Oh definitely. The opportunity to skate with so many high level skaters has really helped strengthen my skating on a personal level. We've been lucky enough to have Belgium and Cardiff to gel as a team in a competitive environment, and I think both have made a really noticeable improvement to our performances as a team together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Both of you have strong connections with Power of Scotland, especially the 2016 Squad who are playing as well - against Belgium! - we know the team are treating this as a "sending off" of the old team, but will a tiny tear be in your eyes to see them playing together for the last time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura&lt;/em&gt;: Hah! I think I got all my emotions out in Calgary when the whole squad was there. It'll be great to see the guys playing together again but I'm looking forward to seeing what our new squad will look like, and so excited about the future of PoS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rosie&lt;/em&gt;: I'm looking so forward to playing the best sport in the world, with the best group of humans I've had the pleasure to know x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The doors open for the double header at &lt;strong&gt;11:30, Saturday 11th&lt;/strong&gt; February, at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/DISC:+Dundee+International+Sports+Centre/@56.4762694,-2.9611212,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48865cfd69198245:0x74e93fd03837f5ac!8m2!3d56.4762665!4d-2.9589272"&gt;Dundee International Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are &lt;strong&gt;£6&lt;/strong&gt; in advance (from Brown Paper Tickets), &lt;strong&gt;£8&lt;/strong&gt; on the door. (Tickets at: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2794252"&gt;http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2794252&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/10/seeing-in-the-new-national-teams-in-dundee/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 11:19:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Nations in the World Cup...</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/22/new-nations-in-the-world-cup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One statement which seems to always be true is that the next World Cup is always bigger than the last. From the very first &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in 2011, with only 13 teams attending, the 2014 edition had ballooned to a massive 30 teams. In 2018, the field looks like being even wider, with at least 35 potential competitors (and more possibles).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give you a taste of what it takes to go from the idea to the reality, we asked the 5 new National Teams who've announced themselves to say a bit about their genesis and their story so far. [We will, of course, be continuing to keep you up to date with all of the National Teams over the period to the 2018 Roller Derby World Cup].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are involved in a new National Team which we haven't featured here, please get in touch with us, via Facebook or email (scottishrollerderbyATgmail.com), we would love to talk to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/22/new-nations-in-the-world-cup/#P"&gt;Philippines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/22/new-nations-in-the-world-cup/#K"&gt;Korea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/22/new-nations-in-the-world-cup/#R"&gt;Russia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/22/new-nations-in-the-world-cup/#I"&gt;Iceland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/22/new-nations-in-the-world-cup/#C"&gt;Czech [Republic]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; all responded - you can jump to the particular team by clicking on their name in this sentence.
&lt;a name="P"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Team Philippines&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-18101" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/logo_philippinerollerderby_02.png?w=300" alt="logo_philippineRollerDerby_02" width="300" height="300"&gt; The Team Philippines Logo (added after this article was completed)
&lt;p&gt;Hey! Actually it started in the FB Asians Derby Group as casual convo. As RDWC started really planning together for 2017 (which of course turned out to be 2018), a couple of people were like "WHAT IF we did a Team Philippines?" It always starts with that "what if?!" Then dreams come true!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the release of the first round of eligibility rules, many of us in the States and abroad found we were eligible to play. Some really enthusiastic skaters then put together a FB Team PI group and asked around for skaters, adding to a Google Doc to see what we would have in terms of numbers. I think we are at 30ish right now for women?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have our uni[form] vendor, are soliciting other potential sponsors, working on branding, figuring out where everyone is and where we can practice/play. The majority of us are on the [US] west coast with smatterings all around the rest of the country and Europe. Who even knows how many people there will be when the ball gets rolling; we might have people in the Philippines! At the very least, it would be great to grow the sport there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's such a crazy opportunity, and all someone had to do was reach out and start the connections! For me, I think while USA Roller Derby is fantastic, it was never a dream of mine to play for them. Not my thing, you know? But the chance to rep our heritage on the derby stage?? That's hard to pass up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Philippines on Facebook: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/1514551035482853/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/groups/1514551035482853/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a name="K"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Team Korea Roller Derby&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-18331" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/teamkorea_logo_rdwc.png?w=510" alt="TeamKorea_Logo_RDWC" width="255" height="300"&gt; Team Korea Logo (added after publication)
&lt;p&gt;Team Korea formed through the power of the internet and the roller derby community. Many members were already involved with a Facebook Group for Asian derby skaters. The Facebook Group was created to empower and inspire Asian derby skaters both within America and worldwide. When the Derby World Cup opened up, enough Asian skaters of Korean descent spoke up to form a team; some magic stardust was sprinkled, a unicorn was petted and voilá. Through the determination and dedication of a couple of active and vocal Korean skaters, like ShortStop from Gotham Girls Roller Derby and Killo Kitty from San Fernando Valley, numerous skaters of Korean descent were contacted and invited to be a part of the inaugural Team Korea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of Team Korea is to inspire Korean women in Korea and globally to strap eight wheels to their feet and open up their world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Korea is proud to represent a country that is going through tremendous changes, and our goal is to be a positive and progressive force for Korean women worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Korea on Facebook: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamkorearollerderby/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/teamkorearollerderby/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a name="R"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Team Russia Roller Derby&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-13241" style="border:1px solid #000000;" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/flag_of_russia-svg.png" alt="flag_of_russia-svg" width="900" height="600"&gt; Team Russia are working on their logo, so here's the Russian flag.
&lt;p&gt;The idea to create Team Russia had been in my mind since 2015, but at that time I didn't even know where to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, I thought that all Russian players who could play could be only from White Night Furies (because I had no idea that someone can be Russian and play derby somewhere and NOT live in Russia), and at that time our derby level was not good enough to play; we had started the team only 2 years ago at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, my second thought was that I can't do this all by myself, but who could I do it with? - I had no idea either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, that year was full of e-mails from people who wrote us, about buying merch or coming to Russia, and it was a huge surprise that some of them actually WERE Russians, living in the USA, for example.
They knew that WNF is the only league in Russia and asked if we want to make Team Russia for the next World Cup. I've tried to work with them, asking how it could be possible and where to start, but in the end didn't get clear answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, 2016, was the year I decided to try it, because I found a girl; she wrote me on our WNF FB page and said she would love to help with Team Russia and that she wanted to play. I thought that this was a sign and wrote her. And after that, step by step, I realised that there are MANY players who can actually skate for Team Russia, who would love to do it, who can help me with organising, coaching, helping or whatever else. From this moment I just started to ask Russian players from other countries if they would like to join Team Russia, I made a page on FB, we asked to share post with a call to find Russian derby players all over the world and people started to write us! That was amazing :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now we are 18, including coach, bench and lineup manager and I expect even more players to find and join us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. When we started White Night Furies in 2013 and were just babies on a track (without a track, to be honest), two coaches from VRDL (Chuck and Ruby Ribcrusher) came to Russia and coached us and showed us what it is like to be a team; how to manage and develop the team, not just the players. When they were leaving, they gave us a Team Australia 2014 patch and said that they'd like to have it back in a year (at the 2014 World Cup). Of course, we spent not 1 year but 4 to make Team Russia, and in 2018 we will give it back to them :) This is one of my own goals for this Cup (from many others).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Russia on Facebook: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamrussiarollerderby/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/teamrussiarollerderby/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="I"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Team Iceland [Roller Derby Iceland]&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-13244 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/team_iceland.jpg?w=300" alt="team_iceland" width="300" height="300"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting up a brand new sport on a small island is no easy feat (especially when none of the equipment needed is available nationally) but, somehow, we made it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started in 2011 when an Icelandic derby girl living in Atlanta knew she’d soon move back home. Only problem was: there was no derby. She decided to test the waters and see if anyone would be interested in starting the sport up and started a group on Facebook adding everyone she could think of and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus the seeds were sown. A group of enthusiastic women began teaching themselves about roller derby and investigating what equipment they’d need. Most of us could only get their hands on 2nd-hand inliners and had to either order online or beg friends who were traveling to bring fresh meat packages back home. As indoor skating has never been big in Iceland, no gymnasium wanted to take the chance and let us skate on their floors, fearing that we would ruin them. So, for the first few months we practiced in a parking garage, but soon were able to upgrade to a go-kart hall. The hall was little less than an unheated warehouse and during the cold winters we skated in woolly sweaters in order to keep warm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a year later, the first gym took a chance on us and once we got our foot in the door other gymnasiums opened their doors to us. Since then, we’ve had a few bootcamps with foreign trainers, six home games (for which we need to lure in foreign teams as there’s only one team in Iceland, so far) and we’ve even gone abroad for two tournaments. It’s been a slippery slope and taken a lot of hard work from seriously dedicated women and men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have our skaters, our ref crew and a few NSO’s and other volunteers, amazing people whom without this never would have been possible. There still isn’t any place we can buy proper derby skates but one store has begun selling the derby pads and mouthguards which makes a big difference, specially when it comes to recruiting fresh meat. We’ve come a long way these past 5 years and are still growing. We hope to learn a lot from the 2018 WC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Iceland on Facebook: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/RollerDerbyIceland/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/RollerDerbyIceland/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a name="C"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Team Czech Roller Derby&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-17727" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/czechlogo.png?w=298" alt="Czechlogo" width="298" height="300"&gt; (This article edited after submission to add the new Czech Roller Derby Team logo, by Ladis Pachmuch ART)
&lt;p&gt;The idea of a Czech national team has been rooted in our minds almost from the beginnings of roller derby in the Czech Republic. As players of Prague City Roller Derby, we have always joked that we already are the national team, because for a long time we were the only team in the country. Our former coach has always wished to create a national team and when we started hearing of more and more derby-playing Czechs, it became obvious that vision could become a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey itself started about a year ago, when representatives of two active leagues in the Czech Republic created a temporary board, which had a goal to create the team foundations, to choose managers and coaches and also to spread a word that Czech national team is finally starting. At this moment, our managers are working on the bylaws of the organization and together with our coaches are preparing first tryouts for the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Czech Roller Derby on Facebook: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/czechrollerderby/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/czechrollerderby/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>national teams</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2018</category><category>team czech</category><category>team iceland</category><category>team korea</category><category>team philippines</category><category>team russia</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/22/new-nations-in-the-world-cup/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 08:48:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Wales Skater: Buccaneer Betty Fear</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/28/team-wales-skater-buccaneer-betty-fear/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing our series of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamwalesrollerderby/"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Interviews, in collaboration with the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UK Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, we present Buccaneer Betty Fear, who skated on the first Team Wales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tryouts are currently open for the next Team Wales, who will compete in the 2017 Roller Derby World Cup. To learn more about the Tryouts, read the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1"&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform"&gt;Application Form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The Application Form also has details of the dates and locations that Tryouts will occur, in &lt;strong&gt;April&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;May&lt;/strong&gt;. If you would like to represent Wales internationally, then sign up to try-out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-6874" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/230c42621.jpg?w=2048" alt="230C4262" width="1024" height="647"&gt; Fear skating in the 2014 World Cup (against New Zealand), on the right. (Courtesy &lt;a href="http://www.girlsofderby.com/"&gt;Sean Murphy&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buccaneer Betty Fear started out in Roller Derby with Severn Roller Torrent in 2011. She remained with Severn, skating and coaching until 2015, when she joined Tiger Bay Brawlers. She was an active member of Tiger Bay during their first and only season in British Champs. She attended the 2014 Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup as a member of Team Wales, playing against Norway, South Africa, New Zealand and Puerto Rico.
Before her retirement from Roller Derby at the end of the last season, she blogged on roller derby and other topics at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://itsahardblocklife.com/author/buccaneerbettyfear/"&gt;It's a Hard Block Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, the obvious first question is at the beginning: why try out for Team Wales?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is so hard to write about why I tried out without relying on cliche. I think it is because it is such a big set of feelings that you run out of words...
Trying out to make a National Squad was not a life experience that I thought I would have. Roller Derby is still at this special, magical time where people who have come to the sport as an adult can have dreams like making a National Squad and have the chance to turn them into reality. If you bring the work and the commitment and the courage to put yourself on the line, you can make it happen. Our sport might not be like that forever (have you seen those juniors??), so grabbing that opportunity now, while we are in this meeting place where hard work can turn you into an elite athlete... was an obvious. At the point of trying out, even the trial felt like a win and an experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell us a bit about the mental game of the tryout process. What did it feel like to go through the tryouts; and wait and then discover you had made it onto the roster?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tryout experience was utterly unlike I expected. I thought it would be this pressurised, lonely experience where everyone was out for themselves. Nope. Within minutes of arrival the skaters trying out were forming bonds with each other. There was a palpable sense of community and support. It was like the larger Roller Derby community, but squeezed into this incredibly intense experience. During drills people were supporting each other and rooting for each other. During scrimmage we were urging each other to jam and to pivot.
Physically and mentally it was one of the toughest experiences I have gone through. The trials were long, demanding and I think they were designed to ensure you were pretty exhausted by the time you scrimmaged. Waiting for the results of the first round of trials was agony, the elation of finding you had made the next round was swiftly followed by the awful realisation you had to do it all again, with more at stake...
Finding out I had made the Squad was an incredibly proud moment. I had spent so long prepping for those trials... I had spent all my money hiring lonely sports halls  at early hours on weekend mornings, I had trained relentlessly in the gym, I'd read pretty much every sports psychology book I could get my hands on. I'd gone all out to make the Squad. Knowing I would wear a Welsh jersey was incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Training for a National Team is a significant additional investment for a skater, on top of their existing league commitments. How did you manage the time needed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the time I was in the Squad, there was no balance in my life. It was Roller Derby, all in. I worked, I played derby and I cross trained. I mumbled 'sorry' to my brilliantly supportive partner as I disappeared every weekend, usually on both days, for League and Squad training. I spent my money on Roller Derby travel, the gym and physio. I missed the wedding of a close friend and countless nights out and weekend adventures.
At some point it stops being about you, and becomes about what you owe the Squad. You know that there were other skaters who would have done anything to have the spot on Squad you have, you owe it to them to go all out. You know that your team mates are missing birthdays and weddings and not seeing their kids in order to train, you owe it to them. And there is always the thought of not letting your Country down. You are going to skate out with a Welsh dragon on your chest, you want to show the World (and the Welsh) that we were serious about this sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the lead up to the World Cup, Wales played several other games, including a kind of home-series (Road To Dallas) against Ireland, Wales and the West Indies. What do you think you and the team gained from these games?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The games we played in the lead-up to the World Cup were an incredibly experience. I think the proliferation of European (and UK-based teams) really lifted the quality of derby that was played at the World Cup. By the time we got there we had played half a dozen games as a National Squad - that makes a huge difference.
Instead of working out kinks in our game at the World Cup, we had a squad who had skated together, understood each other and had developed our game. We also got to learn from the experiences of teams that had skated in the first World Cup. Scotland and Ireland had such strong, experienced Squads. Playing them beforehand gave us a chance to learn and adjust. The West Indies were great to play against as well... they were such a tough, hard-hitting Squad... it totally warmed us up (tenderised us??) for the hard-hitting play we experienced in Dallas.
It also gave us a chance to experience skating as Team Wales and the whole different set of nerves that comes with that. Finally, it meant that more players had the experience of playing for their country. Not everyone made the Squad in Dallas, so some great skaters who didn't get the chance in Dallas still had the incredible experience of skating for their country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representing Wales in Dallas, you played against New Zealand, South Africa, Norway and Puerto Rico. What was your favourite game, and why? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each game was a special and intense experience and created memories that will stay with my forever. South Africa were a great, physical side, having the time of their lives and their spirit was infectious. New Zealand were, well, HUGE! They were formidable and it was brilliant to have the chance to go up against them. Puerto Rico was a joy of a game - the final of the one we played at the World Cup and just a riot.
But my favourite... was Norway. They were skilled, strong and relentless, but we had a moment where Wales came together and realised that everything we had worked for was now and that this was our chance. We went back out on track with a vengeance, lifting our performance. We lost, but that switch in how we were operating on track was special. It was a moment of mental resilience and this incredible sense of skaters going out there for each other. We did each other proud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you planning on trying out for Team Wales again?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've retired now - full of dreams made reality! But to anyone considering it - go.
Try out.
Yes: you.
Imagine being able to say you were at trials for a National Squad... imagine being able to say you made it. Get your butt to training, get to the gym, get watching footage and grab yourself a derby dream. You will get something from any part of the process you go through. Go get it, skater!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We currently don't know much about the 2017 World Cup. If you had a choice, where would you like it to be (and who would you like to face on track?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd love to see it in Europe: the cost for so many teams to travel to North America was prohibitive. I'd love to have it closer to home, and see more European teams able to have all their skaters there and more skaters get the chance to have their moment on track.
Who would I like to see Wales face on track? It's got to be Norway. But this time with a different ending...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team wales</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/28/team-wales-skater-buccaneer-betty-fear/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 13:09:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Wales Manager Dorkmistress</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/24/team-wales-manager-dorkmistress/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, we interviewed the outgoing members of the Team Scotland Management and Coaching Team, in collaboration with the &lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UKRDA&lt;/a&gt;. In an ongoing collaboration with UKRDA, we're happy to present interviews with &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamwalesrollerderby/"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt;' Management and Coaching team, starting with Team Manager: &lt;strong&gt;Dorkmistress&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(You can apply to try out to skate for Team Wales here: &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform&lt;/a&gt; , with a FAQ concerning tryouts here: &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1"&gt;https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1 &lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dorkmistress has had a long and varied time in Roller Derby. Starting in 2011 with the Cardiff Roller Collective, as a skater and announcer, she has since moved to Swansea City Roller Derby (in 2013), and moved into refereeing for both Swansea and the South West Silures in 2014. She was Team Manager for Team Wales Roller Derby for the 2014 Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup, and continues in this role, having been re-elected in the post earlier this year. Her derby CV is extensive, including over 60 games refereed, and 100 announced, over her 5 year period in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full aligncenter" title="wp-1458819373825" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/wp-1458819373825.jpg" alt="image"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In common with other Team Wales roles, you're returning to the role of Manager from the last iteration of the National Team. What led you to decide to continue in the role? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a big decision - I loved the last two years but it's a fairly big commitment. We learnt so much in the last two years, starting the team from scratch and I wanted to make sure that I could see these lessons implemented. I know how I want to do things differently and think that I can do a much better job this time around. Plus, I'm not ready to watch Team Wales on track without being part of it! When I was thinking about how to answer these questions I looked back on the Team Wales Facebook page and seeing the support, encouragement and emotion on there made me remember what an incredible experience and honour it is to be part of Team Wales, and to be part of a team of such amazing people. And I still regularly look at the pictures of the Team Wales supporters gang - those crazy laydees from Neath Port Talbot, the supporters who travelled to Belgium and Dallas with their inflatables and daffodil hats, our own official leader of chants, Rhys Jones. Who wouldn't want to be part of that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managing a National team is quite a complex task, with many things to keep track of (and you've technically managed 2 Nations, what with Team Sealand). What do you think are the most important aspects of the job? (And coping with the workload?) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able and willing to keep all the plates you are spinning in the air is probably the key to success! And you can only achieve that with delegation and lots of communication. I worked with the skaters and other members of the management team to set up committees to cover key areas, like fundraising and events, and each group had an action plan and regular meetings. I did live on Facebook and Google Docs for the year, and ended up missing training a fair bit, but I wanted to make that commitment to make sure Team Wales was in the best place possible in Dallas. I have a busy real life job, but that's given me lots of time management and project planning skills, which were essential. Team Sealand was much easier, I just had to sort out travel and bout contracts ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last time around, a big part of the Management for most National teams was simply raising the funds to make it to Dallas. How did you guys go about managing the process, and finding new ways to get funds?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were really clear that fundraising was the responsibility of everyone in Team Wales, and everyone got involved. We had huge support from leagues from Newcastle to LRG to Severn Roller Torrent to Swansea City Roller Derby, giving us raffle proceeds, holding fundraising events and giving us stall space at their events. We had people donate money, we sold a LOT of t-shirts, we held kare-oke nights, we made loom bands, we had a baby picture competition, we had face painting at our games - literally any way we could get money out of people, we tried. We also decided to hold the fabulous Road to Dallas tournament in Newport in October 2014, hosting Teams Scotland, Ireland and West indies. Fundraising was constant - the challenge was to make it fun and to try and not just ask the same people all the time....same as most leagues face. It will be easier in some ways this time - we have our merch in place and an existing fan base - but harder in a sport where we have more leagues trying to fundraise from the same audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What've you learned from the last time around that you'll be applying this time, to improve Team Wales' management?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you got enough space in this blog? We're starting in a better position - we have a clear identity and design, so we will have t-shirts and merch available sooner and more options for our supporters. Do more on social media - keep everyone updated on our journey towards the World Cup. Delegate more and more completely - easier when you know what you are trying to achieve and know all the details and issues that need to be considered. Get the right partners and sponsors so things are as easy and cheap as possible for us. Play more games - we had 9 months from team selection to the World Cup last time and that wasn't enough - one reason we were keen to kick off the National Squad selection process in the UK. Everyone's going to freak out a bit on this journey - we are all allowed a freakout, just hopefully not at the same time. Sleep more and stop looking at Facebook messages at midnight and then again at 7am. Don't share a room with morning people if you are a night owl - probably the hardest and most important lesson I learnt.....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You've also announced in many places, including at the first Men's World Cup. How would you compare your two World Cup experiences?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very different experiences because they were very different sized events on very different continents. The Men's World Cup memories I have will last me a lifetime. It was my first taste of international roller derby and it was small and perfectly formed - the announcing team was incredible and the size of the schedule and event meant you could keep up with all of the action and see all of the teams and skaters sat next to you. I got to hang out with Team Japan and watch Team Argentina and nearly lost my voice shouting at Team Wales scoring points against Team USA - and those moments were all in the same room, right next to each other. It was the first time I got to introduce the Welsh National Anthem and I can still feel the hairs rising on the back of my neck. I also got to do the in-house announcement for &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; Wales V Australia game and the emotion in the venue at that last jam overwhelmed me so much I cried for 30 minutes at the end of the game - us announcers feed off that crowd emotion and I have never felt anything like it. It was such a personal experience I am not sure anything will ever really be the same as that. I'm desperately proud to have been part of the delivery of that event and I am more than a bit heartbroken that I can't go to Calgary this July - but I know Team Wales will make me and everyone else even prouder than they did that day in Birmingham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blood and Thunder World Cup was just so much bigger. When we arrived at the airport the customs guys said 'you here for the roller derby?'. Thats because they had already seen so many skaters and fans. 30 teams is a lot of people, three tracks in this massive room in a ginormous exhibition centre in America? Much bigger than the Futsal! If I went to the team room (each team had its own room! what?!) it was a good 5 minute walk, which, by the end of the day, felt like 5 miles. We'd gone to the European Roller Derby Tournament in Belgium and shared the underside of the bleachers seating with 7 other National teams and the next thing you knew we had a Team Support person, and a room and all sorts of things to make our time easier. I missed announcing though, you watch games in a different way and I didn't see a lot of other games as I was busy on the merch stall or sorting transport or one of the many other things that went on. And I missed being part of the team that showed you the event and explained what was going on. However, nothing in my life will ever compare to being able to walk out on the biggest Roller Derby stage in the world as part of Team Wales in the Parade of Nations. I can't even now, all this time later, put that experience and feeling into words. It's something I will forever be proud of and proud to have been part of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you were interviewed last time around, you noted that you were most looking forward to Team Wales playing "teams from far off places". In the event, Wales played South Africa, New Zealand, Norway and Puerto Rico, at least three of which probably count! If you could play any teams (announced or not) in the upcoming World Cup, what would they be?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Norway are going down this time ;-) It was almost impossible to watch the game  - seeing the team play out of their skins to claw back to within reaching distance for Norway to pull away just at the end. I'd love to see us play Argentina, they were incredible in Dallas and I think the South American teams are going to go to the next World Cup with a huge step up in skills and strategy. And there will be teams from new places - Iceland, definitely, maybe even Egypt, or Russia [where there are teams, but no established National infrastructure, yet]! We think and talk a lot about European Derby and Derby in North America, but the World Cup is the only place we get to see derby developing as a Global sport, and thats going to be really evident in the next World Cup for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(And if you have a place you'd like the World Cup to be, for any reason…)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would love it to be in Japan as I have always wanted to go there but even pretending I'd have to fundraise for that makes me want to cry! Very boringly I'd like it to be in Europe next - I think that showing as many people as possible international level derby inspires skaters and so would like to see it move around continents to give everyone that experience - watching it on the internet isnt quite the same. So next time Australia or New Zealand. Then South America or Asia or Africa. A true world tour!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team wales</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/24/team-wales-manager-dorkmistress/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 11:38:06 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>