<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about scottish roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/scottish-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:34:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Big Blether 2: Mean City host the return of the Scottish Derby community meetup.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/06/big-blether-2-mean-city-host-the-return-of-the-scottish-derby-community-meetup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, the Scottish Roller Derby Community made a bit of history, by finally getting together in one place for a &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/18/the-big-blether-scotland-together/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big Blether&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This wasn't just a disorganised chat, of course: this was the first ever Roller Derby Conference for Scottish derby, on the model of the European "EROC". On the 7th of October 2017, the vast majority of active Scottish leagues were represented by pairs of delegates [and all but one of those who couldn't make it sent statements by proxy], actively engaged in process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-24409 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/screen-shot-2017-09-13-at-16-17-08.png" alt="Screen Shot 2017-09-13 at 16.17.08" width="335" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the first Big Blether was the brainchild of Auld Reekie Roller Girls' Crazylegs and Skinner, and Glasgow Roller Derby's Head Referee, Candy Moho, it was also agreed that future convocations would pass the torch onto other leagues around the country, spreading the democratic work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as it goes, the first volunteers to do the hard thing of repeating previous success were Glasgow's All-Gender league, Mean City Roller Derby. Very slightly more than a year later, their iteration of the conference, Big Blether 2, is coming to central Glasgow on the 20th October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principal task of a repeat convention is more nuanced than that of a first meeting. The first Big Blether did great things in generating conversation; in spreading knowledge [we personally enjoyed the group discussion elements, and how well they were orchestrated] and sharing problems. &lt;em&gt;More importantly&lt;/em&gt;, it generated actions - foci for future progress and development, mutually agreed by all those present. (It also gained Scottish derby a little bit of publicity, via an article in Five On Five magazine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second Big Blether will have the equally hard task of looking at those actions, a year later, and seeing what has been done, what has not; correcting course, potentially, or pushing forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it might do us well to look at what actions the first Big Blether produced, across the multiple sessions it held (these were scheduled as pairs of parallel sessions, run as facilitated group discussions):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby Oversight&lt;/strong&gt; spread some useful information (and quashed some misapprehensions) about the existing governance structures in Roller Derby. The action produced was to develop a "&lt;strong&gt;Scottish Derby Lobbying Group&lt;/strong&gt;" to provide a unified voice for the Scottish community in representing our needs and desires to larger entities.
We followed up on this, and believe that at least some work was done towards this aim, but as yet there is no formal group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Game Scheduling&lt;/strong&gt; produced some frank discussion between leagues about competition for resources; the low ratio of leagues to halls and fans (as well as to officials), the network effects which mean that smaller leagues can be accidentally outcompeted by older, more established clubs, and so on. The actions for this session were to more strongly adopt the shared &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby Schedule&lt;/strong&gt; for scheduling bouts and events (this common document is hosted on Google Docs, and made available via links in the Scottish Derby Facebook group) and to consider &lt;strong&gt;Sharing Fixtures with Other Leagues&lt;/strong&gt;.
We've seen use of the Schedule increase significantly since the first Big Blether, and there have been a number of "shared fixtures", so we think these actions have been broadly successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Officiating&lt;/strong&gt; involved some extensive discussions about the widespread issues of officials recruitment and training (and respect within leagues). The action for this session was to promote more central training and learning opportunities for Officials (on and off skates) - a &lt;strong&gt;Ref School&lt;/strong&gt; to be run by Glasgow Roller Derby - and for leagues to work towards giving their officials a more "cohesive identity" to form around and generally &lt;strong&gt;treat them as first class citizens&lt;/strong&gt; of the sport.
The Glasgow Roller Derby Ref School has run a few sessions (and Dundee have continued to run their own series of Officiating bootcamps, extant before Big Blether); and the branding of several league's officials as their own "teams" seems to represent a start of the second action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Access to Scottish Derby&lt;/strong&gt; revolved around the perennial issues of costs, access to halls and training certifications; as well as problems with providing kit, and burnout in "highly active" members of the community; and the less discussed issues with cultural homogeneity in derby. This session produced a lot of "personal actions" for leagues to &lt;strong&gt;Share More Resources&lt;/strong&gt;, and investigate community Volunteering Schemes.
It's difficult to measure how well this has been progressed without hearing from all the leagues - so this will be a point of discussion in October!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting as a whole also produced actions to produce and maintain a &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby Ranking&lt;/strong&gt;, which would enable a &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby National Tournament&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Scottish League or Championships&lt;/strong&gt;.
These have progressed very slightly (there's an initial Scottish Derby Ranking derived from Flat Track Stats Europe ratings), but on the meat of the matter - an organised competitive structure - there's a lot of work to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The second ever Big Blether will give those actioned a chance to report on their progress, as well as discussing any new topics which have developed in the past 12 months - since that year has seen three World Cups, a changing structure in other International Gameplay, and at least one new style of Roller Derby, we’re sure that there will be lots to talk about.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2nd Big Blether will be hosted on the 20th October 2018, in &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/bsRwxpsb6Do"&gt;Glasgow Quakers Meeting House, Elmbank Crescent, Glasgow. G2 4PS&lt;/a&gt;. Final timings to be decided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams can register representatives (as can independents) here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSf5LLsKjK3egYsLrcJNX8vWnnoRV5DRErii42kKAsANWbbP-w/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSf5LLsKjK3egYsLrcJNX8vWnnoRV5DRErii42kKAsANWbbP-w/viewform&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;REGISTRATION CLOSES 1 OCTOBER.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can contribute to the discussion topics on offer, and shape the schedule, via this form here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeiKb3UVcj1mKjVAeZmUVUY5krWkziPGH7HKCR4OQirmRKATQ/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeiKb3UVcj1mKjVAeZmUVUY5krWkziPGH7HKCR4OQirmRKATQ/viewform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>communication</category><category>in the news</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>officials</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>team scotland</category><category>the big blether</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/06/big-blether-2-mean-city-host-the-return-of-the-scottish-derby-community-meetup/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 10:00:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Big Blether: Scotland Together</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/18/the-big-blether-scotland-together/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's often been commented that Scotland has seen some of the more dramatic growth (and changes) in Roller Derby, with respect to its population. Since the first league started in Glasgow in 2007, Roller Derby has spread across the Nation - but not always uniformly, or consistently. Whilst there's certainly a lot of Roller Derby in Scotland now - with 19 leagues in existence (by one count) now - communication and organisation across the community has not always been as good as it could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;October 7th&lt;/strong&gt;, in Edinburgh's Charteris Centre, three people aim to change this. Auld Reekie Roller Girls' Crazylegs and (Steph) Skinner, and Glasgow Roller Derby's head referee Candy Moho, are organising what they hope will be the first of a regular series of gatherings of the Scottish Roller Derby Community in one place and one time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-24409 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/screen-shot-2017-09-13-at-16-17-08.png" alt="Screen Shot 2017-09-13 at 16.17.08" width="335" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Big Blether&lt;/em&gt;, as it's now known, aims to bring together all of the extant leagues and clubs in Scotland, as well as others in the sport, in order to share and discuss the future and present of the sport. Every active league in Scotland has been invited to the event as part of the organisation process,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to two-thirds of the Organisers - thrice Team Scotland skater,  founding Roller Derby Nations Committee rep, and founding Auld Reekie Roller Girls member, &lt;em&gt;Crazylegs&lt;/em&gt;; and long-standing Glasgow Roller Derby Head Referee and organiser of the Scottish Roller Derby Events Spreadsheet, &lt;em&gt;Candy Moho&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crazylegs was inspired to kickstart this idea at the last European Rollerderby Organisational Conference, as she told us. "I guess for me the inspiration came from EROC - I love attending that event, and I guess the more I go to events like that and attend sessions, and deliver talks,  I kind of think, we've got such a compact community in Scotland - and I don't think we take advantage of it enough.
Our league [ARRG] gets so much out of events like EROC in terms of knowledge and new ideas to refresh you. It's so much easier for us to get together in Scotland - the leagues in Australia might find it harder to all meet up, for example - but we're so close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chatted to Candy at the end of EROC, and she mentioned that she'd been thinking of something similar, so it was in my mind from then."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candy, meanwhile, had a slightly different perspective. "My main focus was the Officials side, off of the back of a project I'd done for the Open Uni. And also being in the Event Organising Group, the Interleague Liasion group, a lot of the issues there - it just seemed it would be easier to get people in the same room to talk to each other!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;One of the things I am planning to do at The Big Blether is to present the findings from my OU project, which focussed on Scottish Derby Officials - I've not had a chance to pass on the results of that to the community, and I thought this is the perfect forum to do it, and make the results public after. That took in feedback from Officials as well as skaters from leagues. A lot of the stuff from that is still very relevant, and it's relevant to UK officials as well."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Unlike EROC's speaker-centered sessions, The Big Blether is intended to foster a less hierarchical approach - each topic will have a "facilitator" to moderate, but will emphasise communication and discussion between peers, not a top-down dissemination of from on-high.&lt;/p&gt;
Topics on the agenda currently cover the spectrum of community concerns and interests, from best practice in Training, through the creation of better links for interleague support and with local communities, and how to move the sport on in terms of recognition on both local and National/International scales; however, in keeping with the design of the event, there are no topics which are out of bounds if attendees wish to discuss them.
&lt;p&gt;Speaking to the organisers, again, they each have their own favourite areas from the menu presented. For Crazylegs, a key topic is governance and organisation, on all scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We want to cover topics like League Governance - so: the legalities of how you set up a league, how you structure a league, what works for different leagues, of different sizes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I guess leading on from that you'd look at&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt; sports &lt;/span&gt;governance - as in governing bodies, as in the national teams, UKRDA, WFTDA [MRDA], just I think maybe putting a bit of information out there for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I think there's a lot of myths out there concerning the various bodies - but we also need to talk about what Scotland itself needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I know Stef's driving force for this comes from her job, she's a community sports officer, and she's been has been doing a lot of research around the growth of sport, how we can better use Sport Scotland, and have better links with them for funding and support. We were also discussing working on having clear pathways, to show people how they can get to where they want to go - if that's high level competition, or having fun - from where they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;And I think training as well - what support setups different leagues need, if we feel that there needs to be more information out there about training and structures, and how to set things up from beginning to getting wherever your league or team wants to go."&lt;/p&gt;
Candy, with her other hat on, is most concerned with another topic. "On the Events side: getting a Scottish Tournament (doing another "Highland Fling", perhaps) but also the topic of if we need to look into a League structure - as they have in Germany  and France. I think you tend to find that when you have that kind of structure, and people working well together, then you also drive the sport, and the level of competition as well. "
&lt;p&gt;But, most of all, the event is about everyone meeting up and building the community links that can make Scottish Derby stronger together. As Crazylegs notes, "having a relaxed chat to people that you don't know, but you've heard of their leagues - if you get that kind of face-to-face conversation with people you've only interacted with on social media, then you make better connections, and everyone learns something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The venue's amazing, it's close to town, we'll get some nice stuff going on in the breaks to build connections - and we'll be providing a delicious lunch!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Charteris Centre can be found &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Greyfriars+Charteris+Centre/@55.9455414,-3.1817633,19.53z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x104319695d91d9d9!8m2!3d55.9456793!4d-3.1812937"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here on Google Maps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
Sign up for leagues (who are already contacted) is for the &lt;strong&gt;23rd September&lt;/strong&gt;, with potential for other slots for non-league attendees after the initial numbers are known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All questions can be sent to the event organisers at &lt;a href="mailto:scottishderbyevent@gmail.com"&gt;scottishderbyevent@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial shortlist of topics is:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Training: Creation of clear pathways and sharing best practice&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sport recognition (Leagues, National/International Governing Bodies and National Teams)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Club governance; sharing best practices / resources / contacts, league support.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Scottish Events Scheduling: game scheduling, events, opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Partnership working, local communities&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Officiating: recruitment and retention, development pathways, national association&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Volunteering (development, pathways, recruitment, training)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
The organisers would like to thank Auld Reekie Roller Girls for funding both the event, and travel subsidies for the more distant leagues.&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>news</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>the big blether</category><category>training</category><category>upcoming events</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/18/the-big-blether-scotland-together/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 07:09:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mean City Roller Derby: Relaunch 2017</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/17/mean-city-roller-derby-relaunch-2017/</link><dc:creator>meancityrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-19258" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/received_10158754925150594.jpeg?w=300" alt="received_10158754925150594" width="300" height="300"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;Roller derby is a very DIY sport, so people at different levels will always be looking to achieve different goals within the sport. For some, their purpose is to advance as far as their body will allow. For others, it’s a great way to get out a couple of nights per week and let off some steam in a fun, friendly environment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby fall somewhere in the middle, as we're made up of a wide variety of different people and personalities – we have actors, students, scientists and even a Thai masseur! It's our members that make our league special. Although we have lives outside of derby, we'll always be there for each other, both on and off the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we're looking to continue to build upon progress we've made as a league and as a group of friends. Next Saturday&lt;strong&gt;, 20th May 2017&lt;/strong&gt;, will be our first bout of the year and we are hoping to capitalise on the hard work we've put into our training. Not only that, we are rebranding and will be debuting our new logo and team tops for the first time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logo really captures the good humour of the league and the spirit of Glasgow, Mean City's home and stomping ground.  We don't want to give too much away until game day, but we can say the logo is indeed still purple! This has been a long time in the making, but we can proudly say it looks fantastic. A big thank you to our Design Team and to Roller Derby City for our awesome new uniforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are facing tough opposition. Our ladies' team are playing the Granite City Fight Hawks from Aberdeen. We played them up north in &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85548"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and were narrowly defeated, so we will be looking to make the most of the home advantage! Our co-ed/open team will then be playing the Portsmouth Scurvy Wenches who are travelling up to Glasgow for the bout. They are more unknown to us, so should make exciting opponents. We also hear they like a good after party, as do we!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-19259" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/received_10158754874915594.jpeg?w=300" alt="received_10158754874915594" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The action starts at &lt;strong&gt;12pm&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662012,-4.2516905,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8661982!4d-4.2494965"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARC: Health &amp;amp; Fitness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Glasgow Caledonian University, Cowcaddens Road, Glasgow, G4 0BA. Entry is &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; per person/under 14s free,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets available from the Facebook event page here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1288036437909237/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1288036437909237/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>annoucements</category><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>pictures</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/17/mean-city-roller-derby-relaunch-2017/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 14:08:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Scotland's newest, Northernmost league... Orkney ViQueens!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/13/scotlands-newest-northernmost-league-orkney-viqueens/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We hinted a few articles ago that there's lots of new Roller Derby leagues popping up still.. and then we discovered that we'd underestimated even then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/OrkneyViqueens/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orkney ViQueens&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are, to our knowledge, both the newest Roller Derby "league" (they style themselves a "Club" currently), and also now Scotland's northernmost, taking the top spot from Helgin Roller Derby (and returning it to the Isles, after Shetland sadly stopped).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby in the Northern Isles introduces a number of complexities, in addition to the usual issues of starting a new league, and so we were excited to get in touch with the founders and see what their plans are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We managed to catch up with founder DeafWish (Ronie Walters) to find out what kind of person would start a league on an Island!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a longstanding fascination with Roller Derby ever since I first heard about it. I love the culture, the names, the speed – let’s face it, being able to skate round and play full contact sounds awesome (though I might not still be saying that when I have fallen over a few times!) From my Master's research in applied positive psychology, I know that physical activity is extremely beneficial for mental and physical wellbeing. It’s also known that women in general are less likely to play sport – particularly team sports and contact sports - so I wanted to try and change that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love how Roller Derby has benefits on so many levels – physical, social, confidence, body positivity and mental strength. Skating is great fun, and it is a very effective workout. I love that a lot of people start Derby with minimal (or no) skating experience. There's room for a lot of different body shapes and sizes and so it really is open to pretty much anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I moved from one of the smaller Orkney islands (~130 people) to the larger Mainland island I decided to see if anyone else was interested. I half expected to get no response, so I was pretty shocked when the initial FaceBook post resulted in a closed group with 30-odd members within 48 hours!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group was set up on the 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; November and since then we have been busy. I am so lucky to have such a great team of people willing to work with me to make this happen. Our committee currently has 7 members, we have a logo (thanks to a wonderful graphic designer who plans to join us) and we have our first event booked for the &lt;strong&gt;28&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; December&lt;/strong&gt; – a social and information evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a venue booked for twice a week skate sessions, starting &lt;strong&gt;17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; January&lt;/strong&gt;. We will do an hour of recreational skating, followed by 2 hours of more structured skate training. 2 of our members have skating experience so they will be attempting to whip the rest of us into some form of basic skating ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been lucky enough to have our first donation of £300 from my employer [Orkney Micro-Renewables], so that will let us get 3 or 4 sets of basic club kit to lend out, and we are applying to Awards For All for funding to help us establish – we are running on zero budget at the moment! We are also seeking links with local businesses to offer member discounts – the hope is that they will benefit from increased publicity, and we will benefit by making a monthly membership subscription seem more appealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have had some wonderful advice from Krusty and Laura at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.granitecityrollerderby.co.uk/"&gt;Granite [City Roller Derby]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Natorious Red from I&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/InvernessCityRollerDerby/"&gt;nverness [City Roller Derby]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and Hydra-el from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/"&gt;Rule 56&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. We are hoping, once we can all skate at a basic level, to have some of these guys come up and run some bootcamps for us to teach us more derby specific skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think some of the biggest challenges for us are our location, and our lack of derby knowledge. We are all on a steep learning curve over everything from what skates and equipment to suggest and how to stop floors getting marked through to more complicated stuff that is harder to get answers to - like is there an etiquette around when to take a derby name? How do you decide on a number? What the heck is a derby wife and do I need one? And most importantly – deciphering the rules of the game and how to teach them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have also had some issues in finding venue space – in Orkney pretty much every sports team comes inside for the winter, so the venues that are big enough for a track are full. We have found a smaller hall for use till April and then we hope to switch to somewhere bigger, ready for when we are more likely to be benefiting from the increased space (and will hopefully have figured out how to lay a track and have it stay there while you skate!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have big dreams as a club – we would like to be able to get to a level where we can travel and compete. We are really keen to start developing a junior league once we know what we are doing, and we would love to create a dedicated skate venue here in Orkney!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we are at a position to play scrims and bouts we hope folk will be willing to make a trip up here – it’s a beautiful place, and I’m guessing we will be the UK’s most northerly team – and possibly the only island team?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orkney ViQueens' first ever event is scheduled for &lt;strong&gt;28th&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;December 2016&lt;/strong&gt;, a meet-and-learn information event at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Bothy+Bar/@58.9840072,-2.962384,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x489b0163fd0eab57:0x9c0d24c24d68a482!8m2!3d58.9840072!4d-2.96019"&gt;The Bothy Bar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Kirkwall. The event page is here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/346341755740009/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/346341755740009/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>northern isles</category><category>orkney viqueens</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/13/scotlands-newest-northernmost-league-orkney-viqueens/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 13:47:24 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>