<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about scottish mens roller derby)</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/scottish-mens-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:54:39 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>2015 A year in review for Capital City</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/22/2015-a-year-in-review-for-capital-city/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2014 was a year of firsts for  Capital City, which saw them have members take part in the first ever Men's Roller Derby World Cup with Power Of Scotland, play their first ever co-ed game under the name Capital Chums then round off their year off by hosting and playing in their first ever home game.  2015 started with their AGM and voting in a new captain (Despicable V) and vice (Dafty) who would guide them through the next 9 months of games they had booked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2015 was their first full bouting year and their bout management had been working hard to line up games. Unfortunately one of their games had to be cancelled when the opponents lost their training venue and another two games ended up being postponed until 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year saw the first ever Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals tournament being held over the course of the year. This saw all the bouting men's teams in Scotland (Bairn City Rollers, Capital City and Mean City) face off against each other during the year, to see who would be crowned the first Scottish Nationals Champion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/ccrd-bcr.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5260"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5260" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/ccrd-bcr.jpg?w=614" alt="ccrd-bcr" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital City's first game of the year and the first game of Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals was against Bairn City Rollers, which saw them travel to Grangemouth to play the Skelpies on their home turf. The final score was Skelpies 192 to CCRD 127 in what was a hard fought game from beginning to end that saw both teams only fielding 10 skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the cancelled  and postponed games It would be almost 5 months until Capital City took to the track again. In that time they took in a few new skaters (Darth Evader and Mad Science) and were working hard at getting them through their mins ready for the games later on in the year. They also had four skaters (Bounce, Dafty, Tequila Jammer and Despicable V) make it into the 30 training squad for Power of Scotland for the Men's Derby World Cup next year. Of those four two (Dafty and Tequila Jammer)  made it into the final selection of 20 skaters going to Calgary next year and also took part in the 4 nations tournament, which saw England, Scotland, Wales and France all play each other over the course of a weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/darth-evader-54.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4876 size-medium" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/darth-evader-54.jpg?w=240" alt="Darth Evader 54" width="240" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Darth Evader #54&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/mad-science-36.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4875 size-medium" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/mad-science-36.jpg?w=240" alt="Mad Science 36" width="240" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Mad Science #36&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
It want until the 11th of July that Capital City got back on track this time making their first ever trip south of the border heading down to Manchester to take on the Chaos Engine. Unfortunately due to injuries and holidays they were a little light on skaters so drafted in two guest skaters with Momo from The Brawlermen and Bish Bash Josh ex Capital City Skater who now lives down in Manchester  both being unicorns on the day. The final score was Chaos Engine 213 to Capital City 107.
&lt;p&gt;Their Third and final public game of the year was on the 19th of October when Mean City paid them a visit in the final game of the Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals for 2015. As Bairn City had won both of their games they had been crowned the 2015 Champions but this game would decide who got 2nd and 3rd place. At the final whistle the scores were Capital City 158 - Mean City  217, meaning Mean City took 2nd place and Capital City took 3rd in a very hard hitting and fought game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/mc-ccrd.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5259"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5259" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/mc-ccrd.jpg?w=614" alt="mc ccrd" width="614" height="271"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a sadder note, during 2015 Capital City and Scottish derby also said goodbye to a couple of faces. After all our public games were played Deathworm Jim decided to hang up his skates. Having been with Capital City from their inception his presence will definitely be missed on and off the track. At the beginning of the year, an old familiar face returned to Capital City, transferring from Mean City. Unfortunately not long after the Chaos engine game, Bounce also decided that the time was right for him to also hang up his skates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before the end of the year Capital City wanted to fit in one last thing. At the beginning of December they invited everyone's friends from the North, the Granite City Brawler Men down for a closed game, which both enjoyed so much that a return game has already been planned for next year. For that game they also voted in their new Captain (Hajuken) and Vice (Critical Hit) to get them ready for the year ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2015</category><category>articles</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>mens roller derby scotland</category><category>mighty unicorns</category><category>scottish men's roller derby nationals</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/22/2015-a-year-in-review-for-capital-city/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 15:37:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital City Host the Final SMRDN game of 2015</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/27/capital-city-host-the-final-smrdn-game-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year we saw the launch of the Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals (SMRDN), which saw Bairn City Rollers, Mean City and Capital City all fight for the bragging rights of being the top Scottish Men's team. With two games played and two wins to BCR's Skelpies they have taken the title of champions for this year. There is however still one more game left to play which is sure to be an exciting clash for more than one reason, which is Capital City vs Mean City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone wp-image-4863 size-large" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ccrd-banner-smrdfin.jpg?w=614" alt="ccrd-banner-smrdfin" width="614" height="227"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two teams have yet to met on track in a public game, with this their first encounter deciding who will take second place in this years SMRDN and the looser picking up 3rd and last place for 2015. With so much to play for, both teams will be fighting for every point from the first whistle to the last. And if this wasn't enough to tempt you along, Capital City have turned the event into a double header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get everyone ready for the main event, they are putting on a coed game first at which we will get to see some of the the Granite City Brawlermen in action for the first time as they join forces with some of the girls from Granite City Roller Girls as well as other guys and girls from the likes of Capital City, Mean City and Bairn City to form both of the coed teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This double header will take place at Meddowbank on Saturday the 19th of September, for more information visit the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4864" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ccrd-tall-smrdfin.jpg" alt="ccrd-tall-smrdfin" width="513" height="720"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>ccrd</category><category>coed</category><category>double header</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>mcrd</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mens roller derby scotland</category><category>scottish men's roller derby nationals</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><category>smrdn</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/27/capital-city-host-the-final-smrdn-game-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 11:21:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital City travel South of the border for the first time</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/06/capital-city-travel-south-of-the-border-for-the-first-time/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Capital City will once again be taking to the flat track for the second time this year and for the first ever, they will travel south of the border. On the 11th of July they will make their way down south to Manchester and will take on the Chaos Engine. Along with them they will be taking a few of our Scottish Officials to help officiate at the double header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chaos Engine are the B team to New Wheeled Order who some of you may remember them from their trip up to Scotland recently to play Mean City. That game went right down to the last jam and ended in a four point win for Chaos Engine. We are sure that this game will be just as exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/chaosvsccrd.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4768" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/chaosvsccrd.png?w=300" alt="chaosvsccrd" width="300" height="113"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information and details about the bout visit Manchester's event page on facebook
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1576510082598296/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1576510082598296/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital City will also have brand new merch to take down with them, which will also be available at all their upcoming games throughout the rest of the year. The new baseball t-shirt is the first in what will be a few new merch ideas that they have been working on this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/ccrd-new-tshirt.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4767" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/ccrd-new-tshirt.jpg?w=225" alt="Capital City's new merch design" width="320" height="426"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Capital City's new merch design&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>chaos engine</category><category>men's derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mighty unicorns</category><category>new wheeled order</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><category>unicorns</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/06/capital-city-travel-south-of-the-border-for-the-first-time/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 08:11:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Time to lo-go for it to help power Scotland to the World Cup...</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/05/06/time-to-lo-go-for-it-to-help-power-scotland-to-the-world-cup/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aspiring artists and daring designers can enjoy a brush with success … by designing a logo for Scotland’s national male roller derby team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Power of Scotland is challenging people to design a new logo for the team as homegrown preparations continue for the Men’s Roller Derby World Cup in Canada next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scottish skaters from across the UK are dreaming of representing their country in Calgary in 2016 – and they could be proudly sporting your logo design on their uniforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manager Nikki Morris said: “Thanks to all those who have already submitted logos for our competition. Rest assured they are all in contention – with some superb ideas in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“However, we have decided to extend the deadline to 31 May to give as many people as possible the chance to come up with a corking design which will be the talk of the roller derby world.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;“We are looking for something Scottish themed – unicorns, Nessies, tartan, heritage-related – with a twist.&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/05/11194398_10155484951575587_5898386249802980145_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4643 alignright" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/05/11194398_10155484951575587_5898386249802980145_o.jpg?w=219" alt="11194398_10155484951575587_5898386249802980145_o" width="293" height="398"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
“Remember it doesn’t have to be the same as the previous logo – which will be going in the selection anyway.”
&lt;p&gt;Pictured here is the results poster with all the team logos from 2014 to give you an idea of the style being sought and how designs translate onto print roll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be aware the FINAL closing date is 31 May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Meanwhile, the second Power of Scotland Try-out takes place in Grangemouth Sports Complex at 1.30pm on May 23.
• After try-outs the selection committee will choose a training squad of 30 skaters, who will train together once a month and scrimmage until October.
• In October the selection committee will come together again to watch a Scotland vs Scotland scrimmage made up of the training squad. Skaters will be marked using the selection criteria along with feedback from the coaches.
• From here the 20-man squad which will go to Calgary will be selected and will go on to train till the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>competition</category><category>in the news</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/05/06/time-to-lo-go-for-it-to-help-power-scotland-to-the-world-cup/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 22:27:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Porky urges Scots to get their skates on for the try-outs</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/04/09/porky-urges-scots-to-get-their-skates-on-for-the-try-outs/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Playing in the world cup of any sport is a half-dreamt hope for 99% of the population – but for Scotland’s male derby players it’s a tantalisingly-realistic proposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re playing football, Frisbee golf or Hungry Hippos – representing your country is an honour which is rarely bestowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to have born beneath the sound of bagpipes, raised on a diet of Buckfast and thistles, and able to recite Rabbie Burns at the drop of a haggis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neither do you need to be Ballistic McWhistle or a tartan-clad Quadzilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You just need to have the heart of a lion (rampant), a willingness to learn and train, and enough team spirit charging through your veins to power a dozen Dillon Panthers.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Power of Scotland (PoS) is hosting the first of its try-outs on Saturday April 18 – a rare chance to put yourself up for selection for the 2016 Men’s Roller Derby World Cup in Canada.&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/1504054_10151952723786867_568742544_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4607 alignright" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/1504054_10151952723786867_568742544_n.jpg?w=300" alt="1504054_10151952723786867_568742544_n" width="446" height="286"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Jammers, blockers, triple-threats and everything in between – all are being challenged to step up and skate out by one of Scotland’s stars at the 2014 World Cup.
&lt;p&gt;Richard ‘Porky’ Abrams, the revered Tyne &amp;amp; Fear enforcer, advises taking the Nike approach – just do it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said: “Being selected for PoS was a very proud moment. Since I was a child whenever I was asked what team I'd play for I always said Scotland, so getting in the PoS squad was a genuine honour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My advice to anyone considering trying out is ‘do it’. There's plenty of time to train and improve before the next World Cup. Selectors are looking for potential not the finished article. They're looking for team players who take direction and understand the game. Fitness can improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“PoS is ready to go to the next level and needs a range players from varied backgrounds. If you think you have a chance then you probably do! Look at the player of the first Euros, Mr Furieux had only been skating for a few months and he was incredible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Porky was part of the team who played at the 2014 World Cup and it was an experience he will never forget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The World Cup was incredible,” he said. “PoS played out of our skin. I got injured on the first day, my knee swelled up and I got p*ssed on the evening coz I was positive I wasn't going to play the USA the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was gutted, but also slightly relieved as I'd watched them that day and I didn't fancy a beating 1000-0. Unbelievably when I woke up my knee was fine! So that meant I could play the USA. Great/oh sh*t!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The highlight has to be PoS scoring 40 points against the USA. The highest score so far in the World Cup. As we lined up for the first jam of the second half I said to one of the USA team “just let us get one point!!”. He said: "if it were up to me I would, but if I did I'd never play for the USA again". So getting 40 points meant so much coz we earned every single one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My second highlight was being voted one of the all-star blockers of the tournament [all-star team pictured above]. Complete surprise! I was half-cut by the time they announced it and I genuinely didn't expect it. I didn't think I played as well as I could have.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to think it might not have been … without the timely intervention of Mrs Abrams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Porky recalled: “My mum’s a Glaswegian and when I told her I could try out for England or Scotland she just answered "when is the Scotland try-out?" - which meant, you're trying out for Scotland and don't test me on this one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I'd played the majority of Tyne and Fear games to that point and found I was at a half-decent level. I'd also played quite a few of the lads in Scotland so I knew there was a good standard to work with if I made the cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Also, geographically, living in Newcastle meant I was closer to practice with Scotland than people from Aberdeen. I also thought the support from Scottish fans would be better than any other at the World Cup and I wasn't wrong.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first Power of Scotland Try-out is on Saturday April 18 at 9.45am in Grangemouth Sports Complex. Try-out number two is in the same venue at 1.30pm on May 23.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After try-outs the selection committee will choose a training squad of 30 skaters, who will train together once a month and scrimmage until October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October the selection committee will come together again to watch a Scotland vs Scotland scrimmage made up of the training squad. Skaters will be marked using the selection criteria along with feedback from the coaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here the 20-man squad which will go to Calgary will be selected and will go on to train till the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what are you waiting for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head Coach Hannah Grant (aka Ginge) said: “We hope as many eligible skaters as possible attend one or both of the try-outs. Competing for your country is a pipe-dream for the vast majority of the population – but it could be a reality for Scotland’s male skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I would encourage everyone who meets the eligibility criteria to try out. It’s going to be a phenomenal journey to Canada 2016 – and we want as many people as possible to be part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The saddest words in the dictionary are ‘what if’ – you never know what could happen – don’t be left with regrets instead of amazing memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As Porky says, you don’t need to be the best skater in the world – we will be looking for skating skills, tactical awareness, strategy implementation, good sportsmanship and the ability to operate as a team player and not a lone wolf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Try and work on all aspects of your game in the run up to try-outs. If you are an amazing jammer then work on rounding out your blocking. If you always skate backwards to block then try mixing it up and working on being able to fluidly block in lots of different styles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you never pivot then work on that voice - work on being able to pull your wall together when it counts or switch up strategies when you need to. Make sure you are up to date on strategy and tactics, and also double-check your rules knowledge is up to date and relevant.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the latest news on Scotland – as well as information on attendance requirements, eligibility, submitting video evidence and more – visit www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>in the news</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/04/09/porky-urges-scots-to-get-their-skates-on-for-the-try-outs/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 10:35:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Interview with BCR and CCRD Captains after their first clash</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/03/11/interview-with-bcr-and-ccrd-captains-after-their-first-clash/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently Bairn City Rollers, Skelpies welcomed Capital Citys Mighty Unicorns in what was their first game against each other and the first game in the newly created Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals (SMRDNs). We caught up with both team captains to find out their thoughts on their first encounter and the first game of the SMRDNs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dreads #5 Skelpies Captain (D)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Despicable V #5 Mighty Unicorns Captain (V)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;You Both recently made captains of your respective teams, How did it feel to make Captain and lead your team in the first ever SMRDNs game?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D:&lt;/strong&gt; I was our vice captain for the past two years so I suppose that kind of helped with the preparation. With this being the first ever Nationals there was obviously a bit of pressure but I’m glad that I did it. I’m pleased with our win but this game shows we’ve still got plenty to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V:&lt;/strong&gt; I had only been captain for about three weeks before our game and have to admit it was a bit of a shock being voted in as I was up against some tough competition within CCRD for it. It was a bit daunting as this was only our second game and Tequila had done such a great job as captain at our last, so I had big boots to fill. It was all a bit like a baptism of fire as everything passed so quickly from being made captain till after the game. We knew it was always going to be a tough game as the Skelpies are a tough team, congratulations to them on the win they really made us work for every point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/dreads2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4589 size-full" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/dreads2.jpg" alt="dreads blocking" width="550" height="367"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Both teams contained skaters who played with Power of Scotland at the world cup last year, including yourselves. Was it strange to skate against people who you used to look to as teammates?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D:&lt;/strong&gt; To be honest I’m just impressed that I didn’t try to wall up with the wrong skaters or take a whip from one of them! In a way the game was similar to the PoS Team Blue vs Team White game last year in that I was both playing against and alongside my PoS teammates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V:&lt;/strong&gt; Like Dreads said it was a bit like the PoS vs PoS game last year. It was odd having some skaters on the opposition who I've played with in PoS and the jakeys and I did find myself a couple of times having to think twice when I saw one of the skelpies i had skated with previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This was the first time that both teams have played each other and was only CCRD’s second game. How do you feel CCRD played for their second game?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D:&lt;/strong&gt; Having watched the footage I don’t think an outsider would have known that this was only CCRD’s second game. Both teams have very similar playing styles (Venus and Ginge have a lot to do with that!) which meant that The Mighty Unicorns were a really tough opponent and those walls were far stronger than any team only on their second game should have!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V:&lt;/strong&gt; I'm really proud of our performance as all of our skaters really dug down deep throughout the game played their socks off. Since the game I've had a lot of people tell me just how impressed they were by us and how if they didn't know, they would have never have guessed it was only our second game. The Bairns really pushed us hard and took a  lead in the first half but no one got disheartened or lost their focus, which is why i think we managed to dig in and pull ourselves back into the game in the second half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/v1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4590 size-full" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/v1.jpg" alt="Despicable V" width="500" height="431"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Both teams had a mixture of newer and experienced skaters, how do you think your newer skaters played?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D:&lt;/strong&gt; Our newer guys ended up getting a lot more track time than any of us, including them, expected so really that speaks for itself! Everyone held their own that day but the other side of it is that I now expect this from them every time they’re on skates now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V:&lt;/strong&gt; I have to say how impressed I am with all our newer skaters. They really played their socks off and have progressed so much. Some have been training longer with CCRD than others, but all are doing and did so amazingly well and showed everyone how far they have come along. All of our skaters were on track roughly the same amount give or take a couple of jams which shows how much confidence we have in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The only other Scottish vs Scottish mens game so far was BCR vs Mean City last year and BCR took the win. Dread's how does it feel being the undefeated champion against men’s scottish teams?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D:&lt;/strong&gt; We’ve still got the Mean City rematch to come so I won’t say too much just now just in case but so far I’m loving it but now we’ve got the added pressure to make sure we keep this up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/dreads1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4588 size-full" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/dreads1.jpg" alt="Dreads" width="500" height="394"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dreads, seeing as you won your last encounter with Mean City by over 100 pts and they are your next and last opponent in the SMRDNs, are you quietly confident that you can win the game and the SMRDNs for this year?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a difficult one, we’ve scrimmed MCRD a couple of times since we last played them and each time they’ve played a very different game so they’re quite unpredictable. Much like CCRD, both teams have a few skaters who have played together with PoS and/or The Jakey Bites so this should be another really good game to play in and hopefully for the fans too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/v2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4591" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/v2.jpg" alt="Picture courtesy of Laura MacDonald" width="500" height="396"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What can people expect from your teams at their next SMRDNs game?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D:&lt;/strong&gt; Hopefully some new faces, new tactics and a win, maybe another cheesy hashtag. We’ve got a couple of games before we face Mean City so they’ll also be a chance to see what to expect in June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V:&lt;/strong&gt; We have about another 6 ish months till we take on Mean City in the last SMRDNs game this year, so hopefully we will have some new faces in our ranks as we have a few fresh meat coming through who should be mins passed by then. We also have a few games planned between now and then so our newer guys will get some more game experience under their belt. On top of that, we have been watching the game footage and taking notes for things that we need to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;When will be the next time your teams will be in action? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D:&lt;/strong&gt; The Skelpies will be back in action again at home in April when we take on the Knights of Oldham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for BCR vs CCRD, to the best of my knowledge there’s nothing planned yet for another game. But now that this game is out the way we can train together and scrim fairly regularly for the benefit of both teams (possibly featuring some of our Granite City Brawlermen pals?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V:&lt;/strong&gt; We were working on an away game in April, which unfortunately now isnt happening so Capital City's next game should be our next home game on the 16th of May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/all1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4587 size-full" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/all1.jpg" alt="BCR and CCRD" width="550" height="266"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>in the news</category><category>interviews</category><category>mighty unicrons</category><category>scottish men's roller derby nationals</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><category>skelpies</category><category>smrdn</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/03/11/interview-with-bcr-and-ccrd-captains-after-their-first-clash/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 21:38:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BCR Skelpies vs CCRD Mighty Unicorns February 28th 2015</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/02/02/bcr-skelpies-vs-ccrd-mighty-unicorns-february-28th-2015/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There has been a big buzz surrounding the British Roller Derby Champs which kicked off recently and grew out of the heartlands series. Many of the skaters from leagues taking part are now eagerly awaiting their first game in what is Europe's largest Roller Derby tournament, comprising 72 women’s leagues from England, Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland. Along with 10 men's leagues also competing in the men's side of the tournament. With all this going on you may be fooled into thinking that this is the next big new competition for women's and men’s derby, and you may be right. But here in Scotland we now have something new and very exciting to look forward to with our men's derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a considerable amount of discussions between Scottish Men's Derby Leagues over the last couple of years, there will be a brand new tournament taking place this year. The 28th of February 2015 will go down in Scottish derby history as the opening day and first ever game of the newly created &lt;a title="A run down on the Scottish Men’s Roller Derby League/Scottish Men’s Roller Derby (SMRD) Nationals" href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/10/a-run-down-on-the-scottish-mens-roller-derby-nationals/"&gt;Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals (SMRDNs)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1528686777405809/"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4545 size-large" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/bout-bcr-vs-ccrd-280215.jpg?w=614" alt="Poster by Cara Scott (Beatrix Slaughter of BCR)" width="614" height="515"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Poster by Cara Scott (Beatrix Slaughter of BCR)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bairn City Rollers have the honor of hosting the first of the three games being played this year as part of the SMRDNs. This game will take place at Grangemouth Sports Complex on Saturday the 28th of February, doors are at 3pm and &lt;a href="http://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/skelpies-vs-capital-city-roller-derby-tickets-15110714554"&gt;tickets are now available online&lt;/a&gt;. For more information on this visit the event page over on Facebook here: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1528686777405809/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1528686777405809/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital City are a relatively new bouting team having played their first ever game in November of last year, whilst BCR have been bouting since 2013 and have six public bouts to their name.  It may be hard to believe, but this game will be only the second time that two Scottish Men's derby teams have played each other in a public bout. Out of all the three bouting Scottish men's leagues, only BCR and Mean City have played each other in a public bout. That encounter ended with BCR taking the win and the bragging rights.  So come the 28th, BCR will be making sure they will do everything possible to extend that undefeated run against Scottish men's derby opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both sides are expecting it to be an explosive encounter and great inaugural game for the SMRDNs. As starting with a win, will be the best way to be crowned the 2015 SMRDN champions, because both teams will only have 1 more SMRDN game to play this year. After the 28th, the two remaining games will be Mean City vs BCR and the East vs West line up of Capital City v Mean City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With it being the first game in the newly created SMRDNs there has been a lot of excitement and interest in the game and if BCR Skater Archibald Wreck would have us believe there has been a furore of excitement in Russia and Japan since the game was announced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/japan.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4546" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/japan.jpg?w=614" alt="BCR VS CCRD Advert in Japan" width="708" height="408"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image by Archibald Wreck (Graeme McPhail) of BCR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/russia.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4547" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/russia.jpg" alt="BCR VS CCRD Advert in Russia" width="707" height="466"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image by Archibald Wreck (Graeme McPhail) of BCR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bcr</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>ccrd</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby edinburgh</category><category>men's roller derby falkirk</category><category>mighty unicrons</category><category>scottish men's roller derby nationals</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><category>skelpies</category><category>smrdn</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/02/02/bcr-skelpies-vs-ccrd-mighty-unicorns-february-28th-2015/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 12:39:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital City Roller Derby – Round-up of 2014</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/25/capital-city-roller-derby-round-up-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2014 was always going to be a great year for men’s roller derby, with the first ever Men’s World Cup taking place on UK soil in mid march, which we were lucky enough to have some of our own skaters (Tequila, Despicable V, Dafty) representing Power Scotland in the tournament on and off track. In the end Power of Scotland finished in joint 7th place with Argentina firmly putting Scottish Men’s derby on the map and played one the crowd favorites and most memorable games of the tournament when they took on the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/pos-vs-usa.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4427 " src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/pos-vs-usa.jpg?w=614" alt="Picture by Dave McLeavy" width="500" height="281"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture by Dave McLeavy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Scotland we now have Men’s leagues covering Aberdeen, Glasgow, Edinburgh and Central Scotland, so it's safe to say the future of the men's game is brighter than ever and it's an incredibly exciting time for all involved. Especially now that the location of the 2016 Men’s World cup has recently been announced and Power of Scotland is now laying out the time frame for try-outs and team selection to make the team for the 2016 World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the start of 2014 we knew our year was going to be a challenging and one at Capital City, as it was year two of our league. The second year of any league is usually a pivotal one, as it is when most start bouting. This usually heralds changes for any league, as they look to travel to play opponents or put on their own games, as well as a change in focus with training. Although we had made changes last year to our training we knew we had to adapt our advanced training to be more targeted towards game play and tactics. As these aspects of training are vital for all skaters so they can get a feel and focus for how the team is going to play as well as a better understanding of whats going on, on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone who has been involved in putting on a leagues first bout, they will know the sheer amount of work that is needed. As well as involvement from all the league members and the large costs the league need to deal with. At Capital City we are lucky that the vast majority of our members are all very involved with the running of things behind the scenes. The whole league knew and were constantly working towards  one of our main goals for 2014, which was to start bouting. This brought with it some challenges as we have always said we wanted to bout with a full roster of CCRD skaters and no guests, but recruitment during 2013 had been a bit hit and miss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Recruitment&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We really tried to push our fresh meat taster sessions throughout the year, in the hope of bringing in some new faces to help fill our ranks and get a full squad of 14 to play. Unfortunately, 2014’s recruitment seems to have mimicked 2013's in terms of success. We always generated a lot of interest in our fresh meat taster sessions and people would come along for a couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again it was getting people to come back after that, has proven to be the difficult part. From talking to other teams this does seem to be an issue that most men's leagues up and down the country face regularly. However, we have been slightly more successful than in the past with retention and have seven new faces join our ranks. Bolstering the leagues members to it's highest yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the seven, two (JAKILL3 and Wrighteous) have currently made it up to bouting level, with a couple more not far behind and the rest working towards passing their mins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Games&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/chums.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4425 " src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/chums.jpg?w=614" alt="Belter Skelpies vs Capital Chums" width="557" height="276"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Our co-ed bout with the Bairns&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were lucky enough to be approached by Bairn City Rollers earlier in the year, asking if we would like to play them in a co-ed game in July. After agreeing we formed Capital Chums a team comprising Capital City Skaters along with other half's, family and friends of our skaters. The game was a nail biter and entertained the crowd right down to the final whistle until they knew who the winner would be. With a hectic hard fought final jam it ended 166 - 161 to Bairn City Rollers, the bout made such an impression on Bairn City that they awarded it their favorite game of 2014 at their end of year awards ceremony and gave us a trophy to thank us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/ccrd-capitalchums-award.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-4424" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/ccrd-capitalchums-award.jpg?w=614" alt="Receiving our award from the Bairns" width="479" height="319"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Receiving our award from the Bairns&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn't until November 29th we took to the track again and for the first time as the Mighty Unicorns. This was also to be our first home game. To help us raise funds to pay for costs ahead of the bout, we took a new approach and turned to the public and fans to ask to help through our Indiegogo  crowdfunder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only was this our first ever men’s bout, it was our first home bout and Edinburgh's first men's derby headline bout all wrapped up in one. Named “A Bridge too far” it was double header with ARRG’s Cannon Belle’s taking on Malmö’s Crime City Rollers B and then Capital City taking on Bristol's Vice Quads with half time entertainment from Fierce Valley Roller Cubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our opponents Bristol were a bit of an unknown threat, with a few bouts against longer established UK teams already under their belt. Although we entered into the game hoping to win we knew it was going to be a tough task to achieve. From the first whistle it was a hard hitting game that came down once again to the final jam to see who would be victorious. In the end this time it was ourselves who took the honor, winning our first ever game 173 - 164.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/ccrdvsbristol.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4428 " src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/ccrdvsbristol.jpg?w=614" alt="Picture by Scott Carroll Live Photography" width="505" height="284"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture by Scott Carroll Live Photography&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Crowdfunder&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As most leagues will know, putting on your first bout is both terrifying and exciting in equal measure. As we are such a small league, finances proved to be the greatest hurdle. Our only real option for a venue was Meadowbank which came in at £900+ for hall hire and had to be paid 2 weeks before the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This proved to be our biggest stumbling block as we couldn't pay it from tickets sales on the day. Add to that insurance, track equipment, program printing, EMTs and a host of other smaller costs we knew the league couldn't bankroll the bout without some help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We held a couple of meetings and ran through different options but one kept returning, crowdfunding. As far as we knew no one in Scotland or possibly the UK had run Crowdfunding before to put on a roller derby bout, so we knew it could be a big risk. However we had a back up plan if the crowdfunder didn't work, which a bit simpler. Empty our own pockets to cover the costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We worked hard to put together a list of perks to entice people to donate. Our Idea was to run it like a ticket and merch pre sale, so donating got you entry or merch on the day. We offered the likes of t-shirts, tote bags, caps, bout tickets, personal CCRD strips, songs on the bout day playlist, selecting our skate out song and even blowing the start whistle of the bout. In the hope that we could cover something that most people would want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting a goal to raise proved a difficult task as well. Too little and it wouldn't be enough, too high and we may not make the total and lose all the donations in the process. This did provoke a fair amount of discussion between ourselves and in the end we set our goal at £1200. We knew that it was a large sum to raise but we had confidence that it was achievable. In the end we raised over £200 more than our total when our crowdfunder ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crowdfunder stats
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;109 Backers in total&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Raised £1410 in total&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Average pledge was £13&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Broke our target with a week to spare&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Averaged around £35/day&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;All backers bar 1 were from the uk, the other was from Australia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
It is safe to say that everyone who donated to our crowdfunder are our hero’s here at Capital City, as our game wouldn't have been the success that it was if it was not for each and everyone of you, so thank you.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/crd-first-win.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4426" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/crd-first-win.jpg?w=614" alt="" width="512" height="341"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; After our first Home bout, thank you all who donated and came to watch us on the day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rebrand&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of you may have noticed that this year we went through a little re-brand of our league logo. From very early on we have always been known for our very distinctive unicorn, so it was with great trepidation we looked at reworking our logo. We didn't want to lose the Unicorn but we knew it was time let a professional the chance to see what they came up with. As our original logo was pieced together by our members fairly quickly so we could have a logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/ccrd-oldogo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4432 size-medium" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/ccrd-oldogo.jpg?w=212" alt="Original CCRD logo" width="212" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Original CCRD logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We approached Admiral from ARRG in the hope she could come up with something, but not lose what made our old logo stand out. A couple of months later she came back with a design that with a couple of very minor tweaks later became our new logo. We think that you all will agree that she did a fantastic job. Also to coincide with our logo re brand our web guys in the league put their day job talents to good use and put together our first proper website over at &lt;a title="Capital City Roller Derby" href="http://www.capitalcityrollerderby.co.uk/"&gt;capitalcityrollerderby.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/capitalcitylogo-srdb.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4431 size-medium" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/capitalcitylogo-srdb.jpg?w=300" alt="CCRD New Logo" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; CCRD New Logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Achievements in 2014, what to &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;expect in 2015&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I caught up with Capital City's Captain Tequila Jammer and Vice Captain HaJuken to see what they thought were the leagues achievements in 2014 and what they are looking forward to in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HaJuken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="null"&gt;2014 was the year that people began to believe in Unicorns. We had a very successful year as we began to feel, scrim and play like a team. This was down to a number of factors. Our numbers grew to the point where we could do mini scrims at practice, we have several coaches that were able to teach the rest of the team about their specialties, everyone bringing their A-game to practice every week and having a very dedicated and awesome Captain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tequila Jammer&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="_38 direction_ltr"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dundee Rollers Girls have always been instrumental in giving newer skaters their first taste of the game with their awesome coed monthly scrims. I mean if you get hit by Milky you can get hit by anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HaJuken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="null"&gt;We had numerous skaters passing their mins and the first thing we say to them when they do is “get your butt to a Dundee Roller Girls Scrim!” Not only is scrimming great experience but the DRG Scrims usually host skaters from numerous different leagues such as Mean City, Granite City Roller Girls and Glasgow Roller Derby. So you also get to meet and skate with some new faces every time you go.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tequila Jammer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also had our first outing official outing which was in co-ed form was an amazing success. Many CCRD skaters joining forces with local leagues to make the Capital Chums! A tight match up that had everyone in the edge of our seats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HaJuken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="null"&gt;Even though the Chums lost by a few points I can safely say that everyone on the team felt like a winner after the amazing performance they put in that day. Who knows, maybe the Chums will reunite and take the win next time?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tequila Jammer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have to mention our first ever game! A BRIDGE TOO FAR! it was a great feeling to see 2 years of training come together in our debut game against the Vice Quads. The atmosphere was top notch and of course it couldn't of even happened without the support of our crowd funding ventures. Thanks again everyone! But seeing everyone come play as a team and Captain them to victory was euphoric feeling. In fact it's not just a team, it's a community and family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HaJuken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cant not mention A Bridge too far, Getting to skate together as a team for the first time and knowing your are part of history, there is no feeling like it.  It was definitely a hard fought win though as the lads from Bristol Vice Quad put up a serious fight. There was so much planning, hard work and effort by everyone on the team to make sure this game happened. We had a lot riding on this game being a success and seeing the hall fill up with people just made all the stress disappear on the day. Hearing the crowd erupt when we skated out was a great feeling and I definitely think we gave our fans a great show that day. As for the greatest moment for me this year? Definitely being nominated Vice Captain of CCRD. Knowing that I have teammates who thought I could be Vice Captain just boosted my confidence through the roof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tequila Jammer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next season we are looking forward to taking part in the newly formed Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals where we'll take on the formidable Skelpies and Mean City. Away games are on our agenda too, Bristol rematch and even taking the Unicorns overseas... WHAT?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course we hope to grow in numbers, promote derby and build links with local leagues and our community. So watch out 2015 UNICORNS ARE COMING!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HaJuken&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015 we will be looking to really make our mark on the Roller Derby scene by upping the amount of games we are going to play. We want to give back to our dedicated fan base by giving them more chances to see us skate. We have the Scottish Men’s Roller Derby Nationals as well as some away games, can you imagine the Unicorns invading other countries? How awesome would that be!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To all of our fans that have stuck by our sides over the last two years I would just like to say….Thank You! Your support at our first game “A Bridge Too Far” made all of the hard work worth it. We will not disappoint you and in 2015, we are going to show the Roller Derby world what we are made of! U-NI-CORNS! U-NI-CORNS!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 in review</category><category>articles</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>ccrd</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/25/capital-city-roller-derby-round-up-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2014 10:00:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New faces at the Capital City Vice Quad Bout</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/07/new-faces-at-the-capital-city-vice-quad-bout/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few months back, Capital City introduced a few new faces into the world of Scottish roller derby when we took part in a &lt;a title="Capital City’s cherry popping bouters" href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/30/capital-citys-cherry-popping-bouters/"&gt;co-ed bout with Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;. Forward on a few months and we are at it again. This time it's our very first home bout and our first bout as Capital City’s Mighty Unicorns. Our opponents were Bristol Roller Derby’s Vice Quads, a team which may have been around for a similar length of time as ourselves but had already bouted the likes of Quads of War, SWS b, The Crash Test Brummies and a few more to boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bout itself kept all who were watching on the edge of their seats from the first whistle to the last jam. Bristol may have took an early lead but we worked hard to pull the score line back into our favor during the first half. The scores remained close throughout the game right up to the final whistle, when it ended 173 - 164 in our favor (only a 9 point difference).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those of you who were there will have recognized a few familiar faces from the last couple of years in our ranks along with our newer bouters from our co-ed game along with some brand new faces. This time we had the pleasure of introducing you all to Bruise Campbell, JAKILL3, Sassenick and Wrighteous. I managed to catch up with three of our new faces after the bout for a quick interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/bruise-campbell-333.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4322" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/bruise-campbell-333.jpg?w=200" alt="Bruise Campbell" width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Bruise Campbell picture by Capital City&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/jakill3-317.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4318" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/jakill3-317.jpg?w=200" alt="JAKILL3 " width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; JAKILL3 picture by Capital City&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/sassenick-149.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4319" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/sassenick-149.jpg?w=200" alt="Sassenick" width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Sassenick picture by Capital City&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/wrighteous-626.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4320" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/wrighteous-626.jpg?w=200" alt="Wrighteous " width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Wrighteous picture by Capital City&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;b&gt;JAKILL3 #317 (JK)
Sassenick #149 (SN)
Wrighteous #626 ( W)&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How did you find out about Derby and CCRD?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W):&lt;/b&gt; Found out about derby through a friend, derby name Hazzard, who skates with NTRG. She took me to a few of the AARG bouts and i was hooked, and after I was given a link for mens derby bout i knew i had to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I missed the fresh meat intake, but luckily NTRG allowed myself to train with them where i passed my mins. luckily got to join CCRD at the next fresh meat where i was asked if i would like to join the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(SN):&lt;/b&gt; Originally found out about derby through a university friend (Jess E. Ska from GRD), but then my girlfriend got involved in ARRG and dragged me along to an open skating event. I loved it, and as soon as she told me about CCRD, I decided to give it a shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Having not skated previously how did you find working towards and passing your mins?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK):&lt;/b&gt; I found learning to skate with ccrd very easy and the guys at the club are great to get on with, teaching you with a lot of patience and good humor and breaking each lesson down into a skill block at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(SN):&lt;/b&gt; Because we're quite a small league, the first six months or so that I was skating I was thrown in the deep end. There were 4 of us who were new to Derby, but the rest of the regular attendees ended up representing Power of Scotland at the World Cup. It was hard not to compare myself to them at first, but as more new people arrived I realised just how much I'd come on, and that gave me a huge confidence boost and it became a lot easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/scott-carroll.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-4327" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/scott-carroll.jpg?w=300" alt="Picture courtesy of Scott Carroll Photography" width="520" height="346"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/ScottCarrollLivePhotography"&gt;Scott Carroll Photography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What would you say has been your biggest achievement so far in derby?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W):&lt;/b&gt; It would have to be receiving the award for best jammer at the CCRD bout against Bristol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I honestly thought HaJuken or Dafty would have won that award and was completely stunned when my name was called. Plus having my family and friends there to see it made it that much more memorable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK):&lt;/b&gt; Passing my mins and be able to play against bristol vice squad, where our team played well together and I got awarded best blocker from the bristol vice squad guys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(SN):&lt;/b&gt; In Derby generally, I was an NSO for the final of the 2014 Men's European Cup, which was an amazing experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a skater, it has to be the first time we played together as a team. We had a closed scrim against Mean City who are much more experienced at skating together, and I felt like I knew what was happening, and that I was being useful. It was a great feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Did you get any pre first bout nerves?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK):&lt;/b&gt; A little, didnt want to let the team down. But with great organisation and guidance from the more advanced players it made the day a lot more enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(SN):&lt;/b&gt; Oh yes. I was having a major panic, and I had to go and sit on my own in the changing room with my headphones in to calm down. As soon as the warm up started though, all that disappeared and I was fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W):&lt;/b&gt; I was nervous all the way until bout day arrived, where i found myself really relaxed and just pumped up. I could not wait to get on track and just have fun on the day. If you had asked me before bout day i honestly thought i would be so nervous i would have thrown up on the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/scott-carol.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-4326" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/scott-carol.jpg?w=300" alt="Picture courtesy of Scott Carroll Photography" width="520" height="346"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/ScottCarrollLivePhotography"&gt;Scott Carroll Photography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Playing in and winning your first ever bout must be a dream come true, how did you feel after the final whistle and the official score went up on the scoreboard?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK): &lt;/b&gt;Well it was touch and go at the end, but when the final decision came to our advantage I was over the moon a bit emotional. I feel I worked hard to get there and with the team it made it not only my proudest day but the happiest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W):&lt;/b&gt; Ecstatic, I had a great time, the team played amazingly and it was a great and very competitive bout. I was all over the place wondering if we had won or not, but when the score became official i was just ecstatic. My first ever bout with a team i had only just joined a few weeks ago and we won against Bristol Vice Quads, could not ask for anything better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What sticks in your memory most from your first bout?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(SN):&lt;/b&gt; At one point I managed to force a track cut. Not a huge thing in the scheme of things, but I did it without thinking, and it was the first time that I can point to that I was playing smart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W): &lt;/b&gt;There was a point when I was trying to get through the pack as a jammer, when I got hit back slightly. HaJuken was behind me and caught me just before I started to fall, pushed me back up and through the side of the pack to get lead jammer. It was just a fantastic bit of team work by HaJuken and watching it back on video and in pictures shows how good a player he is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK):&lt;/b&gt; Just how much work and time and effort goes into getting the bout ready for the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Did you get any good advice that helped you on track or prepare for the bout?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W):&lt;/b&gt; I think the best bit of advice was just what we had been given as a team which was to keep our heads, keep calm and have fun. Let them make mistakes, don't get riled up when hit just do what we do best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK):&lt;/b&gt; Ginge ..advised us to stay calm all the time which I need, I am easily distracted and get over competitive and can get stuck in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(SN):&lt;/b&gt; "Don't worry about it. You know what you're doing, so stop freaking out. Push yourself in your warm up, and you'll be fine."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Is there any advice you could give others who have their first bout still to come?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W):&lt;/b&gt; Keep calm and have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK): &lt;/b&gt; Stick in, train hard and If your not falling your not trying hard enough. As you have to push yourself to learn quicker. Also remember theres a team to support you. and as my second name sake bobby mcferrin sings "dont worry... be happy" and try and relax&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/chris-renton.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-4325" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/chris-renton.jpg?w=300" alt="Picture by Chris Renton" width="521" height="346"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture by Chris Renton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Are there any skaters (Male or Female) who inspire you?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(SN):&lt;/b&gt; Far too many. I'm still pretty much in awe of Rose City Wheels of Justice blockers after watching them in the WFTDA champs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK):&lt;/b&gt; Well the list is so long I’d love to be as fast as craig (Tequila) and as tough as gregg (Dafty) and but as calm as hannah (Ginge) and as calming as marco (Despicable V). I find that most of the team are great mix of all of the above. Also admiral attackbar from arrg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W):&lt;/b&gt; Hazzard from NTRG, she puts a lot of hard work into her team and is a fantastic skater. Can not wait till she is skating for team Scotland. Optimus Grime from Mean City and now part of Power of Scotland. He is just a great all round player and have been lucky enough to have trained with and scrimmed against him on a couple of occasions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Skaters generally set goals for themselves, now that you have played in your first bout what goal's are you now looking to achieve/work towards?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(S):&lt;/b&gt; The biggest thing I learned about my skating was that I really need to work on the basics - ploughing especially. In almost all the pictures of me, I'm t-stopping which is really ineffective in a game situation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(JK):&lt;/b&gt; Better bridging, walls, stopping faster also building my stamina and strength and not forgetting my dark side over competitiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;(W):&lt;/b&gt; To build on my skills and look to improve my all round game, and hopefully one day maybe even try out for Power of Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10830932_862436320444831_4570080339720243265_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-4324" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/10830932_862436320444831_4570080339720243265_o.jpg?w=300" alt="Picture courtesy of Scott Carroll Photography" width="545" height="363"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/ScottCarrollLivePhotography"&gt;Scott Carroll Photography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mens roller derby scotland</category><category>new faces of derby</category><category>new skaters</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/07/new-faces-at-the-capital-city-vice-quad-bout/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 13:41:42 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>