<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about scotland)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/scotland.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 08:59:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Meanwhile, in Scotland...</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/10/meanwhile-in-scotland/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regular readers will have noticed that we've had something of a diversion from our regular content recently, as the second Men's Roller Derby World Cup, in Calgary, approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, exciting derby hasn't stopped in Scotland, or Europe, so we should catch up on what's coming more locally...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-8166 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/12654276_631717886965980_4588037546842024195_n.jpg" alt="12654276_631717886965980_4588037546842024195_n" width="784" height="295"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who'd like a Roller Derby extravaganza a little closer than Calgary, or Las Vegas, this week sees the very first &lt;a href="http://www.euroderbycon.com/"&gt;Euro Derby Con&lt;/a&gt;, styling itself the "1st Annual European Roller Derby Convention". Organised by Track Advantage, the con will feature plenty of on-track action (including both sanctioned games and more eclectic challenge bouts), as well as off-track seminars and plenty of vendors in the shopping area. Euro Derby Con is in Barcelona, Spain from the &lt;strong&gt;14th&lt;/strong&gt; to the &lt;strong&gt;17th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;July&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope to have feedback and reports from this exciting event from attendees after it completes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-8164 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/school-of-arrg-knocks5.jpg" alt="School-of-ARRG-Knocks5" width="608" height="430"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even more locally, &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; are holding their 5th "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/promotion/the-school-of-arrg-knocks-roller-derby-bootcamp-is-back/"&gt;School of ARRG Knocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" bootcamp on the &lt;strong&gt;16th&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;17th&lt;/strong&gt;, now featuring both co-ed multitiered training (with slots for pre-mins, intermediate and advanced skaters), and a "Sur5al style" tournament on the Sunday afternoon. It seems that tickets are still available, at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://soak5.bpt.me/"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (be sure to pick the tier of ticket you want, there's quite a few options!).
ARRG also have their traditional Fringe events coming up soon, this time featuring a double header against Dundee Roller Girls and Glasgow Roller Derby. Check it out on &lt;strong&gt;August 6th&lt;/strong&gt;, at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/promotion/battle-of-scotland-festival-fringe-double-header/"&gt;event page here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.wix.com/thedrg"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;, they're also in the teaching zone, with their second "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1696079833978398/"&gt;Open Learning Scrims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" of the month, on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 15th&lt;/strong&gt; at their usual venue of the Dundee International Sports Centre. And if you have the taste for bootcamps later on, look out for DRG's first ever Post-Mins bootcamp, "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1769982133234846/"&gt;Skate Tay Victory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" in September!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; also have a busy &lt;strong&gt;August&lt;/strong&gt; planned, following up their challenge against Auld Reekie above with a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/events-calendar/2016/8/20/mixed-teams-double-header-vr-vs-soy-division-plus-science-vs-fantasy"&gt;double header exhibition extravaganza&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;20th&lt;/strong&gt;, which will see Soy Division (the UK's Vegan derby exhibition team) take on Vagine Regime UK (the UK's L(G)BT derby exhibition team), followed by a "Science v Fantasy" themed bout. Glasgow Roller Derby has quite a few skaters in both Soy Division and Vagine Regime UK, so this will be a pretty interesting bout to see...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...but Glasgow's next official bout will be the week after, as their B and C teams (the Maiden Grrders and Canny Gingers) travel all the way up to Aberdeen on the &lt;strong&gt;27th&lt;/strong&gt; to take on &lt;a href="http://www.granitecityrollerderby.co.uk/"&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s Northern Fights and Fight Hawks in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1717081471898842/"&gt;another double header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the midst of all this excitement, we should also note that &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; are also not resting; with Preston Roller Girls hosting the last round of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/454153454770970/"&gt;British Championships Tier 3 North&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, FVRG will be taking on the hosts (and Dundee taking on Hallam Hellcats) to decide the final places on the &lt;strong&gt;17th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;July&lt;/strong&gt;. These are especially important games for both Scottish teams, in opposite directions: Fierce Valley need to win against Preston to move up from the bottom of the table, while a Dundee win against Hallam will give them a good shot at taking the &lt;em&gt;top&lt;/em&gt; of the table from incumbents Manchester!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FVRG will be hosting themselves a month later, as &lt;strong&gt;18th August&lt;/strong&gt; sees the return of their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1385457658148117/"&gt;Charity Co-Ed Scrims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all the derby we are aware of in July and August... but there's exciting things afoot in September as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>scotland</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/10/meanwhile-in-scotland/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 21:09:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls - Home Season Final 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/28/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-season-final-2015/</link><dc:creator>jennifergelignite</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="spotlight alignleft" src="https://scontent.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpl1/v/t35.0-12/12359395_10153180288466022_1192149624_o.jpg?oh=24e2550bb0d345849186b5816bf3ebeb&amp;amp;oe=56835C21" alt="" width="755" height="501"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A HEART-STOPPING home season final saw the Leithal Weapons swoop to victory by just two points.
Auld Reekie Roller Girls' (ARRG) three home teams - the Leithals, Skatefast Club and the Cherry Bombers - had battled throughout autumn for the chance to take home the 2015 trophy.
Skatefast had beaten the Leithals in the first home season head-to-head and, with the Leithals struggling to field a full team for the final due to injury and illness, looked like the stronger team at the first whistle.
Skill levels were closely-matched and the lead switched several times, as both teams pushed their opponents to pull out their very best performance.
Skatefast were leading by half-time and victory seemed likely, but the Leithals re-entered the track with renewed determination.
With five minutes to the end, Skatefast had pulled ahead by 20 points, leaving the Leithals praying for a power jam.
Suddenly, the opportunity opened up with excellent defensive work from the Leithals in the very last jam.
EmKarp blasted through the Skatefast blockers and the crowd held its breath and held back tears as the points gap closed.
A smart star pass to Tuna Lovegood for an extra energy kick sealed the deal... Or so the Leithals hoped.
The unofficial result was carefully checked as both teams teetered on the brink of celebration for a score that could have gone either way.
Finally those two crucial extra points were verified and the Leithal Weapons were officially declared the 2015 winners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="spotlight alignright" src="https://scontent.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpa1/v/t1.0-9/12299301_10156272236840224_1957699839736333339_n.jpg?oh=fddaf7b01dbf9fe3a6fba64e58b5d64f&amp;amp;oe=57194B21" alt="" width="480" height="360"&gt;
Leithals captain Prawncess Die said she was thrilled for her team.
She said: "We went in as the underdogs.
"We thought we had a good chance but we were playing short and we had lost the last game against them.
"It was so close - I kept looking at the score thinking we can still do this.
"We drifted down 20 points a few times and, in the last few minutes, I did think that was it.
"I thought 'at least we've put up a close game'.
"Then to actually win was just fantastic."
Prawncess Die added she was particularly proud of the newest players on the team.
She said: "Dani was just outstanding, especially as a jammer.
"Everybody was playing really well but she played every position and switched from one to the other, which was very impressive."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skatefast Club captain Trifecta Gadget said everyone was very emotional.
She said: "It was a really tight game through every single jam and we never really felt safe.
"It was good to be in the lead at the end of the first half but I knew we were going to have to bring our strongest game.
"The teams were very evenly matched and I think we lost it on just a couple of jams against some really amazing Leithals players."
Gadget also praised the newest skaters on her team.
She said: "We all kept our defence strong and stayed together really well.
"It was only because we played so well as a team the score was so close.
"I could see how much more confident everybody was by the end and I'm really proud of every skater."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>edinburgh</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/28/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-season-final-2015/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 13:12:29 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>