<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about scottish men's roller derby nationals)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/scottish-mens-roller-derby-nationals.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>2015 A year in review for Capital City</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/22/2015-a-year-in-review-for-capital-city/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2014 was a year of firsts for  Capital City, which saw them have members take part in the first ever Men's Roller Derby World Cup with Power Of Scotland, play their first ever co-ed game under the name Capital Chums then round off their year off by hosting and playing in their first ever home game.  2015 started with their AGM and voting in a new captain (Despicable V) and vice (Dafty) who would guide them through the next 9 months of games they had booked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2015 was their first full bouting year and their bout management had been working hard to line up games. Unfortunately one of their games had to be cancelled when the opponents lost their training venue and another two games ended up being postponed until 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year saw the first ever Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals tournament being held over the course of the year. This saw all the bouting men's teams in Scotland (Bairn City Rollers, Capital City and Mean City) face off against each other during the year, to see who would be crowned the first Scottish Nationals Champion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/ccrd-bcr.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5260"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5260" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/ccrd-bcr.jpg?w=614" alt="ccrd-bcr" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital City's first game of the year and the first game of Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals was against Bairn City Rollers, which saw them travel to Grangemouth to play the Skelpies on their home turf. The final score was Skelpies 192 to CCRD 127 in what was a hard fought game from beginning to end that saw both teams only fielding 10 skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the cancelled  and postponed games It would be almost 5 months until Capital City took to the track again. In that time they took in a few new skaters (Darth Evader and Mad Science) and were working hard at getting them through their mins ready for the games later on in the year. They also had four skaters (Bounce, Dafty, Tequila Jammer and Despicable V) make it into the 30 training squad for Power of Scotland for the Men's Derby World Cup next year. Of those four two (Dafty and Tequila Jammer)  made it into the final selection of 20 skaters going to Calgary next year and also took part in the 4 nations tournament, which saw England, Scotland, Wales and France all play each other over the course of a weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/darth-evader-54.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4876 size-medium" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/darth-evader-54.jpg?w=240" alt="Darth Evader 54" width="240" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Darth Evader #54&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/mad-science-36.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4875 size-medium" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/09/mad-science-36.jpg?w=240" alt="Mad Science 36" width="240" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Mad Science #36&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
It want until the 11th of July that Capital City got back on track this time making their first ever trip south of the border heading down to Manchester to take on the Chaos Engine. Unfortunately due to injuries and holidays they were a little light on skaters so drafted in two guest skaters with Momo from The Brawlermen and Bish Bash Josh ex Capital City Skater who now lives down in Manchester  both being unicorns on the day. The final score was Chaos Engine 213 to Capital City 107.
&lt;p&gt;Their Third and final public game of the year was on the 19th of October when Mean City paid them a visit in the final game of the Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals for 2015. As Bairn City had won both of their games they had been crowned the 2015 Champions but this game would decide who got 2nd and 3rd place. At the final whistle the scores were Capital City 158 - Mean City  217, meaning Mean City took 2nd place and Capital City took 3rd in a very hard hitting and fought game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/mc-ccrd.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5259"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5259" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/mc-ccrd.jpg?w=614" alt="mc ccrd" width="614" height="271"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a sadder note, during 2015 Capital City and Scottish derby also said goodbye to a couple of faces. After all our public games were played Deathworm Jim decided to hang up his skates. Having been with Capital City from their inception his presence will definitely be missed on and off the track. At the beginning of the year, an old familiar face returned to Capital City, transferring from Mean City. Unfortunately not long after the Chaos engine game, Bounce also decided that the time was right for him to also hang up his skates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before the end of the year Capital City wanted to fit in one last thing. At the beginning of December they invited everyone's friends from the North, the Granite City Brawler Men down for a closed game, which both enjoyed so much that a return game has already been planned for next year. For that game they also voted in their new Captain (Hajuken) and Vice (Critical Hit) to get them ready for the year ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2015</category><category>articles</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>mens roller derby scotland</category><category>mighty unicorns</category><category>scottish men's roller derby nationals</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/22/2015-a-year-in-review-for-capital-city/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 15:37:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital City Host the Final SMRDN game of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/27/capital-city-host-the-final-smrdn-game-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year we saw the launch of the Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals (SMRDN), which saw Bairn City Rollers, Mean City and Capital City all fight for the bragging rights of being the top Scottish Men's team. With two games played and two wins to BCR's Skelpies they have taken the title of champions for this year. There is however still one more game left to play which is sure to be an exciting clash for more than one reason, which is Capital City vs Mean City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone wp-image-4863 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ccrd-banner-smrdfin.jpg?w=614" alt="ccrd-banner-smrdfin" width="614" height="227"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two teams have yet to met on track in a public game, with this their first encounter deciding who will take second place in this years SMRDN and the looser picking up 3rd and last place for 2015. With so much to play for, both teams will be fighting for every point from the first whistle to the last. And if this wasn't enough to tempt you along, Capital City have turned the event into a double header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get everyone ready for the main event, they are putting on a coed game first at which we will get to see some of the the Granite City Brawlermen in action for the first time as they join forces with some of the girls from Granite City Roller Girls as well as other guys and girls from the likes of Capital City, Mean City and Bairn City to form both of the coed teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This double header will take place at Meddowbank on Saturday the 19th of September, for more information visit the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4864" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ccrd-tall-smrdfin.jpg" alt="ccrd-tall-smrdfin" width="513" height="720"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>ccrd</category><category>coed</category><category>double header</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>mcrd</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mens roller derby scotland</category><category>scottish men's roller derby nationals</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><category>smrdn</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/27/capital-city-host-the-final-smrdn-game-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 11:21:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Interview with BCR and CCRD Captains after their first clash</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/03/11/interview-with-bcr-and-ccrd-captains-after-their-first-clash/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently Bairn City Rollers, Skelpies welcomed Capital Citys Mighty Unicorns in what was their first game against each other and the first game in the newly created Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals (SMRDNs). We caught up with both team captains to find out their thoughts on their first encounter and the first game of the SMRDNs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dreads #5 Skelpies Captain (D)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Despicable V #5 Mighty Unicorns Captain (V)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;You Both recently made captains of your respective teams, How did it feel to make Captain and lead your team in the first ever SMRDNs game?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D:&lt;/strong&gt; I was our vice captain for the past two years so I suppose that kind of helped with the preparation. With this being the first ever Nationals there was obviously a bit of pressure but I’m glad that I did it. I’m pleased with our win but this game shows we’ve still got plenty to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V:&lt;/strong&gt; I had only been captain for about three weeks before our game and have to admit it was a bit of a shock being voted in as I was up against some tough competition within CCRD for it. It was a bit daunting as this was only our second game and Tequila had done such a great job as captain at our last, so I had big boots to fill. It was all a bit like a baptism of fire as everything passed so quickly from being made captain till after the game. We knew it was always going to be a tough game as the Skelpies are a tough team, congratulations to them on the win they really made us work for every point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/dreads2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4589 size-full" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/dreads2.jpg" alt="dreads blocking" width="550" height="367"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Both teams contained skaters who played with Power of Scotland at the world cup last year, including yourselves. Was it strange to skate against people who you used to look to as teammates?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D:&lt;/strong&gt; To be honest I’m just impressed that I didn’t try to wall up with the wrong skaters or take a whip from one of them! In a way the game was similar to the PoS Team Blue vs Team White game last year in that I was both playing against and alongside my PoS teammates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V:&lt;/strong&gt; Like Dreads said it was a bit like the PoS vs PoS game last year. It was odd having some skaters on the opposition who I've played with in PoS and the jakeys and I did find myself a couple of times having to think twice when I saw one of the skelpies i had skated with previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This was the first time that both teams have played each other and was only CCRD’s second game. How do you feel CCRD played for their second game?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D:&lt;/strong&gt; Having watched the footage I don’t think an outsider would have known that this was only CCRD’s second game. Both teams have very similar playing styles (Venus and Ginge have a lot to do with that!) which meant that The Mighty Unicorns were a really tough opponent and those walls were far stronger than any team only on their second game should have!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V:&lt;/strong&gt; I'm really proud of our performance as all of our skaters really dug down deep throughout the game played their socks off. Since the game I've had a lot of people tell me just how impressed they were by us and how if they didn't know, they would have never have guessed it was only our second game. The Bairns really pushed us hard and took a  lead in the first half but no one got disheartened or lost their focus, which is why i think we managed to dig in and pull ourselves back into the game in the second half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/v1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4590 size-full" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/v1.jpg" alt="Despicable V" width="500" height="431"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Both teams had a mixture of newer and experienced skaters, how do you think your newer skaters played?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D:&lt;/strong&gt; Our newer guys ended up getting a lot more track time than any of us, including them, expected so really that speaks for itself! Everyone held their own that day but the other side of it is that I now expect this from them every time they’re on skates now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V:&lt;/strong&gt; I have to say how impressed I am with all our newer skaters. They really played their socks off and have progressed so much. Some have been training longer with CCRD than others, but all are doing and did so amazingly well and showed everyone how far they have come along. All of our skaters were on track roughly the same amount give or take a couple of jams which shows how much confidence we have in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The only other Scottish vs Scottish mens game so far was BCR vs Mean City last year and BCR took the win. Dread's how does it feel being the undefeated champion against men’s scottish teams?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D:&lt;/strong&gt; We’ve still got the Mean City rematch to come so I won’t say too much just now just in case but so far I’m loving it but now we’ve got the added pressure to make sure we keep this up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/dreads1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4588 size-full" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/dreads1.jpg" alt="Dreads" width="500" height="394"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dreads, seeing as you won your last encounter with Mean City by over 100 pts and they are your next and last opponent in the SMRDNs, are you quietly confident that you can win the game and the SMRDNs for this year?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a difficult one, we’ve scrimmed MCRD a couple of times since we last played them and each time they’ve played a very different game so they’re quite unpredictable. Much like CCRD, both teams have a few skaters who have played together with PoS and/or The Jakey Bites so this should be another really good game to play in and hopefully for the fans too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/v2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4591" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/v2.jpg" alt="Picture courtesy of Laura MacDonald" width="500" height="396"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What can people expect from your teams at their next SMRDNs game?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D:&lt;/strong&gt; Hopefully some new faces, new tactics and a win, maybe another cheesy hashtag. We’ve got a couple of games before we face Mean City so they’ll also be a chance to see what to expect in June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V:&lt;/strong&gt; We have about another 6 ish months till we take on Mean City in the last SMRDNs game this year, so hopefully we will have some new faces in our ranks as we have a few fresh meat coming through who should be mins passed by then. We also have a few games planned between now and then so our newer guys will get some more game experience under their belt. On top of that, we have been watching the game footage and taking notes for things that we need to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;When will be the next time your teams will be in action? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D:&lt;/strong&gt; The Skelpies will be back in action again at home in April when we take on the Knights of Oldham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for BCR vs CCRD, to the best of my knowledge there’s nothing planned yet for another game. But now that this game is out the way we can train together and scrim fairly regularly for the benefit of both teams (possibly featuring some of our Granite City Brawlermen pals?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V:&lt;/strong&gt; We were working on an away game in April, which unfortunately now isnt happening so Capital City's next game should be our next home game on the 16th of May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/all1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4587 size-full" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/03/all1.jpg" alt="BCR and CCRD" width="550" height="266"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Picture courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>in the news</category><category>interviews</category><category>mighty unicrons</category><category>scottish men's roller derby nationals</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><category>skelpies</category><category>smrdn</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/03/11/interview-with-bcr-and-ccrd-captains-after-their-first-clash/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 21:38:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BCR Skelpies vs CCRD Mighty Unicorns February 28th 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/02/02/bcr-skelpies-vs-ccrd-mighty-unicorns-february-28th-2015/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There has been a big buzz surrounding the British Roller Derby Champs which kicked off recently and grew out of the heartlands series. Many of the skaters from leagues taking part are now eagerly awaiting their first game in what is Europe's largest Roller Derby tournament, comprising 72 women’s leagues from England, Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland. Along with 10 men's leagues also competing in the men's side of the tournament. With all this going on you may be fooled into thinking that this is the next big new competition for women's and men’s derby, and you may be right. But here in Scotland we now have something new and very exciting to look forward to with our men's derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a considerable amount of discussions between Scottish Men's Derby Leagues over the last couple of years, there will be a brand new tournament taking place this year. The 28th of February 2015 will go down in Scottish derby history as the opening day and first ever game of the newly created &lt;a title="A run down on the Scottish Men’s Roller Derby League/Scottish Men’s Roller Derby (SMRD) Nationals" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/01/10/a-run-down-on-the-scottish-mens-roller-derby-nationals/"&gt;Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals (SMRDNs)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1528686777405809/"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4545 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/bout-bcr-vs-ccrd-280215.jpg?w=614" alt="Poster by Cara Scott (Beatrix Slaughter of BCR)" width="614" height="515"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Poster by Cara Scott (Beatrix Slaughter of BCR)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bairn City Rollers have the honor of hosting the first of the three games being played this year as part of the SMRDNs. This game will take place at Grangemouth Sports Complex on Saturday the 28th of February, doors are at 3pm and &lt;a href="http://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/skelpies-vs-capital-city-roller-derby-tickets-15110714554"&gt;tickets are now available online&lt;/a&gt;. For more information on this visit the event page over on Facebook here: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1528686777405809/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1528686777405809/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital City are a relatively new bouting team having played their first ever game in November of last year, whilst BCR have been bouting since 2013 and have six public bouts to their name.  It may be hard to believe, but this game will be only the second time that two Scottish Men's derby teams have played each other in a public bout. Out of all the three bouting Scottish men's leagues, only BCR and Mean City have played each other in a public bout. That encounter ended with BCR taking the win and the bragging rights.  So come the 28th, BCR will be making sure they will do everything possible to extend that undefeated run against Scottish men's derby opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both sides are expecting it to be an explosive encounter and great inaugural game for the SMRDNs. As starting with a win, will be the best way to be crowned the 2015 SMRDN champions, because both teams will only have 1 more SMRDN game to play this year. After the 28th, the two remaining games will be Mean City vs BCR and the East vs West line up of Capital City v Mean City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With it being the first game in the newly created SMRDNs there has been a lot of excitement and interest in the game and if BCR Skater Archibald Wreck would have us believe there has been a furore of excitement in Russia and Japan since the game was announced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/japan.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4546" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/japan.jpg?w=614" alt="BCR VS CCRD Advert in Japan" width="708" height="408"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image by Archibald Wreck (Graeme McPhail) of BCR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/russia.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4547" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/russia.jpg" alt="BCR VS CCRD Advert in Russia" width="707" height="466"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image by Archibald Wreck (Graeme McPhail) of BCR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bcr</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>ccrd</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby edinburgh</category><category>men's roller derby falkirk</category><category>mighty unicrons</category><category>scottish men's roller derby nationals</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><category>skelpies</category><category>smrdn</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/02/02/bcr-skelpies-vs-ccrd-mighty-unicorns-february-28th-2015/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 12:39:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A run down on the Scottish Men's Roller Derby League/Scottish Men's Roller Derby (SMRD) Nationals</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/01/10/a-run-down-on-the-scottish-mens-roller-derby-nationals/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of you may have noticed during the same weekend of the Womens Roller Derby World Cup, a page went up on Facebook for the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/SMRDN"&gt;Scottish Men's Roller Derby League&lt;/a&gt; now named then Scottish Men's Roller Derby (SMRD) Nationals. At first many thought it was a new men’s league in Scotland, but it is something much more exciting for the Men’s leagues and derby in Scotland. Due to the confusion of it being a league, they have since changed their name to the &lt;a title="Scottish Mens Roler Derby Nationals" href="https://www.facebook.com/SMRDN"&gt;Scottish Men's Roller Derby (SMRD) Nationals&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you will know In 2015 we will see some of the women's leagues in Scotland taking part in the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BritishRollerDerbyChamps"&gt;British Championships&lt;/a&gt; which will pull together leagues fom all over the UK playing against each other in regional/level based groups. In essence this is what the the SMRDN is about, but on a smaller scale. Bringing together all the Scottish mens leagues (Bairn City Rollers, Capital City, Granite City Brawlermen and Mean City) to play each other over the course of the year, tracking scores and wins and providing a winner with the most points at the end of the year. For the first season (2015) there will only be three leagues competing (Bairn City Rollers, Capital City and Mean City) with Granite City Brawlermen working hard to put together a team for 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/1549327_613471468758290_2453333471572179977_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4514 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/1549327_613471468758290_2453333471572179977_n.jpg?w=614" alt="1549327_613471468758290_2453333471572179977_n" width="614" height="215"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; All the Scottish Men's Derby Leagues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For well over a year now, all four of the men's leagues in Scotland have been in discussion about putting together the SMRDN. As they knew that they would all be playing each other regularly and were looking for a way in which to make it more interesting for spectators and fans of the leagues.  With this in mind they knew that crowning a league the champion of Scottish Men’s roller derby for a year could help to promote the bouts and give everyone something to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How it will work:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The 2015 Season will see three teams play each other once during the year&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;2 points will be awarded for each game won and 0 for a loss&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Points Scored (PS), Points Against (PA) and Points Difference (PD) will be tracked over the year&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Each league will host 1 home game&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Games will be played to latest MRDA ruleset&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Teams must not field "guest" skaters, all skater must be a full member of their respective league&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The season table will be updated on SMRDN facebook page for all to track see after each game&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The Team with the most points at the end of the year will win that season&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
However, if at the end of the season there is a draw of points between teams, then PD will be compared. If the PD is also a draw, the team with the  highest PS will be chosen as the winner of the season.
&lt;p&gt;They have also announced the first game of the 2015 Season and the first game ever of the SMRDN which will see Bairn City Roller host Capital City on the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1528686777405809/%20"&gt;28th of February at Grangemouth Sport Complex&lt;/a&gt; in whats is bound to be a great bot to start this exciting new championship between all the Scottish Men’s Derby Leagues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>in the news</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>scottish men's roller derby league</category><category>scottish men's roller derby nationals</category><category>smrdn</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/01/10/a-run-down-on-the-scottish-mens-roller-derby-nationals/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 22:20:05 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>