<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about silvery tayzers)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/silvery-tayzers.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:41:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Dundee's call for skaters in double header event!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/16/dundees-call-for-skaters-in-double-header-event/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dundee is hosting a double header on the &lt;strong&gt;25th August &lt;/strong&gt;at the &lt;strong&gt;DISC in Dundee&lt;/strong&gt; with tickets sold on the door for &lt;strong&gt;£6!&lt;/strong&gt; There will also be a donation table for Dundee's local &lt;em&gt;WRASAC&lt;/em&gt;, looking for wellness packages donations and home goodies, as listed on their &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/191754218184900/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-27218 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/fbimage-01.png?w=212" alt="FBImage-01" width="262" height="371"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;12:3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0, &lt;/strong&gt;with the Bonnie Colliders taking on&lt;strong&gt; Mean City&lt;/strong&gt; first and the Silvery Tayzers taking on a mixed side of skaters from across the land!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to an unfortunate drop out of a previous opponent. The Silvery Tayzers have switched up the second game to a mixed side open to opt ins! DRD are still on the look out for skaters to play in this game, starting at &lt;strong&gt;3pm. &lt;/strong&gt;It is open to: WFTDA gender policy, ideally advanced, skaters and Dundee are offering hosting, if that is needed. If you would like to opt in for the game, all you need to do is email &lt;strong&gt;DundeeRollerDerby@gmail.com&lt;/strong&gt; with your details! The deadline for opt in to play is &lt;strong&gt;22/08&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/2018.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the run up to these fantastic games, we had a wee catch up with both Mean City and The Bonnie Colliders to see how the sides are shaping up!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;"Throughout our sessions we have remained focused on our skills and gameplay while having the best time with our fellow meanies. We look forward to the challenge, the team building and most importantly, skating on track with the Bonnie Colliders."&lt;strong&gt; - Megatron&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Mean City)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;"The Colliders are buzzed to be playing on their home turf! We have a strong team and have outlined strong focuses for each skater. New tactics for ourselves and new players coming into our team have us really excited for this game. Especially since we haven't had the chance to play the wonderful meanies yet!" &lt;strong&gt;- Tiny Tearaway&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Bonnie Colliders)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-27230" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/39127098_1349993311803752_1458506761269936128_n.jpg?w=300" alt="Mean City" width="300" height="200"&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;"..We are super excited in anticipation of our bout with the Bonnie Colliders on the 25th August.  It is sure to be an exciting game that is both challenging and exceptionally rewarding.  As a league we are keen to show everyone a good time while playing our beloved sport with some amazing skaters." - &lt;strong&gt;Magatron&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Mean City)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-27231 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/32915322_1821085297956877_529342680438669312_n.jpg?w=300" alt="32915322_1821085297956877_529342680438669312_n" width="300" height="225"&gt;"Playing with other local leagues is such a rewarding challenge, we've all seen each other play in open scrims and each others' games, and its really fun to have us all come together! The Colliders work hard as a team, and as part of the DRD. We all grow together, work together and have fun together! We can't wait to get on track!" - &lt;strong&gt;Tiny Tearaway&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Bonnie Colliders)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/191754218184900/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
Where: D.I.S.C.
When: Doors open 12:30&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>mean city</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/16/dundees-call-for-skaters-in-double-header-event/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 08:00:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Final Champs game for DRG</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/04/final-champs-game-for-drg/</link><dc:creator>julezw</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girls Silvery Tayzers will travel to Sheffield this Saturday (8th August) to compete in the final triple header of the British Championships T3 Regional North. After securing victory against Sheffield Steel Roller Girls in July, Dundee have left themselves in a great position to secure a play-off spot. Victory against Furness Firecrackers will see Dundee progress but with three teams still in with a chance (Furness Firecrackers, Liverpool Roller Birds and Dundee), it’s all to play for. Last time the teams met, Dundee emerged victorious and will be looking for a similar outcome this time round.
In the days other games, GCRG take on Halifax Bruising Banditas and hosts Sheffield take on Liverpool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ssrg.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4836" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ssrg.png?w=214" alt="SSRG" width="214" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come down and join the fun!
Concord Sports Centre, Shiregreen Lane, Sheffield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors 9.30am.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/04/final-champs-game-for-drg/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 16:32:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Parma Violents vs. Silvery Tayzers</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/26/parma-violents-vs-silvery-tayzers/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Saturday 6th September, FVRG's Parma Violents will take on DRG's Silvery Tayzers in Grangemouth Sports Complex. Doors open at 3:30pm, with the game starting at 4pm.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;The two teams first met in February 2012 in the Parma Violents first public game. Although the Silvery Tayzers took home the victory, the Parma Violents jumped at the chance for a rematch in November 2013, and again for the chance to play them again next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Tickets are available online from &lt;a title="Buy Tickets Online" href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/836544" target="_blank"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt; for £5 (+ admin fee), or £7 on the door. Under 14s go free with a paying adult.  Join FVRG's &lt;a title="FVRG Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1515534441994379/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt; for more information - and details on their ticket give-away competition!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/header.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3632" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/header.jpg" alt="Image courtesy of Fierce Valley Roller Girls" width="614" height="292"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Fierce Valley Roller Girls
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>parma violents</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/26/parma-violents-vs-silvery-tayzers/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 18:50:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hinnies Head for Scotland - Newcastle Roller Girls on their Month of Scottish Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/05/27/hinnies-head-for-scotland-newcastle-roller-girls-on-their-month-of-scottish-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Up in Scotland, we're no strangers to &lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.org.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;; they've played most of our established leagues over the last few years. This year, however, they've made slightly more of an impression, scheduling 4 bouts against Scottish leagues all within the month of May!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we approach the last of those dates, which sees Newcastle's B-team (The Whippin' Hinnies) take on &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie&lt;/a&gt;'s B Cannon Belles in Edinburgh on the 31st, we thought we'd have a chat to Newcastle's A and B teams about their experience so far, and some other exciting things that have happened in the last few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/theasaurus-wrecks.jpg"&gt;&lt;img id="i-3456" class="size-full wp-image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/theasaurus-wrecks.jpg?w=615" alt="Theasaurus Wrecks"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big event was always planned to be the one Newcastle hosted, a double-header at their usual venue, the Walker Activity Dome, featuring the Whippin' Hinnies taking on &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee&lt;/a&gt;'s Silvery Tayzers, followed by Newcastle A, the Canny Belters, facing off against &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; B, the Maiden Grrders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hinnies had previously taken on Dundee at the Into The Nitemare organised tournament, Battle of Britain, in November last year. Battling for the title, the Hinnies won with 60 points to Dundee's 51, in an extremely low scoring bout.
Theasaurus Wrecks, Hinnies Captain both for that bout and this year, remembers it fondly: “Battle of Britain was amazing. We were the underdogs, and I always think we perform really well as underdogs. ... we had a fantastic bench who knew the rules very well, and that worked incredibly well to our advantage. We also had a really strong team at the time with a lot of great crossovers [skaters who are on the 20 player pools for both the A and B teams, and thus eligible to roster for either].”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming into the Dundee bout this year, the team composition was a little different, the Hinnies roster having collected newer, less experienced skaters in the interim. In addition, Dundee's Tayzers had already demonstrated a very powerful team for the new year, with an impressive win over &lt;a href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/"&gt;Granite City&lt;/a&gt; at the end of March. So, it should not, perhaps, have been surprising that the first game of the double header went to Dundee Roller Girls, 163 to 131.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That the score was that close was a testament to the Hinnies' grit and determination, “In the first section of the 2nd half, the Hinnies were quite battered and feeling a bit down about it, but we kinda escalated away and picked up 70 pts in 15 minutes or so. So we sort of really brought it back in,” Thea told us, adding, “[it] shows what a psychological game roller derby is as well. Quite often if you start to think that you're losing it, then you kind of lose your psychological game and sort of give up. If you're willing to battle through to the end, then you can bring it back 'round to your favour.” While the Hinnies didn't quite manage that this time around, Dundee certainly felt the need to work hard, “They said to us afterwards that it was one of the best games they'd played in a long time, because they'd felt really challenged by it as well.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/gin-jamming-close-up.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3458" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/gin-jamming-close-up.jpg?w=614" alt="Gin and Sonic, on track." width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Gin and Sonic, on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the second bout of the day was not to happen, as a leak in the roof of the Walker Activity Dome began to let water on to the track during the inter-game break. With the referees ruling the track unsafe as long as water continued to fall, there was no choice but to call off the game. The Belters' Gin and Sonic was not alone in feeling extremely frustrated by the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So, you think when you play an &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;indoor &lt;/span&gt;sport that it will go ahead rain or shine... Our home venue is in many ways the perfect space for roller derby, and it’s not long since it was refurbished, so to say we were gutted when our GRD bout was rained off after a leaky roof issue is a MASSIVE understatement. We have so much love for GRD, they were really understanding (not to mention incredibly patient on the day while we waited to hear if the bout could go ahead safely...) and we’re hoping to reschedule very soon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently Newcastle are in negotiations with Newcastle City Council to resolve their venue issues – either by fixing the roof or getting a new venue – but they are determined not to let it affect their schedule at all. (Their next home fixture, seeing the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/486333931501291/?ref=5"&gt;Belters take on Birmingham Blitz Dames (in a double header with Tyne and Fear v The Inhuman League)&lt;/a&gt; is still on for the 7th of June, in the Centre for Sport, on the West Road, and has been rescheduled to a later time (but the same date) as a result.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Breaking News, added to this document after publication: The cancelled Glasgow Roller Derby bout has been rescheduled for June 28th, and will be hosted by &lt;em&gt;Glasgow&lt;/em&gt; at their usual venue, the ARC, as a replacement to the previously scheduled Glasgow A v Hot Wheels game (which is now cancelled).]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/theasurus-jamming.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3459" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/theasurus-jamming.jpg?w=614" alt="Theasaurus, pushing past the final blocker." width="614" height="614"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Theasaurus, pushing past Dundee's Milky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the loss of their venue is a setback, it didn't affect the next Scottish bout for the Hinnies, as they travelled up to Stirling to play &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' Parma Violents. This was a return bout, as Fierce Valley had travelled down to Newcastle in April 2013, and while a Newcastle win was expected, the Hinnies weren't going to relax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thea noted “the Hinnies, being a B-Team, being dynamic, is always changing, so we had a completely different lineup to the Dundee game. ... I'm one of the few people who's been with the Hinnies all this time, as the Team Captain, so yeah, we had a great opportunity with FVRG that we could try out lots of new players. So we had 1 brand new player, and 3 or 4 players who'd only played 1 or 2 games before, that was a really good learning curve for a lot of the newer people in the team.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And indeed, taking the opportunity to gain experience for the newer skaters still paid off, with the Hinnies pulling out a close (201 to 169) win – less than predicted, but nothing to sneeze at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we look ahead to the final bout in Newcastle's packed Scottish schedule (and it is exciting for multiple reasons), we should note that Scotland is not the &lt;span style="font-weight:bold;"&gt;only &lt;/span&gt;place that Newcastle Roller Girls have been involved with recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/gin-sonic-high-fives.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3460" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/gin-sonic-high-fives.jpg?w=614" alt="Gin and Sonic, taking high-fives post bout." width="614" height="345"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Gin and Sonic, taking high-fives post bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a start, three of the Canny Belters have made the roster for Team Wales Roller Derby, and will be playing for the Valleys in the Blood and Thunder World Cup in December. Gin and Sonic was one of the three, and was happy to talk to us about her choice of Wales over England:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was eligible to try out for both England and Wales. I tried out for England on a bit of a whim and really steeled my resolve to try out for Wales and gave it everything I have. I’m so glad I did as we have a really great team and they make me really proud of my Welsh side. It’s been brilliant sharing the try out process with [fellow Belters] Hit One Purl One and Marie Bayonet as we’ve been each other’s cheerleaders and it’s great having travel buddies for long trips to training! NRG have been so supportive of us and I know we’re going to learn lots from the experience and bring it all back to Newcastle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Belters have been getting skaters onto National teams, the Hinnies have gone the international route, playing their first European away bout against Eindhoven's Rockcity Rollers in January. Winning by a single point, the experience has whetted the Hinnies' appetite for Euroderby, in Thea's words: “That was one of the most Emotional games [she laughs] that I've ever played. It was really close.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While normally it would be the A team that gets into International derby first, in this case it was an existing connection that brought the Hinnies to the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It came about because we had a skater from &lt;a href="http://www.domcitydolls.com/"&gt;Dom City&lt;/a&gt; which is in Utrect. She came over and skated with NRG for three months, and we kind of just built up a really good friendship. So she said that since they were kind of an up and coming league, they would love to have us come over and do some coaching.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanting to get as much our of the trip as possible, the Hinnies found &lt;a href="http://rockcityrollers.nl/"&gt;Rockcity Rollers&lt;/a&gt;, ranked very closely to them, in Eindhoven, and managed to arrange a bout for the dates they were over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thea is still emotional about the event “we'd been travelling for ages, and it was a covered outdoor venue, and it just... it just was so close.
In final jam, we had our jammer, Torville and Scream, up and I saw her calling it off, and I didn't even know if she'd made the points, but she just was absolutely shattered, so she had to call it off and we were all there holding our breath just hoping that she'd picked up the points, and she had, so it was amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that was the first game that my parents had ever seen me play, so they said they kind of got how exciting roller derby could be from that game.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And more international bouts might be on the cards:
“I think it's all about funding and finances. I think I'd really like to play Amsterdam. One Love is really good as well, I would like to play a lot more teams of similar to us in the rankings, cause the games that we've had recently with Scottish teams have all been so challenging, and so exciting, and really pushing us to our limit. And that's really .. when you learn a lot about your team.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Canny Belters, meanwhile, are focussed on the American side of International derby, as Gin and Sonic revealed: “we’re dead proud of our Hinnies flying the NRG flag in Europe earlier this year and the Canny Belters have big aspirations for the next year! We became WFTDA apprentices earlier this year and we’re hoping to graduate as full members very soon. We’ll be focussing on the Northern Series which is a round robin of UKRDA/WFTDA games between Leeds Roller Dolls, Rainy City Roller Girls and Middlesbrough Milk Rollers. Hopefully our first round of WFTDA sanctioned bouts will put us in a good ranking position to go further afield in 2015. We’re itching to go a big international tournament like ARRG and Glasgow!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it's only an hour and a half from Newcastle to Edinburgh, the Belters will surely be discussing how to dominate America with Auld Reekie's Twisted Thistles, as both watch their B team sistren play this coming weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This looks like being a particularly close fought bout, with the rankings very close between the teams. Theasaurus Wrecks agrees, “
[I'm] Really excited. This is going to be the highlight of the year, I think. I think it's going to be the toughest challenge that the Hinnies have had; obviously ARRG are a really strong team, they've got a fantastic foundation, fantastic coaching from their A Team, they're in a really strong position on the table. So I'm really looking forward to us having that real focused challenge, and trying to achieve the best that we can for that. Having a battle - it's going to be very tough.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is not all, as Fierce Valley's junior derby league, the &lt;a href="http://www.fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs&lt;/a&gt;, are making a debut appearance at half-time, with a demonstration scrim. The Cubs are all big derby fans as Thea has already discovered, “I'm really excited to see that! They sent a really nice email to us, asking if we could do a photo with them at the end. I'm looking forward to that one :D”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe she'd sign an autograph or two as well (as the Cubs have been known to collect in the past)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;laughs&lt;/em&gt; Oh, I'm looking forward to it.
I feel like a minor celebrity(!)”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hinnies won't be the only celebrities present, either. Recently, Auld Reekie revealed that (known derby fan) Phill Jupitus will be co-announcing the bout, alongside long-standing ARRG announcer Stephen Tawking.
“I have noticed, that on QI, he's worn Kent Roller Girls t-shirts quite a bit, so I'm hoping that he'll wear ARRG and Newcastle shirts after this bout,” said Thea. We're pretty sure that Phill will end up getting freebie tshirts from all the leagues present after this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to see the Whippin Hinnies take on Auld Reekie Roller Girls on Saturday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;31 May, doors open at 2pm, for skateout at 2:30. Tickets can be bought at
&lt;a href="http://m.bpt.me/event/643612"&gt;http://m.bpt.me/event/643612
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Newcastle Roller Girls' Theasaurus Wrecks, Gin and Sonic, and PR Pretty Skate Machine.
All photographs from Newcastle Roller Girls - photographers please contact me for attribution!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was edited after publication to include details of the rescheduling of the GRD v NRG bout, and to improve cross-linking to league pages.
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>cannon belles</category><category>canny belters</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>interviews</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>nrg</category><category>parma violents</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>whippin hinnies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/05/27/hinnies-head-for-scotland-newcastle-roller-girls-on-their-month-of-scottish-derby/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 18:55:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee and Granite City - A Retrospective.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/03/23/dundee-and-granite-city-a-retrospective/</link><dc:creator>clinicallywasted</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the 29&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of March 2014 Granite City Roller Girls will face off against Dundee Roller Girls’ Silvery Tayzers. This will be the third time the teams have played each other in the space of 4 years – a period of time that has seen a change in the look, the feel and the integrity of our sport and as such, a change in The Fights and The Tayzers. Clinically Wasted and Milky offer an interesting retrospective into how their leagues have developed in this time, and their aspirations for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City and Dundee were the first younger leagues to spring up in Scotland after the teams on the central belt had become more established. As a result, the leagues formed a symbiotic relationship, assisting each other wherever they could.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;-Roller derby in Dundee has always been close with GCRG. They made the journey week after week to help us with every aspect of derby - from putting us through our minimum skills to helping us structure our league. It's fair to say that we wouldn't be the team we are without the help they gave us in the start, and their continuing support.&lt;/em&gt; (Milky)&lt;em&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;-The relationship between Aberdeen and Dundee goes back along time, before I had even put on a pair of skates myself. The maturing of both leagues has ran side by side, and for a while it almost felt like we had a conjoined league of Dundeen where we would attend each others training and in fact GCRG’s first ever closed door bout featured a few of the Dundee girls.&lt;/em&gt; -(Clinically Wasted)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/935888_10153084748090392_1488004219_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3344" alt="Courtesy of Zenspirations Photography" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/935888_10153084748090392_1488004219_n.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Courtesy of Zenspirations Photography&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Riding off the back of Highland Fling, Dundee hosted their first ever home game in November 2010. Their opponents - GCRG's Northern Fights.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;-A select few of us remember bouting GCRG  - our first home bout as Dundee Destroyers. We didn't have any tactics really, we were just ecstatic to be sharing the track with our big sister league. We didn't take ourselves or the bout too seriously. As newbies we were all still caught up in the novelty of bouting - I think the majority of our time was spent considering uniforms, chants and face paint. Needless to say, GCRG had the edge on the day and took home the win. &lt;/em&gt;(M)&lt;em&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;-We were flying high with all the good intentions and in our fishnets, high socks and pants we were ready to kick butt. Dundee so kindly got somebody to film the occasion so it can eternally be watched. The video always makes me smile, because I remember how much fun we had that game, playing against our sisters. &lt;/em&gt;(CW)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/gcrgvsrk1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3346 " alt="Courtesy of Andrew Leatherbarrow." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/gcrgvsrk1.jpg" width="614" height="407"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Courtesy of Andrew Leatherbarrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you haven't seen it already, here is a link to the video by Dylan Drummond: &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IPylGsXKJAE" target="_blank"&gt;Northern Fights vs Rippin Kittens 2010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time marched on. Outside of these two league's UKRDA were fighting for recognised sport status, London RollerGirls had joined WFTDA, people were taking knee down starts…remember them? Our sport evolved. And then these sister leagues played again, this time in Aberdeen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;-By our return bout the following year, we were now Dundee Roller Girls. Skating under a new name and colour and with new ambitions and values. The team was much more focused - we'd spent months studying our tactics, rules and honing our skills. The atmosphere for us was a little more tense this time as we were aiming for a win. The bout was hard fought from both sides, but again GCRG just pipped us in the final minutes. It was the best we'd skated as a team and the closest we'd come to victory. We finished proud of ourselves and incredibly proud of our friends in GCRG who had grown so much and who continued to teach and support us.&lt;/em&gt; (M)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- The game was hard, well fought, close and most of all fun. The level of derby and strategy had changed, but that buzz of seeing your friends play well made it all worth while. (CW)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/nfvsst.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3348" alt="Courtesy of Granite City Roller Girls" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/nfvsst.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Courtesy of Granite City Roller Girls&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fast forward to now, in 2014. DRG and GCRG have both had an incredible few seasons. Both teams are serious about progressing our sport and promoting the athleticism and empowerment they've worked so hard to achieve. Each team has changed vastly since they first lined up against each other in 2010; Dundee are in fact a completely different league with only 4 rostered skaters playing from the original line up, and Granite City only having 3 original Fights playing. Despite all the changes the two teams have experienced, they've continued to meet on track throughout the years, together and as opponents, still supporting our derby sisters and always proud of each teams acheivements.
&lt;/strong&gt;
-&lt;em&gt;We've remained each other's biggest fans. For me, I still frantically follow Twitter feeds for away scores as if it were for my own league. Regardless of the outcome of our upcoming bout, there's not a team in the world I'd rather share a track with, and not a team in the world I'd rather drag my battered body to share a pint with afterwards! &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;(&lt;/em&gt;M)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;em&gt;We always love catching up with the Dundee girls, and when we hear of their upcoming games it's as if we are skating with them! Tentatively waiting for scores on twitter and facebook! &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;People have come and gone and attitudes have changed but I know for certain one thing; at the final whistle, we will all hug, we will go grab a beer and we will all party like it’s 2010! (&lt;/em&gt;CW)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Girls play Dundee Roller Girls Saturday 29th of March 2014 at the Beach Leisure Centre in Aberdeen. Doors at 2.00pm for 3.00pm. Free Entry.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/blamming-season.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3347" alt="Courtesy of Granite City Roller Girls." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/03/blamming-season.jpg" width="614" height="868"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Courtesy of Granite City Roller Girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>aberdeen</category><category>articles</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>pictures</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>video</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/03/23/dundee-and-granite-city-a-retrospective/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 19:50:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Review 2014: Dundee Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/14/derby-review-2014-dundee-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another day, another league Review for 2013. Moving a little further North than the last few, Silvery Tayzers Captain Psychomilly was happy to talk about &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/img_0341-copy.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3158" alt="Dundee Roller Girls taking on Lothian Derby Dolls at Battle of Britain (Photo: Laura MacDonald)" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/img_0341-copy.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Dundee Roller Girls taking on Lothian Derby Dolls at Battle of Britain (Photo: Laura MacDonald)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compared to 2012, 2013 has been a slightly more mixed year for the Silvery Tayzers; a couple of losses at the start of the season against Rainy City and Glasgow's Maiden Grrders, followed by an improving streak (a narrow loss against Newcastle's Whippin' Hinnies, and an almost unbroken winning streak since). You said last year that Dundee were aiming higher for their competition in 2013; how did you work to raise your game and fight back over the year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team has worked really hard this year to push our skills and to keep our tactics current with the new rules set introduced. We saw more losses this year than last, but we really were playing with the big girls this year! Over the year I think we settled into our new roster and became more comfortable working together as a team. In the latter half of the year, we took our tactics back to basics and worked on developing our skills together, which definitely paid off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There's also been several changes to the roster over 2013, starting the season with several regulars missing or moved to other locations, and then Suffra-Jet moving to Glasgow to join GRD in the middle of the year, and Cult Friction moving to Edinburgh to join ARRG (and changing her skatename!), ending with Dr Carnage's last bout You've also picked up a bunch of new (or returning) skaters, who we saw in the last few bouts of the year. How are you adapting to the changing makeup of Dundee this year? Do you think this kind of cyclic mutability is good for the team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DRG have always had a pretty fluid roster as we're a university team - there's two universitys in Dundee, but it's a small city when it comes to finding a job, so a lot of our veteran skaters have moved for the sake of their careers. It's always hard to see someone you've trained with leave, but we're so, so proud of everyone who has moved on and become even more skilled.
This season, we've had some absolutely inspirational skaters move from newbies to Tayzers almost seamlessly. Having so many new skaters get on the Tayzer's roster has meant that as a team we've worked even harder to bond on track and to support each other. BoB and our home game against FVRG were the most 'together' I felt the team all year and it's a total pleasure to skate with so many committed new skaters. I think having new skaters move up to the Tayzers is good for us as a team - they bring fresh ideas and their enthusiasm and motivation is infectious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With all the preparation for the second ever (Women's) Roller Derby World Cup in 2014, several of Dundee's skaters have been trying out for national teams. Crazily InSanne got into Team Netherlands, and there's a few of your skaters who attended the Team Scotland first round tryouts. It's a great thing for Scottish derby to have skaters featured in potentially multiple national teams… do you see more of this and other international involvement in Dundee's future?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm so excited to see DRG represented at the World Cup. Sanne has gone from strength to strength this year and I think you'd struggle to find someone more committed to the sport. Her behind the scenes work to keep our team running as well as the time she spends honing her skills, fitness and knowledge is outstanding. It'd be a total dream to represent DRG as part of Team Scotland, but the competition is so, so high!
I'd love to see Dundee more involved in international derby, particularly now that there's more and more leagues in Europe visiting Scotland. Hopefully this year we can experience our first international bout!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking outside of Dundee, there's been a continuing growth in Scottish Roller Derby over 2013, with Bairn City Rollers, Lothian Derby Dolls and New Town Roller Girls all holding their first bouts this year. Dundee played two of those league already, and donated a skater or two to New Town's cherry popping bout roster. Now that Dundee is firmly in the upper-half of Scottish teams in terms of experience, do you feel you have a responsibility to newer teams? How does the increasing breadth of derby spread interact with how you see DRG placing itself in Scotland?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expansion of derby in Scotland this year has been amazing. We've found the newer leagues have provided a great opportunity for some of our newer skaters to get involved with scrimmages and bouts with skaters of their level. We've also seen skaters from a lot of the newer leagues in Scotland visiting us for our open scrimmages, which is a really good way of sharing learning and techniques, as well as getting to know the leagues better. In the beginning, DRG received so much training and advice from the larger leagues at the time, we realise how important it is to be supported by more experienced teams. We love to help out other leagues in any way we can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This was the first year Dundee Roller Girls played in a tournament, signing up to IntotheNitemare's Battle of Britain at the last minute due to cancellations. Despite Newcastle pipping you to the top spot, Dundee did very well - are you planning on more tournaments after this experience? How did the tournament compare to the usual single-bout context?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd love to take part in more tournaments. It's a fantastic way of bonding as a team and I think we kept the momentum going throughout the day. I couldn't have been any more proud to captain DRG at the tournament. We worked together so well as a team - particularly with 6 skaters new to the Tayzers. BoB was one of my favourite experiences in derby.
I think tournaments differ to single bouts in that it's over just as you get into your stride. Keeping the motivation and morale up through the day was really important to us - we had a team quiz, a poster of the roster made up of pugs and a gold-star system of goals to keep us all focused and smiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For much of this year, Dundee have continued their support of Co-ed Derby with the Dundee Co-ed Scrims continuing to be extremely popular for skaters across Scotland, and the Jakey Tayzers returning to play more co-ed derby on track. How's Dundee's relationship with Co-Ed developed over the year? Will the Jakey Tayzers remain a more exhibition team, or is there possibility of a more formal arrangement?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dundee have always supported co-ed derby and will continue to do so. This year we've moved to having monthly co-ed scrimmages. Co-ed is a great way to challenge ourselves, as skating with men means we have to skate that little bit smarter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the Jakey Tayzers...I think we already see ourselves as more than an exhibition team. Still unbeaten!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On a personal note, you’ve had a busy year: referreeing at as many bouts as you’ve played in, appearing on Team Steve for Scotland’s first Men v Women bout against the Jakey Bites, as well as regaining the captaincy of Dundee for the last bouts of the season (and trying out for Team Scotland(!)). How do you fit it all the derby in? Is there a temptation to choose one or other of refereeing or bouting?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been really lucky over the past few years, with ARRG and GRD giving me the opportunity to officiate loads of their bouts, including my first WFTDA Sanctioned bouts, which was a total honour. I also loved reffing the Men's European Roller Derby Champs. It was an incredible experience and I met loads of really inspirational officials. I'm also lucky to have such a supportive home league who've given me the opportunity to captain them again and help build the team and I've had the most fun bouting with them this year, especially at Battle of Britain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart is definitely still in bouting, I love DRG, though I do often get told that I'll have to choose either skating or officiating eventually. I find that a really strange idea and one that I think only female officials seem to be pushed into - I can think of a number of male skaters who skate high level derby who also officiate, but women in the same situation seem to be expected to choose one or the other. Until my schedule means I can't manage both, I'm happy sharing my time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, can you let us in on any of Dundee Roller Girls' plans for 2014?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm...well, we have a massive year planned for the team, but sadly I can't reveal too much just yet! It's safe to say we're working hard to expand and develop our wee team, so watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>derby review 2014</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>review</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/14/derby-review-2014-dundee-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 11:49:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls vs Fierce Valley Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/13/dundee-roller-girls-vs-fierce-valley-roller-girls-2/</link><dc:creator>louisepants</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a busy weekend for Dundee Roller Girls travel team, The Silvery Tayzers. Sunday 17th November sees them take on Fierce Valley Roller Girls travel team, The Parma Violents. It has been over a year and half since these 2 teams met, both having refreshed their rosters and experience since then. Come along to the DISC, Dundee to see who will win in what is sure to be a most exciting bout. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 1.30pm with the bout beginning at 2pm. Tickets are available in advance for the reduced price of £5 (£6 on the door on the day). There will be merchandise from both teams available and beautiful cakes baked by the skaters/refs/NSO's themselves! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is absolutely not to be missed. See you trackside for some Live Action Roller Derby!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/fvrg.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-3036" alt="Image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/fvrg.png?w=650"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>disc</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>parma violents</category><category>roller derby</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/13/dundee-roller-girls-vs-fierce-valley-roller-girls-2/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 16:02:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Double Header: GCRG Presents Cherry Poppers and Co-ed</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/05/31/double-header-gcrg-presents-cherry-poppers-and-co-ed/</link><dc:creator>zenrhe</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Girls are proud to announce an exciting day of Roller Derby to take place at the home of our sisters - Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We will be supplying you derby fans with two exciting bouts!
&lt;p&gt;Granite City’s co-ed team ‘&lt;strong&gt;Of Fights and Men&lt;/strong&gt;’ skate together for the first time against the much respected and fantastic ‘&lt;strong&gt;Jakey Tayzers&lt;/strong&gt;’.
So come along and watch the mixed teams of men and women battle it out on track!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s not all...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are so excited to also announce that the first bout of the day will be&lt;strong&gt; an all female ‘Cherry Popper’&lt;/strong&gt; to get you warmed up! Two teams made up from 7 different Scottish leagues, with some skaters making their debut. Ladies from Nasty Nessies Roller Girls, Dundee Roller Girls, Bairn City Rollers, Fierce Valley Roller Girls, Auld Reekie Roller Girls, Glasgow Roller Derby and of course Granite City. Watch, support and take note -
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; You will be witnessing some of Scotland’s best new talent on track.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="ngg-singlepic ngg-center" alt="Double Header 130713" src="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/wp-content/gallery/events/double_header_130713.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So get this date in to your diaries, it's not to be missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets on Sale soon! Online Advance: £5, Door: £6 Under 14s Free with paying adult
Doors open: 11.30am. First bout 12pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cakes, Merchandise and Local Vendors will also be there.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;Join our &lt;span class="fblink"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/232381250219767/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disc&lt;/strong&gt;
Dundee International Sports Centre, Mains Loan - Dundee
&lt;a href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/locations/disc-2/"&gt;Details&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date/Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date(s) - 13/07/2013
&lt;i&gt;11:30 am - 5:00 pm&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Disc" href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/locations/disc-2/"&gt;Disc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[googlemaps https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=s_q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=Disc+Dundee+International+Sports+Centre,+Mains+Loan,+Dundee&amp;amp;aq=3&amp;amp;oq=dundee+in&amp;amp;sll=53.800651,-4.064941&amp;amp;sspn=10.717687,28.54248&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hq=Disc+Dundee+International+Sports+Centre,&amp;amp;hnear=Mains+Loan,+Dundee,+Dundee+City,+United+Kingdom&amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;ll=56.476266,-2.958927&amp;amp;spn=0.008882,0.006295&amp;amp;output=embed&amp;amp;w=425&amp;amp;h=350]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>aberdeen</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>double header</category><category>dundee</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><category>jakey bites</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/05/31/double-header-gcrg-presents-cherry-poppers-and-co-ed/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 10:44:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls Vs Rainy City Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/02/21/dundee-roller-girls-vs-rainy-city-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/02/feb.png"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/02/feb.png" alt="feb" width="614" height="868" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2233"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of DRG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls'&lt;/a&gt; Silvery Taysers host their first bout of the year against &lt;a href="http://www.rcrg.co.uk/"&gt;Rainy City Roller Girls'&lt;/a&gt; Tender Hooligans at the DISC Sports Centre,Mains Loan,Dundee on Saturday the 23rd of February.
Entry is £6 on the door, or £5(plus booking fee) &lt;a href="http://drgvsrcrg.bpt.me/"&gt;in advance&lt;/a&gt;.Doors open at 13:30 and the bout will start at 14:00.
More details on the Facebook &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/192612720877110/"&gt;event page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As some will have noticed,this bout takes place on the same day as &lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/02/21/glasgow-roller-derby-vs-auld-reekie-roller-girls/"&gt;GRD play ARRG&lt;/a&gt; ,which presents quite a choice to make,whichever one you attend,it's bound to be a good bout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>drg</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/02/21/dundee-roller-girls-vs-rainy-city-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 21:50:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls Vs Dundee Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/10/24/auld-reekie-roller-girls-vs-dundee-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/10/cb-v-d.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/10/cb-v-d.jpg" alt="" title="cb v d" width="614" height="227" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1815"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of ARRG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' Cannon Belles take on &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' Silvery Taysers on Saturday the 27th of October,in the last ARRG home bout of the year.The action takes place at Meadowbank Sports Centre,Edinburgh,entry £7 on the day,advance tickets &lt;a href="http://arrgbellesvsdrg.eventbrite.com/#"&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt; at a cost of £5,plus booking fee.
&lt;strong&gt;Please note&lt;/strong&gt; that this bout starts slightly earlier than normal,doors open at 1pm.
More details at the Facebook &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/387004381371486/"&gt;event page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>cannon belles</category><category>drg</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/10/24/auld-reekie-roller-girls-vs-dundee-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 02:25:48 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>