<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about smarty pants)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/smarty-pants.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:34:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>UK Coaching: Rule 56, Webinars, and more!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/16/uk-coaching-rule-56-webinars-and-more/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of our short series on Coaches and Coaching initiatives in the UK (which started with a look at the Derby Form Check initiative), it would be remiss of us not to cover this next topic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-19248 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/rule56.jpg?w=600" alt="Rule56" width="300" height="300"&gt; Logo by Lee Moyer Designs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule 56&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the North-of-England based coaching business responsible for the UK's first Coaching Summit last year, have not been resting on their laurels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuing their association with Texas Rollergirls' Smarty Pants, (also of &lt;a href="http://www.getsmartycoaching.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get Smarty Coaching&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) Rule 56 have been spreading communication via their series of Coaching Webinars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hosted on &lt;a href="https://rule56.clickmeeting.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ClickMeeting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the Webinars make use of videoconferencing technology to allow coaches and skaters from around the world to attend a virtual seminar-like experience - with the advantage that collaboration is enhanced by shared whiteboards and the like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRD attended two of these hour-long sessions, where Smarty took the attendees (representing leagues from Illinois through Spain, and within the UK from Southhampton all the way up to Orkney) through an engaging look at a particular topic. In our cases, these were the "general purpose" introductory Coaching sessions - called Coaching 101 and 201 on the model of American University course numbering - which covered concepts such as "how to coach adults", "different styles of interaction when coaching", and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants were all engaged regularly by Smarty - and the advantage of the online format was that Smarty could always look back at the chat stream at a later moment, without breaking her flow, to pick up responses and questions. This was definitely handled well as a component of the seminar - whilst Smarty stuck to her slides generally, the responses from the attendees were woven into variation and extension on each topic as it was addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-19251" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/screen-shot-2017-05-01-at-19-45-51-a.png" alt="Screen Shot 2017-05-01 at 19.45.51-a" width="3080" height="1750"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explicitly collaborative "brainstorming" sessions were also well managed, with the shared whiteboard eliciting some genuinely free discussion, as you can see below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-19252" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/screen-shot-2017-05-01-at-20-23-43-a.png" alt="Screen Shot 2017-05-01 at 20.23.43-a" width="3070" height="1746"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spoke to Steph Howarth, of Tiger Bay Brawlers, who also participated in both sessions, who was equally positive. "Although I've been playing roller derby for a while, I'm relatively new to coaching. So it was great to have the chance to learn from Smarty's experience - she's clearly cares passionately about good coaching. I was particularly interested in learning how to structure practices and communicate my ideas better. Smarty's seminars really helped with this - I came away with a heap of new ideas."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remaining sessions are still available to book from the Rule 56 Facebook Events page: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/rule56/events/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/pg/rule56/events/&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;/strong&gt;or the ClickMeeting link earlier in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next session will be on "Indicators in Coaching", on the 5th June - there's still time to book this! After that, the 12th sees a session titled "Creating Team Success", and the 19th a seminar on dealing with "Questions at Practice".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other initiatives on the way from Rule 56, apart from actually coaching people, include a series of bootcamps - starting with one at the most northerly league in the UK, Orkney ViQueens! This is going to be an exciting one to attend, as Team England (and Rainy City)'s Missy Rascal is making her way up to lead the event as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can catch up with Rule 56 at their coaching venue in Manningham Sports Centre in Bradford, online at their webinar series, or meet Hydra (#56 herself) at &lt;a href="http://www.euroderbycon.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Euro Derby Con&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in mid-July, Barcelona!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coaching</category><category>rule56</category><category>smarty pants</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/16/uk-coaching-rule-56-webinars-and-more/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 20:50:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UK's first Coaching Summit: Derby Stance</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/03/uks-first-coaching-summit-derby-stance/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back when we&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/27/an-interview-with-ukrda-chair-tess-robinson/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; interviewed&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;UKRDA Internal Chair, Tess Robinson, one of the ongoing projects she mentioned was to support Coaching, via certifications and other events.
Well, in combination with Coaching outfit &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/derbystance-1/"&gt;Rule 56&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Female-Coaching-Network-900335303354547/"&gt;Female Coaching Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, part of this is coming to pass: in &lt;strong&gt;November 19th&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;20th&lt;/strong&gt;, the UK's first "Coaching Summit" will be held, in &lt;strong&gt;Leeds&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/536421803211316/"&gt;"Derby Stance"&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;will be a two day event, with sessions available to see on the website, and including aspects across the community, including Junior Derby Coaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A host of guest speakers and presenters will be there, of who more in a bit, but this is also seen as being an opportunity for Roller Derby Coaches across the UK to get together to influence the future of coaching, the certification process and any other developments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To support this, Rule 56 have managed to get coaches from some of the top teams in the UK: Auld Reekie's own Stef Skinner, London Rollergirls/Team England and Double Threat Skates' Kirsten "Kitty Decapitate" Lee, ex Team England/current Wizards of Aus/Southern Discomfort Ballistic Whistle (who we &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/10/an-interview-with-outgoing-team-england-coach-ballistic-whistle/"&gt;interviewed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; not long ago) and many more. But, more than this, they've also managed to get Texas Rollergirls' own Smarty Pants (Nadia Kean) to come across to provide her own sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smarty is a very experienced coach, both in Roller Derby and other sports; she runs Get Smarty Coaching to provide coaching services across the USA and worldwide, as well as skating for Texas. She's also working on a book on coaching!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were lucky enough to get the chance to talk to her about her experience in coaching, roller derby and a lot of other topics. You can hear the interview, in a first for us at the blog, here (forgive the initial uming from yours truly, this is a new thing for us):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[soundcloud url="https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/285835975" params="auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true" width="100%" height="450" iframe="true" /]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you're inspired by that, get booking your tickets for Derby Stance, if you haven't already!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>annoucements</category><category>coaches</category><category>interviews</category><category>rule56</category><category>smarty pants</category><category>texas rollergirls</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/03/uks-first-coaching-summit-derby-stance/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 19:07:51 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>