<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about talk derby to me)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/talk-derby-to-me.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 09:46:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The First SRDB Awards - Nominations Open!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/srdbawards-nom-2019/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;End of Year awards are a tradition in a lot of communities, and they're one way to highlight and recognise contribution within that community. For the last several years, the Talk Derby To Me podcast ran them for Roller Derby. With TDTM in a quiescent state currently, we reached out to the podcast's founder to get permission to take on the mantle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you might guess from this post existing, he agreed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this article will introduce the ground-rules for the first ever &lt;strong&gt;SRDB Awards&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="srdb-awards-2019"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SRDB AWARDS 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt='The SRDB Award Logo: the Scottish Roller Derby Blog Logo (concentric circles, outer circle containing words "Scottish Roller Derby" all-capitals, separated by five-pointed stars, and an inner ring of stars just outside the boundary of the inner circle; inner circle containing a modification of the "lion of scotland", a heraldic lion, facing right, rampant, with a jammer cover on its head), but with a gold/bronze colour scheme applied.' src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/SRDB-Award.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SRDB Awards, as with the TDTM Awards before them, are entirely delivered by the &lt;strong&gt;community&lt;/strong&gt;, and provide a chance to recognise contributions to Roller Derby in a range of categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anyone can nominate&lt;/strong&gt; any number of candidates for each and any of our categories: you must, however, provide a suitable reason for why they should win. This reason will be shown to voters when voting, so try to make it convincing! You can nominate for any reason, as long as you explain it. You may nominate in any language, and we will translate [but we may need to talk to you to confirm - please specify your contact details if you want to be contacted].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Even being nominated will give your nominee visibility, so please do nominate even if you are worried about them &lt;em&gt;winning&lt;/em&gt; - winning isn't everything, and being nominated is really the core thing here.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(SRDB reserves the right to remove obviously trolling nominations, but we promise to have a light touch here; we will also remove or recategorise nominations which don't match their category.) SRDB will &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; nominate anyone for any categories themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/srdbawards-nom-2019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>awards</category><category>end of year</category><category>nominations</category><category>scottish roller derby blog</category><category>talk derby to me</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/srdbawards-nom-2019/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 09:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>TDTM Awards: The NSOs</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/16/tdtm-awards-the-nsos/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you're probably aware, the second ever&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/talkderby/"&gt; Talk Derby To Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Listener Awards are currently up for votes, with an extended set of categories since last time.
Several of those categories were added to allow nominations for roles which are frequently under-represented, and less visible, than those of Skaters - Referees, NSOs, Announcers and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it became somewhat clear that one of the issues with NSO awards is that... well, NSOs are less visible (some of them would argue that if they're visible, they're doing it wrong), and less public than Skaters, and people don't really know what the nominees were have been doing. And many of them have been doing a huge amount, and some very big things - as well as being necessary for the running of every game (and even more important for tournaments, where there's geometrically increasing amounts of organisation needed), they're also in the background keeping stats and data safe and up to date, both locally and in shared community resources like Flat Track Stats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in the spirit of the Award itself, we've given each Nominee for the NSO Award a small (too small!) amount of space to say something about what they did this year... which we've topped with a brief description of their association and history. NSOs were also given the opportunity to provide a photo - if they didn't, we've applied the universal NSO placeholder!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSOs are covered in the order they appear in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdXySN7hUTbQGCepCzq5ifeS5qK9dglaRXZxchv0kymMGuzUg/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1"&gt;TDTM Awards Voting form, here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. We've added their "actual" NSO name after their name on the form, if it differs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Blind Io&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-12729" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/blindio.png?w=300" alt="blindio" width="300" height="194"&gt; Photo: John Hesse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Blind Io is an independent NSO in the Edinburgh area. He's been NSOing for 3 years. His favourite event to NSO this year was The European Smackdown.

"I became an Independent NSO at the start of this year, helped manage 2 WFTDA Recognised Tournaments as a GTO, visited 5 countries and NSOed my first ever WFTDA D1 &amp;amp; Top-10 games!"&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Bomb Weasley&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-12699" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/bombweasely.jpg" alt="bombweasely" width="300" height="720"&gt; -&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bomb Weasley is an independent NSO based in Wales. She's been an NSO for 2 years now, and her favourite event to NSO was the Louisey Rider Cup, as "I was the PBM and had two unicorn PBTs. AND GLITTER. "

"This year I have been DHNSO for BCW-T4W, HNSO for Wales Men and have transferred to a new league. I have also been to Mons for my first tournament abroad, attended a WFTDA clinic and co-THNOsed for the first time. I have officiated across the UK and Ireland, making new friends, catching up with old ones and sampling many many many gins on the way."&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Pettichoke&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-12706" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/petti.png?w=300" alt="petti" width="300" height="200"&gt; Petti is in the left hand side here...click here for closeup Photo: Ken LeBleu ("JammerTime")&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Petti is affiliated with Eastbourne Roller Derby, and has been NSOing for 5 and a half years. Her favourite event to NSO this year was the Japan Open, in Okinawa, as "sorry to break loyalty to Eastbourne Extreme, but crew heading the first ever tournament in Asia was pretty frickin special!"

"I became the first level 3 WFTDA certified NSO in Europe from a non-WFTDA league. NSOd to Japan and back, as well as being mentor to many. If you haven’t seen the work that I do…then I’m doing it right. NSOs are the glue that make things awesome :-)"&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Sara Tonin&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-12758" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/saratonin.jpg?w=300" alt="saratonin" width="300" height="300"&gt; Photo: Shirlaine Forrest&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sara Tonin is an independent NSO based in the Manchester area. She's been an NSO for 2 years, and her favourite event to NSO this year was the Men's Roller Derby World Cup in Calgary.

"I was HNSO with Manchester Roller Derby until recently, I've been THNSO of the men's side of British Championships, and I was lucky enough to LT at MRDWC in Calgary, as well as travel to Rollercon. I've had a busy year, nearly hitting the 200 game mark!"&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Dr Stevel&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-12751" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/stevel.jpg?w=300" alt="stevel" width="300" height="300"&gt; Photo : John Hesse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dr Stëvël is NSO for Southern Discomfort Roller Derby, and has been NSOing for 5 years. His favourite event to NSO this year was The European Smackdown.

"Being heckled by close to a thousand people has to be the highlight... It was great to see the crowds having so much fun. I have been mainly Jam Timing or hiding from Team Heckle"&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Disorder Lee&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-12762 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/creative-tail-animal-flamingo-svg.png?w=300" alt="creative-tail-animal-flamingo-svg" width="200" height="200"&gt; -&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DisorderLee is affiliated with London Rockin' Rollers, where she also skates. She's been NSOing for almost 5 years now. Her favourite event to NSO this year was the Men's Roller Derby World Cup in Calgary.

"I've NSO'ed a lot of close door/challenge team games, NSO'ed some games in Tier 2 South British Champs, as many of the Tier 1 Men's British Champs as I could go to (dates sometimes overlap as I also skate), including my first open door game as HNSO, most of our B teams home games and the Men's World Cup in Calgary, CA."&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Iain Wilson [Dor-Iain Grey]&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-12734" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/doriaingrey.png?w=300" alt="doriaingrey" width="300" height="200"&gt; Photo: Graeme Willetts&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dor-Iain NSOs for Bath Roller Derby Girls, where he has been for 2 years. His favourite event to NSO this year was The Louisey Rider Cup.

"This year I was a Divisional HNSO for British Championships, and a Crew Head for the promotion playoffs. I officiated at The European Smackdown in Sweden, the first WFTDA recognised tournament outside of America, as well as Eastbourne Extreme, Men's European Cup, Road to TBC and many more, covering 70+ games in total."&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Bath Vader&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-12762 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/creative-tail-animal-flamingo-svg.png?w=300" alt="creative-tail-animal-flamingo-svg" width="200" height="200"&gt; -&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bath Vader also NSOs with Bath Roller Derby Girls, where they've been for 14 months. Their favourite event to NSO was the Suomi Cup Final.

"NSOd Champs Tier 3 South, SWUK, BRDG closed door games, playoffs, hyper unicorn tourney, Road to TBC, Soumi Cup final, Oslo, London Brawling, Tattoo Freeze. Lots still to learn which is why it's great when I get to work with really seasoned NSOs."&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;V-ictoria Tickle [Miss Tickle]&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-12773" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/misstickle.jpg?w=300" alt="misstickle" width="300" height="300"&gt; -&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Miss Tickle NSOs for Glasgow Men's Roller Derby, as of only a month ago - she was previously independent. She's been NSOing for 1 year, after stepping down from skating. Her favourite event to NSO this year was 5th Blocker's 5th Birthday Party, as "it was my first time NSOing a Junior game!".

"I've travelled the length and breadth of the UK for scrims, bouts &amp;amp; tournaments. I’ve learnt to be Jam Timer as well as a penalty box official and can now confidently be PBM! When all NSO roles were filled, I’ve been LUM, Bench as well as photographed many a game!"&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Krystal Vice&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-12826" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/kv.jpg?w=169" alt="kv" width="169" height="300"&gt; -&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Krystal Vice Head NSOs for Seaside Sirens Roller Girls and Southern Discomfort, as well as &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; Team Englands. She's been an NSO for 5 years. Her favourite event to NSO this year was The European Smackdown, as "Crew Head - terrifying but awesome (got to CH with Acid!)"

"HNSO for two leagues and two national teams, THed Sevens x 2, MEC and Suomi Cup. Went to RollerCon and MRDWC, West Track Story, Mayday, Sci Fight, London/Gotham, ERDT, HUUEB, DDT, Road to TBC, among other things! :)"&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Peggy Kreuger&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-12877" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/peggy.jpg?w=298" alt="peggy" width="298" height="300"&gt; -&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Peggy Kreuger is Head NSO for Auld Reekie Roller Girls, and has been NSOing for about 3 and a half years (in Edinburgh and Aberdeen). Her favourite event to NSO was the WFTDA Clinic, although she also includes "reaching 100 games and the charity games where everyone dressed to a theme".

"Increasing my knowledge as a NSO through Head NSOing and helping the training of others. I've head NSO'd single games, double headers, a Sur5al and even a small tournament [ARRGmageddon]! This year has taught me a lot and NSOing will only teach me more in time. "&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Resting Bexface&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-12762 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/creative-tail-animal-flamingo-svg.png?w=200" alt="creative-tail-animal-flamingo-svg" width="200" height="200"&gt; -&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Resting Bexface NSOs for Newcastle Roller Girls and Tyne &amp;amp; Fear Roller Derby, where she's been for 18 months. Her favourite event to NSO was Newcastle's first C Team game.

"Mostly developing my skills and learning lots. Started the year with 6 months experience, half way through the year was HNSO for two big leagues. Lots of learning. Lucky to have worked with some amazing people who have helped me so much."&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Emily of the State&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-12714" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/emilyotstate.png?w=300" alt="emilyotstate" width="300" height="399"&gt; -&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Emily of the State NSOs for Rainy City Roller Derby, where she's been for 3.5 years. Her favourite event to NSO this year was SKOD: A Skate Odyssey, for the "great officials, great derby, great graphics!"

"I have done loads of travelling to various tournaments including The European Smackdown, The Big O, A Skate Odyssey, Skates of Glory, MEC and The Suomi Cup. As well NSOing many other games in and around the UK for British Champs. (As well as dipping my toe in the ref lane back at the Thunderdome!)"&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Linz &amp;amp; Needles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-12890" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/linzheadshot.png?w=300" alt="linzheadshot" width="300" height="300"&gt; -&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Linz &amp;amp; Needles is affiliated with Oxford Roller Derby and Southern Discomfort Roller Derby, and has been NSOing for 3 and a half years. Her favourite event to NSO this year was the Men's European Cup.

"I officiated at 7 tournaments (including my first NSOing trips outside the UK, to Canada for MRDWC and Belgium for ERDT). I worked games from multiple tiers of British Champs, and was a divisional Head NSO. I became MRDA Recognised! I spent about 36 hours in the penalty box…"&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Yoshi [DominAsian]&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-12673" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/yoshi.jpg?w=300" alt="yoshi" width="300" height="300"&gt; Photo: John Hesse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yoshi NSOs for Suffolk Roller Derby, and is one of the longest serving NSOs up for an award, having been NSOing for 7 years! His favourite event to NSO this year was Eastbourne Extreme.

"Stepped in as a Divisional Head NSO for Brit Champs in Tier 3 Mens. Jam timed everywhere. Popped my Mainland Europe officiating cherry at ERDT 2016. Teamed with Funk as Puck to run a couple officiating boot camps. NSO’d Road to TBC. WON SO MANY AFTERPARTIES!"&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Halo Jones&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;

&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-12722" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/halojones.png?w=200" alt="halojones" width="200" height="300"&gt; Photo: Eloise Rees&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Halo Jones is affiliated with Oxford Wheels of Gory, and has been NSOing for more than 3 years. Her favourite event to NSO was Essex Sevens, as "every year it gets better!".

"All the Sevens format games it feels! Handling the Men’s Southern Sevens Cup was amazing-I got to work with great officials. That experience was reflected throughout my year, working with shiny new officials and brilliant veterans. 2016 was a lot of teaching others, watching others and importantly, learning from others!"&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flamingo image licenced CC:BY by&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.creativetail.com/licensing/"&gt; Creative Tail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Blind Io for making contact with the other NSOs and generally supporting this project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>listener awards</category><category>nso</category><category>talk derby to me</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/16/tdtm-awards-the-nsos/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 14:07:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>First time tournament announcing, or: How Chasing Katy survived MEC 2o16</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/17/first-time-tournament-announcing-or-how-chasing-katy-survived-mec-2o16/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Last weekend's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MensEuropeanCup/"&gt;Men's European Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (2016) in Newcastle was a great success, not least because of the high quality stream, and the commentary provided. One of the MEC2016 announcers was Chasing Katy, co-host of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://tdtmpodcast.wordpress.com"&gt;Talk Derby To Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; podcast, and independent announcer; she's graciously written up her experience for the blog here. (Comments in [ ] are editorial)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;To be honest, I hadn't initially applied to announce at this year's Men's European Cup. Not because I didn't want to do it, but because I hadn't thought I was ready for that big an event. But after some cajoling (thanks, Mags Payne!) and some reassurance (thanks [fellow Talk Derby To Me Podcast Hosts] sMACk and King), I submitted my application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Part of the application was an announcer CV, something I'd never done before. It was interesting to go back throughout my time in roller derby and try and remember all the games I'd announced (the first being waaaaay back in September 2011 when the Fair City Rollers took on the Wakey Wheeled Cats). Doing that slightly reassured me that I'd been doing it long enough that I should know what I'm doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;A couple of weeks later I got the news...I was on the crew and we were given access to the super-secret MEC 2016 Announcers' Facebook group, where I got to see who I would be announcing with. There were some familiar names and faces, but the great thing was I'd only announced with two people before (Archie [Bairn City Rollers' man of many names] and sMACk) so it was going to be a good way to meet other announcers and learn some new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I know that I'm portraying an image of me being cool, calm and collected about this whole process. That's intentional, because I can't spell the noise my brain was making the entire time. It was something between a whimper, a scream and a panic attack. It involves lots of vowels, that much&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Then, about a week before the tournament, we got the schedule for day 1 and I learned I would be doing feed announcing as well as in house. I'd never done feed prior to MEC, but made a point of listening to the WFTDA Champs announcers the weekend before. I was also down to do house announcing for Tyne and Fear (the hosts) against Panam Squad with Helliverance, who I'd known for years but never announced with. Then, for the final game of the day, I was back on feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;As MEC got closer, my nerve-citement increased and on Friday, myself, sMACk, [Granite City's] Krusty and [Auld Reekie's Terrifying] Tink headed to Newcastle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We had to be at the Walker Activity Dome for 7.30am on Saturday, so I was extremely bleary-eyed and in need of coffee when I met Sven and Malice, our THAs for the weekend. We were shown the workings of the feed, where everything was (loos, coffee, all the essentials) and given the chance to get sorted. I had prepped with some notes on the teams, so I read over the ones I needed for my first call, got a coffee and spoke to some other very tired people. Coffee, I soon realised, is the elixir of life for people involved in roller derby tournaments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Thankfully, my first time on the feed (10am on Saturday for De Ronnys vs the Mad Riders) was with sMACk. Given the many hours we have spent talking on microphones to each other, that definitely made it a bit less scary (I tried to ignore the fact that, unlike the Talk Derby To Me podcasts, this was live and we were actually sitting in the same place) and I&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;enjoyed it. Beforehand, a lot of seasoned announcers were telling me that they preferred feed to house and after doing that game, I can see why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;For me, the main difference was that I could say more. When you do in-house announcing, there's a risk that the teams will hear something that could give them an advantage in the game (for example, the cardinal rule, never announce a jammer getting released from the penalty box or approaching the back of the pack) but that risk is reduced on feed. I could happily chat about why a team was doing certain things tactically or how I feel they could make changes to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Another thing I also found fun was interacting with people watching the feed. There were tweets and YouTube comments coming in throughout and it was cool to get tidbits of information about the teams or just a “good job, guys”. I did not agree with King Crazy and StatMan that sMACk and I needed subtitles, however. (Haggis, haggis, Irn Bru to you too!!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The house game went well, but as it was the home team in action, the crowd got loud and I soon began to realise that I needed to take care of my voice. This wasn't like a single or double header, after which I could go home and rest. I had a whole other day to get through and I wanted to be able to speak by the end of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The rest of the day went well. I ate a Hippo burger and got to watch some fantastic roller derby, and speak to a whole bunch of people I hadn't met before or hadn't seen in ages. I even managed to squeeze in a bit of dancing! But it was about 10pm before we got back to the hotel and I was ready to just chill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The next morning we didn't need to be at the venue until 8.30 – a long lie going by the previous day! First up, I got to do house announcing with the fantastic Archie, whose enthusiasm and showmanship really got me in the mood for another day of announcing, then I was back on feed later with Roller Polar Bear and finally I closed out my day house announcing the third place game between Lincolnshire Rollin' Thunder and South Wales Silures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I've got to admit, by the end of my last call, I was ready to not speak again for a while and I really wanted to go home to my own bed. Six amazing games of roller derby, out of a total of 13 played over the weekend, that I got to blether on about. The Hall's Soothers and hot water with lemon have been flowing ever since (and I even managed to pick up a bit of lurgy at some point over the weekend).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;But all in all, it was a fantastic experience, during which I learned a lot, met some great people, saw the best of European Men's Roller Derby and got the chance to grow as an announcer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Hopefully, they will have me back next year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>men's european cup</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>talk derby to me</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/17/first-time-tournament-announcing-or-how-chasing-katy-survived-mec-2o16/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 10:27:18 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>