<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about team wrdj)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/team-wrdj.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:41:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Tomodachi Cup: Team Women's Roller Derby Japan [トモダチダービートーナメント:チームWRDJ]</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/09/the-tomodachi-cup-team-womens-roller-derby-japan-tomodachidabitonamentochi/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; approaches, we're interviewing another team - the last team in the non-Sanctioned tier of the tournament. This article will be in both Japanese and English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14030 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/teamwrdj-sm.jpg" alt="teamwrdj-sm" width="250" height="154"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/WRDJapan/"&gt;Women's Roller Derby Japan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Team WRDJ] is a mixed subscription team, which was open to anyone applying to join. It was organised by Women's Roller Derby Japan, the body which organises the Japanese Women's National Team. チームウィメンズローラーダービージャパン[チームWRDJは]への参加を適用する誰にでも開かれていた混成チーム、です。 これは、日本女子代表チームを組織しているウィメンズローラーダービージャパンが主催したものです。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its roster consists of:
名簿には次のものが含まれます：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From (Tokyo Roller Girls Home Team): Neon Roller Monsters (Yokohama)
[横浜のローラーダービーチーム から]
・Thunder BELL #950
・Where's The Fire #75
・Inga Knee'her #235
・Rice Rocket #278
・Savage Dragon #5360
・Lisa Slamtimes #413
From Tokyo Three Rollers (Tokyo)
[東京のローラーダービー・チーム Tokyo3Rollersから]
・Red Eye #88
From Kokeshi Roller Dolls (Okinawa)
[沖縄のコケシローラードルスから]
・Loveless #0
・Lil N. Gin #9
・Lemmy Killmisstress #1975
・PurpleHaze #21
・Atomic Jenny #88
From Devil Dog Derby Dames (Okinawa)
[沖縄のデヴィゥドグダービダメスから]
・Madam Vice #7
・Christine Westbrook
・Mermaid Mayhem #20
From Echo City Knockouts (Hawaii)
[ハワイのエコシチノクアウツから]
・Bandit Angel #18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Captain Thunder BELL was good enough to answer questions for us.　チームキャプテンThunder BELLが私たちの質問に答えて&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="popup" title="くれる - to give"&gt;くれた。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did the idea for Team WRDJ occur? (チームWRDJのアイデアはどうやって起こったのですか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tomodachi Tournament originally had only a method to participate with full teams, and we felt this was a little sad. We looked for a good way to allow the opportunity for domestic skaters who can't join as their team, or players from foreign countries who are visiting without their team, to participate. We hit on the idea of making Team WRDJ. We hope that this team will help enjoyment of the tournament.
当初トモダチトーナメントにはチーム単位で参加する方法しかなく、それはとても限定的だと少し残念に思いました。トーナメントに参加しないチームの国内選手や海外から来日する選手達など、もっと沢山の人達に日本でダービーをプレイできる機会を作りたくて、Team WRDJを作るアイディアを思いつきました。このチームがより多くの人が友達トーナメントを楽しむ為に役に立つ事を願ってます。
&lt;strong&gt;The Women's Roller Derby Japan Team contains a lot of skaters from Neon Roller Monsters - Tokyo Roller Girls' "Japanese" team. With the experience you have playing the Sushi Rollers already, do you think this will be an advantage in the tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(Team WRDJには、東京ローラーガールズの「日本人」チームであるネオンローラーモンスターのスケーターがたくさん含まれています。すでに寿司ローラーを経験している経験があれば、これがトーナメントで有利になると思いますか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team WRDJ is a mixed team, so I think it is stronger than Neon Roller Monsters. If there is something to be advantageous, if we use Japanese language during the game, they can't understand our strategy...But Sushi Rollers is smart and very strong team, so it might not matter!
Team WRDJはミックスチームなので、ネオンローラーモンスターズよりも強いと思います。有利になる事があるとしたら、私達が日本語を使用すれば作戦が彼らにバレない事です。しかしスシローラーズはとても強いチームなので、そんな事は関係ないかもしれません…笑
&lt;strong&gt;With skaters from Honshu, Okinawa and Hawai'i, how have Team WRDJ been practising together before the Tomodachi Tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(本州、沖縄、ハワイの選手と一緒に、チームWRDJはTomodachiトーナメントの前にどのように練習していましたか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can not practice together as Team WRDJ. We will think about our strategy.
チームWRDJとして皆んなで一緒に練習する事出来ません。これから作戦を考えます。
&lt;strong&gt;Outside of your own division, there's a lot of other Roller Derby to watch at the tournament: which teams, or games, are you most looking forward to seeing?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(自身の部門外には、トーナメントで観戦できる多くのローラーダービーがあります。どのチームや試合が最も楽しみですか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I'm looking forward to the Pan-Asian match. I'm very interested in how Asian players will play derby. WRDJ would like Roller Derby to spread further across Asia in the future.
Pan-Asianの試合が最も楽しみです。
アジアの選手達がどんなプレイをするのかとても興味があります。これからもっとアジア全域にローラーダービーが広がっていってほしいです。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After the Tournament, will Team WRDJ continue in other events? &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(トーナメント終了後、WRDJチームは他のイベントを続行しますか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is undecided right now, but we would like to do it again if we have good opportunities.
今のところ未定ですが、良い機会があればまたやりたいです。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Women's Roller Derby Japan also has a mandate to manage the National Japanese team. Looking towards 2018's Roller Derby World Cup, how is this going, what are your plans?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(ウィメンズローラーダービージャパンには、日本人のチームを統括する権限もあります。 2018年のローラーダービーワールドカップを目指していかがですか、予定はどんな感じですか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started new Team Japan for World Cup 2018. Twenty-five skaters from all over the world have applied for this time. Last time, our major goal was [just] participation in the World Cup, but this time, our new major goal is getting &lt;em&gt;victories&lt;/em&gt; at the World Cup! Team practice has started in Japan. We need figure out how we work together with overseas skaters, but we are sure that new Team Japan will be stronger than last time. Please expect the Team Japan 2018!!
私達は2018年の為のチームジャパンを結成しました。今回は世界中から25人の選手達が応募をしてきました。前回はワールドカップに出場する事が私達の大きな目標でしたが、今回は勝つ事を大きな目標において、チーム作りをすると決めています。日本国内ではチーム練習が始まりました。パワーアップしたチームジャパンを是非期待していて下さい。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tomodachi Derby Tournament will be held between the 24th and 26th of March, in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/%E6%B2%96%E7%B8%84%E7%9C%8C%E7%B7%8F%E5%90%88%E9%81%8B%E5%8B%95%E5%85%AC%E5%9C%92+%E4%BD%93%E8%82%B2%E9%A4%A8/@26.3104722,127.8208903,18.72z/data=!4m8!1m2!2m1!1sOkinawa+Comprehensive+Park!3m4!1s0x0:0xd83f29f95619b3f0!8m2!3d26.3106488!4d127.8200047"&gt;Okinawa Comprehensive Sports Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Okinawa.トモダチダービートーナメントは３月２４日から３月２６日まで&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/%E6%B2%96%E7%B8%84%E7%9C%8C%E7%B7%8F%E5%90%88%E9%81%8B%E5%8B%95%E5%85%AC%E5%9C%92+%E4%BD%93%E8%82%B2%E9%A4%A8/@26.3104722,127.8208903,18.72z/data=!4m8!1m2!2m1!1sOkinawa+Comprehensive+Park!3m4!1s0x0:0xd83f29f95619b3f0!8m2!3d26.3106488!4d127.8200047"&gt;沖縄県総合運動公園 体育館&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;で開催されます。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>team wrdj</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>women's roller derby japan</category><category>日本語</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/09/the-tomodachi-cup-team-womens-roller-derby-japan-tomodachidabitonamentochi/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 12:03:43 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>