<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about team sweden)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/team-sweden.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 11:56:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Road to TBC: Lessons from ERDT and the last World Cup!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Blood &amp;amp; Thunder still have yet to formally announce the location and date for the 2017 Women's Roller Derby World Cup, by the end of November we will have already seen two of the "lead up" events for next year's tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is the the already complete &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://euroderbytournament.eu/"&gt;European Roller Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, held in Mons, Belgium. The second will be Team Wales Roller Derby's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1224163900948144/"&gt;"The Road To TBC"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, scheduled for the &lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;27th&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;November&lt;/strong&gt; 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the two tournaments, we will get a good look at most of Europe's competitors in the Third World Cup, albeit at an early stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attending the European Roller Derby Tournament were &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Denmark&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Switzerland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Portugal&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Italy&lt;/strong&gt; and new team &lt;strong&gt;Iceland&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Road To TBC will bring you &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt; again, with the addition of &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Sweden&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;West Indies&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; all showing their national team debuts at the event!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what can we predict, if anything, about The Road to TBC from what has come &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we can look at ERDT. Whilst only 50% of the lineup overlaps between ERDT and TRtT, we can judge some expectations about absolute strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the now-traditional Bayesian inferred strength charts from ERDT, with the top four teams also singled out in separate highlights [as usual, these charts are relative to the winner - in this case, France - and so they are not directly represented]. We've marked vertical lines to show the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/"&gt;performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (also relative to France) in the Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Women's World Cup 2014, for those teams who attended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="8997,9001,8998,8999,9000" type="slideshow" link="file"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is pretty clear, whilst Spain is just about separate from the top three, although closely competitive with Wales and Belgium; the distributions for Belgium and Wales are almost indistinguishable. While France was indisputably the strongest team at ERDT, it's reasonable to suggest that the tournament also showed that Belgium and Wales are almost identical in strength. (Wales was the victim of one of the classic problems with single elimination tournaments, being relegated to the consolation brackets by an early encounter with the eventual Champions, and achieved Third as their highest possible relegation place.)
It's also possible to see that, assuming France is still relatively similar in strength, that Wales, Spain and Portugal have all noticeably improved in strength from 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/2/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over the page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we'll talk about the teams at The Road to TBC in more detail...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we can expect the hosts to be strong competitors in November... but what about their challengers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9075" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14448951_1432178393465450_4812609206374398804_n.jpg?w=600" alt="14448951_1432178393465450_4812609206374398804_n" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/"&gt;back at the last World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Sweden&lt;/em&gt; was one of the strongest teams in the tournament, reflecting the strength of Scandinavian Roller Derby even back then. Since then, Swedish roller derby has gone from strength to strength, with both Stockholm Roller Derby and Crime City Rollers in WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs this year!
A quick count of their recently published training team for 2016/17 [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamswedenrollerderby/photos/a.517256094957689.143365.224501220899846/1432139023469387/?type=1&amp;amp;theater"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] suggests that at least &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt; of the skaters from 2014 are returning as possible rosters (as several skaters were recorded under their legal names for the 2014 roster, and under their skatenames here, it's a little tricky to be 100% certain).
We expect, on the balance of this, and the general health of Swedish derby, for Sweden to be a contender for the top spot at The Road to TBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3901" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamfrance.png?w=570" alt="TeamFrance" width="285" height="300"&gt; Team France logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team France&lt;/em&gt; were a top 8 team for us in 2014 (although they narrowly missed the actual final 8 at the tournament itself. We see at least 12 skaters from 2014 in the 2016 roster so far, which is about an average rate of returns in Europe. Almost 50% of the roster is drawn from Paris and Toulouse (with the rest mostly from the other strong French leagues), and both teams have experienced strong growth since 2014. Paris Rollergirls, in particular, have rocketed up the WFTDA rankings in the last two years, currently at #77 in the World.
We would consider France to be one of our three contenders for 2nd place, with chance at taking on Sweden for the top spot too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Belgium&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Wales&lt;/em&gt;, as we mentioned above, statistically drew at ERDT. At the 2014 World Cup, Belgium was the stronger team, by some distance, so this represents a particular improvement on Wales's part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9087" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/1957831_642788809139747_4859931912064326634_o.jpg?w=600" alt="1957831_642788809139747_4859931912064326634_o" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the composition of 2016 &lt;em&gt;Team Wales&lt;/em&gt; is quite different to that in 2014, with only a handful of skaters shared betwen the two rosters. What is still true, however, is the dominance of Tiger Bay Brawlers and Swansea City Roller Derby in the training team, making up 18 of the 30 spots. Both teams have have exceptional years, with Swansea City particularly excelling at British Champs (where they defeated all comers in promotion to Tier 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3897" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teambelgium.jpg?w=582" alt="TeamBelgium" width="291" height="300"&gt; Team Belgium logo: Anouk Paepen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Belgium&lt;/em&gt;, meanwhile have at least 14 skaters returning from the strong 2014 roster in 2016. Belgian Roller Derby has always been pretty strong, on the basis of Gent Go-Go Rollergirls and One Love Roller Dolls amongst their many teams. However, we've not seen, perhaps, the explosive performance increase that, for example, Scandinavia has. We'd say that Team Belgium is, indeed, about as strong as it was in 2014.
We expect Wales to be keen on taking on Belgium on their home turf, and cautiously predict a win for the hosts on this basis. Overall rankings are hard to predict, but there are some particularly strong teams competing in The Road to TBC, and we wonder if the battle here will be for 4th place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3842" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamspain.jpg?w=600" alt="Team Spain logo -" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2014, &lt;em&gt;Spain&lt;/em&gt; have clearly come on in leaps and bounds.
The 2014 Team Spain consisted almost entirely of skaters from Barcelona and Tenerife, along with a few from outside Spain. The 2016 Training Team contains 13 skaters from 2014, but a huge number of new faces. We expect that Barcelona and Tenerife will still be strongly represented, however, and note that both leagues have significantly improved their rankings in the last 2 years (Tenerife has a steadily increasing ranking on Flat Track Stats, with no drops at all over that period!). We'd say that Spain have a good chance of placing well, assuming no surprises - although the general strength of teams at The Road to TBC is also higher than ERDT, so another 4th place is unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3773" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamwestindies.jpg?w=424" alt="Team West Indies Logo" width="212" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team West Indies&lt;/em&gt; was new to the Roller Derby scene in 2014, and also had the aim of trying to promote the sport back in the West Indies itself, with all of the skaters being from leagues outside of the islands (and many from the UK). Two years later, it seems that they're planning even greater things - but there's no official roster published for the team to date. We gather that Birmingham Blitz Dames and London Rockin' Rollers are still the core of the UK branch of the team, however, and both teams have had strong years - the Blitz Dames in particular benefitting from a change of coaching style which has improved their performance. While we rated West Indies as a little weaker than Spain and Wales in 2014, we wouldn't rule out surprising things from the team after 2 more years to build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4007" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/team-ireland.jpg?w=600" alt="team ireland" width="300" height="300"&gt; Team France logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Ireland Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt; did pretty well at the 2014 World Cup - in fact, on some metrics, we considered them competitive with France! The 2016 iteration is totally unknown, however - they're literally recruiting and selecting as we write this. On the basis of the performance of Dublin Roller Derby (who recently had a US trip and came back even stronger), we wouldn't rule the new Team Ireland out of a top 3 spot in this tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9080" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14390622_1111812092237414_410042907831655880_n.png?w=600" alt="14390622_1111812092237414_410042907831655880_n" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we come to our local team: &lt;em&gt;Team Scotland&lt;/em&gt;!
Scotland performed very creditably in the 2014 World Cup, placing around 10/11th place by our calculations. In 2014, the Scotland team was strongly dominated by Glasgow Roller Derby and Auld Reekie Roller Girls, with only a few skaters from Granite City, 1 from Dundee, and 1 each from Seaside Sirens and London Rollergirls.
This time around, due to both changes at Glasgow, and the strong growth in strength at Dundee and Granite City, we have a more rounded mix of representation in the training team (5 skaters from Dundee, and one from Fierce Valley!); as well as more skaters from outside Scotland itself, with 2 from Wirral, 2 from Newcastle and 1 each from Hallam, Leicester, London Rockin' Rollers!
We're not sure how the team roster for Team Scotland has been selected for The Road to TBC, but we've seen the team in practice, and they look pretty cohesive already. We'd tip Scotland for a chance at upsetting Ireland's dreams of a Top 3 spot, if anyone does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the only way to actually see if we're right is to make your way to Cardiff for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1224163900948144/"&gt;The Road to TBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; itself. Ticket sales are open for the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;27th November,&lt;/strong&gt; and sales are going fast, we believe!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>european roller derby tournament</category><category>international derby</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>statistics</category><category>team belgium</category><category>team france</category><category>team ireland</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team spain</category><category>team sweden</category><category>team wales</category><category>team west indies</category><category>the road to tbc</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 10:36:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interviews: Scandinavia</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/27/world-cup-interviews-uk-ireland/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last week, we have interviewed the 4 teams from Scandinavia who will be taking part in the upcoming &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you missed any of them, here’s a recap:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Denmark" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/22/world-cup-interview-team-denmark/"&gt;Team Denmark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Norway" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/21/world-cup-interview-team-norway/"&gt;Team Norway&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Finland" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/23/world-cup-interview-team-finland/"&gt;Team Finland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Sweden" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/24/world-cup-interview-team-sweden/"&gt;Team Sweden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, we are heading over to North America to chat with two newcomers to the World Cup, and two who played in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team denmark</category><category>team finland</category><category>team norway</category><category>team sweden</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/27/world-cup-interviews-uk-ireland/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 11:53:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Sweden</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/24/world-cup-interview-team-sweden/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a title="Team Sweden on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/teamswedenrollerderby" target="_blank"&gt;Team Sweden &lt;/a&gt;are no strangers to playing as a national side, having competed in the 2011 Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup and also taking part in many preparation games for the 2014 World Cup.
&lt;p&gt;Swede Hurt and the team's media team very kindly took time out of their busy training schedule to tell us how they are feeling about their upcoming World Cup appearance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/10356690_917939274889367_1670650037814336947_n.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4035" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/10356690_917939274889367_1670650037814336947_n.png" alt="Team Sweden Logo" width="614" height="292"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Team Sweden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Team Sweden is filled with skaters from many different teams. How did you organise the team selection process since your skaters come from all over the country?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our team we have skaters from seven different leagues, both Swedish, English and American. During try outs there were even more leagues represented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone that was interested in trying out were asked to fill in an application, and out of the nearly 70 girls that applied we invited about 40 girls to the try-outs. The actual try-out was held in Gothenburg and people who didn't have the opportunity to be there were asked to send video footage of themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. How often are you able to meet up, and what do you focus on to make the best use of your training time together?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We practice together approximately every other month. During the spring we've had a couple of bouts and scrimmages against other teams as well. For example we played against Team USA, Team England, LRG Brawl Saints and Team Finland. When we practice together we aim to become more cohesive, and we really have been trying to mix up skaters from different leagues. Even though a lot of us know each other from before, we might not know how to play with each other. So that's one of the most important things we do: get to know our teammates on the track. We discuss different strategies and try what works for our team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Several of the other European national teams are participating in tournaments before the World Cup to get in some extra practice ahead of the World Cup. What does Team Sweden have planned?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As said earlier, we have a few bouts under our belt at this point. We have cut our training group down to the actual 19 people who will skate at the World Cup. We still have some training ahead of us, and maybe even a bout or scrimmage. We have a very skilled and fit team, and we are confident that all the time we have spent on trying to get to know each other will pay off in Dallas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. As a team which did participate in the 2011 World Cup, you already have experience of playing in a tournament. This must test your team mentally, as well as physically – how will you ensure that Team Sweden stays motivated throughout?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a lot of experienced players that have played tournaments before and will support each other the best we can. Our bench management and physiotherapist will also be a huge help to our mental game in Dallas. We anticipate that Dallas is going to be very different from Toronto, but we really learned that we need access to good food and sleep to be successful. But also time for the team to chill and to have a  game plan. We are going to Dallas to play kick-ass roller derby!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Given the expense of getting to Dallas for the World Cup, how are you raising funds and gaining sponsorship?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have reached out both locally and globally for sponsors and we are really happy to have Cheeseballs, Radar Wheels, Quad Skateshop, SISU mouthguards and hopefully some other sponsors with us. We also have had a fundraiser; we are &lt;a title="Buy Team Sweden Merchandise" href="http://teamsweden.tictail.com/" target="_blank"&gt;selling merch online &lt;/a&gt;(please buy some!); and we have a &lt;a title="Team Sweden's GoFundMe" href="http://www.gofundme.com/bzkdbk" target="_blank"&gt;'go fund me' &lt;/a&gt;for people who feel compelled to donate money to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. And just for fun, does your team have a mascot? If you don’t, what would type of mascot would symbolise your national team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the deepest forests of Sweden hides a great big animal that will horn all the competition away... Just you wait!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/ts-training-group-2014.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4037" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/ts-training-group-2014.jpg" alt="Team Sweden Training Group 2014" width="614" height="327"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Team Sweden Training Group 2014&lt;br&gt;Image courtesy of Team Sweden&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team sweden</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/24/world-cup-interview-team-sweden/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 10:00:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interviews: Team Sweden coach Swede Hurt.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/18/world-cup-interviews-team-sweden-coach-swede-hurt/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every nation has a few famous skaters, who have brought a large influence on the development of roller derby. For Sweden, arguably one of the most well known is Swede Hurt, who has a strong involvement in both of Sweden's leagues in Stockholm and Crime City, and is coaching Team Sweden to boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught up with her to get her opinions on the state of modern roller derby, with a slightly European perspective.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="mceTemp mceIEcenter" style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;dl class="wp-caption  aligncenter"&gt;&lt;dt class="wp-caption-dt"&gt;&lt;img title="Swede Hurt" src="http://www.trishries.com/teamsweden/res/img/players/sh.jpg" alt="" width="295" height="327"&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd class="wp-caption-dd"&gt;Swede Hurt by... Swede Hurt (or Mad Maloony, possibly)&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;You got into Roller Derby mainly in the 'States, how does the experience of playing for the big US teams compare with European Derby?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;It has been about finding a different place for me, I am extremely competitive, and I miss playing in US, but it has also been an experience to move back home to Europe and helping derby here. I have been able to coach all-over Europe, and it has also taught me about myself and derby. European Derby is for sure on the right track, and I love to see how there are new teams popping up every month, I love that so many girls realize that it is not about the fishnets but about being an athlete. I always try to tell girls that you cannot skip your basic skating and derby skills, and you cannot forget the off-skate parts either. Both is really important in the process of building a team, that and being a good listener and resolve conflicts before they become gigantic.
I had to take a decision when I moved back to Sweden; if I was gonna sit around and be upset that people weren't playing derby on the level I was used to OR if I was gonna start coaching people and bring them up to the level I wanted to play on. And since I don't really like just sitting around being unhappy - I started to coach and push people upwards.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As someone who's played in the highest levels of American roller derby (with Gotham), how has this influenced your coaching of Team Sweden?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Keep it clean, know the rules, be confident and have fun and keep fit. I loved being a part of Gotham, and  I admire many of the Gotham skaters for their dedication and hard work. Becoming a great derby player is about hard work, dedication to your team and lots and lots of fun. I expect lots from my skaters, but they also know that I listen to them, and that I only push them because I belive in them.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it a problem that most of the national teams seem to have tried to get a "US skater" to make themselves seem competitive?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I think it is a problem if you get a coach just for the name, but if the coach is there to work with them, I do not see a problem. Mad Maloony (my assistant coach) and Titty Twista (head coach Team Germany) are two good examples of girls that are coaching national teams and they never skated for a US team - but they are both very competent coaches that do good work with their teams.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You're also part-owner of the SwedeVix store for roller derby supplies. How has your experience of skating and coaching informed the company's policies?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Well, of course we always listen to skaters about how they like equipment, and if something isn't working out for our customers, we will not sell it anymore. I try to ask around how different skaters like different plates, wheels, etc. etc. Of course I could try it all myself (and I do try lots of our products) but something I like might not work for a shorter and lighter girl. I don't sell things just to sell, I sell things because I want girls to get great derby gear, that will make them perfom better.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it a foregone conclusion that Team USA and Team Canada will take &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the two top spots in the World Cup? Which teams are you most worried &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;about competing against?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I think that England is underestimated, I for sure think they can give Canada a run for their money. I am quite confident in saying that Team US will take the number one spot.  I have no clue where Australia are at, and same goes for New Zealand. I think that every team is a challenge, in different ways, I never write a team off until the last whistle.  I think it be fun to play any team, and we will get on the track and do our best no matter what team we are playing - with a smile on our lips.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-World Cup, would you like to see Team Sweden continue in other &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bouts? You've already played Team Finland - does a European cup sound &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;out of the question?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I think that a European Cup would be fun, I am always up for playing/coaching more derby. And I think Team Sweden has been a great place for Swedish derby to grow, and I hope that we can continue to play, maybe a re-match with Finland next year, maybe play Germany.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; I would love to stay as a head coach for Team Sweden and keep playing, but I would not be able to help organizing such a fun thing. I am going to concentrate on Stockholm Roller Derby's WFTDA status, it be great if we could get through the Apprentice Program during 2012. And me and Vix are also arranging Battle of Nordic Light again in Malmö.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generally, when do you think European Derby will be seriously &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;competitive with US derby, in both actual skill and perception?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Once again, I am impressed by lots of the Euopean teams, LRG are really great, and I was very impressed by their performance during Eastern Regionals. There is a thirst for knowledge all over Europe, and a drive that is amazing. Derby girls are getting fitter, studying strategies and playing smart. I think with implementing minimum skills and leagues getting more structure, and also introducing off-skate sessions, we will not be very far behind, there is so much talent all over Europe - just coaching CCR has been so rewarding.  Now with so many teams joining into the WFTDA Apprentice Program I'm hoping for a European Regional Tournament in 2013 - that really would be amazing.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Swede Hurt blogs at &lt;a href="http://swedehurtgoesfit.blogspot.com/"&gt;Swede Hurt Rambles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2011 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><category>swede hurt</category><category>team sweden</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/18/world-cup-interviews-team-sweden-coach-swede-hurt/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 22:16:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Sweden-Roller Derby World Cup 2011</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/14/team-sweden-roller-derby-world-cup-2011/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/14/team-sweden-roller-derby-world-cup-2011/www.teamswedenrollerderby.com"&gt;Team Sweden&lt;/a&gt; might be relatively new on the scene, but their constituent teams have both been performing well in bouts across Europe. They could be a surprise for the more established teams out there.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/11/teamswedenlogga1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-495" title="teamswedenlogga" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/11/teamswedenlogga1.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="614"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Roster
Swede Hurt - Head Coach + skater (ex of Gotham Girls Roller Derby and Rat City, now Stockholm Roller Derby, after coaching Crime City Rollers)
Mad Maloony - Assistant Coach + skater (ex of Copenhagen, now Stockholm Roller Derby, after coaching Crime City Rollers)
Sloppy Boggins - Assistant Coach (GTAR (Toronto), exStockholm)
Alotta Riot - Crime City Rollers
Ankefar - Crime City Rollers
Barbara Barfight - Crime City Rollers
Becky Lawless - Stockholm Roller Derby
Bess I’rv Cold - Stockholm Roller Derby
Fenix Fortsomfan - Crime City Rollers
Firebird Steele - Crime City Rollers
Fisty - Crime City Rollers
HussInsane - Stockholm Roller Derby
HyperNova - Stockholm Roller Derby
Jazz Ass - Stockholm Roller Derby
Jo Evil Eye - Crime City Rollers
Kit Kat Power  - London Rockin' Rollers
Kix deVille - Stockholm Roller Derby
Knickerblocker Glory - London Rollergirls
Ninja - Crime City Rollers
Twist’d T - Stockholm Roller Derby
Vix Viking - Crime City Rollers (ex of London Rollergirls)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is plain from the roster, Team Sweden draws almost entirely from the two Swedish leagues, Stockholm and Crime City (Malmö). As with many of the national teams, however, they have a smattering of impressively sourced coaches and head skaters, of which Swede Hurt, who has previously played for East Region champions Gotham Girls Roller Derby and for Rat City (including a trip to West Regionals), and will presumably be bringing her intimidating experience to her Head Coach role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Sweden have played one public bout, against Team Finland, which they won handily. Since then, they have been engaging in regular practices to build team cohesion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Sweden is sponsored by the SwedeVix skate store, which just happens to have been founded by two of their players, Swede Hurt and Vix Viking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be getting more information about Team Sweden in a later article, as I interview Swede Hurt on various topics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2011 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><category>team sweden</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/14/team-sweden-roller-derby-world-cup-2011/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 14:45:38 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>