<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about team scotland roller derby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/team-scotland-roller-derby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 08:59:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Team Scotland Events: Fundraiser coming to a close!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/06/team-scotland-events-fundraiser-coming-to-a-close/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While over on Facebook, we've been regularly sharing info about the preparations for the various National Teams heading for the two Roller Derby World Cups next year... we've been saving a blog post for the Scottish National teams, starting with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Team-Scotland-Roller-Derby-235701999922927/"&gt;Team Scotland Roller Derby.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13779 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/scotland.png" alt="scotland" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In common with many of the teams heading for the 3rd Roller Derby World Cup in Trafford, England, Team Scotland are &lt;a href="https://www.crowdfunder.co.uk/team-scotland-roller-derby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;raising money&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to support their attendance. (Being a National Team has all the costs you would expect, from training venues, equipment, travel and accommodation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a special consideration this time around, &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; of the funds raised by TS will be donated to the charity &lt;strong&gt;Mind&lt;/strong&gt;, in support of mental health - and if you feel like you need a more tangible personal benefit for donating, all donations above &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; are eligible for Team Scotland branded merch, with donations above &lt;strong&gt;£75&lt;/strong&gt; enabling you to sponsor a specific Team Scotland Rostered Skater (who will wear a sponsors patch provided, during the World Cup).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have just until the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; to donate to the fundraiser, and help it reach its goal of just £2000, so please consider donating!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donation link is here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.crowdfunder.co.uk/team-scotland-roller-derby/"&gt;https://www.crowdfunder.co.uk/team-scotland-roller-derby/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in competing with Team Scotland, as well as supporting them, there's also the opportunity still to sign up as part of the mash-up team who will get to scrim against TS at their November training session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up in the Manhattan Works venue (Dundee Roller Girls' training venue), you will get to play with the best skaters that Scotland has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's still time to sign up here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/111479986185051/?"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/111479986185051/?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, if you'd like to help Team Scotland, rather than compete against them, applications are now open for the position of "Team Sports Therapist" attending the team for their training sessions, and competition, including the World Cup itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apply here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScwqegWr0F1-lAoO0hrXqrFLDx-fi1ueSwz7K9wZP4D3HugcA/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScwqegWr0F1-lAoO0hrXqrFLDx-fi1ueSwz7K9wZP4D3HugcA/viewform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on in the Year, Team Scotland will be making appearances at a few other events, so stay tuned to see how you can catch them on track before the World Cup!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>crowdfunding</category><category>fundraising</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/06/team-scotland-events-fundraiser-coming-to-a-close/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 14:13:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: Team Scotland Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/14/euroclash-interviews-team-scotland-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With less than two weeks to go before &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.euro-clash.com"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;' first International Tournament - we're also now just two interviews away from covering all of the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This interview is a particularly special one for us, though, as we're covering the second National Team attending EuroClash - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Team-Scotland-Roller-Derby-235701999922927/"&gt;Team Scotland Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current Team Scotland has only played publicly in two events: The Road to TBC in Cardiff last year (placing 6th); and against Team Belgium in February. Neither of those events featured the final roster of skaters, however: EuroClash will be the first public appearance of the Final 20 in competition.
At EuroClash, Team Scotland will be competing against Team Ireland, who they lost to (in a very tough game for both teams) in Cardiff. This time around, with more training, and the final 20 selection, TS will be hoping to change the result.
The Team Ireland/ Team Scotland bout at EuroClash is a National Teams Event leading up to the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 2018 in Trafford, Greater Manchester, hosted by Rainy City Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13779 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/scotland.png" alt="scotland" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to properly represent Team Scotland, we talked to Crazylegs - the sole three-times member of the Team Scotland roster, and Malin Landsborough - one of the skaters new to the team this time around - about all things Team Scotland and EuroClash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Scotland has been at both previous World Cups - placing 11th the first time, and around the same place the second (slightly underranked each time). The Scottish spirit has always been strong - but how has the experience of the National Team changed (if it has) between versions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crazylegs: It’s definitely changed a lot from World Cup to World Cup; I'd like to say the uniforms have been getting better, but we went from the unfortunate dresses of 2011, to the giant name misprints in 2014, and our training shirts for 2017 have been causing all sorts of jammer body part entrapment issues with the loose arm holes. Let's hope for a successful 2018 squad uniform - we are wide open for sponsorship if anyone is up for a challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess for Toronto in 2011, everything was an unknown - I kept a proper daily diary during my 2011 World Cup journey and I read it back the other day; mind blowing. We knew absolutely nothing! It was the first time any of us had been part of such a big tournament structure and outside of Europe. For a lot of skaters it was their first time skating outside of Scotland. We were excited by every single thing - every shout out, every freebie, the school buses, every time someone asked us to sign a programme. Our wee Scotch corner of supporters made us cry, it was so cool to see people travel to far to come and cheer. I remember being totally shocked that they came!
It happened again in Dallas, with our amazing support from home, and by 2014 we knew much more about setting expectations with skaters and planning and organising beforehand so it was a bit of a calmer experience, but still, playing National teams is always going to be a bit of an unknown because we don’t tend to see them regularly play outside of WC tournaments, and, coupled with shorter qualifier games, and a last minute changing schedule, it’s definitely a different kind of challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, I think we’re focusing more on heads-down regular team training just now, we started sooner and that will hopefully give us more time to build on skills and tactics as a team and will translate into a more consistent level of play for Manchester. The team is looking really strong with a load of potential and I’m all fired up for my third World Cup!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This iteration of Team Scotland's first public outing was at The Road to TBC, long before the selection happened. Despite the early point in TS' training, the team placed pretty well, although the close bout against Spain was unlucky for your resulting placement. What were the high points for you at the tournament, and what did you learn from it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C: It was great! I think the best thing that any team can do to forge fast bonds and get to know each other really well is to travel together and play in a tournament, so for that reason it was a huge success for our training squad, we have a team of characters and they are all lovely. We got to know each other better, learned how we each react to nerves, pressure and being away from our usual team environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was challenging because as a training squad of 30, the management selected teams by picking from a hat, and we also had skaters playing in multiple positions to test out strengths, so we really had to approach it as a training opportunity, which can be difficult in a public tournament, but I think we managed beautifully and the whole team vibe in the games was really positive and focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few of the team got to learn just how bad I am at navigating Google Maps, yet how amazing I am at summoning random taxis to resolve emergency lost-in-Wales situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malin: Road to TBC was a great opportunity for the team to skate together early on in the TS training, and because of this (still being the top 30) we couldn’t all skate in it. But as one of those whose name unfortunately didn’t come up for it, I still truly enjoyed watching it from the side line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel the high point of this tournament was really that it brought us together as a team! It allowed us the chance to really get to know each other in a competitive setting early on in our training. Plus the performance that Scotland put out was fantastic to see – too many close games for my wee heart to take. It did also help us identify our training focuses in moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One striking thing about this Team Scotland selection is the continuing increase in the proportion of Dundee (and Granite City) skaters in the 20. The 2011 TS was almost entirely Auld Reekie and Glasgow, and now all 4 teams are much more equally represented. How does it feel [Malin] to be part of this trend, and what do you [both] think it says about the development of roller derby in Scotland?
&lt;/strong&gt;
C: I think this is a really important question. It's great to see a broader spread of skaters representing from across the teams in Scotland, it's kind of shaping up to look how it should and I think this is reflected in a few other countries this time around. Having wider representation means a more extensive set of experiences to draw from on the team. I'd love to see that trend continue and see competition in Scotland being pushed year on year across all competitive teams, so that we collectively drive the level of play much higher for the athletes here who aspire to that, and want to find the hardest challenges without always having to travel so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to help us build a Team Scotland that the strongest eligible players in our sport are all really keen to be part of, and we can enable that with smart planning; aligning training and game commitments, creating clear training and rest cycles and by working to understand the sanctioned play demands on the skaters teams taking part in WFTDA Play Offs or British Champs - all of which happens in tandem with the National team training. Having that understanding of the priorities of the leagues and teams representing on Team Scotland can ensure that we get the best out of our athletes. This will ensure the continued growth of our sport in National and local play and this is really important as we move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M: It’s a fantastic feeling to be part of such an increase of Northern skaters making the TS cut: we at Dundee have been putting so much into our training the past couple of years, so to make it to this point just cements to us that it is all worth it. For so many of us to make the training squad was such an incredible achievement, especially looking back to the last selection where we at Dundee only had wee Milky representing us, words couldn’t even describe the feeling finding out such a high percent of us made the top 20! This feeling is only heightened by the response we received when the selection was made public, the support we feel behind us is incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is incredible to see the development in Scottish Roller Derby over the past few years! The support we have received from the larger Scottish leagues has been inspiring and has allowed us to level up (and gain WFTDA apprenticeship). Passing on knowledge and camaraderie throughout Scottish derby has brought all levels of leagues together; it’s exciting to see how all the Scottish teams are moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This interview is partly to promote the EuroClash Tournament in Newcastle. Speaking of that, Team Scotland will be attending to compete with Ireland again, who you last encountered at Road to TBC. How are you preparing for the rematch, and what do you hope to achieve this time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C: Team Ireland is such a good, solid team to play, we never seem to get pitched against them in WC tournaments, so it’s great to play them outside of that. There was a lot of positive feedback from within our team about that game – we felt like we had some really strong moments. It was one of those ‘if only we’d had 20 more minutes’ games! It will be really interesting to play again so soon and I hope we can better our score differential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like Team Scotland is hitting the ground running having just been given news of the final squad, so there really hasn’t been much time to prepare for this one - but we have been training every month for the last few months and we have a lot of trust in each other. A lot of the Team Scotland skaters are playing in 2 or 3 of our own league games in the tournament, so we’ll be nice and warmed up for the Ireland game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M: Yes, when we played at Road to TBC it was a close, hard fought game on both sides. As a league we’re continuing with our training focuses and gelling as a team on track, so we can go into this rematch as a united front. This is another step on our road to Greater Manchester, so if we can use this opportunity to put everything we’ve been training into practice, it’ll be a success to us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love a rematch and can’t wait to meet the Team Ireland squad on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And when you're not on skates, what teams or games are you most looking forward to catching?
&lt;/strong&gt;
C: I'm really looking forward to seeing Paris play and also Tiger Bay - I've not seen either of those teams play for a wee while, and both are usually really good to watch. Auld Reekie are playing Paris in April, so it's always good to get a wee spy on them beforehand. I'll be playing with Auld Reekie against MMR, Berlin and the new Leeds team at EuroClash, and I think each of those games will offer a really good and potentially very different kind of challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M: It’ll be great to see all the talent on show throughout the weekend, but I have to say I’m most excited to be there to support our pals at ARRG through their games!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's next for Team Scotland on the road to Greater Manchester?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C: There will be lots of scrimmage and game opportunities set up before the WC I'm sure - we've just upped our training to twice monthly, and our management are looking about for opportunities to help us train against the toughest teams. After Euro Clash we'll probably know more about team positions and move into a more focused training cycle. I'd love to play some more of the European teams in preparation, because we can get to them fairly easily. We'll also most definitely be working on our uniform game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M: I think for Team Scotland moving forward will be for us to settle into our positions within the team and understand how we all work together, just like any newly formed team. It’s great to see how we’ve improved from the first selection to the final 20 and so I’m excited to see this carry on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also anticipating a busy period of fundraising leading up to Greater Manchester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, given the performance of Scotland in the last two World Cups - and the likely even greater scope of the 2018 Roller Derby World Cup in Greater Manchester - how are you hoping that Scotland will do third time around?
&lt;/strong&gt;
C: Well obviously, we want to win it. Falling somewhere above USA, Australia and Team England would be fab :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M: If we can improve on our position from the previous World Cups that would be fantastic, but this is a huge opportunity to bring back experience and knowledge from higher level roller derby, which can only benefit Scottish Roller Derby as a whole. EXCITED!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash will be held from the &lt;strong&gt;25th&lt;/strong&gt; to the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/strong&gt;, Newcastle. Ticket available here:&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets"&gt;https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; , and on the door.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>euroclash</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/14/euroclash-interviews-team-scotland-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 10:07:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Seeing in the New: National Teams in Dundee.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/10/seeing-in-the-new-national-teams-in-dundee/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend sees a double-dose of National Teams action for those in Scotland, as Dundee hosts a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1382676465099043/"&gt;combined event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with Team Scotland Roller Derby and Power of Scotland both on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14736 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/02/tspostb.jpg" alt="tspostb" width="1071" height="400"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, the Training Team for Team Scotland will be holding a Black v White bout, competing against themselves as part of the selection process for the new Team Scotland. After playing as two teams last weekend in Belgium (and winning both games), all of the skaters will be at their best, and bringing you (by definition), the highest level roller derby in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the Power of Scotland roster from the 2016 Men's World Cup will be playing their swansong bout, against Team Belgium Men's Roller Derby. Symbolically, this is their passing of the torch to the new Power of Scotland training team, who are currently undergoing the selection process after their tryouts in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the close connection between the National Teams, we were delighted to be able to talk with Rosie Peacock (PoS 2016 LUM/Assistant Coach, TS 2017/8 Head Coach) and Laura "Milky" Liston (PoS 2016 Coach, member of TS 2017/8 Training Team) about things. Between them, the two were selected to Captain the Team Scotland rosters in Belgium, so they have a great feel for the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First question, then: How did it feel to be selected as a Captain for the bouts last weekend?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rosie:&lt;/em&gt; So, Milky captained both in the end because I had too much caffeine and got super radge... Me and Milks were the only two who were nominated, but it was good the team trusted us to do the thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura&lt;/em&gt;: It was lovely knowing some of the team had nominated us, and it was such an amazing opportunity to Captain the squad, but yeah, we were the two nominated haha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, following up on that: Team Scotland won both their games, with both rosters against Belgium. How do you feel the games went - what are you happiest about, and is there anything you might work on?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rosie&lt;/em&gt;: I think outer defence side walls are really tight and fluid and adaptive; I'd love to work more on our offer credit and jammer pairings, but that's something we can't progress too much further until we have our final squad and definitely establish roles...
I need to keep my temper and not drink red bull when pmsing 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura&lt;/em&gt;: I really loved some of the bonds and partnerships we starting building on track, which I think were really apparent throughout the day. I'm looking forward to seeing how they develop in the final squad. Both of the games brought different challenges so it was great to see how we adapted to the change in gameplay style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And moving to this weekend: obviously we can't talk too much about selection itself, but clearly everyone there is hoping to make the final selection - do you see changes in both your own performance (and gelling) and your teammates already at this point?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura&lt;/em&gt;: Oh definitely. The opportunity to skate with so many high level skaters has really helped strengthen my skating on a personal level. We've been lucky enough to have Belgium and Cardiff to gel as a team in a competitive environment, and I think both have made a really noticeable improvement to our performances as a team together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Both of you have strong connections with Power of Scotland, especially the 2016 Squad who are playing as well - against Belgium! - we know the team are treating this as a "sending off" of the old team, but will a tiny tear be in your eyes to see them playing together for the last time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura&lt;/em&gt;: Hah! I think I got all my emotions out in Calgary when the whole squad was there. It'll be great to see the guys playing together again but I'm looking forward to seeing what our new squad will look like, and so excited about the future of PoS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rosie&lt;/em&gt;: I'm looking so forward to playing the best sport in the world, with the best group of humans I've had the pleasure to know x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The doors open for the double header at &lt;strong&gt;11:30, Saturday 11th&lt;/strong&gt; February, at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/DISC:+Dundee+International+Sports+Centre/@56.4762694,-2.9611212,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48865cfd69198245:0x74e93fd03837f5ac!8m2!3d56.4762665!4d-2.9589272"&gt;Dundee International Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are &lt;strong&gt;£6&lt;/strong&gt; in advance (from Brown Paper Tickets), &lt;strong&gt;£8&lt;/strong&gt; on the door. (Tickets at: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2794252"&gt;http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2794252&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/10/seeing-in-the-new-national-teams-in-dundee/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 11:19:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Training Team Scotland to Success: Alison "Ella Bella Bang Bang" Noble, Team Scotland Head Coach 2013-2016</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/04/training-team-scotland-to-success-alison-ella-bella-bang-bang-noble-team-scotland-head-coach-2013-2016/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last of our features in collaboration with &lt;a href="http://ukdra.org.uk"&gt;UKRDA&lt;/a&gt;, we're talking to Team Scotland's outgoing Head Coach, Alison "Ella Bella Bang-Bang" Noble.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Ella has been involved in Roller Derby almost as long as it has existed in Scotland. She joined Auld Reekie Roller Girls as an official on their founding in 2008, and refereed her first public game at the start of 2009. Since then, she has officiated a huge number of bouts, including Roll Britannia (Europe's first Roller Derby Tournament, 2009), Highland Fling (Scotland's  Derby Tournament, 2010, for which she was Head Referee), and the 2011 Blood &amp;amp;Thunder Women's Roller Derby World Cup.
She has coached since 2011, when she became Bench Coach for Auld Reekie's A team, the then Twisted Thistles, and later for ARRG's Home Team the Leithal Weapons.
Since 2014, she has transferred to Bairn City Rollers, where she returned to primarily officiating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Ella served as Head Coach for Team Scotland Roller Derby for the period leading up to and including the 2014 Women's World Cup. She performed this role under her legal name of Alison Noble, in common with some other members of the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6137" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/10629723_350040428489083_3796144537420746402_n.jpg" alt="10629723_350040428489083_3796144537420746402_n" width="960" height="960"&gt; Ella modelling Team Scotland Merch! (Credit: Team Scotland PR)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ella, you're perhaps known as much for your extensive refereeing experience as you are for coaching. What led you to apply to Coach Team Scotland?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p3"&gt;Before applying to be Team Scotland Head Coach I had quite a lot of extensive discussions with previous members of Team Scotland. I wanted to get a sense of what they hoped for Team Scotland and for the 2014 World Cup. I also discussed at length with the Captains and Line Up Manager&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;of ARRG's All-Star team, as that was who I worked closely with as a bench coach. It was after a lengthly chat with Crazylegs of ARRG and a friendly word of support from Mistress Malicious from GRD that I decided to apply. I was bowled over by the support I was offered from my application and many people in the Scottish derby community provided references and letters of support, some of which where very moving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As well as Coaching, the Coaching roles are also involved in Team selection. What were you looking for when selecting Team Scotland in the tryouts?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p3"&gt;At try-outs we where looking for a range of skills and qualities. We wanted this Team Scotland to be as strong as we could make it. We wanted the team to be well bonded, we wanted the team to be able to grow and develop as a team, we wanted dedicated people who would strive to do their best for the team. We had agreed Selection Criteria and Process. And I have to say that the level of skill and talent on display at the try-outs was phenomenal!! It was incredibly difficult to select our training squad, and then to select our Roster of 20 for the World Cup itself was exceptionally hard. We had a great team of hard working and dedicated skaters, who were all brilliant at responding to advice and criticism and were constantly improving and pushing each other on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the difficult issues with National team training can be bringing together skaters from different leagues into one coherent force. How did you get Team Scotland working together in the relatively short time you had?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p3"&gt;We had regular training which helped this and we spent some time discussing groupings and establishing roles within the team. We looked at strengths and areas for development and how we could support each other. Once we had established roles within the training squad, it allowed us to develop focused training where people could work on assigned roles and with pairings or groups that we felt would work for the teams. We had warm up games, which really helped us test these out in real game situations, which was brilliant for us as it allowed us to make important little tweaks. We also had fantastic Captains who really helped the team bond and become focused on common goals. The Captains did an incredible job of pulling the skaters together and making Team Scotland a solid unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obviously, the big event for Team Scotland was the World Cup in Dallas - but TS had lots of other experiences along the way. What were your highlights of the whole coaching experience?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p3"&gt;Obviously I loved the World Cup. But I would have to say the highlights for me would be our warm up games. The team really pulled together for our Hot or What game and a closed game we had against Brawl Saints. It was great to see that in the early stages the hard work that everyone single skater was putting in was really paying off. But the biggest Highlight was the Road to Dallas tournament in Wales. The team did an astounding job. And every one of those games brought us new challenges that every member of Team Scotland rose to. I think it was then that we really showed how far Team Scotland had come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What advice would you give the next Head Coach of Team Scotland?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p3"&gt;My advice for the next coach would be that you remember to take the time to really see how truly inspiring the team can be. The drive and determination demonstrated by every single member of the Scottish derby community who tried out for the team, or supported the team or who worked with the team, or who attended our training to support the teams develop through participating in drills or officiating is awe inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p3"&gt;I loved being part of Team Scotland. I would do it all again and I would give it everything I could possibly give. I am sorry that I can not apply this time round but I can not give Team Scotland the time it deserves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p3"&gt;I will support the team in any way I can and I offer my full support to whoever takes up this brilliant opportunity to help lead Team Scotland to the 2017 World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6135" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/10888830_10204899480920862_8651333446670708096_n.jpg" alt="10888830_10204899480920862_8651333446670708096_n" width="640" height="800"&gt; Ella Bench Coaching for Team Scotland against Team Australia at the 2014 B&amp;amp;T Roller Derby World Cup. (Credit: Dave McAleavy)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p3"&gt;If you feel that you can help to Coach Team Scotland into the 2017 World Cup, following in Ella's example, then you can still apply. Applications close at midnight, &lt;strong&gt;Monday 7th March&lt;/strong&gt;, and the form can be downloaded here: &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B-XTeOpUghUFdUJjMGQxczVVMnM/view?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1"&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B-XTeOpUghUFdUJjMGQxczVVMnM/view?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p3"&gt;You can also apply to be Assistant Coach via the same form (it is possible to apply for multiple roles at once, via the same form, as well).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/04/training-team-scotland-to-success-alison-ella-bella-bang-bang-noble-team-scotland-head-coach-2013-2016/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 19:36:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lining Team Scotland Up: Erin "Rufi-Ohh" Murphy, Team Scotland's Line-up Manager 2013-2016</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/04/lining-team-scotland-up-erin-rufi-ohh-murphy-team-scotlands-line-up-manager-2013-2016/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the second of our features in collaboration with &lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UKRDA&lt;/a&gt;, we're talking to Team Scotland's outgoing Line-Up Manager, Erin "Rufi-Ohh" Murphy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rufi has been involved with Roller Derby since late 2010, when she started skating with the then-named Dundee Destroyers, under a different skatename herself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rufi joined Stirling/Falkirk's Fierce Valley Roller Girls in 2011, and captained the team during their first ever (closed) bout. In 2012, she was vice-captain during FVRG's first public bout, against old team Dundee Roller Girls. Unfortunately, due to injury, Rufi had to take an extended absence from skating, but continues to support the league as Line-Up and on other committees, as well as in the Coaching team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rufi was Line-Up Manager for Team Scotland Roller Derby during the period including the 2014 Women's World Cup in Dallas. In common with several of the skaters, she performed this role under her legal name, Erin Murphy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/wp-1457080455069.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full" title="wp-1457080455069" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/wp-1457080455069.jpg" alt="image"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rufi, you've been in Roller Derby for quite a while, since 2010! What led you to apply to be Line-Up Manager for the Scottish National Team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Applying for Team Scotland was not an easy decision to make for me but I applied because I believed that although I was from one of the younger leagues in Scotland that I was up to the challenge. I wanted the opportunity to learn and work with great scottish skaters and officials and have fun in the process.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As Line-Up, you were also present during the Tryout and selection process for Team Scotland. What was it like being involved in selecting the National team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Selecting the National team was a big learning curve for me. From the applications, through to the try outs, and also video submissions, it was a very interesting and challenging experience. Although it was stressful at points, it was also great fun and I had a great time! Although running the second round one tryout was a tad scary!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The most visible and obvious aspect of Line-Up is beside the track during a bout, managing the selection of skaters for each jam. How did you approach this, under the pressure of the World Cup in Dallas - against such opponents as Australia, for example?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Luckily for me Scotland is full of talented and fantastic skaters which made my job that bit easier, although as always there will always be pressure during games. I was also lucky to have an amazing Bench Coach in Ella [Bella Bang Bang] who was supportive, and who I worked well with, along with 2 fantastic co-captains in Crazy[legs] and Mona [Rampage]. We worked as a unit and their support and opinions were always valued in my approach to game line ups.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Line-Up Role also involves supporting Coaching and training in general for the National Squad. What's the most important contribution to you that you made to Team Scotland's development?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Wow... That is a tough question. I feel that my most important contribution was my time and dedication to the team prior to arriving on Dallas. A lot of work goes on behind the scenes before the tournament that no one ever really sees, but that is what keeps the team running and that is what gets us there!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's the most important thing that being a managerial/coaching role for a National Team has taught you, and what was the best memory of the whole TS experience?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The most important thing it taught me was to be confident in my own skills and my knowledge of the sport. If you are dedicated you will get to where you want to be! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;My best memory.... That is tough. I have so many amazing memories from the whole experience. From the sleeper bus to Cardiff, to my line traveller award in Dallas. The one moment that sticks in my mind was when Louise 'Splat' Kerr took the star pass during our game against Australia and scored that important first point. The reaction of the crowd, the reaction of the team and the look on Splat's face when it all happened. That to me is what roller derby is all about. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What advice would you give the next Line-Up Manager for Team Scotland?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My advice to the next Line-Up Manager - expect to work hard, expect to learn, expect to be pushed to your limits but enjoy every second of it. You are part of Team Scotland for a reason.&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to follow in Rufi-Ohh's path, and take on the role of Line-Up Manager for Team Scotland, working towards the 3rd Women's Roller Derby World Cup, you can apply here [Applications close Midnight &lt;strong&gt;Monday 7 March&lt;/strong&gt;]: &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B-XTeOpUghUFdUJjMGQxczVVMnM/view"&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B-XTeOpUghUFdUJjMGQxczVVMnM/view&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/04/lining-team-scotland-up-erin-rufi-ohh-murphy-team-scotlands-line-up-manager-2013-2016/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 08:39:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Managing Team Scotland: Jill Antonic, Team Scotland's Team Manager 2013-2016</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/03/managing-team-scotland-jill-antonic-team-scotlands-team-manager-2013-2016/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the first in a series of interviews in collaboration with &lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk/"&gt;UKRDA&lt;/a&gt;, we're talking to Team Scotland Roller Derby's outgoing Team Manager, Jill Antonic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jill has been involved in Roller Derby since 2009, when she started skating with the newly formed Fair City Rollers in Perth. After 4 years with the league, including one year as Captain, she left to join Dundee Roller Girls in late 2013, where she remains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Dundee, Jill currently holds the role of Head of Social Committee, as well as being an active skating member (generally filling the pivot or blocker roles) of their A team, the Silvery Tayzers. In the past, she has also been Head of Fundraising, and has also co-captained the Tayzers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over her extensive skating career, Jill has skated in over 40 public games, including a host of charity and exhibition bouts. She was also Team Manager for the Scottish National Women's Team, Team Scotland Roller Derby, for the period leading up to (and following) the 2014 Blood and Thunder Roller Derby World Cup, in which the team placed approximately 13th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/03/managing-team-scotland-jill-antonic-team-scotlands-team-manager-2013-2016/teamscotland2014-012-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-6069"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-6069" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/teamscotland2014-0121.jpg" alt="Jill Antonic (Team Scotland Roster Photo. Credit: Dave McAleavy)" width="480" height="600"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Jill Antonic (Team Scotland Roster Photo. Credit: &lt;a href="http://boutday.com"&gt;Dave McAleavy&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jill, while you've had a lot of experience in managing Dundee Roller Girls' league matters, what led you to apply to Manage Team Scotland?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;I applied to be Team Scotland manager because I wanted to help and also to be involved in the team.  I had travelled to Toronto in 2011 to watch Team Scotland compete and wanted to be a part of that.  I knew I was not at the skating or coaching standard to do either of those things, but as I'd helped to set up a league in Perth before I joined the Dundee Roller Girls I knew I could apply my skills to the managerial role instead.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managerial Roles are a lot less visible, perhaps, than Coaching and Line-up. For you, what are the most important aspects of the role?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The most important aspects of being team manager are organisation and communication.  There are so many things that the job entails, some large, some small, but too many to list individually really!  I found the most important things I had to be on top of were communications with the tournament organisers and UKRDA, and also the fundraising and finance side of things.  Everything else is important, don't get me wrong, but I found these to be the essentials!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just the fundraising and financial aspects of Team Scotland were fairly foreboding, what with just the travel and accommodation for Dallas being a large sum in themselves (quite apart from everything else TS needed). How did you approach this huge challenge?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;One step at a time.  We did discuss what our expectations were in regards to how much funding each person on the team would receive and how much would have to be self-funded.  By far our biggest money maker was the merch we produced.  Jenny [Admiral Attackbar] Gow designed a fab new logo for the team and we came up with slogans to go along with that.  "Bunch of Fannies" was my favorite, although the amount of time I spent explaining exactly what that meant to the Americans while in Texas was fairly extensive!! We also organised several home games as fundraisers, this benefited the team two-fold, in that it both gave us additional funds, and also allowed the team to spend more time working together on track.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Staying on top of all of the committees and workflows involved in PR, fundraising and sponsorship, training, and even arranging uniforms!, could be overwhelming. How did you manage all of the various responsibilities of managing a National team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Organisation and delegation!! I cannot stress how important these two things are within the managerial role.  It's simply not possible for one person to do all the work to get a National team to a tournament like the the World Cup, especially one so far from home.  There are so many things to do that I'd never thought of before, so going through them one at a time and spreading the tasks across the different committees was the way to go.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What things did you learn about yourself through Managing a National Team? (and what was the best memory of the whole TS experience?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;I learned just how much I can achieve when I put my mind to it.  One of my best memories from the tournament is singing the National Anthem.  We'd been told we'd be singing it on the first day of the tournament, so arranged for local piper to come and play Flower of Scotland for us.  Unfortunately, the organisers changed things round so that the anthems were to be sung on day 2 instead; we had to carry the tune for the whole arena!
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; Growing up watching rugby, the National Anthem is just such a proud moment, so to do that was amazing.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Although starting a kangaroo kidnapping war with the Aussies comes a close second!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What advice would you give the next Team Manager for Team Scotland?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Delegate, write lists and keep on top of things. and Enjoy it, it's been one of the best experiences of my life!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to take on the challenges of managing the next Team Scotland, taking them into the 3rd Women's Roller Derby World Cup in 2017, applications for the position of Team Scotland Team Manager are &lt;strong&gt;open&lt;/strong&gt; until Midnight, &lt;strong&gt;Monday 7th March&lt;/strong&gt;. The application details are available at the following link: &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B-XTeOpUghUFWDBLQTRFdmVYa0k/view"&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B-XTeOpUghUFWDBLQTRFdmVYa0k/view&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/03/managing-team-scotland-jill-antonic-team-scotlands-team-manager-2013-2016/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 22:32:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pride, passion and no regrets … except perhaps the kangaroo!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/01/25/pride-passion-and-no-regrets-except-perhaps-the-kangaroo/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that the derby dust has settled on the 2014 Blood and Thunder World Cup – and a new year of our sport is already underway – it’s a good time to look back and reflect on a stellar set of performances from Team Scotland in Dallas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flat-track facts are two wins, a narrow loss and a Davina and Goliath-like performance against one of the best teams on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/1559577_10204841834359734_5493801035271240774_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4535 " src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/1559577_10204841834359734_5493801035271240774_n.jpg?w=300" alt="1559577_10204841834359734_5493801035271240774_n" width="380" height="253"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Pic by Dave McAleavy
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;But that doesn’t begin to tell the story of just how sensational the Team Scotland players were – on and off the track – flying the flag for their country and impressing everyone who saw the blue belles rock their stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
Team Scotland kicked off the tournament with a terrific win over Team Mexico (207-45) and then – within hours – narrowly lost to Team Finland (126-78).
&lt;p&gt;The following day, Team Scotland turned on the thrusters to beat Team Colombia (230-53), but they knew they had a daunting task ahead – with the mighty Team Australia in their path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, the Aussies beat Scotland 464-35, but the scoreline doesn’t reflect the skill, stamina and heart that was poured into the game by all the players, coaching staff and supporters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRD spoke to Team Scotland’s Captain Fantastic – Lianne Parry – on her memories of the World Cup, Kangaroogate and what’s next for Caledonian derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How was the World Cup for you, Captain?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great experience! The tournament was huge this time and the venue was brilliant. The whole weekend had a completely different feeling to the last - bigger and a lot more hectic, but I loved seeing the new teams involved, and the semi-final and finals games were really inspiring to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS started strongly against Mexico, played well against Finland and beat Colombia convincingly. Are you pleased with how Scotland played?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course! It was a huge deal for us to face up against unknown teams like Mexico and Colombia - it's hard to describe how different a team’s style can be outside of Europe; it's always a good experience to be exposed to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Finland game was one that a lot of the team enjoyed playing most, even though it was the most heartbreaking to lose! It felt like we could definitely have taken the win - we brought it to within a few points - but ultimately they played a really strong game and held it together better at the end. It felt like how playing roller derby should feel all of the time - I wish that game could have lasted two hours instead of 40 minutes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your thoughts on the Australia game? They are an excellent side, but Scotland gave as good as they got – especially second half. What were the differences between the teams in the end?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thoughts on the Australia game at the time were that it was probably going to feel as challenging as when we faced Team USA in 2011. I'm not sure all of the team were really fully prepared for just how tough it was going to be though, and in the first half I think we definitely struggled mentally in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The style of play was nothing like I'd come up against before, they are quite simply, just really really flipping good at roller derby! Strong, focused, technically excellent, amazing at forcing penalties on their opponents, and they use their whole bodies way more intelligently than I've ever encountered in another team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was difficult to get a handle on how to block them, or do effective offence against their walls, and it probably took us until half-time to really get a grip on that a little! But what an opportunity - so much stuff to figure out and learn from that game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights on and off track?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gahd too many to mention - on track definitely Australia - every jam I played against them - even if it was totally frustrating. Off track mostly food-related (giant steaks) in Dallas, Kangaroogate (being caught by the Dallas police hot footing it up the road with the Team Australia mascot), failing at the human knot game with the whole team but laughing so hard we forgot to be nervous, making up the stupid team awards at the end and just spending time with the best people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any regrets? Perhaps if Scotland had got a better draw…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously - who bloody regrets anything from such an amazing experience! You do it, you try your best, you learn, you grow, you move on. We've started to gather feedback, stats and footage ready to start preparing for the next challenge. We've loads to work on and loads to change up, so I'm raring to get started. The way it worked out, we got to play Australia and I think I learned more from that game than any other game I've played in the last two years so I'm happy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does playing for your country compare to league? Is it tricky when you don’t know the players as well or did find you all worked well together?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, I guess playing for your country feels like it has way more pressure attached to it - you don't want to let a whole nation down and it seems like the whole world is watching. With your own league you just know each other so well, you know that even if you act like a complete tit by accident, they will still love you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess it can be tricky on mixed teams - skaters from different leagues often have different 'defaults' on track, different cultural norms and are used to different ways of managing their teams - especially decision-making both on and off track - there is quite a lot to try to navigate through, but as you know the derby scene in Scotland is really closely knit so we all know each other fairly well, and there is a lot of respect and support between the leagues. I think the team gelled so well both on and off track this past year, that it won't take much work at all to really build on it and see fast improvements. It takes a big event like this to boost you to the next level sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How proud were you of your team? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So - even though this was the second time Team Scotland has played in a World Cup tournament, the team this time was mostly made up of skaters who hadn't played last time; some of whom have never been to the US or outside of Europe to play derby before, and a couple of whom were cheering Team Scotland on as spectators last time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They all seriously just took it in their stride, prepared well, stepped up to the challenge, gave so much positivity and energy to each game - even (especially!) when not on the game roster. I'm mostly proud of the sportswomanship the team showed, both to each other and to the teams we played. Even though there were difficult moments, decisions and disappointments, there were also huge smiles, happy tears, so much laughter in the changing room and lots of sweat (and a bit of facial bleeding too).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where will Captain Parry and Team Scotland go from here?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the drawing board! A wee break to let everyone re-focus on their own league challenges and then we'll start up a new training programme. Look out for some changes to the team leadership structure, it's always good to breathe new life and ideas into a team and we'll definitely be looking to open up some extra team roster spots to ensure we keep providing opportunities to skaters across Scotland. So - watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>an interview with...</category><category>in the news</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/01/25/pride-passion-and-no-regrets-except-perhaps-the-kangaroo/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 18:29:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Roller Derby World Cup - Day 3 Review</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/07/roller-derby-world-cup-day-3-review/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 3 of the second ever Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup was devoted to the first stage of the Elimination round, along with the completion of the Consolation bouts for those teams not finishing in the top of their group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, due to the pairing of Group #1 seeds against Group #2 seeds in the Elimination bracket, it has to be said that the closest and most exciting bouts of the day were mostly in the Consolation round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While they seemed less certain in the first period, Team Japan pulled out easily the best performance of their tournament in the second period of their Consolation bout against Mexico, really showing how much they've developed as a team over the past few days (even if both teams had an overflowing penalty board by the end of the game...).  Switzerland v Italy was a very close to-and-fro game, especially in the first period. Once again, accumulated penalties told on both teams, and Italy pulled ahead for the win in Period 2. And Denmark v Portugal once again repeated the same story - a close first period, with Denmark turning on the gas in the second to secure a convincing win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over in the Elimination bouts, Norway, West Indies and Brasil all had predictably crushing bouts against the probable top three in the tournament; USA, England and Canada. Brasil managed to score an impressive 75 points against Canada, however, showing what a great team they've become since the 2011 Cup!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweden, New Zealand, Finland and Argentina had less easy groups to win, but triumphed over Ireland, Netherlands, Belgium, France in the end. Of these, the Argentina v France bout was the only truly close bout of the Top 16 playoffs, with the result completely unpredictable during the first period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rankings going into the Final 8 being determined by score difference in the previous single bout, this close Argentina win rather sealed their fate, as the #8 Seed must play #1, the dominant USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over to Scotland, however, where our team was unlucky enough to be drawn against Australia, #4 placed team from 2011, and probable #3 or #4 place contestors in this tournament. It was a difficult first period for Scotland, with some incredible displays of blocking and jamming on track; however, Australia managed to control the lead jammer position for the entire first period, preventing Scotland's excellence from doing anything other than limiting Aussie scoring. In the very last jam of the period, a star pass to Kerr during a leadless jam, allowed a literal last-second score, putting a single point on the board for Scotland!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejuvenated by breaking their duck, Scotland returned to the 2nd Period determined to mix it up. Liston, jamming for the first time in the game (tournament?), picked up the first lead jammer call for Scotland during the opening (power) jam and the first grand slam pass seconds later. This was the start of a much more confident play by Scotland, with Gow taking a natural lead jammer call soon after, although being forced to call after a single scoring pass after a block knocked her face first into the concrete floor (this also put her out of action in the line-up while she was checked out by the medics). A few power jams for both teams (including a couple of jams where both Scotland and Australia's jammers headed to the box simultaneously), and the Australian blocking mostly told, despite sterling blocking by Maclean, Davis, Liston, Parry (until she fouled out), Cider, Kerr, Simpson and Skinner in particular on the Scottish team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, a scrappy final jam featuring more alternating jammer penalties, brought the score to 464-35 for a deserved Australia win, but a hard fought one against Scotland's resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the quarter final, then, the drawing of high seeds against low continued to produce some predictable blowouts, with USA destroying Argentina just like they destroyed everyone else in the tournament, and England taking a very convincing win over Sweden. Being closer to the middle of the seeds, the Canada - Finland and Australia - New Zealand bouts were slightly less one sided, with Finland standing up pretty well to the #3 seed and taking home 145 pts to Canada's 290.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USA will play #4 seed Australia today, before number #2 and #3 seeds England and Canada duke it out. The winners will go through to the Final, while the losers will play for 3rd place in a last minute change to the schedule (check our&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/10/bloodthunder-world-cup-timings-uk/"&gt; UK timetable&lt;/a&gt; for the accurate timings).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, a brief digression for a slightly controversial statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blood and Thunder's official "Knockout standings" (which are based on the score differentials only for the Group of 16 bouts, as far as we can tell) are [taken from their Facebook page]:
OFFICIAL KNOCKOUT ROUND STANDINGS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team USA Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team England Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Canada B&amp;amp;T World Cup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Australia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team New Zealand Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Finland (Roller Derby)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Sweden Rollerderby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selección Argentina de Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team France Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Ireland Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Belgium Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Netherlands - Women's Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Scotland Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roller Derby Brasil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team West Indies - Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Norway Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, the Top 8 rankings may change based on the games still to play (although we at the Blog believe that England &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; have a strong chance to beat Canada to 2nd place).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's more problematic is that the placements in the bottom 8, including Scotland, are apparently based only on a single score differential, so teams like Norway, Scotland, West Indies and Brasil are penalised by taking on the eventual number 1-4 seeds in their only rank-contributing bout.
We at the Blog disagree strongly with this ranking approach, as it can be shown to underrank those 4 teams - the highest rank Scotland could expect would be 12, under this approach, which they have been assigned.
In the particular case of Scotland, it rankles more, however, as, if we compare the results of Scotland v Finland in the group stage (126-78 for Finland, a 2/3 length bout), and the results of Belgium v Finland in the Elimination stage (383:124 for Finland), it is very clear that Scotland should be ranked above Belgium. Based on other pairwise score-comparison considerations, we believe that Scotland's "true" rank in the tournament is probably &lt;strong&gt;10th&lt;/strong&gt;, narrowly ranked just above Ireland (who Scotland beat not long ago at the Road to Dallas tournament). We believe Norway is strongly penalised by their matching against USA as well, and think their rank should also be at least 2 higher than it actually is in the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full score table for the day is below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SATURDAY, DECEMBER 6, 2014
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(FULL 60 MINUTE BOUTS)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 1 (ROLL-LINE TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 2 (BLOOD &amp;amp; THUNDER TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 3 (TBD TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 7-1 (&lt;strong&gt;Canada 581&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 2-2 (Brazil 75)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 3-1 (&lt;strong&gt;Sweden 303&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 6-2 (Ireland 133)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 3 ( Japan 114) VS. 4 (&lt;strong&gt;Mexico 278&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 1-1 (&lt;strong&gt;NZ 356&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 8-2 (Netherlands 91)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 8-1 (&lt;strong&gt;USA 854&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 1-2 (Norway 6)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 2 ( Switzerland 136) VS. 5 (&lt;strong&gt;Italy 193&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 2-1 (France 162) VS. GR 7-2 (&lt;strong&gt;Argentina 205&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 4-1 (&lt;strong&gt;Finland 383&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 5-2 (Belgium 124)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 3 (&lt;strong&gt;Wales 395&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. 6 (Puerto Rico 75)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 5-1 (&lt;strong&gt;Australia 464&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 4-2 (Scotland 35)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GR 6-1 (&lt;strong&gt;England 708&lt;/strong&gt;) VS. GR 3-2 (West Indies 31)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 2 (Portugal 135) VS. 7 (&lt;strong&gt;Denmark 245&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TEAM 1 (&lt;strong&gt;USA&lt;/strong&gt; 569) VS. TEAM 8 (Argentina 14)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TEAM 3 (&lt;strong&gt;Canada&lt;/strong&gt; 290) VS. TEAM 6 (Finland 145)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 1 (Chile 116) VS. 8 (&lt;strong&gt;Germany&lt;/strong&gt;330)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;01:00AM(SUN)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TEAM 3 (&lt;strong&gt;England&lt;/strong&gt; 278) VS. TEAM 7 (Sweden 72)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TEAM 4 (&lt;strong&gt;Australia&lt;/strong&gt; 284) VS. TEAM 5 (New Zealand 56)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;01:10AM(SUN)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CONSOLATION 7 (&lt;strong&gt;Denmark&lt;/strong&gt; 332) VS. 8 (Puerto Rico 169)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>articles</category><category>blood and thunder world cup 2014</category><category>bout reports</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/07/roller-derby-world-cup-day-3-review/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 09:05:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blood and Thunder World Cup Day 1 Review</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/05/blood-and-thunder-world-cup-day-1-review/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, that was exciting. 27 games in the placement groups, lead to the scores in the groups now sitting as below (assuming one point for each win):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BRACKET STRUCTURE COURTESY OF THE WOMENS FLAT TRACK DERBY ASSOCIATION (DAY 1)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GROUP 8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NEW ZEALAND 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FRANCE 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SWEDEN 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FINLAND 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AUSTRALIA 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ENGLAND 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CANADA 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;USA 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NORWAY 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SWITZERLAND 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WEST INDIES 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SCOTLAND 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ITALY 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GERMANY 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DENMARK 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PUERTO RICO 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SOUTH AFRICA 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BRAZIL 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;JAPAN 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COLOMBIA 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BELGIUM 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SPAIN 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ARGENTINA 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;THE NETHERLANDS 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WALES 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PORTUGAL 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CHILE 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MEXICO 0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GREECE 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;IRELAND 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
While &lt;a href="http://www.derbycentral.net/2014/12/2014-roller-derby-world-cup-central/"&gt;Derby Central&lt;/a&gt; is working hard on a more complete review of the day, we'll try to summarise a bit before we talk about Scotland.
&lt;p&gt;We believe that the structure for the tournament is that the 4th-placed team in any group will drop out after the group rounds, the 3rd position will take the Consolation position with the same number as their group, and the 1st and 2nd positions will enter the Elimination rounds to play for ranking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, New Zealand, France, Sweden, Finland, Australia, Ireland, Canada and the USA are all safely through to the Elimination rounds already, as 2pts would already place them all at 1st or 2nd place in their group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South Africa, Switzerland, Mexico, Italy are probably already "out" after losing both their games, with only a tough game left today, although Switzerland have a chance at winning their game v Brazil and bringing their group to a points-difference call; West Indies and Japan will play to see which of them gets into the Consolation round for their group today, as will Germany &amp;amp; Spain, Denmark &amp;amp; Argentina, Puerto Rico &amp;amp; The Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Scotland in particular, they played two bouts on Thursday:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some brilliant play against Mexico, Team Scotland picked up their important first win, displaying good control of the track for the entire 40 minute game. Beautiful jamming from Jenny "Attackbar" Gow, Marshall Lawless and Rogue Runner in particular, with Mexico's jammers overwhelmed by the usual solid play by "Crazylegs" Parry, Ciderella, (Steph) Skinner Alive, "Splat" Kerr, and Grace "Mona" Maclean on the blocking side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finland proved a tougher test for Scotland, as they were always going to be. Nevertheless, the scores after the first half were within 15 points of each other, and it looked like Scotland were still within reach of a win. After Finland's Mia, jamming, gave away 3 power jams in a row, it looked even more achievable, despite some very hard blocking from Finland making it hard for any of Scotland's talented jammers to pick up points. However, some excellent performances from Finland's star jammer, SuperMaria, and a little penalty trouble, kept Finland's lead ahead, resulting in a Scotland loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 1 pt in the group, Scotland will enter the Consolation round if they fail to defeat Colombia today at 7pm. Given Finland's performance against the Colombians, however, it seems most likely that Scotland will prevail, gaining the 2nd point in the group to place them into the Elimination round as the 2nd place seed from Group 4. (This makes them very likely to play Australia as their first opponent!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of Team Scotland, but still involving Scottish Players: Auld Reekie's Lilo &amp;amp; Stitches contributed strongly to Belgium's jamming line up (under the first part of her birth surname, deBuyl), and Sarah McMillan and Chemikill Hazard were big parts of Ireland's lineups. Jen Sykes, who spent some time down in London, still counts as a Scottish skater now she's up in Glasgow again, and she did her usual sterling work as part of the mighty English team, and Crazily Insanne at least got to play against the USA as part of Team Netherlands (although of course, no-one is going to &lt;em&gt;defeat&lt;/em&gt; team USA!). Scottish referee Righteous Oxide was also spotted officiating several of the bouts, and Granite City's smacklemore was in evidence commentating (including on the Scotland/Finland game).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our full score matrix from Day One is below (&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/33509"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt; are also tracking scores as usual):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THURSDAY, DECEMBER 4, 2014  (40 MINUTE BOUTS)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 1 (ROLL-LINE TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 2 (BLOOD &amp;amp; THUNDER TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRACK 3 (TBD TRACK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NEW ZEALAND&lt;/strong&gt; (218) VS. NORWAY (59)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AUSTRALIA&lt;/strong&gt; (513) VS ITALY (5)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CANADA&lt;/strong&gt; (290) VS. ARGENTINA (50)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:20PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SOUTH AFRICA (97) VS. &lt;strong&gt;WALES &lt;/strong&gt;(200)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BELGIUM&lt;/strong&gt;  (174) VS. GREECE (96)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4:30PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;USA&lt;/strong&gt; (505) VS. NETHERLANDS (15)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:40PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRANCE&lt;/strong&gt; (369) VS. SWITZERLAND (27)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENGLAND&lt;/strong&gt; (272) VS. GERMANY (31)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5:50PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FINLAND&lt;/strong&gt; (248) VS. COLOMBIA (32)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BRAZIL&lt;/strong&gt; (167) VS. PORTUGAL (144)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SPAIN (74) VS. &lt;strong&gt;IRELAND &lt;/strong&gt;(203)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCOTLAND&lt;/strong&gt; (207) VS. MEXICO (45)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8:20PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SWEDEN&lt;/strong&gt; (319) VS. WEST INDIES (41)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CANADA&lt;/strong&gt; (301) VS. DENMARK (23)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8:30PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AUSTRALIA&lt;/strong&gt; (349)VS. BELGIUM (24)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9:40PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;JAPAN (53) VS. &lt;strong&gt;CHILE&lt;/strong&gt; (296)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;USA&lt;/strong&gt; (637) VS. PUERTO RICO (3)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9:50PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ITALY (82) VS. &lt;strong&gt;GREECE &lt;/strong&gt;(125)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11:00PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FINLAND&lt;/strong&gt; (126) VS. SCOTLAND (78)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NEW ZEALAND (315)&lt;/strong&gt; VS. SOUTH AFRICA (15)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11:10PM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENGLAND&lt;/strong&gt; (290) VS. SPAIN (20)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;00:20AM(FRI)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COLOMBIA&lt;/strong&gt; (163) VS. MEXICO (75)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NORWAY&lt;/strong&gt; (150) VS. WALES (105)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;00:30AM(FRI)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GERMANY (129) VS. &lt;strong&gt;IRELAND&lt;/strong&gt; (142)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;01:40AM(FRI)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRANCE&lt;/strong&gt; (315) VS. BRAZIL (14)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SWEDEN&lt;/strong&gt; (459) VS. JAPAN (0)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;01:50AM(FRI)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SWITZERLAND (132) VS. &lt;strong&gt;PORTUGAL&lt;/strong&gt; (139)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>articles</category><category>bout reports</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/05/blood-and-thunder-world-cup-day-1-review/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 12:40:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interviews: UK and Ireland</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/20/world-cup-interviews-uk-and-ireland/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last week, our &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; tour covered The UK and Ireland. Over the weekend, Ireland, Wales and Scotland (and Team West Indies) played against each other in the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/724704624268299/"&gt;Road to Dallas&lt;/a&gt; tournament, with Scotland placing 1st, ahead of Ireland in second place, and the hosts, Wales, taking up the 4th place position, despite a close game against third-place West Indies.
If you missed any of our interviews, here’s a recap…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Ireland" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/14/world-cup-interview-team-ireland/"&gt;Team Ireland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Wales" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/15/world-cup-interview-team-wales/"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Scotland" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/16/world-cup-interview-team-scotland/"&gt;Team Scotland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team England" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/17/world-cup-interview-team-england/"&gt;Team England&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week we will be hopping over to Scandinavia to interview the teams from Norway, Denmark, Finland and Sweden!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team england</category><category>team ireland</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>team wales</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/20/world-cup-interviews-uk-and-ireland/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 09:50:52 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>