<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about team scotland)</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/team-scotland.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:54:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Big Blether 2: Mean City host the return of the Scottish Derby community meetup.</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/06/big-blether-2-mean-city-host-the-return-of-the-scottish-derby-community-meetup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, the Scottish Roller Derby Community made a bit of history, by finally getting together in one place for a &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/18/the-big-blether-scotland-together/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big Blether&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This wasn't just a disorganised chat, of course: this was the first ever Roller Derby Conference for Scottish derby, on the model of the European "EROC". On the 7th of October 2017, the vast majority of active Scottish leagues were represented by pairs of delegates [and all but one of those who couldn't make it sent statements by proxy], actively engaged in process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-24409 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/screen-shot-2017-09-13-at-16-17-08.png" alt="Screen Shot 2017-09-13 at 16.17.08" width="335" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the first Big Blether was the brainchild of Auld Reekie Roller Girls' Crazylegs and Skinner, and Glasgow Roller Derby's Head Referee, Candy Moho, it was also agreed that future convocations would pass the torch onto other leagues around the country, spreading the democratic work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as it goes, the first volunteers to do the hard thing of repeating previous success were Glasgow's All-Gender league, Mean City Roller Derby. Very slightly more than a year later, their iteration of the conference, Big Blether 2, is coming to central Glasgow on the 20th October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principal task of a repeat convention is more nuanced than that of a first meeting. The first Big Blether did great things in generating conversation; in spreading knowledge [we personally enjoyed the group discussion elements, and how well they were orchestrated] and sharing problems. &lt;em&gt;More importantly&lt;/em&gt;, it generated actions - foci for future progress and development, mutually agreed by all those present. (It also gained Scottish derby a little bit of publicity, via an article in Five On Five magazine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second Big Blether will have the equally hard task of looking at those actions, a year later, and seeing what has been done, what has not; correcting course, potentially, or pushing forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it might do us well to look at what actions the first Big Blether produced, across the multiple sessions it held (these were scheduled as pairs of parallel sessions, run as facilitated group discussions):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby Oversight&lt;/strong&gt; spread some useful information (and quashed some misapprehensions) about the existing governance structures in Roller Derby. The action produced was to develop a "&lt;strong&gt;Scottish Derby Lobbying Group&lt;/strong&gt;" to provide a unified voice for the Scottish community in representing our needs and desires to larger entities.
We followed up on this, and believe that at least some work was done towards this aim, but as yet there is no formal group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Game Scheduling&lt;/strong&gt; produced some frank discussion between leagues about competition for resources; the low ratio of leagues to halls and fans (as well as to officials), the network effects which mean that smaller leagues can be accidentally outcompeted by older, more established clubs, and so on. The actions for this session were to more strongly adopt the shared &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby Schedule&lt;/strong&gt; for scheduling bouts and events (this common document is hosted on Google Docs, and made available via links in the Scottish Derby Facebook group) and to consider &lt;strong&gt;Sharing Fixtures with Other Leagues&lt;/strong&gt;.
We've seen use of the Schedule increase significantly since the first Big Blether, and there have been a number of "shared fixtures", so we think these actions have been broadly successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Officiating&lt;/strong&gt; involved some extensive discussions about the widespread issues of officials recruitment and training (and respect within leagues). The action for this session was to promote more central training and learning opportunities for Officials (on and off skates) - a &lt;strong&gt;Ref School&lt;/strong&gt; to be run by Glasgow Roller Derby - and for leagues to work towards giving their officials a more "cohesive identity" to form around and generally &lt;strong&gt;treat them as first class citizens&lt;/strong&gt; of the sport.
The Glasgow Roller Derby Ref School has run a few sessions (and Dundee have continued to run their own series of Officiating bootcamps, extant before Big Blether); and the branding of several league's officials as their own "teams" seems to represent a start of the second action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session on &lt;strong&gt;Access to Scottish Derby&lt;/strong&gt; revolved around the perennial issues of costs, access to halls and training certifications; as well as problems with providing kit, and burnout in "highly active" members of the community; and the less discussed issues with cultural homogeneity in derby. This session produced a lot of "personal actions" for leagues to &lt;strong&gt;Share More Resources&lt;/strong&gt;, and investigate community Volunteering Schemes.
It's difficult to measure how well this has been progressed without hearing from all the leagues - so this will be a point of discussion in October!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting as a whole also produced actions to produce and maintain a &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby Ranking&lt;/strong&gt;, which would enable a &lt;strong&gt;Scottish Roller Derby National Tournament&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Scottish League or Championships&lt;/strong&gt;.
These have progressed very slightly (there's an initial Scottish Derby Ranking derived from Flat Track Stats Europe ratings), but on the meat of the matter - an organised competitive structure - there's a lot of work to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The second ever Big Blether will give those actioned a chance to report on their progress, as well as discussing any new topics which have developed in the past 12 months - since that year has seen three World Cups, a changing structure in other International Gameplay, and at least one new style of Roller Derby, we’re sure that there will be lots to talk about.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2nd Big Blether will be hosted on the 20th October 2018, in &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/bsRwxpsb6Do"&gt;Glasgow Quakers Meeting House, Elmbank Crescent, Glasgow. G2 4PS&lt;/a&gt;. Final timings to be decided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams can register representatives (as can independents) here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSf5LLsKjK3egYsLrcJNX8vWnnoRV5DRErii42kKAsANWbbP-w/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSf5LLsKjK3egYsLrcJNX8vWnnoRV5DRErii42kKAsANWbbP-w/viewform&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;REGISTRATION CLOSES 1 OCTOBER.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can contribute to the discussion topics on offer, and shape the schedule, via this form here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeiKb3UVcj1mKjVAeZmUVUY5krWkziPGH7HKCR4OQirmRKATQ/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeiKb3UVcj1mKjVAeZmUVUY5krWkziPGH7HKCR4OQirmRKATQ/viewform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>communication</category><category>in the news</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>officials</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>team scotland</category><category>the big blether</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/06/big-blether-2-mean-city-host-the-return-of-the-scottish-derby-community-meetup/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 10:00:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Scotland Events: Fundraiser coming to a close!</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/06/team-scotland-events-fundraiser-coming-to-a-close/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While over on Facebook, we've been regularly sharing info about the preparations for the various National Teams heading for the two Roller Derby World Cups next year... we've been saving a blog post for the Scottish National teams, starting with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Team-Scotland-Roller-Derby-235701999922927/"&gt;Team Scotland Roller Derby.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13779 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/scotland.png" alt="scotland" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In common with many of the teams heading for the 3rd Roller Derby World Cup in Trafford, England, Team Scotland are &lt;a href="https://www.crowdfunder.co.uk/team-scotland-roller-derby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;raising money&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to support their attendance. (Being a National Team has all the costs you would expect, from training venues, equipment, travel and accommodation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a special consideration this time around, &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; of the funds raised by TS will be donated to the charity &lt;strong&gt;Mind&lt;/strong&gt;, in support of mental health - and if you feel like you need a more tangible personal benefit for donating, all donations above &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; are eligible for Team Scotland branded merch, with donations above &lt;strong&gt;£75&lt;/strong&gt; enabling you to sponsor a specific Team Scotland Rostered Skater (who will wear a sponsors patch provided, during the World Cup).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have just until the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; to donate to the fundraiser, and help it reach its goal of just £2000, so please consider donating!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donation link is here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.crowdfunder.co.uk/team-scotland-roller-derby/"&gt;https://www.crowdfunder.co.uk/team-scotland-roller-derby/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in competing with Team Scotland, as well as supporting them, there's also the opportunity still to sign up as part of the mash-up team who will get to scrim against TS at their November training session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up in the Manhattan Works venue (Dundee Roller Girls' training venue), you will get to play with the best skaters that Scotland has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's still time to sign up here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/111479986185051/?"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/111479986185051/?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, if you'd like to help Team Scotland, rather than compete against them, applications are now open for the position of "Team Sports Therapist" attending the team for their training sessions, and competition, including the World Cup itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apply here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScwqegWr0F1-lAoO0hrXqrFLDx-fi1ueSwz7K9wZP4D3HugcA/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScwqegWr0F1-lAoO0hrXqrFLDx-fi1ueSwz7K9wZP4D3HugcA/viewform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on in the Year, Team Scotland will be making appearances at a few other events, so stay tuned to see how you can catch them on track before the World Cup!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>crowdfunding</category><category>fundraising</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/06/team-scotland-events-fundraiser-coming-to-a-close/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 14:13:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Upcoming National Teams Bouts</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/12/upcoming-national-teams-bouts/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With both World Cups now less than a year away - the&lt;a href="http://www.rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;in February, and the &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in April, there's an increasing number of National Teams related fixtures being announced, as all the teams get in some practice, some visibility, and some fundraising opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's easy to miss what's happening, so maybe it helps to keep them all in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the events we're aware of (and do please let us know if we've missed anything!)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Women's National Teams&lt;/h3&gt;
15th July: Equipe de &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt; play an exhibition bout hosted by Les Passeuses Dâmes [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1394914887229155/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;p&gt;15th July: Team &lt;strong&gt;Portugal&lt;/strong&gt; have an open training session for Portuguese skaters [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1887307271583565/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16 July: at least some of Team &lt;strong&gt;Germany&lt;/strong&gt; are at Euro Derby Con participating in events [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/596116850567901/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22 July: Team &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; Roller Derby turn up to play London Rollergirls B, the Brawl Saints as part of a double header in London [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/431163560596192/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29 July: Team &lt;strong&gt;Korea&lt;/strong&gt; and Team &lt;strong&gt;Philippines&lt;/strong&gt; make their world debuts at Rollercon, playing against each other on Saturday! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/143735569514656/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29 July: Team &lt;strong&gt;South Africa&lt;/strong&gt; have their final round of tryouts! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1932492993665870/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5-6 August: Team &lt;strong&gt;England&lt;/strong&gt; host Team &lt;strong&gt;Sweden&lt;/strong&gt;, Team &lt;strong&gt;Finland&lt;/strong&gt; and Team &lt;strong&gt;Canada&lt;/strong&gt; for a weekend round-robin event, in Nottingham! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1883460565201595/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5-6 August: &lt;strong&gt;Aotearoa&lt;/strong&gt; Roller Derby (Team &lt;strong&gt;New Zealand&lt;/strong&gt;) play a black v white scrim, followed by a bootcamp run by their coach, Mick Swagger. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/147390622507530/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 August: Team &lt;strong&gt;England&lt;/strong&gt; will also be scrimming with an open subscription team after that round-robin [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/203298956860930/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 August, 20th August: Team&lt;strong&gt; West Indies&lt;/strong&gt; scrim against all comers in two open subscription bouts in Bedford (6th) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1962826457294629/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;] and Birmingham (20th) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/738090882982520/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 September: Team &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; will be taking on a scrimmage against an open subscription team [Applications open] [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1874512536208906/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23 September: Équipe de &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt; Feminine host a fixture against 2 undisclosed National Teams, in Tourcoing, France [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/276715376142982/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 October: Team &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt; host Team Italy and Team Netherlands for a triple header [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/298561590623060/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;Austria&lt;/strong&gt; are hosting Team Germany and Team Switzerland for a triple header [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/138743263531937/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; are playing an undisclosed team in Dublin [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/666484320215767/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; are again scrimmaging with an open subscription team (applications open) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/111479986185051/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;England&lt;/strong&gt; take on an undisclosed team in Peterborough. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/105377736693871/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2-3 December: Team &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt; welcomes undisclosed opponents to the Road to Manchester tournament! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/222986121542528/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Men's National Teams&lt;/h3&gt;
(Some time during this period, Team &lt;strong&gt;Finland&lt;/strong&gt; are planning... something.)
&lt;p&gt;15 July: Team &lt;strong&gt;New Zealand&lt;/strong&gt; have their tryouts in Kawerau [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/287594671647468/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23 July: Team &lt;strong&gt;England's&lt;/strong&gt; Stage 1 Tryouts (open submission) happen in Nottingham [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1409006599141670/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5-6 August: Team &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt; host the Torneo Barcelona City... but aren't playing in it? [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1906063339640738/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 October: Team &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt; have a mysterious event [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/246263629227122/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18-19 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;Netherlands&lt;/strong&gt; hosts &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Italy&lt;/strong&gt; in a "Road to Barcelona" event. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/259318537912275/?"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18-19 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;Germany&lt;/strong&gt; hosts undisclosed opponents in a... "Road to Barcelona" event [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/482556138758766/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25 November: Team &lt;strong&gt;England&lt;/strong&gt; take on an undisclosed team in Peterborough (double header with Women's team above) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/105377736693871/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2018</category><category>team scotland</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/12/upcoming-national-teams-bouts/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 16:08:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: Team Scotland Roller Derby</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/14/euroclash-interviews-team-scotland-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With less than two weeks to go before &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.euro-clash.com"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;' first International Tournament - we're also now just two interviews away from covering all of the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This interview is a particularly special one for us, though, as we're covering the second National Team attending EuroClash - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Team-Scotland-Roller-Derby-235701999922927/"&gt;Team Scotland Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current Team Scotland has only played publicly in two events: The Road to TBC in Cardiff last year (placing 6th); and against Team Belgium in February. Neither of those events featured the final roster of skaters, however: EuroClash will be the first public appearance of the Final 20 in competition.
At EuroClash, Team Scotland will be competing against Team Ireland, who they lost to (in a very tough game for both teams) in Cardiff. This time around, with more training, and the final 20 selection, TS will be hoping to change the result.
The Team Ireland/ Team Scotland bout at EuroClash is a National Teams Event leading up to the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 2018 in Trafford, Greater Manchester, hosted by Rainy City Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13779 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/scotland.png" alt="scotland" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to properly represent Team Scotland, we talked to Crazylegs - the sole three-times member of the Team Scotland roster, and Malin Landsborough - one of the skaters new to the team this time around - about all things Team Scotland and EuroClash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Scotland has been at both previous World Cups - placing 11th the first time, and around the same place the second (slightly underranked each time). The Scottish spirit has always been strong - but how has the experience of the National Team changed (if it has) between versions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crazylegs: It’s definitely changed a lot from World Cup to World Cup; I'd like to say the uniforms have been getting better, but we went from the unfortunate dresses of 2011, to the giant name misprints in 2014, and our training shirts for 2017 have been causing all sorts of jammer body part entrapment issues with the loose arm holes. Let's hope for a successful 2018 squad uniform - we are wide open for sponsorship if anyone is up for a challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess for Toronto in 2011, everything was an unknown - I kept a proper daily diary during my 2011 World Cup journey and I read it back the other day; mind blowing. We knew absolutely nothing! It was the first time any of us had been part of such a big tournament structure and outside of Europe. For a lot of skaters it was their first time skating outside of Scotland. We were excited by every single thing - every shout out, every freebie, the school buses, every time someone asked us to sign a programme. Our wee Scotch corner of supporters made us cry, it was so cool to see people travel to far to come and cheer. I remember being totally shocked that they came!
It happened again in Dallas, with our amazing support from home, and by 2014 we knew much more about setting expectations with skaters and planning and organising beforehand so it was a bit of a calmer experience, but still, playing National teams is always going to be a bit of an unknown because we don’t tend to see them regularly play outside of WC tournaments, and, coupled with shorter qualifier games, and a last minute changing schedule, it’s definitely a different kind of challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, I think we’re focusing more on heads-down regular team training just now, we started sooner and that will hopefully give us more time to build on skills and tactics as a team and will translate into a more consistent level of play for Manchester. The team is looking really strong with a load of potential and I’m all fired up for my third World Cup!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This iteration of Team Scotland's first public outing was at The Road to TBC, long before the selection happened. Despite the early point in TS' training, the team placed pretty well, although the close bout against Spain was unlucky for your resulting placement. What were the high points for you at the tournament, and what did you learn from it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C: It was great! I think the best thing that any team can do to forge fast bonds and get to know each other really well is to travel together and play in a tournament, so for that reason it was a huge success for our training squad, we have a team of characters and they are all lovely. We got to know each other better, learned how we each react to nerves, pressure and being away from our usual team environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was challenging because as a training squad of 30, the management selected teams by picking from a hat, and we also had skaters playing in multiple positions to test out strengths, so we really had to approach it as a training opportunity, which can be difficult in a public tournament, but I think we managed beautifully and the whole team vibe in the games was really positive and focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few of the team got to learn just how bad I am at navigating Google Maps, yet how amazing I am at summoning random taxis to resolve emergency lost-in-Wales situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malin: Road to TBC was a great opportunity for the team to skate together early on in the TS training, and because of this (still being the top 30) we couldn’t all skate in it. But as one of those whose name unfortunately didn’t come up for it, I still truly enjoyed watching it from the side line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel the high point of this tournament was really that it brought us together as a team! It allowed us the chance to really get to know each other in a competitive setting early on in our training. Plus the performance that Scotland put out was fantastic to see – too many close games for my wee heart to take. It did also help us identify our training focuses in moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One striking thing about this Team Scotland selection is the continuing increase in the proportion of Dundee (and Granite City) skaters in the 20. The 2011 TS was almost entirely Auld Reekie and Glasgow, and now all 4 teams are much more equally represented. How does it feel [Malin] to be part of this trend, and what do you [both] think it says about the development of roller derby in Scotland?
&lt;/strong&gt;
C: I think this is a really important question. It's great to see a broader spread of skaters representing from across the teams in Scotland, it's kind of shaping up to look how it should and I think this is reflected in a few other countries this time around. Having wider representation means a more extensive set of experiences to draw from on the team. I'd love to see that trend continue and see competition in Scotland being pushed year on year across all competitive teams, so that we collectively drive the level of play much higher for the athletes here who aspire to that, and want to find the hardest challenges without always having to travel so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to help us build a Team Scotland that the strongest eligible players in our sport are all really keen to be part of, and we can enable that with smart planning; aligning training and game commitments, creating clear training and rest cycles and by working to understand the sanctioned play demands on the skaters teams taking part in WFTDA Play Offs or British Champs - all of which happens in tandem with the National team training. Having that understanding of the priorities of the leagues and teams representing on Team Scotland can ensure that we get the best out of our athletes. This will ensure the continued growth of our sport in National and local play and this is really important as we move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M: It’s a fantastic feeling to be part of such an increase of Northern skaters making the TS cut: we at Dundee have been putting so much into our training the past couple of years, so to make it to this point just cements to us that it is all worth it. For so many of us to make the training squad was such an incredible achievement, especially looking back to the last selection where we at Dundee only had wee Milky representing us, words couldn’t even describe the feeling finding out such a high percent of us made the top 20! This feeling is only heightened by the response we received when the selection was made public, the support we feel behind us is incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is incredible to see the development in Scottish Roller Derby over the past few years! The support we have received from the larger Scottish leagues has been inspiring and has allowed us to level up (and gain WFTDA apprenticeship). Passing on knowledge and camaraderie throughout Scottish derby has brought all levels of leagues together; it’s exciting to see how all the Scottish teams are moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This interview is partly to promote the EuroClash Tournament in Newcastle. Speaking of that, Team Scotland will be attending to compete with Ireland again, who you last encountered at Road to TBC. How are you preparing for the rematch, and what do you hope to achieve this time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C: Team Ireland is such a good, solid team to play, we never seem to get pitched against them in WC tournaments, so it’s great to play them outside of that. There was a lot of positive feedback from within our team about that game – we felt like we had some really strong moments. It was one of those ‘if only we’d had 20 more minutes’ games! It will be really interesting to play again so soon and I hope we can better our score differential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like Team Scotland is hitting the ground running having just been given news of the final squad, so there really hasn’t been much time to prepare for this one - but we have been training every month for the last few months and we have a lot of trust in each other. A lot of the Team Scotland skaters are playing in 2 or 3 of our own league games in the tournament, so we’ll be nice and warmed up for the Ireland game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M: Yes, when we played at Road to TBC it was a close, hard fought game on both sides. As a league we’re continuing with our training focuses and gelling as a team on track, so we can go into this rematch as a united front. This is another step on our road to Greater Manchester, so if we can use this opportunity to put everything we’ve been training into practice, it’ll be a success to us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love a rematch and can’t wait to meet the Team Ireland squad on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And when you're not on skates, what teams or games are you most looking forward to catching?
&lt;/strong&gt;
C: I'm really looking forward to seeing Paris play and also Tiger Bay - I've not seen either of those teams play for a wee while, and both are usually really good to watch. Auld Reekie are playing Paris in April, so it's always good to get a wee spy on them beforehand. I'll be playing with Auld Reekie against MMR, Berlin and the new Leeds team at EuroClash, and I think each of those games will offer a really good and potentially very different kind of challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M: It’ll be great to see all the talent on show throughout the weekend, but I have to say I’m most excited to be there to support our pals at ARRG through their games!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's next for Team Scotland on the road to Greater Manchester?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C: There will be lots of scrimmage and game opportunities set up before the WC I'm sure - we've just upped our training to twice monthly, and our management are looking about for opportunities to help us train against the toughest teams. After Euro Clash we'll probably know more about team positions and move into a more focused training cycle. I'd love to play some more of the European teams in preparation, because we can get to them fairly easily. We'll also most definitely be working on our uniform game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M: I think for Team Scotland moving forward will be for us to settle into our positions within the team and understand how we all work together, just like any newly formed team. It’s great to see how we’ve improved from the first selection to the final 20 and so I’m excited to see this carry on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also anticipating a busy period of fundraising leading up to Greater Manchester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, given the performance of Scotland in the last two World Cups - and the likely even greater scope of the 2018 Roller Derby World Cup in Greater Manchester - how are you hoping that Scotland will do third time around?
&lt;/strong&gt;
C: Well obviously, we want to win it. Falling somewhere above USA, Australia and Team England would be fab :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M: If we can improve on our position from the previous World Cups that would be fantastic, but this is a huge opportunity to bring back experience and knowledge from higher level roller derby, which can only benefit Scottish Roller Derby as a whole. EXCITED!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash will be held from the &lt;strong&gt;25th&lt;/strong&gt; to the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/strong&gt;, Newcastle. Ticket available here:&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets"&gt;https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; , and on the door.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>euroclash</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/14/euroclash-interviews-team-scotland-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 10:07:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: Auld Reekie Roller Girls</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/10/euroclash-interviews-auld-reekie-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a bonus for this week, we're returning to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for one more interview before the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we're talking to&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk"&gt; Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The second oldest league in Scotland, ARRG have been active on the European stage almost as long as they've been competing - and their trip to the USA last year was their third. Whilst they qualified for WFTDA Division 2 Playoffs in 2016, the team declined the invitation for a host of good reasons - unfortunately, given the changes in competitive divisions in 2017, it will be harder work to make it a second year running.
Last year, Auld Reekie's All-Stars competed against Dublin and Newcastle out of the other EuroClash attendees - with a win against the former, and mixed results (a win and a loss) against the latter.
Team Scotland Roller Derby, who will also be competing at EuroClash, have 6 Auld Reekie skaters on their roster of 20, so they will also be represented in the bout between Ireland and Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13740 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/arrg-logo.png" alt="arrg-logo" width="200" height="89"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auld Reekie's Sharlotte Patterson (also a Team Scotland Rostered skater) talked to us about the team's past and future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The ARRG All-Stars had a pretty good 2016 - starting off with a couple of wins against two other EuroClash attendees, Dublin and Newcastle.What was the high point of the year for you?&lt;/strong&gt;
Oh my goodness where to start? It was a fantastic year for us. We really played well together as a team. It’s hard to pick just one point in the year, there were so many good times for ARRG and myself. I think that I am just proud to a part of this wonderful team and play with very talented people. Everyone works hard at fostering togetherness and making us all feel like part of a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You then went across the Atlantic to compete in the Big O 2016, a return to the tournament from 2014. Despite facing even tougher opponents than the last time, we think you held up pretty well and reached the playoffs selection point with a high enough ranking to be invited to D2, which you declined. Overall, how was the transatlantic experience - does it ever get "normal" to travel across to the USA? And do you think you'll be keeping up the tradition, now that more WFTDA things are being scheduled on this side of the Atlantic?&lt;/strong&gt;
The Big O was an incredible experience and it was my first time visiting the USA. It was a really good environment and the organisers of the tournament were super welcoming. It was a great chance for the team to bond being together for a long period of time away from home.
I’m not sure you could ever say that it be ‘normal’ to travel such a huge distance to play roller derby - an amazing experience, yes! One that I will always remember as my first far flung trip away and my first tournament. The team were really strong and we came out with some very good results which helped us move up the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to say anything further on tradition about going over but it is really exciting that there are more WFTDA things being scheduled this side of the Atlantic; this will mean more opportunities for European teams as cost is always something that will impact teams on going far away for games. I can’t wait to see how this progresses and watch/play in all the high level derby that is out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coming up this weekend, though, you're still giving yourselves the tough challenges, playing current-hot-stuff league in the UK, Rainy City Roller Derby! How did that come about, and how are you feeling about challenging the WFTDA #26 team?&lt;/strong&gt;
This was a game arranged last year, and we have travelled down to scrimmage Rainy on a few occasions over the last year. They are a lovely team to play against and it has provided us with some valuable extra training.
This weekend is going to be an incredibly challenging game but one we can absolutely rise to the challenge of. We have been training hard and have had extra team training sessions this year, not just for this game but for our upcoming season. I know that the All Stars will go down and will always give their absolute best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At EuroClash, Auld Reekie will be playing Middlesbrough Milk Rollers, Bear City Roller Derby and Leeds Roller Derby. How are you feeling about the three bouts, and are there any specific plans you're making for them?&lt;/strong&gt;
Really excited. The last time we played against Middlesbrough Milk was back in 2015 for British Champs and it all came down to the last jam. I still replay that in my head at times because I was the jammer for Auld Reekie during the last jam and it was nerve-racking. Bear City and Auld Reekie have played each other a few times in the past and remained fairly close in the rankings. This will be our first time playing the new merged Leeds team. All three games are going to bring their own challenges, but we have been training as hard as we always do and really nailing our tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you're not on skates, are there any teams, or matchups, which you're particularly looking forward to seeing?&lt;/strong&gt;
There’s so many amazing teams taking part in Euro Clash that it’s too hard to pick. I’m really excited to watch all the other teams because each game is going to be as exciting as the next! It’s so good to see such high level teams have the chance to play in a European tournament and hopefully this is the start of many many more to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EuroClash also features a rematch between Team Ireland and Team Scotland. Last time, Ireland had had a single training session, and Scotland had a selection from the training team - this time you both have more experience of playing together, and Scotland has selected its final 20. (Congratulations on being a member!) How did it feel to be selected for the team - and how are you feeling about the rematch with Ireland?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, I am so proud to have been selected as one of the final 20 to play for my country. It’s an honour and I can’t wait to get stuck in. To be able to go to the World Cup to play and watch some of the best skaters in the world is going to be an unforgettable experience. I’m excited about the rematch with Ireland, it’s going be a challenging game as well as a great training opportunity for Team Scotland; we now have our final 20 selected and will be settled into our specific roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After EuroClash, what's next for ARRG's All-Stars? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The All Stars have a trip coming up to play Kallio and Paris at the end of April, and we will also be playing Newcastle again on 27 May. Our league has been pretty busy since the start of the year and our C team the ASTROs have a game against Bairn City on the 25 March and our B team the Reserves will be taking part in their first British Champs game on 22 April. It’s a really exciting time to part of ARRG and we have many more games coming up for all three of our teams over the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash is held between the &lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt;th and &lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt;th &lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt;, by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at the Walker Activity Dome. Tickets available at the EuroClash website: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets"&gt;https://www.euro-clash.com/tickets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the door.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>euroclash</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>team scotland</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/10/euroclash-interviews-auld-reekie-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 12:23:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Seeing in the New: National Teams in Dundee.</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/10/seeing-in-the-new-national-teams-in-dundee/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend sees a double-dose of National Teams action for those in Scotland, as Dundee hosts a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1382676465099043/"&gt;combined event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with Team Scotland Roller Derby and Power of Scotland both on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14736 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/02/tspostb.jpg" alt="tspostb" width="1071" height="400"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, the Training Team for Team Scotland will be holding a Black v White bout, competing against themselves as part of the selection process for the new Team Scotland. After playing as two teams last weekend in Belgium (and winning both games), all of the skaters will be at their best, and bringing you (by definition), the highest level roller derby in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the Power of Scotland roster from the 2016 Men's World Cup will be playing their swansong bout, against Team Belgium Men's Roller Derby. Symbolically, this is their passing of the torch to the new Power of Scotland training team, who are currently undergoing the selection process after their tryouts in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the close connection between the National Teams, we were delighted to be able to talk with Rosie Peacock (PoS 2016 LUM/Assistant Coach, TS 2017/8 Head Coach) and Laura "Milky" Liston (PoS 2016 Coach, member of TS 2017/8 Training Team) about things. Between them, the two were selected to Captain the Team Scotland rosters in Belgium, so they have a great feel for the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First question, then: How did it feel to be selected as a Captain for the bouts last weekend?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rosie:&lt;/em&gt; So, Milky captained both in the end because I had too much caffeine and got super radge... Me and Milks were the only two who were nominated, but it was good the team trusted us to do the thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura&lt;/em&gt;: It was lovely knowing some of the team had nominated us, and it was such an amazing opportunity to Captain the squad, but yeah, we were the two nominated haha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, following up on that: Team Scotland won both their games, with both rosters against Belgium. How do you feel the games went - what are you happiest about, and is there anything you might work on?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rosie&lt;/em&gt;: I think outer defence side walls are really tight and fluid and adaptive; I'd love to work more on our offer credit and jammer pairings, but that's something we can't progress too much further until we have our final squad and definitely establish roles...
I need to keep my temper and not drink red bull when pmsing 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura&lt;/em&gt;: I really loved some of the bonds and partnerships we starting building on track, which I think were really apparent throughout the day. I'm looking forward to seeing how they develop in the final squad. Both of the games brought different challenges so it was great to see how we adapted to the change in gameplay style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And moving to this weekend: obviously we can't talk too much about selection itself, but clearly everyone there is hoping to make the final selection - do you see changes in both your own performance (and gelling) and your teammates already at this point?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura&lt;/em&gt;: Oh definitely. The opportunity to skate with so many high level skaters has really helped strengthen my skating on a personal level. We've been lucky enough to have Belgium and Cardiff to gel as a team in a competitive environment, and I think both have made a really noticeable improvement to our performances as a team together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Both of you have strong connections with Power of Scotland, especially the 2016 Squad who are playing as well - against Belgium! - we know the team are treating this as a "sending off" of the old team, but will a tiny tear be in your eyes to see them playing together for the last time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laura&lt;/em&gt;: Hah! I think I got all my emotions out in Calgary when the whole squad was there. It'll be great to see the guys playing together again but I'm looking forward to seeing what our new squad will look like, and so excited about the future of PoS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rosie&lt;/em&gt;: I'm looking so forward to playing the best sport in the world, with the best group of humans I've had the pleasure to know x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The doors open for the double header at &lt;strong&gt;11:30, Saturday 11th&lt;/strong&gt; February, at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/DISC:+Dundee+International+Sports+Centre/@56.4762694,-2.9611212,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48865cfd69198245:0x74e93fd03837f5ac!8m2!3d56.4762665!4d-2.9589272"&gt;Dundee International Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are &lt;strong&gt;£6&lt;/strong&gt; in advance (from Brown Paper Tickets), &lt;strong&gt;£8&lt;/strong&gt; on the door. (Tickets at: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2794252"&gt;http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2794252&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/10/seeing-in-the-new-national-teams-in-dundee/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 11:19:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2016 in Review</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst on a general level, 2016 has been labelled a bad year (perhaps unfairly - it's been a mixed bag, it's just that the negatives have been big and prominent, and the positives less so), for Roller Derby, in Scotland and World wide, it's been pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're capping off the year by talking about the things that happened in the past 12 months, first in Scotland (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/1"&gt;page 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and secondly across the World (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/2"&gt;page 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;), before rounding up our hopes for 2017 (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/3"&gt;page 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Scotland&lt;/h3&gt;
Scottish Roller Derby continued to Grow: several new leagues popped up, which we recently brought to you [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/06/scotlands-newest-coed-league-inverclyde-roller-derby/"&gt;Inverclyde Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/13/scotlands-newest-northernmost-league-orkney-viqueens/"&gt;Orkney ViQueens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/15/west-lothians-newest-league-west-lothian-roller-derby/"&gt;West Lothian Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/09/glasgow-mens-roller-derby/"&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/30/glasgows-new-inclusive-junior-derby-resistance-roller-derby/"&gt;Resistance Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] and others continued to grow.
Ayrshire Roller Derby had their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/08/16/ayshire-roller-derby-hit-the-track/"&gt;first public bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (against Lothian Derby Dolls) as did &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/12/granite-city-brawlers-debut-home-game/"&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and GMRD, and Helgin Roller Derby  and the renewed Fair City Rollers have scheduled their (joint) first bout for next year (if we were to bet, we'd expect Doonhame Roller Derby to be the next to be bout-ready).
Scotland's only bouting junior derby team, Fierce Valley Roller Cubs, also played their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/07/cubs-take-on-new-opposition/"&gt;first ever interleague bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, against a mixed team from Sheffield and Newcastle.
Even the larger leagues continued to expand, with Auld Reekie Roller Girls' ASTROs founded this year, and taking the number of ARRG travel teams to 3. As our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/19/yearrgly-review-2016/"&gt;Auld Reekie review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; shows, the whole league had a pretty good year, with the All-Stars qualifying for WFTDA Division 2 playoffs (after an impressive performance at The Big O in the USA), and sensibly declining in favour of working on longer term goals.
&lt;p&gt;Further north, both Dundee Roller Girls and Granite City Roller Derby had very good years as well. Both leagues' A-teams performed impressively in their Divisions at British Champs (Granite City qualifying for promotion to Tier 3 from Tier 4, and Dundee just missing out on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/17/british-champs-at-dundee/"&gt;the promotion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to Tier 2 at the Tier-3 playoffs). Whilst Dundee has withdrawn from Champs to focus on their national and international game (especially after playing their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/08/dundees-international-debut/"&gt;first international away&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, in Tenerife, just scant weeks ago), Granite City will indeed be in Tier 3 of Champs next year, alongside Auld Reekie's Reserves! The two leagues' B-teams also had very good years, with Dundee's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/16/a-chat-with-bonnie-colliders-captains-khilleesi-and-g-wrecks/"&gt;Bonnie Colliders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; winning basically every bout they played until ARRG's ASTROs late in the year, and GCRD's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/21/granite-citys-hawks-flock-to-the-arrgmageddon/"&gt;Fight Hawks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; playing three times as much derby as they did in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Central Belt, Bairn City Rollers' Skelpies managed a few bouts, despite many of them also making Power of Scotland, which prevented them taking fixtures in the first half of the year!. Alongside GMRD, they'll be joining the British Champs Men's T3 in 2017, and we expect good things of them. Meanwhile, BCR's &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/12/bairn-city-belters-captain-and-vice-interview-2016/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central Belters&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;continued their own upward rise in the rankings - a win against the newly-reformed Furness Firecrackers sealing that trend for the year, and setting the Belters the challenge of maintaining expectations in 2017 (the problem with upward growth is that people start expecting it to never stop!). The open-gender Belter Skelpers had a much quieter year, taking on just Mean City's coed-team and then hosting Granite City Brawlers and friends for BCR's 4th Anniversary event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Mean City, they were also extremely busy this year, hosting a vast range of events, including &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/24/powers-of-two-at-mean-city/"&gt;double-headers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; supporting Power of Scotland. With the growth of coed leagues in Scotland (several of our newer non-bouting leagues are open), hopefully Mean City will have an even busier year next year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the Scottish Men's National Team, Power of Scotland also had a very big year, representing well at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/30/mrdwc2016-rankings-and-statistics/"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Calgary, placing a creditable 10th, just below the tournament's surprise unseeded upset of Mexico. Several members of the 2016 team are also now involved with Team Scotland Roller Derby, who will be hoping (along with PoS) to represent the nation strongly in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not to say that there weren't some wobbles in Scottish Derby: due to an unfortunate series of retirements, Glasgow Roller Derby has spent the season with a very different roster to 2015, resulting in the 2015 British Champs Champions placing near the bottom of the Premier Division in 2016.  They'll be aiming to pull back their WFTDA ranking position over 2017... although they've retired from British Champs to focus their team on this goal.   Similarly, a series of transfers and other movements lead to Fierce Valley Roller Girls performing less well than they would have liked in the Champs Tier 3, resulting in potential relegation to Tier 4 in 2017. (Despite this, both FVRG and GRD have been drivers of many Scottish events in the past year - Fierce Valley hosting a pair of massive &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/18/the-team-who-sur5ed-fierce-valley-host-harry-potter-themed-open-event/"&gt;Sur5al&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; tournaments and hosting an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/23/international-roller-derby-in-the-forth-valley/"&gt;international&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; against Zurich, and Glasgow hosting &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/28/glasgow-roller-derby-close-the-year-with-festive-charity/"&gt;Charity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; events and playing &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/01/glasgow-at-europes-first-wftda-division-1-tournament/"&gt;all&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/25/glasgow-cross-the-irish-sea-dublin-v-irn-bruisers/"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Europe themselves, as well as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/29/international-derby-at-glasgow-and-edinburgh/"&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Berlin, and playing a big part in Vagine Regime UK.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another growing trend in Scotland (and the UK) this year was "cherry popper" or "rookie" bouts, with almost every league in Scotland hosting at least one such event this year, including Livingston's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/09/new-skaters-on-track-for-new-town-cherry-popper/"&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we shouldn't just talk about the Leagues themselves. Scottish Referees and NSOs also continued to represent at the highest levels of the sport, with Dundee's Righteous Oxide particularly visible at international level events like MRDWC and ; but many other referees like , and NSOs (many of whom were nominated in the TDTM Listener awards) travelled huge distances and devoted much time to supporting the sport.
Scottish photographers were also supporting international events this year, with Dave McAleavy and Laura MacDonald being both ubiquitous at Scottish games, but also travelling to Tenerife in Dave's case, and to the Men's World Cup in Laura's. (As the two are, between them, the photographers for the two national teams, we expect even more travel in their future.)
Our Announcers didn't do too badly either, with Helliverence near-ubiquitous across UK events, Bairn City's man of many names Graeme "Archie" McPhail supporting MEC [and announcing two tournaments in Scotland without a break in each],  MRDWC media director Chasing Katy appearing at several events, but especially MEC, and Granite City's sMACklemore doing both MEC and  Track Head Announcing at MRDWC itself. The latter two also helped to push on the Scottish contributions to Roller Derby media, with the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://tdtmpodcast.wordpress.com/"&gt;Talk Derby To Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; podcast [also hosted by King Crazy] going from strength to strength over the year (especially with their excellent coverage of tournament-level events), culminating in a rather huge Listener Awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(For us at the Scottish Roller Derby Blog, it's also been a good year - we've expanded our coverage again, introduced our own rankings, and even managed to expand into some new fields of video and audio interviews. We also &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/category/mrdwc2016/"&gt;covered&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the Men's Roller Derby World Cup in more depth than we have any previous event. In order to handle this, we &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/"&gt;launched our own annex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to the blog, which hosts links to content which doesn't work well with Wordpress.
We also managed to hit more then 1500 likes on our Facebook page just a few days ago, which was our own goal for 2016!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to Scotland (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/1"&gt;page 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) , forward to "The Future" (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/3"&gt;page 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;UK and Europe&lt;/h3&gt;
Obviously one of the most exciting developments of 2016 was the announcement of so much International Derby coming to Europe in the next two years. Both World Cups will be in Europe - the Men's in Barcelona and the Women's in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/05/a-rainy-day-for-international-roller-derby/"&gt;Greater Manchester&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - in 2018; but before that, one MRDA playoff and the Championship itself will be in Europe as well.
With so many Europe-wide international tournaments already happening in Europe (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/"&gt;ERDT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/27/a-quick-analysis-of-road-to-tbc/"&gt;The Road to...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, SKOD, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/17/first-time-tournament-announcing-or-how-chasing-katy-survived-mec-2o16/"&gt;MEC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/01/glasgow-at-europes-first-wftda-division-1-tournament/"&gt;European Smackdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and so on... with Newcastle's EuroClash joining the set in 2017), this was almost inevitable at some point, but no-one expected everything but WFTDA to happen at once.
&lt;p&gt;Another positive development in the UK was the coming together of Coaches at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/03/uks-first-coaching-summit-derby-stance/"&gt;Derby Stance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Coaching Summit (followed by the Summit at the Ramps, which brought together skaters from multiple disciplines) organised by Rule 56 and the Female Coaching Network. We're very much in favour of people working together to progress the community...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...which is also why we were cheered by the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/19/by-their-powers-combined-they-are-leeds-roller-derby/"&gt;announcement very recently&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that Leeds Roller Derby had formed from fusion of Hot Wheel and Leeds Roller Dolls. We'd love to report on more "collaborations" rather than the politics which leads to splits in Roller Derby, and hope this can be a trend for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Roller Derby media also had some growth in the UK as well, with two new podcasts - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hellyeahrollerderby.com/"&gt;Hell Yeah! Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Croydon and elsewhere] and the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://goodarrows.libsyn.com/podcast"&gt;Good Arrows Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Nottingham Roller Derby] both launching this year, with good content already!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;International&lt;/h3&gt;
Internationally, the most exciting places for Roller Derby are always where growth and development is still raring ahead.
&lt;p&gt;So, in East Asia, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/"&gt;Japan Open Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was possibly the most significant event of the year - the first ever international tournament in the region, hosted in Okinawa and with attendees from the Pacific Region, Australiasia and beyond (Alaska and Copenhagen!). We're very excited to see what the sequel (now managed directly by a consortium of the Japanese leagues) tournament - the Tomodachi in March 2017 - manages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also in East Asia, after literally years of development, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/"&gt;first ever public bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in China happened, with Beijing Roller Derby hosting a mixed team from the rest of the Asian leagues. This was also a great example of the still-political purpose of Roller Derby, as the event was in promotion of the UN HeForShe project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growth has also continued in other regions, with Latin America now hosting a huge number of teams (although their terminology for leagues and teams differs from the USA and Europe), including 3 now in WFTDA (as full members, with more Apprentices). Across Europe and the Middle East, increasing number of countries are growing not just one, but multiple teams - and in the more established countries we've seen huge growth in national level tournaments (the French Nationale is a mighty thing), and other regular events (for ex. the Finnish &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/06/the-pohjola-cup-finland-and-russia-compete/"&gt;Pohjola Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; now trans-national as it includes Russia's White Night Furies this year).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of National Teams representation, 2016 has seen continued growth in both the Men's and Women's parts of the sport - MRDWC 2016 saw a massive surge in teams attending, filling out Europe and Latin America [Colombia having a last-minute technical hitch which prevented this being even more impressive]; and there are already at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/22/new-nations-in-the-world-cup/"&gt;least 5 new Nations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the 2018 Roller Derby World Cup in Manchester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we were very pleased that WFTDA has started adopting positive policies such as releasing the (alpha) of their new bout stats management tool, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/19/bouttime-open-source-what-is-it-and-why-is-it-relevant-to-roller-derby-and-wftda/"&gt;bouttime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, as an open-source project, truly for the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And International Derby Media has also continued to grow, with the startling appearance of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://thederbyapex.com/@thederbyapex"&gt;The Derby Apex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; earlier this year, and their meteoric rise to popularity. We're sure we'll see more good things from them in 2017 and beyond. (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.derbycentral.net/"&gt;Derby Central&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, of course, continued to do great work, covering all of the international things above, and many more.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to Scotland (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/1"&gt;page 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and back to the World (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/2"&gt;page 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The Future&lt;/h3&gt;
So, what would we like to see in 2017?
&lt;h4&gt;National Teams leveraging PR to promote growth in their "home" nations.&lt;/h4&gt;
Whilst Teams Korea, Philippines and West Indies are all representing their nations, none of them have any leagues &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; those nations to draw skaters from. With all three declaring their intent to use their existence to promote the sport, we'd love to see this bear fruit. (Korea has a league, but like most leagues in East Asia [except Kamikaze Badass in Tokyo, and Tokyo Roller Girls' Neon Roller Monsters team] it is almost entirely composed of non-nationals.)
&lt;h4&gt;The Derby Apex's "Stat Rataissance" actually happening.&lt;/h4&gt;
One of The Apex's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://thederbyapex.com/our-10-favourite-things-from-the-2016-wftda-season-d516ae8284e4#.jmhiwv3pm"&gt;high points&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of the year has been the improved availability of stats for WFTDA bouts, alongside the promotion of bouttime. We're a little more skeptical of this as a global phenomenon - Roller Derby is not just WFTDA teams [in fact, they're still a minority, especially if you include the fact that only A teams count for WFTDA member leagues], and stats availability for the sport as a whole is still relatively poor, despite the best efforts of Flat Track Stats and others. We'd like to see this happen, though, and still have some hope. (Our own effort in this regard - the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; rating system - is still very much dependant on FTS's own records, which are themselves dependant on both the site's few volunteers and the Roller Derby community itself.)
&lt;h4&gt;Increased openness, transparency and collaboration.&lt;/h4&gt;
One reason why stats are an issue feeds into this next wish: Roller Derby still has problems with openness and transparency. The bouttime release was definitely a positive step from WFTDA, but we think that most Derby bodies (international and national) could improve on their transparency (the MRDA gets points for having a public forum!) and communication. Alongside this, we'd also like to see positive elements of collaboration continue to grow - more things like Derby Stance, more mergers of leagues to make stronger bodies, and generally more "derby spirit".
&lt;h4&gt;A WFTDA Playoff outside North America (and a non-US team winning Champs).&lt;/h4&gt;
As The Apex noted, WFTDA is now the only major entity with "international" contests not to have some component held outside North America. It would be great to see some movement on this, especially with the increasing number of ranked European teams at D2 and even D1 level. (We'd also love to see a non-US team win the WFTDA Championships - Victorian have come ever so close twice now [and they've beaten Rose on neutral ground this year], so 2017 could still be it.)
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what would you like to see in 2017 - from us, or from Roller Derby? Let us know via our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/scottish.rollerderby/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; page, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/scotrollerderby"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or just email (scottishrollerderbyATgmailDOTcom)!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>articles</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>international derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>review of the year</category><category>team scotland</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/12/31/2016-in-review/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 14:21:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A quick analysis of Road to TBC</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/27/a-quick-analysis-of-road-to-tbc/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Team Wales' Road to TBC now complete, and France taking a victory over Sweden for 1st place, we've now seen 13 of the potential competitors at the Roller Derby World Cup on track in Europe, between this tournament and the earlier "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/"&gt;European Roller Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's quite interesting about comparing ERDT and Road to TBC is just how much the balance of power in some of the teams common between them has changed in a relatively short space of time; and how different some of the newer teams may be to their 2014 versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at returning teams first: at ERDT, Wales and Belgium took 3rd and 2nd, but looked very close in strength indeed. We predicted that home advantage would make Wales likely to win against the Belgian team at Road to TBC... but didn't predict by just how much! In fact, Wales did take our expected 3rd place, with an impressive performance; but Belgium was likely disappointed by their 7th place position by comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;France and Sweden, as predicted, duked it out for 1st and 2nd, and France emerged victorious. Sweden's performance, whilst easily good enough to win against everyone else [despite some opening issues with both Wales and Ireland], wasn't quite as commanding as their 2014 iteration managed at the World Cup - however, this was also their first tournament, after a relatively recent selection, so this may just be a reflection of the stage of their training so far, versus a more experienced France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tipped Ireland for a strong placement, purely on the basis of their 2014 performance, and it seems we were right - despite their team being as new as Sweden's, Ireland managed to perform creditably and take a convincing 5th place position from Scotland...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...whilst Spain took the 4th place to Wales that we had thought destined for Belgium.
The case of Spain and Scotland is an unusual one, with their bout the closest in the tournament, but having the result of essentially forcing one to take 4th and one 6th place (as Ireland and Wales would likely have taken their eventual positions against either team). This is an issue with this kind of group selection process, where the seeding is designed for "exagony" (the desire for teams to play teams they've not played before), rather than technical ranking.
Ironically, Scotland actually performed better than Spain against France, and the two performed almost identically well against West Indies...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On principle, then, we performed the same kind of Bayesian inference on the Road to TBC that we did on ERDT, to determine what the most likely underlying strengths of the teams were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(As an aside, one key difference from this is that the same method tells us that the performances at Road to TBC were much less &lt;em&gt;consistent&lt;/em&gt; than they were at ERDT - the inference needs to assume around twice as much variation in performance for a given team in order to make predictions. This may be a reflection of the relative newness of some of the competing teams.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, the inferred strength distributions (relative to France) are below (this is a slideshow, with different teams highlighted for ease of identification).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="11765,11764,11761,11762,11763" type="slideshow"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As can be seen, it's fairly obvious that Sweden was most likely the 2nd strongest team in the tournament, and Wales the 3rd. What's more strikingly different from the tournament result is that the most consistent interpretation of the scores is that Ireland were the 4th strongest team, with Scotland, Belgium and Spain all quite close together in 5/6/7th positions (but with enough overlaps that upsets - like Spain/Scotland - were not unlikely).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the way in which the teams have changed in strength even since ERDT, however (and how some of the rosters were selected for Road to TBC), we would be hard pressed to predict performance at the next Roller Derby World Cup across these two tournaments - other than to say that Sweden will probably get stronger, and none of matchups below 3rd place might happen the same way in just a few months time...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>statistics</category><category>team scotland</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/27/a-quick-analysis-of-road-to-tbc/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 21:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City Brawlers Debut Home Game</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/12/granite-city-brawlers-debut-home-game/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's November, the winter duvet has been brought out of hibernation and it is rather chilly up here in Aberdeen. You may be thinking that the time for fun things is gone and that you will have to wait till next year for more roller derby up in Aberdeen (or south, I don't know who is reading this or from where, I'm hedging my bets here). Well, you are wrong. Very wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;b&gt;Saturday 19th &lt;/b&gt;November, Granite City Brawlers will take on Birmingham’s Crash Test Brummies B team for what promises to be a memorable game of roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11281" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/image.jpeg" alt="image" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why so special? Well...this is a very special game for a myriad of reasons, the biggest one being that it will be the FIRST EVER HOME GAME of GCB!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you may recognise a few faces and names, the brawlers have never played a public home game as a team. The brawlers did take on Bairn City Rollers’ Skelpies last year in Grangemouth but that was different, this time it's home turf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Brawlers have been preparing for their home debut for quite some time and a lot of people have been waiting eagerly. Well now the time is here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important facts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who? &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/662329417258500/?ti=cl"&gt;Granite City Brawlers vs Crash Test Brummies B&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What? Some first class roller derby. Considering the skaters taking part, I am expecting nippy footwork, hard hitting, near impenetrable walls and excellent sportsmanship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where? The &lt;b&gt;Beach Leisure Centre&lt;/b&gt;, Sea Beach, Aberdeen, AB24 5NR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When? Saturday 19th November 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at &lt;b&gt;2.15pm&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First Whistle at 2.45pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? Because roller derby is excellent and both of the teams playing are fabulous and it promises to be a good game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How? Entry is a bargain at £&lt;b&gt;4.00&lt;/b&gt; per human. Although under 12s get in free if accompanied by a paying adult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have heard rumours of there being a raffle...not rumours, it's totally true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So come and see some local roller derby history being made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11282" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/image1.jpeg" alt="image" width="665" height="960"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>crash test brummies</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>team scotland</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/12/granite-city-brawlers-debut-home-game/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 10:25:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Road to TBC: Lessons from ERDT and the last World Cup!</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Blood &amp;amp; Thunder still have yet to formally announce the location and date for the 2017 Women's Roller Derby World Cup, by the end of November we will have already seen two of the "lead up" events for next year's tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is the the already complete &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://euroderbytournament.eu/"&gt;European Roller Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, held in Mons, Belgium. The second will be Team Wales Roller Derby's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1224163900948144/"&gt;"The Road To TBC"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, scheduled for the &lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;27th&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;November&lt;/strong&gt; 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the two tournaments, we will get a good look at most of Europe's competitors in the Third World Cup, albeit at an early stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attending the European Roller Derby Tournament were &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Denmark&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Switzerland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Portugal&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Italy&lt;/strong&gt; and new team &lt;strong&gt;Iceland&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Road To TBC will bring you &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt; again, with the addition of &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Sweden&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;West Indies&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; all showing their national team debuts at the event!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what can we predict, if anything, about The Road to TBC from what has come &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we can look at ERDT. Whilst only 50% of the lineup overlaps between ERDT and TRtT, we can judge some expectations about absolute strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the now-traditional Bayesian inferred strength charts from ERDT, with the top four teams also singled out in separate highlights [as usual, these charts are relative to the winner - in this case, France - and so they are not directly represented]. We've marked vertical lines to show the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/"&gt;performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (also relative to France) in the Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Women's World Cup 2014, for those teams who attended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="8997,9001,8998,8999,9000" type="slideshow" link="file"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is pretty clear, whilst Spain is just about separate from the top three, although closely competitive with Wales and Belgium; the distributions for Belgium and Wales are almost indistinguishable. While France was indisputably the strongest team at ERDT, it's reasonable to suggest that the tournament also showed that Belgium and Wales are almost identical in strength. (Wales was the victim of one of the classic problems with single elimination tournaments, being relegated to the consolation brackets by an early encounter with the eventual Champions, and achieved Third as their highest possible relegation place.)
It's also possible to see that, assuming France is still relatively similar in strength, that Wales, Spain and Portugal have all noticeably improved in strength from 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/2/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over the page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we'll talk about the teams at The Road to TBC in more detail...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we can expect the hosts to be strong competitors in November... but what about their challengers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9075" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14448951_1432178393465450_4812609206374398804_n.jpg?w=600" alt="14448951_1432178393465450_4812609206374398804_n" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/"&gt;back at the last World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Sweden&lt;/em&gt; was one of the strongest teams in the tournament, reflecting the strength of Scandinavian Roller Derby even back then. Since then, Swedish roller derby has gone from strength to strength, with both Stockholm Roller Derby and Crime City Rollers in WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs this year!
A quick count of their recently published training team for 2016/17 [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamswedenrollerderby/photos/a.517256094957689.143365.224501220899846/1432139023469387/?type=1&amp;amp;theater"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] suggests that at least &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt; of the skaters from 2014 are returning as possible rosters (as several skaters were recorded under their legal names for the 2014 roster, and under their skatenames here, it's a little tricky to be 100% certain).
We expect, on the balance of this, and the general health of Swedish derby, for Sweden to be a contender for the top spot at The Road to TBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3901" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamfrance.png?w=570" alt="TeamFrance" width="285" height="300"&gt; Team France logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team France&lt;/em&gt; were a top 8 team for us in 2014 (although they narrowly missed the actual final 8 at the tournament itself. We see at least 12 skaters from 2014 in the 2016 roster so far, which is about an average rate of returns in Europe. Almost 50% of the roster is drawn from Paris and Toulouse (with the rest mostly from the other strong French leagues), and both teams have experienced strong growth since 2014. Paris Rollergirls, in particular, have rocketed up the WFTDA rankings in the last two years, currently at #77 in the World.
We would consider France to be one of our three contenders for 2nd place, with chance at taking on Sweden for the top spot too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Belgium&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Wales&lt;/em&gt;, as we mentioned above, statistically drew at ERDT. At the 2014 World Cup, Belgium was the stronger team, by some distance, so this represents a particular improvement on Wales's part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9087" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/1957831_642788809139747_4859931912064326634_o.jpg?w=600" alt="1957831_642788809139747_4859931912064326634_o" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the composition of 2016 &lt;em&gt;Team Wales&lt;/em&gt; is quite different to that in 2014, with only a handful of skaters shared betwen the two rosters. What is still true, however, is the dominance of Tiger Bay Brawlers and Swansea City Roller Derby in the training team, making up 18 of the 30 spots. Both teams have have exceptional years, with Swansea City particularly excelling at British Champs (where they defeated all comers in promotion to Tier 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3897" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teambelgium.jpg?w=582" alt="TeamBelgium" width="291" height="300"&gt; Team Belgium logo: Anouk Paepen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Belgium&lt;/em&gt;, meanwhile have at least 14 skaters returning from the strong 2014 roster in 2016. Belgian Roller Derby has always been pretty strong, on the basis of Gent Go-Go Rollergirls and One Love Roller Dolls amongst their many teams. However, we've not seen, perhaps, the explosive performance increase that, for example, Scandinavia has. We'd say that Team Belgium is, indeed, about as strong as it was in 2014.
We expect Wales to be keen on taking on Belgium on their home turf, and cautiously predict a win for the hosts on this basis. Overall rankings are hard to predict, but there are some particularly strong teams competing in The Road to TBC, and we wonder if the battle here will be for 4th place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3842" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamspain.jpg?w=600" alt="Team Spain logo -" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2014, &lt;em&gt;Spain&lt;/em&gt; have clearly come on in leaps and bounds.
The 2014 Team Spain consisted almost entirely of skaters from Barcelona and Tenerife, along with a few from outside Spain. The 2016 Training Team contains 13 skaters from 2014, but a huge number of new faces. We expect that Barcelona and Tenerife will still be strongly represented, however, and note that both leagues have significantly improved their rankings in the last 2 years (Tenerife has a steadily increasing ranking on Flat Track Stats, with no drops at all over that period!). We'd say that Spain have a good chance of placing well, assuming no surprises - although the general strength of teams at The Road to TBC is also higher than ERDT, so another 4th place is unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3773" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamwestindies.jpg?w=424" alt="Team West Indies Logo" width="212" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team West Indies&lt;/em&gt; was new to the Roller Derby scene in 2014, and also had the aim of trying to promote the sport back in the West Indies itself, with all of the skaters being from leagues outside of the islands (and many from the UK). Two years later, it seems that they're planning even greater things - but there's no official roster published for the team to date. We gather that Birmingham Blitz Dames and London Rockin' Rollers are still the core of the UK branch of the team, however, and both teams have had strong years - the Blitz Dames in particular benefitting from a change of coaching style which has improved their performance. While we rated West Indies as a little weaker than Spain and Wales in 2014, we wouldn't rule out surprising things from the team after 2 more years to build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4007" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/team-ireland.jpg?w=600" alt="team ireland" width="300" height="300"&gt; Team France logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Ireland Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt; did pretty well at the 2014 World Cup - in fact, on some metrics, we considered them competitive with France! The 2016 iteration is totally unknown, however - they're literally recruiting and selecting as we write this. On the basis of the performance of Dublin Roller Derby (who recently had a US trip and came back even stronger), we wouldn't rule the new Team Ireland out of a top 3 spot in this tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9080" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14390622_1111812092237414_410042907831655880_n.png?w=600" alt="14390622_1111812092237414_410042907831655880_n" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we come to our local team: &lt;em&gt;Team Scotland&lt;/em&gt;!
Scotland performed very creditably in the 2014 World Cup, placing around 10/11th place by our calculations. In 2014, the Scotland team was strongly dominated by Glasgow Roller Derby and Auld Reekie Roller Girls, with only a few skaters from Granite City, 1 from Dundee, and 1 each from Seaside Sirens and London Rollergirls.
This time around, due to both changes at Glasgow, and the strong growth in strength at Dundee and Granite City, we have a more rounded mix of representation in the training team (5 skaters from Dundee, and one from Fierce Valley!); as well as more skaters from outside Scotland itself, with 2 from Wirral, 2 from Newcastle and 1 each from Hallam, Leicester, London Rockin' Rollers!
We're not sure how the team roster for Team Scotland has been selected for The Road to TBC, but we've seen the team in practice, and they look pretty cohesive already. We'd tip Scotland for a chance at upsetting Ireland's dreams of a Top 3 spot, if anyone does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the only way to actually see if we're right is to make your way to Cardiff for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1224163900948144/"&gt;The Road to TBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; itself. Ticket sales are open for the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;27th November,&lt;/strong&gt; and sales are going fast, we believe!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>european roller derby tournament</category><category>international derby</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>statistics</category><category>team belgium</category><category>team france</category><category>team ireland</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team spain</category><category>team sweden</category><category>team wales</category><category>team west indies</category><category>the road to tbc</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 10:36:01 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>