<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about team indigenous rising)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/team-indigenous-rising.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Rollercon Nations Tournament 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/08/RNT-2019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the last few years, the National teams bouts have become a fixture of Rollercon.
Founded in 2017, before the last Roller Derby World Cup, they've been a great way for newer, or less visible National teams to be seen; and for raising awareness of the globally diverse nature of Roller Derby in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year was a particularly important point in the tournament's history, as two borderless nations - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/teamindigenousrollerderby/"&gt;Team Indigenous Rising&lt;/a&gt; (link to Facebook), and the new &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/jewishrollerderby/"&gt;Jewish Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; - competed in the tournament, and even played each other. (In fact, even the styling of the series of games as a true, all-day, tournament was a change this year, as previously there had not been enough competitors to realise this.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking for Team Indigenous, Jumpy McGee explained the importance of this to both teams:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Team Indigenous is extremely grateful to have this platform to bring our teams together and highlight that not all humans are defined by borders or citizenship.  There are centuries of displacement, violence, and oppression that have occurred causing people indigenous to their homeland to create home elsewhere.  We believe it was critical then to create a space where players identifying as a member of a nation had a place to belong.  And when WE talk about nation, we're talking about nation in the sense of a collection of humans who have the same cultures, beliefs, languages and traditions who cannot be contained or defined by borders.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2019 Nations tournament was run as an efficient double-elimination bracket, with seedings voted on by the competing teams. This means that each team could lose once in the tournament - that loss knocking them out of the "winners" bracket, and into a sudden-death bracket against other teams with a single loss. The eventual survivor of that sudden death bracket, having proven themselves the best of the teams, other than sole unbeaten team, gets to play in the final against that undefeated remainder. In this case, for time, all games were single period WFTDA-rules bouts, except for the final, run as a full-length WFTDA-rules game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as the two borderless nations, there were also three Asian nations represented: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/teamphilippines_rollerderby/"&gt;Team Philippines&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/teamkorearollerderby/"&gt;Team Korea&lt;/a&gt;, and Team "Japan-fam" (so named because they did not have a tryout and offered this opportunity to all skaters of Japanese heritage). This is also an important aspect of the event, and has been since it began, with Philippines and Korea founding members in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Action from the Korea / Philippines game, Philippines jammer on inside line passing blocked Korea jammer in pack." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/09/TristanKing-KoreaPhilippines.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Action from Korea versus Philippines (Photo: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/TKvisualarts"&gt;Tristan King&lt;/a&gt; [see link for license])&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As ShortStop noted for Korea, in particular:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
As a small nation, with relatively low representation in Roller Derby, [we] submitted an initial roster that included 8 Koreans, two skaters from OH Roller Derby Team (the only roller derby league in South Korea), and skaters from China, Vietnam, Thailand and Hong Kong. All of our non-Korean Asians are currently involved in building their own nations teams, and we thought it was a wonderful way to include them as start to gather their own teams.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Philippines' Electric PIRANHA, it's an equally strong, and personally important opportunity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
I have played sports throughout my whole life and have been playing roller derby now for four years. I never once in my life thought I would be able to represent a national team, a team that represents my heritage and culture. I had the opportunity to represent Team Philippines at the World Cup in Manchester and just recently in the Nations Tournament at RollerCon. Words cannot describe the feeling I get skating for Team Philippines. I am surrounded by smart, beautiful, athletic Filipinas. When we are together, there is an extraordinary and undeniable bond we have, like we've been skating together as a team for years when we only have had the chance to skate together a handful of times. We represent a country that has gone through colonization, war, and the fight for independence. I skate for my cultural heritage and I skate for my family. #pamilypirst #poweredbylumpia #poweredbyrice&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even for Japan, where there has been derby in some form for more than a decade, visibility is low, as we've discussed before on this blog.
Kris Rago, for Japan-fam noted to us that this was a factor in their participation here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Japan Fam was unique in the sense that roller derby is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/rdjapan/photos/a.316960268326566/2053816941307548/?type=3&amp;amp;permPage=1"&gt;present in Japan&lt;/a&gt; and that some of our skaters from both Japan and Hawaii were able to fly over and join our U.S. Japanese skaters. It was really wonderful to be able to come together and work together to represent our heritage and do amazing things on the track. My hope is more opportunities like this will help to strengthen the relationship between our U.S. Japanese skaters and skaters and leagues in Japan.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/08/RNT-2019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>international roller derby</category><category>jewish roller derby</category><category>team canada roller derby</category><category>team indigenous rising</category><category>team indigenous roller derby</category><category>team korea roller derby</category><category>team philippines roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/08/RNT-2019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 20:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>