<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about team england)</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/team-england.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:54:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: England Men's Roller Derby</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/26/mrdwc-2016-team-review-england-mens-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our coverage of the Men's Roller Derby World Cup has returned slightly closer to home, as the time has come to speak to the UK and Ireland. First up is the English National Team - England Men's Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014, England were in Group Green with Argentina, the Netherlands and Sweden. They made it to the final game to play against Team USA for the shiny, shiny cup and whilst Team USA took the win, England took the silver medal finishing second. I, for one am rather excited to see these chaps play in July!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466933286146.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466933286146.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466933286146.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team England logo 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Manager Niks Kent was kind enough to answer some questions about how the team have been getting ready for the world cup.Please note that I spoke to Niks before England held their sevens tournament, did you see it? It was most excellent!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are preparations going for the world cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really well! We're in the refining stage. We have a couple of warm up games, and a highly competitive red v white game as part of our upcoming sevens tournament before we leave for Calgary though, so still plenty to do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How often do you train?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've been training once a month since July, plus a few training games.
We're delighted to have been supported at all our training by world cup level officials, so there's been no getting away with any sneaky forearms or cut tracks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any off skates training? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each skater has their own individual fitness regime, depending on their personal goals.
We have also been working on our mental game, and the lovely Katie from The Treasure Hunt Company took us out for a rather competitive treasure hunt round Nottingham as a team building adventure - not even the monsoons could stop us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From which leagues have your players been selected? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our squad consists of players from across England Wales. We have representatives from Southern Discomfort, South Wales Silures, Crash Test Brummies, Lincolnshire rolling thunder, Manchester Roller Derby, Barrow Infernos and Tyne and Fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your team goals for the World Cup? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to play really good roller derby. REALLY GOOD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about your fundraising and sponsorship.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundraising and sponsorship in roller derby is really difficult. Over the past two to three years, the market has been flooded with teams competing for fans funds, which are finite, so everyone has had to become more creative. We've hosted tournaments, crowd funders and sold merch, but we won't make anywhere near our costs. We don't qualify for any funding from national bodies or charities either, so it's been hard. We have however been supported by our fantastic sponsors, in no particular order: Double Threat Skates - keeping our hardware working Roller derby City - our official kit and merch supplier Hoodlum Fang - creator of helmet covers and flags Bont- making our feet and compression clad legs do their thing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can we expect to see from team England at the World Cup? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An innovative and creative display of roller derby, by a skilled team of gentleman skaters.
And bowler hats. Lots of bowler hats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time around, England are in Group Orange with old pals Sweden and Argentina as well as Chile and Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their first game of the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup will be against Sweden (tune to track 2 for this one) at 12pm which is 5am UK time. Make a nice cup of tea to wake you up for this one. In a nice cup with a saucer because it's the World Cup, you can be fancy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466935371393.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466935371393.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466935371393.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>england men's roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>team england</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/26/mrdwc-2016-team-review-england-mens-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 20:26:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interviews: UK and Ireland</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/20/world-cup-interviews-uk-and-ireland/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last week, our &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; tour covered The UK and Ireland. Over the weekend, Ireland, Wales and Scotland (and Team West Indies) played against each other in the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/724704624268299/"&gt;Road to Dallas&lt;/a&gt; tournament, with Scotland placing 1st, ahead of Ireland in second place, and the hosts, Wales, taking up the 4th place position, despite a close game against third-place West Indies.
If you missed any of our interviews, here’s a recap…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Ireland" href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/14/world-cup-interview-team-ireland/"&gt;Team Ireland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Wales" href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/15/world-cup-interview-team-wales/"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Scotland" href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/16/world-cup-interview-team-scotland/"&gt;Team Scotland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team England" href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/17/world-cup-interview-team-england/"&gt;Team England&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week we will be hopping over to Scandinavia to interview the teams from Norway, Denmark, Finland and Sweden!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team england</category><category>team ireland</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>team wales</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/20/world-cup-interviews-uk-and-ireland/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 09:50:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team England</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/17/world-cup-interview-team-england/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamenglandrollerderby"&gt;Team England&lt;/a&gt; nabbed third place in the 2011 &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;Blood and Thunder World Cup&lt;/a&gt;. Lynn Huynh, also known as Shaolynn Scarlett, was originally rostered for the Team England 2011 team but unfortunately missed out by breaking her ankle. Now she is back and fighting fit for the World Cup in December!
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/team-england.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4011" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/team-england.jpg?w=300" alt="Team England logo" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Team England logo by Sally Felton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you tell me a bit about how your team selection process worked?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;England's team selection went through an extensive tryouts process to select the training squad, then the management team selected the most suitable players for the World Cup roster based on performance and which players worked well together, over the course of games and training throughout 2014. The management staff have been selected through application and a rigorous process as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are your training sessions going?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training sessions have been really fun! It's been really refreshing working with a range of skaters from around the country and great to collaborate and learn even more from training with different styles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training occurs around every 6 weeks or so and luckily sessions don't clash with league training - it just means more skating in the week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you had to alter your personal training as part of you World Cup preparation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preparation for the World Cup actually falls at a fortuitous time for me, as it's just after the long period of training that London Brawling have for WFTDA Playoffs and Champs, so I'll just be extending the training through till December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This includes regular DSA sessions, which mix weights, ladder training and lots of tough circuits, additional skating sessions and eating healthily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then having a very indulgent Christmas!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have you been fundraising and achieving sponsorship?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've had some great events like the Red V White game, and loads more coming up over the autumn, like a special comedy fundraiser with famous roller derby supporter Phill Jupitus, and the Sur5al tournament. Get your tickets and sign up via the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamenglandrollerderby?fref=ts"&gt;Team England Facebook&lt;/a&gt;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What teams are you most looking forward to playing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gosh everyone! It's just great to be part of such a global celebration of the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you most looking forward to about the World Cup this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See above! Although I am an extra bit of excited to meet Team Japan &lt;em&gt;YELLOW FEVER&lt;/em&gt; - there's gonna be loads of photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Manager Laura Jones also spoke to us about the recent announcement from Team England to no longer be part of UKRDA;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially Blood &amp;amp;Thunder have different affiliation criteria to UKRDA.  All 32 of the training squad are eligible under Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup criteria, but not everyone would be under UKRDA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that if England Roller Derby adhered to UKRDA criteria, we'd be putting ourselves at a disadvantage that no other non-UK squad will face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UKRDA understandably don't wish to change their criteria at this late stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our dealings with the UKRDA Board have been very pleasant, there's no bad feeling and we both genuinely wish each other well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Team England Roster&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bloxie Blackout
Ella Storey
Fay Roberts
Ruth Wilkinson
Hell Vetica Black
Jen Sykes
Kamikaze Kitten
Kid Block
Kristen Lee
Lexi Lightspeed
Lorrae Evans
Missy Rascal
Olivia Coupe
Amy Ruffell
Rogue Runner
Shaolynn Huynh
Stefanie Mainey
Terri Sudron
Trisha Smackanawa
Gemma Campbell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bench Coach: Ballistic Whistle
Assistant Coach: Rollin Stone R
Team Manager: Laura Jones&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team england</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/17/world-cup-interview-team-england/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 09:00:41 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>