<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about team japan)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/team-japan.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Men's Roller Derby Japan</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/08/mrdwc-2016-team-review-mens-roller-derby-japan/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the second &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, in Calgary July 21-24th, fast approaching, we thought some profiles for the 21 teams competing would be useful. Over the next weeks, we'll be presenting profiles on each team attending, based on interviews and other statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, we have the fan-favourites from 2014's World Cup; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mensrollerderbyjapan.com/"&gt;Men's Roller Derby Japan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7506" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/1473007_138427009676951_1222915006_n.jpg" alt="1473007_138427009676951_1222915006_n" width="744" height="960"&gt; NinJapan Rollers Logo (retained from last World Cup)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time around, the Japanese team were very much the underdogs, both least experienced and also relatively short in roster (11 skaters). While they ended up last in the rankings overall, they played with strong determination and clearly improved in performance over the course of the tournament (as can be seen by their scores against Belgium in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/45959"&gt;initial group rounds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and then &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/47094"&gt;rematched&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in the elimination phase). Such was their team spirit that they quickly became the spectators' favourites, and the overwhelming demand for their merchandise led to a pre-order system being established for t-shirts this time around...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Japan (The Ninjapan Rollers) are placed in &lt;strong&gt;Group Red&lt;/strong&gt;, along with the national teams from USA, Scotland, Ireland, Finland and Mexico. Of these, only Mexico is new to the tournament; Finland, Scotland and Ireland all finished within a place of each other in 2014, grouped solidly in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/results/"&gt;middle of the table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. (Team USA needs no reminder of their position in 2014!)
This is also the largest group, due to a few teams dropping out of the tournament earlier on, which slightly increases the difficulty of placement in it, as only the top 2 spots in each group progress to the highest-tier knockout round with a chance at the Tournament 1st place spot - with USA in this group, this means that only 1 spot is really up for grabs here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, however, the Japanese team has a stronger roster, with 16 skaters listed, and most of the skaters from last time returning. Ninjapan Rollers were recruited/managed under the auspices of the Men's Roller Derby Japan group. The team have been practising with the Tokyo and Okinawa based leagues, and also &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1612941555696799/"&gt;held a scrim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; against the international skaters from the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/16/the-japan-open-the-other-wftda-first-this-year/"&gt;Japan Open Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.  They've also already garnered some additional support at the host venue, with Calgary-local derby photographer GI Jones accepted as their Official Photographer for the Tournament!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-7512" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13041037_427493637436952_1003713003488960251_o.jpg?w=1024" alt="13041037_427493637436952_1003713003488960251_o" width="1024" height="428"&gt; Team Japan Uniform 2016 (selected by public vote)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keisuke Ohtsuki, "Bubble" on track, was kind enough to answer some questions about the team's current processes and plans for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With only one team with male (native Japanese) skaters in Japan (Tokyo3Rollers), how did you go recruiting for the team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 2014 World Cup, we felt that our participation suffered from lack of numbers. As a result, we concentrated on the uncovering and training of new players this time, from an early stage. We tried very hard to recruit skaters for MRDWC 2016. Handing out leaflets, talent scouting, playing and running classes for new skaters who are interested in Roller Derby (which is new in Japan), with all of our skaters, friends, family and collaborators. We strove with various activities including the promotion of Roller Derby in Japan, and the promotion of activities up to last September. As a result, we attained six new members, including skaters who converted from other (roller) sports, and one skater from a US league!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last time around, Team Japan won the hearts of the tournament, but unfortunately finished last despite showing great spirit and determination. What are your aims for this time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a big aim for us to also make the competition an environment in which we would also practice as we played.   We did not win any of our bouts in the last World Cup, but still we gained a lot of audience support. So, this experience fed each skater's motivation to live up to the audience's expectation this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We value the team work of the players, and the staff which enables this. In addition, we will try our best to participate with the MRDA's international organisation to promote this great sport more positively, as we are presently doing in our own country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This time around, Team Japan is in the largest group, including Team USA as an opponent! What teams are you most looking forward to playing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we may have lack of experience in the game, even playing one bout is good - it's great to do so with any other national teams! The bout against Team USA, the champions of the last World Cup, holds with it an opportunity to learn many more things, so we are particular excited to play against them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After the last World Cup, was there an increase in interest in Roller Derby in Japan?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We still have only one male league (Tokyo3Rollers), so the environment is extremely limited at the moment. The overseas leagues from around the world voiced their support to play or practice with us. It's a thing that we were very thankful for, and there was a feeling that we wanted to fly immediately to each country and bout and practice with them for our experience; but, unfortunately, travel costs were too high, and in terms of time commitment is very difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, three (mainly U.S. Forces in Japan) WFTDA women's leagues (Tokyo Roller Girls/ Tokyo and Kanagawa, Kokeshi Roller Dolls/ Okinawa, Devil Dog Derby Dames/ Okinawa) in Japan are helping us a lot with shared practices and scrimmage for our training regime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of supporters for these sports is increasing little by little in Japan. Of course, this World Cup appearance is a big thing for our promotional activity for Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Japan's &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/27/mens-roller-derby-world-cupschedule-timezone-adjusted/"&gt;first fixture&lt;/a&gt; in the tournament is against Mexico, at midday Thursday 21st (Calgary-local-time) on Track 1, followed by USA on Track 2 at 3pm local time. [The official MRDWC schedule is located here: &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/"&gt;http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The official Team Japan 2016 Roster is (* denotes a skater returning from the 2014 roster):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UMESAN &lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; (Captain)
&lt;/em&gt;U2 &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;
Kabukimono &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;
HARAKIRI &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;MAYUGE-Born-Die &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;
Chuck Breaker&lt;strong&gt; 6&lt;/strong&gt;
NARUTO &lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;
Honey Badger &lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt;
Bob &lt;strong&gt;29&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;IKAGESOYARO &lt;strong&gt;32&lt;/strong&gt;
ShowGun &lt;strong&gt;77&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Bubble &lt;strong&gt;99&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;SHOW &lt;strong&gt;110&lt;/strong&gt;
*ZORRO &lt;strong&gt;136&lt;/strong&gt;
Porkchop Express &lt;strong&gt;0242&lt;/strong&gt;
RedBull &lt;strong&gt;615&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Staff&lt;/em&gt;
Honey Guide
The Bash
Red Eye
Kaoru
Ayami
Miki
Emi&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>team japan</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/08/mrdwc-2016-team-review-mens-roller-derby-japan/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 10:44:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup 2014: Africa and Asia-Pacific Round-up</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/22/world-cup-2014-africa-and-asia-pacific-round-up/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're one week into our series of National Teams interviews, covering all of the teams entering the &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder 2014 Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, we covered the "Africa and Asia-Pacific" set of nations. If you missed the Interviews, you can read them here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Japan [ローラーデービーのワールドカップ：日本のチーム]" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/15/world-cup-interview-team-japan-%e3%83%ad%e3%83%bc%e3%83%a9%e3%83%bc%e3%83%87%e3%83%bc%e3%83%93%e3%83%bc%e3%81%ae%e3%83%af%e3%83%bc%e3%83%ab%e3%83%89%e3%82%ab%e3%83%83%e3%83%97%ef%bc%9a%e6%97%a5/"&gt;Team Japan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team South Africa" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/16/world-cup-interview-team-south-africa/"&gt;Team South Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team West Indies" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/17/world-cup-interview-team-west-indies/"&gt;Team West Indies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Australia" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/18/world-cup-interview-team-australia/"&gt;Team Australia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/19/world-cup-interview-team-new-zealand/"&gt;Team New Zealand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, we start our coverage of the European Teams, beginning tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team australia</category><category>team japan</category><category>team new zealand</category><category>team south africa</category><category>team west indies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/22/world-cup-2014-africa-and-asia-pacific-round-up/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 09:51:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Japan [ローラーデービーのワールドカップ：日本のチーム]</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/15/world-cup-interview-team-japan-roradebinowarudokatsupuri/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like most of the Roller Derby community, we at the Scottish Roller Derby blog are increasingly excited by the prospect of seeing a whole 30 nations competing at the &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Blood and Thunder World Cup&lt;/a&gt; in December. In fact, we're so excited, we've been following up with all of those national teams to learn a little about their plans and progression towards that important meet up in Dallas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because there are so many teams, we've grouped them together into regions, roughly geographically, which we'll be devoting a week each to. We're starting with the "Africa and Asia-Pacific" region, and with one of the new entrants to the World Cup - Team Japan!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/10448746_1467216233517248_5449562808216430157_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3754" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/10448746_1467216233517248_5449562808216430157_n.jpg" alt="The excellent Team Japan logo." width="516" height="516"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The excellent Team Japan logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This interview is in both Japanese and English. I apologise to Japanese readers for my poor Japanese. 「私の日本語が下手です。すみません。」The interview was conducted about a month ago, and I've inserted some updates accordingly.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Captain Hiroe Somekawa 「染川 ヒロエ」(who skates as Thunder BELL) was kind enough to answer our questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="im"&gt;1) On your website, I see that you have really started in June! How are things progressing?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;日本代表チームの ウェブサイトは  6月から 始めた と言う. ドのように進んでいます?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;はい、私達は今年の6月に日本チームを結成したばかりです。
きっと参加国の中で一番最後に結成されたチームですね。
日本人選手はまだ非常に人数が少ないので、私達は8月31日まで選手の募集をしています。
そして日本の男性選手(Ninjapanの選手達)が協力をしてくれて、現在は男女混合で練習を行っています。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, we just formed a team for Japan in June of this year.
We think team Japan is probably the last team that was formed out of the participating countries.
Japan has fewer number of female derby players, so we are recruiting Team Japan members until August 31.
And we are getting a lot of cooperation from male players of Japan (Ninjapan players) and practicing in mixed-gender with them now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) There are many teams in Japan, but they seem to have many Americans in them (Kokeshi Roller Dolls, and the others from Okinawa, for example). How are you recruiting skaters for Team Japan? Will you be requiring Japanese nationals?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 日本に多くのチームでますでも多くのアメリカの スケーターデスやら。&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; など　オ機縄のKokeshi Roller Dolls).ドのように 日本代表チームの スケーターを募集している。&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; 日本人要求したいるか.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;確かに日本には多くのチームがありますが、その99%はアメリカ人の選手です。
現在、日本人選手はTokyo Roller Girlsリーグにだけ在籍します。
初心者を合わせても、全員で15人程度です。
私達はインターネーット等で日本国外に住んでいる日本人選手を探して連絡を取り、
4名のアメリカ在住者が日本チームに参加する事になりました。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exactly, there are a lot of teams in Japan. But 99% of players are Americans.
Actually, Japanese Nationals players are in only Tokyo Roller Girls league now.
There are about 15 people in all Japanese Nationals including fresh meat.
We were looking for Japanese players who live outside of Japan in Internet
and referral from derby sisters, and made contact with them.
And Team Japan has four players who live outside of Japan now.　[These skaters are from El Paso Roller Derby, San Diego Derby Dolls and Green Mountain Derby Dames.]
&lt;span class="im"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;3) Most of Roller Derby is conducted in English. Does language cause problems for Roller Derby in Japan?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; ローラーダービー イギリスごで 実施すっている　は 問題ですか.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;日本に居るほとんどのスケーターはアメリカ人なので、通常は特に問題なく試合が行われていますが、
私達日本人スケーターにとって、英語で行われている状況は非常に厳しいものです。
しかし、Tokyo Roller Girlsリーグの全てのアメリカ人選手達は、英語が理解出来ない私達日本人選手に
ジェスチャーを使いながらとても親切にローラーダービーのルールや作戦を教えてくれています。
私達は彼女達に本当に感謝しています。しかし、やはり実際はまだ、日本人がローラーダービーをやりたくても
英語を理解出来ないとローラーダービーをする事が難しいです。
特にルールブックは、内容がとても複雑なので、私達はそれを理解するのがとても大変です。
日本語のルールブックが発表されたら、日本人選手も増えると思います。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually the game has been held without any particular problem because most derby players who live in Japan are Americans.
But for Japanese skaters like us, the situation that derby is carried out in English is really hard.
However, the American players of all of Tokyo Roller Girls league are very kindly telling us the strategy and rules of roller derby while using gestures for us who doesn't understand English. We are really grateful to them.
Actually, even if some Japanese girl want to play roller derby, they can't do it without understanding English.
The rule book has such very complex contents in particular, it's really hard to understand it for us.
We think that Japanese players will be increased if an official Japanese rule book was announced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) How are you raising money and finding sponsors?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; ドのように金銭をやスポンサーを 募集している？&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;寄付金については、私達はGofundmeで世界中からの寄付を集めようとしましたが、
日本のPaypalでは寄付を受け取る事が出来ないそうです。
なので現在、違う方法を考えています。現在の日本では、
シンプルに日本チームのオリジナル商品を販売し、それを資金にする方法しか無さそうです。
これから商品作りを始めてオンラインショップを立ち上げる予定です。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;スポンサーについては、ローラーコンで私達のスポンサーになってくれるメーカーと出会う事が出来ました。
あとは日本国内の企業に資料を持って周る活動をこれからしていきます。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About donations, we tried to collect donations from all over the world in Gofundme.
But we could not receive a donation via Paypal in Japan by Japanese law.
So now, I am thinking a different way. We can have only simple way for gather money. That is selling team Japan merchandise.
We are planning to launch an online shop for the first time, and are creating products now.
About sponsors, I was able to meet with manufacturers who will become our sponsor at RollerCon.
We will visit to companies to found our sponsors in Japan.
&lt;span class="im"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;5) As a relatively unknown team, what are your aims going into the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; チーム 若い ですは 私の目的が 何 World Cupに します？&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;私達のワールドカップでの最大の目標は
今後日本中にスポーツとしてのローラーダービー、
更にその背景にある文化(カルチャー)としてのローラーダービーを広める為に
世界に認識されるチームへの成長を遂げることです。
そして....トーナメントで3回くらいは勝ちたいな、とも思っています。笑&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our biggest goal at the World Cup is that team Japan grow to be gained world recognition for roller derby.
If we can do it, we can spread Roller Derby in Japan.
We would like to spread Roller Derby as a sport, and the great culture also.
And... we wish that we get at least three wins at the World Cup tournament if possible(!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since our interview, Team Japan has gained a sponsor in Atom Wheels, and begun &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/289173411265953/"&gt;regular&lt;/a&gt; practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Japan can be followed at their &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamjapanrollerderby?fref=ts"&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt; page and the &lt;a href="http://wrdjapan.com/"&gt;Women's Roller Derby Japan&lt;/a&gt; website. Merchandise will be available soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Japan's Roster is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slamurai #7
HELL OH KITTY #13
AYAMI #17
NOBUE #30
Chee Fighter #31
YUMI #52
AYA #54
Axel Managarmr #75
Ninja Plz #143
Secret Asian Slam #303
MARK #229
MIHO #555
chikai #719
Oscar Little Wild #831
Thunder BELL #950
Vagichael Jakson # 5umo
Mocha Panic # pa29&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their gofundme (running since the last week in September) is: &lt;a href="http://gofundme.com/ewvvng"&gt;http://gofundme.com/ewvvng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>blood and thunder world cup 2014</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team japan</category><category>world cup</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/15/world-cup-interview-team-japan-roradebinowarudokatsupuri/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 10:36:01 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>