<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about team spain)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/team-spain.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 11:56:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Road to TBC: Lessons from ERDT and the last World Cup!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Blood &amp;amp; Thunder still have yet to formally announce the location and date for the 2017 Women's Roller Derby World Cup, by the end of November we will have already seen two of the "lead up" events for next year's tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is the the already complete &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://euroderbytournament.eu/"&gt;European Roller Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, held in Mons, Belgium. The second will be Team Wales Roller Derby's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1224163900948144/"&gt;"The Road To TBC"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, scheduled for the &lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;27th&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;November&lt;/strong&gt; 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the two tournaments, we will get a good look at most of Europe's competitors in the Third World Cup, albeit at an early stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attending the European Roller Derby Tournament were &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Denmark&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Switzerland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Portugal&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Italy&lt;/strong&gt; and new team &lt;strong&gt;Iceland&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Road To TBC will bring you &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt; again, with the addition of &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Sweden&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;West Indies&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; all showing their national team debuts at the event!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what can we predict, if anything, about The Road to TBC from what has come &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we can look at ERDT. Whilst only 50% of the lineup overlaps between ERDT and TRtT, we can judge some expectations about absolute strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the now-traditional Bayesian inferred strength charts from ERDT, with the top four teams also singled out in separate highlights [as usual, these charts are relative to the winner - in this case, France - and so they are not directly represented]. We've marked vertical lines to show the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/"&gt;performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (also relative to France) in the Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Women's World Cup 2014, for those teams who attended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="8997,9001,8998,8999,9000" type="slideshow" link="file"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is pretty clear, whilst Spain is just about separate from the top three, although closely competitive with Wales and Belgium; the distributions for Belgium and Wales are almost indistinguishable. While France was indisputably the strongest team at ERDT, it's reasonable to suggest that the tournament also showed that Belgium and Wales are almost identical in strength. (Wales was the victim of one of the classic problems with single elimination tournaments, being relegated to the consolation brackets by an early encounter with the eventual Champions, and achieved Third as their highest possible relegation place.)
It's also possible to see that, assuming France is still relatively similar in strength, that Wales, Spain and Portugal have all noticeably improved in strength from 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/2/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over the page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we'll talk about the teams at The Road to TBC in more detail...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we can expect the hosts to be strong competitors in November... but what about their challengers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9075" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14448951_1432178393465450_4812609206374398804_n.jpg?w=600" alt="14448951_1432178393465450_4812609206374398804_n" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/"&gt;back at the last World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Sweden&lt;/em&gt; was one of the strongest teams in the tournament, reflecting the strength of Scandinavian Roller Derby even back then. Since then, Swedish roller derby has gone from strength to strength, with both Stockholm Roller Derby and Crime City Rollers in WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs this year!
A quick count of their recently published training team for 2016/17 [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamswedenrollerderby/photos/a.517256094957689.143365.224501220899846/1432139023469387/?type=1&amp;amp;theater"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] suggests that at least &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt; of the skaters from 2014 are returning as possible rosters (as several skaters were recorded under their legal names for the 2014 roster, and under their skatenames here, it's a little tricky to be 100% certain).
We expect, on the balance of this, and the general health of Swedish derby, for Sweden to be a contender for the top spot at The Road to TBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3901" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamfrance.png?w=570" alt="TeamFrance" width="285" height="300"&gt; Team France logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team France&lt;/em&gt; were a top 8 team for us in 2014 (although they narrowly missed the actual final 8 at the tournament itself. We see at least 12 skaters from 2014 in the 2016 roster so far, which is about an average rate of returns in Europe. Almost 50% of the roster is drawn from Paris and Toulouse (with the rest mostly from the other strong French leagues), and both teams have experienced strong growth since 2014. Paris Rollergirls, in particular, have rocketed up the WFTDA rankings in the last two years, currently at #77 in the World.
We would consider France to be one of our three contenders for 2nd place, with chance at taking on Sweden for the top spot too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Belgium&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Wales&lt;/em&gt;, as we mentioned above, statistically drew at ERDT. At the 2014 World Cup, Belgium was the stronger team, by some distance, so this represents a particular improvement on Wales's part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9087" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/1957831_642788809139747_4859931912064326634_o.jpg?w=600" alt="1957831_642788809139747_4859931912064326634_o" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the composition of 2016 &lt;em&gt;Team Wales&lt;/em&gt; is quite different to that in 2014, with only a handful of skaters shared betwen the two rosters. What is still true, however, is the dominance of Tiger Bay Brawlers and Swansea City Roller Derby in the training team, making up 18 of the 30 spots. Both teams have have exceptional years, with Swansea City particularly excelling at British Champs (where they defeated all comers in promotion to Tier 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3897" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teambelgium.jpg?w=582" alt="TeamBelgium" width="291" height="300"&gt; Team Belgium logo: Anouk Paepen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Belgium&lt;/em&gt;, meanwhile have at least 14 skaters returning from the strong 2014 roster in 2016. Belgian Roller Derby has always been pretty strong, on the basis of Gent Go-Go Rollergirls and One Love Roller Dolls amongst their many teams. However, we've not seen, perhaps, the explosive performance increase that, for example, Scandinavia has. We'd say that Team Belgium is, indeed, about as strong as it was in 2014.
We expect Wales to be keen on taking on Belgium on their home turf, and cautiously predict a win for the hosts on this basis. Overall rankings are hard to predict, but there are some particularly strong teams competing in The Road to TBC, and we wonder if the battle here will be for 4th place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3842" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamspain.jpg?w=600" alt="Team Spain logo -" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2014, &lt;em&gt;Spain&lt;/em&gt; have clearly come on in leaps and bounds.
The 2014 Team Spain consisted almost entirely of skaters from Barcelona and Tenerife, along with a few from outside Spain. The 2016 Training Team contains 13 skaters from 2014, but a huge number of new faces. We expect that Barcelona and Tenerife will still be strongly represented, however, and note that both leagues have significantly improved their rankings in the last 2 years (Tenerife has a steadily increasing ranking on Flat Track Stats, with no drops at all over that period!). We'd say that Spain have a good chance of placing well, assuming no surprises - although the general strength of teams at The Road to TBC is also higher than ERDT, so another 4th place is unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3773" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamwestindies.jpg?w=424" alt="Team West Indies Logo" width="212" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team West Indies&lt;/em&gt; was new to the Roller Derby scene in 2014, and also had the aim of trying to promote the sport back in the West Indies itself, with all of the skaters being from leagues outside of the islands (and many from the UK). Two years later, it seems that they're planning even greater things - but there's no official roster published for the team to date. We gather that Birmingham Blitz Dames and London Rockin' Rollers are still the core of the UK branch of the team, however, and both teams have had strong years - the Blitz Dames in particular benefitting from a change of coaching style which has improved their performance. While we rated West Indies as a little weaker than Spain and Wales in 2014, we wouldn't rule out surprising things from the team after 2 more years to build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4007" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/team-ireland.jpg?w=600" alt="team ireland" width="300" height="300"&gt; Team France logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Ireland Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt; did pretty well at the 2014 World Cup - in fact, on some metrics, we considered them competitive with France! The 2016 iteration is totally unknown, however - they're literally recruiting and selecting as we write this. On the basis of the performance of Dublin Roller Derby (who recently had a US trip and came back even stronger), we wouldn't rule the new Team Ireland out of a top 3 spot in this tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9080" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14390622_1111812092237414_410042907831655880_n.png?w=600" alt="14390622_1111812092237414_410042907831655880_n" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we come to our local team: &lt;em&gt;Team Scotland&lt;/em&gt;!
Scotland performed very creditably in the 2014 World Cup, placing around 10/11th place by our calculations. In 2014, the Scotland team was strongly dominated by Glasgow Roller Derby and Auld Reekie Roller Girls, with only a few skaters from Granite City, 1 from Dundee, and 1 each from Seaside Sirens and London Rollergirls.
This time around, due to both changes at Glasgow, and the strong growth in strength at Dundee and Granite City, we have a more rounded mix of representation in the training team (5 skaters from Dundee, and one from Fierce Valley!); as well as more skaters from outside Scotland itself, with 2 from Wirral, 2 from Newcastle and 1 each from Hallam, Leicester, London Rockin' Rollers!
We're not sure how the team roster for Team Scotland has been selected for The Road to TBC, but we've seen the team in practice, and they look pretty cohesive already. We'd tip Scotland for a chance at upsetting Ireland's dreams of a Top 3 spot, if anyone does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the only way to actually see if we're right is to make your way to Cardiff for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1224163900948144/"&gt;The Road to TBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; itself. Ticket sales are open for the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;27th November,&lt;/strong&gt; and sales are going fast, we believe!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>european roller derby tournament</category><category>international derby</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>statistics</category><category>team belgium</category><category>team france</category><category>team ireland</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team spain</category><category>team sweden</category><category>team wales</category><category>team west indies</category><category>the road to tbc</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 10:36:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup 2014: Southern Europe Round-up</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/28/world-cup-2014-southern-europe-round-up/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the second week of our ongoing coverage of all of the National teams heading to the &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;, we concentrated on Southern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's our interviews, in case you missed them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Spain" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/23/world-cup-interview-team-spain/"&gt;Team Spain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Portugal" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/24/world-cup-interview-team-portugal/"&gt;Team Portugal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Italy" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/26/world-cup-interview-team-italy/"&gt;Team Italy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Greece" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/25/world-cup-interview-team-greece/"&gt;Team Greece&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, we'll move a little north, and cover the Northern and Central European Teams.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>blood and thunder world cup 2014</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team greece</category><category>team italy</category><category>team portugal</category><category>team spain</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/28/world-cup-2014-southern-europe-round-up/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 08:09:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Spain</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/23/world-cup-interview-team-spain/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned yesterday, this week's &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;B&amp;amp;T Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; coverage is focussing on Europe, specifically Southern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We start today with new team to the cup, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamSpainRollerDerby"&gt;Team Spain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This interview was conducted in July. Since the interview, Team Spain competed in the &lt;a href="http://euroderbytournament.eu/"&gt;European Championship Tournament&lt;/a&gt;, placing 2nd-from-bottom (defeating Team Portugal, who we will cover tomorrow).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Violent Femme was happy to answer our questions in a face to face interview in Barcelona. This article is edited from the conversation we had. [This article has been edited on the 24th of October to include Team Spain's fundraising site: &lt;a href="http://www.lanzanos.com/proyectos/volando-voy-volando-vengo-dallas-2014/L/EN/"&gt;http://www.lanzanos.com/proyectos/volando-voy-volando-vengo-dallas-2014/L/EN/&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamspain.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-3842 size-large" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamspain.jpg?w=614" alt="Team Spain logo - " width="614" height="614"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Team Spain Logo: Alicia Reyes Schwartz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, Team Spain has quite an international line-up, how are you handling the travel and the language issues?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have people from London, from Tenerife, Barcelona, Lisbon, Madrid, Cáceres... One of our players lives in Manchester, some are in the US and Canada…  Right now it’s quite even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[As to the language barrier] It’s derby, so it’s quite an international language. Even in Spanish derby’s early stages it was never a huge problem to have English in the middle – we had to read the rule set in English anyway, and most derby stuff on the Internet is in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[On travel] it’s tricky. But actually, you know, our country’s geographical spread is not that good anyway – Tenerife is down by the coast of Africa, and it’s super expensive for us to fly there and for them to come here [Barcelona]. So, I think that’s our biggest handicap – if most of the girls were from Madrid, or Valencia, I guess it would be more manageable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, what we’ve had is two practices together – one in Barcelona, one in Tenerife – basically because it’s where the most skaters are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All the flying between Barcelona and Tenerife must place a significant cost on your training, compared to most of the other national teams?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMG, it’s so expensive. And we’re all so broke. Yeah, there are planes involved [for Team Spain] every single time. It’s just really, really tricky. Because even Lisbon is closer – if we had to travel to Portugal!  So, you know, having players from the UK and US and Canada, like we have and had, didn’t pose much of an additional problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, what are your aims coming in to the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a good question.  We’re aiming to perform to the best of our ability. We’re well aware that we don’t have that much experience, both within the World Cup –we’re new to that—, but also as players. I mean, Tenerife is a really good league, they’re such an amazing set of skaters. However, I think they’ve existed for about four years and their ability to play bouts is really limited due to their geographical location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Barcelona – we have less problems to have bouts, but I wouldn’t say that we’re all that experienced whatsoever. Also, Barcelona is a city where, you know, people come and go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, you’ve had a lot of turn over?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah.  Most of the selected players from Barcelona have been there pretty much from the get-go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do think that we have a chance against the smaller, newer, teams. But I don’t even want to jinx it – ask me again after the European Tournament in September, and I’ll have a better gauge. Hopefully, September will give us a bit of an idea of where we’re standing, what we need to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And any teams you’re particularly looking forward to skating against at the Cup itself?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal feeling is that I’d love to play New Zealand. Like, love, love. And [playing] England  would be so awesome. I mean, I’m sure that after that, they’d have to put us all out of commission, but it would be so amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love when you go against a much stronger team, it’s kind of like you see that there is no roof to what you’re doing, so it doesn’t matter how good your team is. When you play against England, or Germany, or France, and you just see them work like that, it’s just so inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It just shows that you have to keep going.  That there’s no comfortable spot, you know? No-one should ever get comfortable, and that’s the fun of it. So, it can inspire people who might be a little shy, or those who have lots of potential but might not display it just out of fear: “I don’t want to hit as hard as I can” – No, you should! You should and you can! And, look, nothing happens, no-one gets hurt… or some people get hurt, but rarely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I’m looking forward to a big challenge. As well, I would really love to win some bouts with Team Spain. That would be amazing. I don’t want to name names, but I think we have some chances – we’re probably not going to place, but we will win something. Maybe some afterparties or something! But in all seriousness, we’re looking forward to it, it’s going to be such an incredible experience. And I’m looking forward to seeing my friends, you know, some friends in Team Scotland, some friends in Team Sweden, some friends in Team England, some friends in Team Portugal, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Given your increased costs especially, how are you raising money for the trip? Crowdfunding seems to be popular now…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, we’ve just started a crowdfunding page; we’ve been studying different options. But the thing is that it is a little difficult because Spain right now is not in its best moment, economically; people don’t donate. So we’ve been focusing on merch, that’s been probably our biggest funds income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Well, in my experience, merchandise is always the bigger source of actual funds for most leagues in any case.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I mean, I guess it happens with everything. We’re thinking of different options and there are things happening that I don’t want to jinx. But there’s options, like maybe some sponsorship, not that we’ll  be getting monetary rewards from it, but we’re working on having this Spanish company pay for our uniforms, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the first questions that was asked to us, when we tried out, before we even made any ‘Team Spain’, or anything was: “Could you afford it?” In case there’s no funds. So, that’s one of the things that everyone understood from the beginning. That we might each have to pay for our own ticket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also had an open scrimmage in Tenerife, there was some money from that. We’re going to do the same now in Barcelona, so, I mean, maybe you don’t make a lot of money, but you make some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, several of the national teams seem to have decided to skate under their legal names, rather than their derby names. Others are keeping their skate names. Do you (or Team Spain) have feelings on this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it’s a tendency that’s happening more and more. To give derby some legitimacy, to make the sport more of a sport. I don’t know. I don’t really have thoughts on that. Some days I’m like, “No, I want to be Violent Femme forever!”, and other days I’m like, “I could just be Mia, and just own it”. I’m not a persona, it’s just fun.  But I can see why people go under their legal names. Also, I think one of the things that use to make roller derby special is that it was this small gang of ladies with cool nicknames, but when everyone has a cool nickname, then it’s not cool anymore! I do like derby names though, because usually you speak about someone, you know it’s just that one player. I don’t know how true this is anymore, because I think there’s like four or five ‘Violent Femme’s out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But, you said that “legal names give some legitimacy” – the counter argument is that this is a kind of retreat from the position that derby is already legitimate, even with skate names.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think everyone knows [that roller derby is legitimate], though. I guess it’s like one of these tendencies… like everyone started off skating wearing fishnets, and then they realized that sports clothing is a lot more comfortable. I don’t know, this is my personal opinion, but there’s also been a trendification of the sports clothes, if that makes any sense? So there are all these leggings with cool patterns, and there’re sporty but super-fashionable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it’s awesome, by all means – I’m a legging-loving lady!—, but the leggings are kind of the new fishnets;  and after the leggings it’ll be something more serious and more sporty. With derby there’s always these two currents that kind of criss-cross, between “we’re a serious sport”, and “but we’re so punk!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Spain’s roster is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;11 Rakel Mesa&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;111 Esther Arocha&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;12 Mercedes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;17 Pólvora&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;19 Lola Vulkano&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;22 Sherry Bomb&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;23 Maggie Love&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;25 Malicia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;247 Violent Femme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;301 MiniRoss&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;314 Stacy Malibú&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4 Angry Kris&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;72 Cookie Monster&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;77 Teremoto&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;78 Hija de Odín&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;8 Dadá&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;83 La Mano&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team spain</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/23/world-cup-interview-team-spain/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 10:37:52 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>