<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about team wales)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/team-wales.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:41:33 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Road to TBC: Lessons from ERDT and the last World Cup!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Blood &amp;amp; Thunder still have yet to formally announce the location and date for the 2017 Women's Roller Derby World Cup, by the end of November we will have already seen two of the "lead up" events for next year's tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is the the already complete &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://euroderbytournament.eu/"&gt;European Roller Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, held in Mons, Belgium. The second will be Team Wales Roller Derby's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1224163900948144/"&gt;"The Road To TBC"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, scheduled for the &lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;27th&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;November&lt;/strong&gt; 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the two tournaments, we will get a good look at most of Europe's competitors in the Third World Cup, albeit at an early stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attending the European Roller Derby Tournament were &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Denmark&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Switzerland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Portugal&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Italy&lt;/strong&gt; and new team &lt;strong&gt;Iceland&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Road To TBC will bring you &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt; again, with the addition of &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Sweden&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;West Indies&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; all showing their national team debuts at the event!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what can we predict, if anything, about The Road to TBC from what has come &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we can look at ERDT. Whilst only 50% of the lineup overlaps between ERDT and TRtT, we can judge some expectations about absolute strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the now-traditional Bayesian inferred strength charts from ERDT, with the top four teams also singled out in separate highlights [as usual, these charts are relative to the winner - in this case, France - and so they are not directly represented]. We've marked vertical lines to show the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/"&gt;performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (also relative to France) in the Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Women's World Cup 2014, for those teams who attended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="8997,9001,8998,8999,9000" type="slideshow" link="file"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is pretty clear, whilst Spain is just about separate from the top three, although closely competitive with Wales and Belgium; the distributions for Belgium and Wales are almost indistinguishable. While France was indisputably the strongest team at ERDT, it's reasonable to suggest that the tournament also showed that Belgium and Wales are almost identical in strength. (Wales was the victim of one of the classic problems with single elimination tournaments, being relegated to the consolation brackets by an early encounter with the eventual Champions, and achieved Third as their highest possible relegation place.)
It's also possible to see that, assuming France is still relatively similar in strength, that Wales, Spain and Portugal have all noticeably improved in strength from 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/2/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over the page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we'll talk about the teams at The Road to TBC in more detail...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we can expect the hosts to be strong competitors in November... but what about their challengers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9075" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14448951_1432178393465450_4812609206374398804_n.jpg?w=600" alt="14448951_1432178393465450_4812609206374398804_n" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/"&gt;back at the last World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Sweden&lt;/em&gt; was one of the strongest teams in the tournament, reflecting the strength of Scandinavian Roller Derby even back then. Since then, Swedish roller derby has gone from strength to strength, with both Stockholm Roller Derby and Crime City Rollers in WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs this year!
A quick count of their recently published training team for 2016/17 [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamswedenrollerderby/photos/a.517256094957689.143365.224501220899846/1432139023469387/?type=1&amp;amp;theater"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] suggests that at least &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt; of the skaters from 2014 are returning as possible rosters (as several skaters were recorded under their legal names for the 2014 roster, and under their skatenames here, it's a little tricky to be 100% certain).
We expect, on the balance of this, and the general health of Swedish derby, for Sweden to be a contender for the top spot at The Road to TBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3901" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamfrance.png?w=570" alt="TeamFrance" width="285" height="300"&gt; Team France logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team France&lt;/em&gt; were a top 8 team for us in 2014 (although they narrowly missed the actual final 8 at the tournament itself. We see at least 12 skaters from 2014 in the 2016 roster so far, which is about an average rate of returns in Europe. Almost 50% of the roster is drawn from Paris and Toulouse (with the rest mostly from the other strong French leagues), and both teams have experienced strong growth since 2014. Paris Rollergirls, in particular, have rocketed up the WFTDA rankings in the last two years, currently at #77 in the World.
We would consider France to be one of our three contenders for 2nd place, with chance at taking on Sweden for the top spot too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Belgium&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Wales&lt;/em&gt;, as we mentioned above, statistically drew at ERDT. At the 2014 World Cup, Belgium was the stronger team, by some distance, so this represents a particular improvement on Wales's part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9087" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/1957831_642788809139747_4859931912064326634_o.jpg?w=600" alt="1957831_642788809139747_4859931912064326634_o" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the composition of 2016 &lt;em&gt;Team Wales&lt;/em&gt; is quite different to that in 2014, with only a handful of skaters shared betwen the two rosters. What is still true, however, is the dominance of Tiger Bay Brawlers and Swansea City Roller Derby in the training team, making up 18 of the 30 spots. Both teams have have exceptional years, with Swansea City particularly excelling at British Champs (where they defeated all comers in promotion to Tier 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3897" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teambelgium.jpg?w=582" alt="TeamBelgium" width="291" height="300"&gt; Team Belgium logo: Anouk Paepen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Belgium&lt;/em&gt;, meanwhile have at least 14 skaters returning from the strong 2014 roster in 2016. Belgian Roller Derby has always been pretty strong, on the basis of Gent Go-Go Rollergirls and One Love Roller Dolls amongst their many teams. However, we've not seen, perhaps, the explosive performance increase that, for example, Scandinavia has. We'd say that Team Belgium is, indeed, about as strong as it was in 2014.
We expect Wales to be keen on taking on Belgium on their home turf, and cautiously predict a win for the hosts on this basis. Overall rankings are hard to predict, but there are some particularly strong teams competing in The Road to TBC, and we wonder if the battle here will be for 4th place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3842" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamspain.jpg?w=600" alt="Team Spain logo -" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2014, &lt;em&gt;Spain&lt;/em&gt; have clearly come on in leaps and bounds.
The 2014 Team Spain consisted almost entirely of skaters from Barcelona and Tenerife, along with a few from outside Spain. The 2016 Training Team contains 13 skaters from 2014, but a huge number of new faces. We expect that Barcelona and Tenerife will still be strongly represented, however, and note that both leagues have significantly improved their rankings in the last 2 years (Tenerife has a steadily increasing ranking on Flat Track Stats, with no drops at all over that period!). We'd say that Spain have a good chance of placing well, assuming no surprises - although the general strength of teams at The Road to TBC is also higher than ERDT, so another 4th place is unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3773" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamwestindies.jpg?w=424" alt="Team West Indies Logo" width="212" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team West Indies&lt;/em&gt; was new to the Roller Derby scene in 2014, and also had the aim of trying to promote the sport back in the West Indies itself, with all of the skaters being from leagues outside of the islands (and many from the UK). Two years later, it seems that they're planning even greater things - but there's no official roster published for the team to date. We gather that Birmingham Blitz Dames and London Rockin' Rollers are still the core of the UK branch of the team, however, and both teams have had strong years - the Blitz Dames in particular benefitting from a change of coaching style which has improved their performance. While we rated West Indies as a little weaker than Spain and Wales in 2014, we wouldn't rule out surprising things from the team after 2 more years to build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4007" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/team-ireland.jpg?w=600" alt="team ireland" width="300" height="300"&gt; Team France logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Ireland Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt; did pretty well at the 2014 World Cup - in fact, on some metrics, we considered them competitive with France! The 2016 iteration is totally unknown, however - they're literally recruiting and selecting as we write this. On the basis of the performance of Dublin Roller Derby (who recently had a US trip and came back even stronger), we wouldn't rule the new Team Ireland out of a top 3 spot in this tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9080" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14390622_1111812092237414_410042907831655880_n.png?w=600" alt="14390622_1111812092237414_410042907831655880_n" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we come to our local team: &lt;em&gt;Team Scotland&lt;/em&gt;!
Scotland performed very creditably in the 2014 World Cup, placing around 10/11th place by our calculations. In 2014, the Scotland team was strongly dominated by Glasgow Roller Derby and Auld Reekie Roller Girls, with only a few skaters from Granite City, 1 from Dundee, and 1 each from Seaside Sirens and London Rollergirls.
This time around, due to both changes at Glasgow, and the strong growth in strength at Dundee and Granite City, we have a more rounded mix of representation in the training team (5 skaters from Dundee, and one from Fierce Valley!); as well as more skaters from outside Scotland itself, with 2 from Wirral, 2 from Newcastle and 1 each from Hallam, Leicester, London Rockin' Rollers!
We're not sure how the team roster for Team Scotland has been selected for The Road to TBC, but we've seen the team in practice, and they look pretty cohesive already. We'd tip Scotland for a chance at upsetting Ireland's dreams of a Top 3 spot, if anyone does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the only way to actually see if we're right is to make your way to Cardiff for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1224163900948144/"&gt;The Road to TBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; itself. Ticket sales are open for the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;27th November,&lt;/strong&gt; and sales are going fast, we believe!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>european roller derby tournament</category><category>international derby</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>statistics</category><category>team belgium</category><category>team france</category><category>team ireland</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team spain</category><category>team sweden</category><category>team wales</category><category>team west indies</category><category>the road to tbc</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 10:36:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Wales Men's National Roller Derby Squad</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/26/mrdwc-2016-team-review-wales-mens-national-roller-derby-squad/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2014, Wales were in Group Red with Finland and USA. Their final game was against Australia with the winner taking the shiny plate. Australia took that win and Team Wales took 6th place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466933587792.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466933587792.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466933587792.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Wales' logo, retained from the 2014 MRDWC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spoke to team Wales skater Ben Phillips who was lovely enough to answer some questions for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;BENPHILLIPS!!!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are preparations going for the world cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prep is going well, we've been training quite regularly since the start of this squad's tenure. Coming from the previous squad, which was consisted more of a ragtag group of skaters, into a more structured system with a HR and a proper Head Coach in Oceanne Esparcieux, the benefits have been felt greatly.
A large number of the previous squad tried out again and made it so it feels similar to the old squad but with a much needed injection of new blood in the shape of the coaching and new players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How often do you train?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twice a week with South Wales Silures and twice a week with Cardiff Bay Crossbones (Roller Hockey team), Refereeing local women's teams when I feel the itch for skating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International duties are once a month training then games on top of that. We had a pretty good showing in 4 Nations and a friendly against Ireland so we feel like we should be firing on all cylinders come July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any off skates training?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to cycle to work as much as I can (17miles each way) as a form of cardio and try to get the gym when I have time in the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From which leagues have your players been selected?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly South Wales Silures but not as much as the 2014 squad, returning from the previous squad is the Underrated and outstanding Berserker from Southern Discomfort and Swifty from Milton Keynes. We've had some great new blood in the form of U-go Boss from NWO, J-Wrecks from Sons of Icarus, Tom Thump from Wirral Pack Animals, to name a few. We have a resident canadian in the form of Hung Solo who is with River City Riot in Calgary so hopefully he can give us the skinny with the Canadians when we meet them in our group match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your team goals for the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To rise in the world rankings, 6th last time round so anything above that would be a success. We're pretty confident we can qualify through our group with our biggest game is against the hosts Canada. Having played them in MRDWC14 I cant wait to meet them on track again, great bunch of guys with some fancy footwork to boot! My personal goal is to have Tim Horton's (Timmy H) for breakfast the entire time in Canada... Dem DoubleDoubles...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally believe, depending on how we do in the group stages, we can reach the semis but it'll all depend how we react to the transatlantic flight and Calgary altitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about your fundraising and sponsorship.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So our facebook page, &lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/Wales-Mens-National-Roller-Derby-Squad-278766772249805/&lt;/strong&gt; has been running a gofundme at &lt;strong&gt;www.gofundme.com/teamwalescalgary&lt;/strong&gt; as well as a helmet competition with Swift Customs &lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/Swiftcyclesandskates/&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the hopes of raising donations we have pitted each player against another in a series of 'hilarious' challenges ranging from funny to just a bit weird, the internet seems to like stuff like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can we expect to see from team Wales at the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some heavy hitting as is standard in our derby heritage but with much more control and swish than people may expect. We've got what it takes to be part of the big dogs in this World Cup and hopefully we can prove it. Thanks for listening/reading to my rambling answers and hope you enjoy Wales' games at MRDWC16!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup Wales are in Group Green with Canada, Colombia,  Spain and Germany.  Their first game will be on track 1 against Colombia at 10am Calgary time...which is like 5pm UK time, from the looks of both of these teams, it's definitely going to be a fantastic game to watch! [Due to Colombia dropping out of the Cup, Mexico replaces them - so Wales' first game is at the same time, but against Mexico...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466938690275.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466938690275.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466938690275.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>team wales</category><category>wales men's national roller derby squad</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/26/mrdwc-2016-team-review-wales-mens-national-roller-derby-squad/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 20:36:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Wales Assistant Coach: Chant-Hell</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/21/team-wales-assistant-coach-chant-hell/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Completing our set of interviews, in collaboration with &lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UKRDA&lt;/a&gt;, with &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamwalesrollerderby/"&gt;Team Wales Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s coaching and management team, we present Wales' Assistant Coach: Chant-Hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;(Tryouts for skaters in the current Team Wales Roller Derby are this Sunday!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/wp-1461262604145-jpg/"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-7084 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1461262604145.jpg?w=678" alt="Chant-Hell, playing with Tiger Bay Brawlers against London Rollergirls (Photo: Adam Chard)" width="678" height="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Chant-Hell, playing with Tiger Bay Brawlers against London Rollergirls (Photo: &lt;a href="http://www.croatoandesign.co.uk"&gt;Adam Chard&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Chant-Hell started out in the Cardiff Roller Collective in 2011, before moving to coach and skate for Tiger Bay Brawlers in 2012, where she remains. She is also owner of the Skate Alley skate store. Pregnancy ruled out Chant Hell from trying out for positions in the 2014 Team Wales, but this time around she is both Assistant Coach, and also planning to try out for the team itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;What led you to apply to coach Team Wales?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted a new challenge, I think getting to know and then coach a group of skaters that I don't really know in a high pressure and competitive environment will be both fun and challenging. Obviously representing my country in a sport I love is a pretty huge bonus too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last time around you had to sit out tryouts. What was it like to experience Team Wales from the sort-of-outside, as a Welsh skater? (And, as Assistant Coaches are eligible to try out, are you planning to tryout yourself this time around?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time around I was heavily pregnant over the Team Wales try out period so if I'm honest as I didn't skate during my pregnancy I spent a lot of time pretending Roller Derby didn't exist. I did volunteer at the first stage of try outs in Cardiff but other than that I experienced Team Wales from a complete outsider perspective and was really impressed by their performance and the progression of each individuals skater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes I'm planning on trying out this time around, its super exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the duties of the Assistant Coaching position is to sit on the selection panel for try outs. What will you be looking for in skaters trying out for Team Wales (and what advice would you give prospective applicants)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I'm trying out myself I have no involvement in the try outs or selection process at all, I think this makes it more exciting as I have no idea who or how many people have put themselves forward. The advice I'm giving myself is to let go of any nerves, have fun and be badass 😊&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The other main duty of an Assistant Coach is to, well, assist with coaching! From your experience coaching Tiger Bay Brawlers, what aspects of training are you planning to focus on for the National Team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coaching and being part of Tiger Bay has taught me so much, I think focussing on team work is going to be really important as we are essentially a mixed Roller Derby team made up of skaters who have potentially never even met each other! I would think that skaters on a National squad would already have a high level of skating skills so I think strategy &amp;amp; team work are going to be a main focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last time around, Team Wales hosted the Road To Dallas event as an intermediate tournament before the World Cup. There's a training and coaching advantage to playing a number of bouts before the Cup itself - are you planning any similar things this time around?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I'm aware we do intend to host another Road to Dallas style tournament, like you said there are huge advantages of playing bouts/tournaments before the Cup and it's a great way for all of our skaters to gain tournament experience even if  they don't play in the World Cup itself. Tournaments are tough so I think we should take as many opportunities as we can to prepare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We don't know much about Blood &amp;amp; Thunders plans for the 2017 World Cup yet: if you could have the tournament anywhere, where would you pick? Last time around, Wales played an eclectic mix of teams from across the world. What teams would you most like to see Team Wales play in 2017?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe!!! I would love for us to play Norway and Team West Indies (again!).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>team wales</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/21/team-wales-assistant-coach-chant-hell/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 18:54:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Wales Head Coach: Smirkcules</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/05/team-wales-head-coach-smirkcules/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The chance to learn more about &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamwalesrollerderby"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;' Management team continues, in collaboration with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UKRDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, as we cover the first of the two Coaching positions with Team Wales Head Coach Smirkcules.&lt;/p&gt;
If you would like to try out for Team Wales as a skater, then you can apply via the form here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The FAQ concerning applications is here:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1"&gt;https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; . The application deadline is April 17, so there's only 2 weeks to get yours in!
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/05/team-wales-head-coach-smirkcules/11816794_870899459662448_9095224078660854342_n/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-6933"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-6933" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/11816794_870899459662448_9095224078660854342_n.jpg" alt="Smirkcules, " width="700" height="467"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Smirkcules, benching Birmingham Blitz Dames (Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Cinderwreckerphotography/"&gt;Cinderwrecker&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Smirkcules has had an extensive Coaching career in Roller Derby, starting out with London Rockin' Rollers in 2010, before moving to Croydon Roller Derby, and &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; moving the considerable geographical distance to Newfoundland, coaching 709 Roller Derby there. After a few years coaching in Canada and Australia, he arrived back on British shores in time to coach Birmingham Blitz Dames to top of the Tier 3 table in British Champs 2015. He's also an ex-skater for Southern Discomfort!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;As well as all of that, he's a fairly prolific announcer, and announced at the Road to Dallas event in 2014 where Team Wales last battled it out against the UK's other teams (and Team West Indies). He's co-announced with Team Wales Manager &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/24/team-wales-manager-dorkmistress/"&gt;Dorkmistress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, at other events, as well as being involved along with her in the short-lived Team Sealand, placing him in good stead to collaborate in his current role as Team Wales Head Coach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;You've got a whole host of coaching experience, in the UK and Canada and Australia, but not especially in Wales. Why did you apply to coach Team Wales specifically?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wales is where I took my first guest coaching session and where I've returned multiple times to coach, announce and watch matches. It's also where I played the majority of my games in mixed scrims and co-ed matches, before injury knocked me out as a player for a long time. I have a lot of friends and derby colleagues I like working with in Wales. I have a lot of love for Wales and as a roller derby coach I like working with the Welsh derby community in different ways.
In my personal statement during the application process I summed it up with the following:
"I am really excited to be applying for the position with Team Wales as I enjoy working with passionate, hard fighting athletes who give their all."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's still true today. I'm really looking forward to our tryouts on April 24&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; to see these passionate fighters turn up and give their all to earn a spot to represent Wales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part of the Head Coach role is sitting on the selection panel for skater tryouts. What will you be looking for in Skaters trying out for Team Wales? (And what advice would you give those thinking about trying out?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of things we'll be looking for. We're looking to build a squad of skaters who can work and develop together. Boiling it down as simply as possible I'd say the two main things are: ability and attitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're looking for skaters who can perform at the highest level comfortably and confidently. Who have the capacity for moments of greatness. But we're also looking for skaters who are determined and have a strong work ethic, who don't mind doing what is asked of them at any time. Skaters who know and play roller derby as a team sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two aren't mutually exclusive. Skaters should be able to demonstrate both of these during tryouts. So if you are coming to tryout or want to sign up, I'd say put your best skills on show and work hard during your session. The expectations are high because they will one day be up against some of the best skaters in the world and we are building a squad to work together and compete at that high level. So as long as skaters understand this and give their best, they'll do fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In common with Team Wales Manager Dorkmistress, you've also done a lot of announcing, including at the Road to Dallas pre-World Cup event in 2014. How did you feel announcing Road to Dallas?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've done a lot of things in roller derby; coach, player, bench staff, NSO. The only thing I've not done in a bout is ref. Announcing is fantastic because you act as the middle person between the game and the crowd. You have to know both of these aspects well to get a good vibe going and ensure the game isn't compromised by your announcing whilst also keeping the crowd informed. It's a challenge but a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Announcing at Road to Dallas was great! It had four great national teams playing, one of which was making their international tournament debut. I love watching Team Scotland's packwork. Team Ireland showed some great high speed derby. West Indies was a new team to watch. Team Wales included skaters I like to watch play at anytime. So was really exciting and fun day. For anyone wanting international experience in the crowd, NSO or reffing, these smaller scale events are great opportunities if they come around. The audience was fantastic for Road to Dallas for all the teams playing. Was great derby to watch and commentate on and a great crowd to work with and for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The other component of being Head Coach is, well, coaching Team Wales. What principles are you going to be adopting to take the Team as far as they can go in the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well I don't want to give too many secrets away just yet but I have a personal coaching style and play mentality I refer to as the Complete Game. This involves not letting any moment go wasted. Every second counts and I want the team to make every second matter. Essentially I want to create a squad of ruthless, fierce warriors who are a challenge to any team they come up against, giving no quarter and expecting none in return. The image and motif I often use to describe it is a bunch of elite guerrilla warriors getting in, getting the job done and sticking the knife in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We don't know much about the potential location of the 2017 World Cup. Where would you like it to be, and what teams would you most like to see Wales play at it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My top three locations would be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wales – home crowd and Wales is a very welcoming, friendly place that people should visit. Derby just makes it better.
Finland – I love Helsinki and if at the end of the year, lots of snow and winter fun.
Australia – Outdoor tournament anyone? BBQs, beaches and huge love of sport! Lots of Summer fun if at end of year again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three teams I'd love for Wales to come up against at the next World Cup are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Norway – I'd like to have another game against them as I think the game against them in 2014 was a good match up. Be good to see how both teams have progressed since then.
England – Classic England vs Wales matches in every sport are always exciting so let's make it happen in roller derby.
Finland – I like Team Finland. I think it'd be a tough game but exciting.
Dream Final:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wales vs Australia – The team I coach vs the nation I was born in competing for the world cup. Couldn't ask for more than that!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>team wales</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/05/team-wales-head-coach-smirkcules/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 20:07:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Wales Line-Up Manager: Professor Moriarty</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/03/team-wales-line-up-manager-professor-moriarty/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier, we covered &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamwalesrollerderby/"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;' &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/24/team-wales-manager-dorkmistress/"&gt;Manager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and one of their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/28/team-wales-skater-buccaneer-betty-fear/"&gt;skaters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from the 2014 team, but we shouldn't forget the Coaching team, who will be training and organising Team Wales on track into the 2017 World Cup. In collaboration with &lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UKRDA&lt;/a&gt;, we're happy to start off our run of Coaching team interviews with Team Wales' returning Line-Up Manager, Professor Moriarty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to try out for Team Wales as a skater, then you can apply via the form here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The FAQ concerning applications is here:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1"&gt;https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; . The application deadline is April 17, so there's only 2 weeks to get yours in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/03/team-wales-line-up-manager-professor-moriarty/10858600_885961641434940_5869953106835376334_n/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-6918"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-6918" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/10858600_885961641434940_5869953106835376334_n.jpg" alt="Professor Moriarty, at the left, walking out with Team Wales in Dallas. (Photo: Jason Ruffell, Roller-derby-on-film.)" width="700" height="382"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Professor Moriarty, at the left, walking out with Team Wales in Dallas. (Photo: Jason Ruffell, &lt;a href="http://www.roller-derby-on-film.co.uk/"&gt;Roller-derby-on-film&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Moriarty has been a member of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/NPTRD"&gt;Neath Port Talbot Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; since she started in the game, 3 years ago. She bench coached the team through last year's British Champs, and into this year's. Selected as Line-Up Manager for the first Team Wales which competed in the 2014 Roller Derby World Cup in Dallas, she reapplied for the role, and was successful in this earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In common with other members of Team Wales, you're returning in your role as LUM from last time around. What lead to you reapply to the role for a second run?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yep, I’m a glutton for punishment! I had an amazing time during my first term with Team Wales but it was quite an emotional rollercoaster due to us being a brand new team.  We had to start everything from scratch; some said that we would never make it to Dallas, but we proved the doubters wrong and were placed 17th in our very first World Cup. I feel like Team Wales is our baby and I want to be able to nurture it and watch it grow from the fledgling team we were last time. I want to be able to say; "I was part of that. I helped that grow to new heights within the Derby community."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The LUM is also involved in selection and training for the National Teams. What things were you looking out for in Team Wales selection last time (and what are you looking out for in the new applicants this time)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During our first try outs we were trying to find as many skaters that were able and prepared to give the commitment to a new team that was needed. I remember seeing Jen (R27) for the first time and she blew my mind with her passion and love of the sport.
With our ability to now prove we are a country that wants to be present on the World Stage of Derby, I think our thoughts are different. We want to build on what we did last time and need to be more specific in the direction we take. We’ve done the “Got there, did that”, we now want to inspire local skaters to want to be part of their countries team. This can only be done by ensuring that we look for not only existing talent, but also rough diamonds.
I may offend a few skaters but my ideology is: we are Welsh, we are not pretty players but what we do, we do well, with the grit and determination of a country that is hardworking and focused on being the best they can possibly be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And how are you planning on contributing to the training process for the selection?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a coach and will never claim to be one; what I bring to the table is the ability to read people and be able to know what they are capable of. During the last term we had a skater that was not the best, but her communication was second to none. I fought against a lot of opposition to ensure that she was given the chances she deserved and it paid off. Just because you don’t have the right footwork or the right build shouldn’t mean that you’re not suitable to play for your country. This sport was built on inclusivity and I am a huge believer in the underdog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LUM can get fairly pressured, especially when playing against a tough team (like New Zealand), on a national stage. How you do manage the job in that kind of situation (and what's it like)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a very level headed person (my Husband may disagree with that). When others are losing their heads around me, I am looking ahead to see where we can make changes to improve what we are doing, so as to alleviate the problem. I like to know each and every one of my skaters, their abilities and what I think they are capable of. With this in mind, I am able to read situations and correct them without causing any pressure on my skaters. I believe in forward thinking, analysing what could and may go wrong and having strategies in place to combat them even before they arise, so as to make sure my skaters are in their Zen place when playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Returning to the role means that you bring a lot of experience with you. What you do think the last World Cup taught you about LUMing the National Team (and is there anything you'll be doing differently this time?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last World Cup taught me to be prepared for all eventualities: Know who does what and where, so when something does crop up it can be dealt with immediately. It taught me to appreciate help and to work as a team. To quote Fear's mantra, “Team work, makes the dream work”. The only thing I’d do differently this time is to try and soak more of the atmosphere in, as while it's happening it’s like a whirlwind all around you and then, poof it’s over!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(And what has been the best part of LUMing Team Wales so far…)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part for me was during the World Cup each country had its own room, which was situated on the floor below the auditorium. Before each game we would congregate here and walk up as a team singing. We sang everything from the National Anthem to Tom Jones, it was amazing!!!!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last time around, you were reluctant to say who you'd like to see Team Wales take on in the World Cup. But, we're going to try again! If you could have any team (existing or not) play Team Wales, who would it be? (And if the World Cup could be anywhere, where would you want it to be?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to see the World Cup in Europe this time. It’s a very expensive time and I think the European countries need a chance to be able to show what we can do. I'm still reluctant [to pick opponents] but would love to see a proper  6 Nations competition, just like the rugby!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>team wales</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/03/team-wales-line-up-manager-professor-moriarty/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 18:00:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Wales Skater: Buccaneer Betty Fear</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/28/team-wales-skater-buccaneer-betty-fear/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing our series of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamwalesrollerderby/"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Interviews, in collaboration with the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UK Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, we present Buccaneer Betty Fear, who skated on the first Team Wales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tryouts are currently open for the next Team Wales, who will compete in the 2017 Roller Derby World Cup. To learn more about the Tryouts, read the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1"&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform"&gt;Application Form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The Application Form also has details of the dates and locations that Tryouts will occur, in &lt;strong&gt;April&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;May&lt;/strong&gt;. If you would like to represent Wales internationally, then sign up to try-out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-6874" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/230c42621.jpg?w=2048" alt="230C4262" width="1024" height="647"&gt; Fear skating in the 2014 World Cup (against New Zealand), on the right. (Courtesy &lt;a href="http://www.girlsofderby.com/"&gt;Sean Murphy&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buccaneer Betty Fear started out in Roller Derby with Severn Roller Torrent in 2011. She remained with Severn, skating and coaching until 2015, when she joined Tiger Bay Brawlers. She was an active member of Tiger Bay during their first and only season in British Champs. She attended the 2014 Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup as a member of Team Wales, playing against Norway, South Africa, New Zealand and Puerto Rico.
Before her retirement from Roller Derby at the end of the last season, she blogged on roller derby and other topics at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://itsahardblocklife.com/author/buccaneerbettyfear/"&gt;It's a Hard Block Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, the obvious first question is at the beginning: why try out for Team Wales?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is so hard to write about why I tried out without relying on cliche. I think it is because it is such a big set of feelings that you run out of words...
Trying out to make a National Squad was not a life experience that I thought I would have. Roller Derby is still at this special, magical time where people who have come to the sport as an adult can have dreams like making a National Squad and have the chance to turn them into reality. If you bring the work and the commitment and the courage to put yourself on the line, you can make it happen. Our sport might not be like that forever (have you seen those juniors??), so grabbing that opportunity now, while we are in this meeting place where hard work can turn you into an elite athlete... was an obvious. At the point of trying out, even the trial felt like a win and an experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell us a bit about the mental game of the tryout process. What did it feel like to go through the tryouts; and wait and then discover you had made it onto the roster?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tryout experience was utterly unlike I expected. I thought it would be this pressurised, lonely experience where everyone was out for themselves. Nope. Within minutes of arrival the skaters trying out were forming bonds with each other. There was a palpable sense of community and support. It was like the larger Roller Derby community, but squeezed into this incredibly intense experience. During drills people were supporting each other and rooting for each other. During scrimmage we were urging each other to jam and to pivot.
Physically and mentally it was one of the toughest experiences I have gone through. The trials were long, demanding and I think they were designed to ensure you were pretty exhausted by the time you scrimmaged. Waiting for the results of the first round of trials was agony, the elation of finding you had made the next round was swiftly followed by the awful realisation you had to do it all again, with more at stake...
Finding out I had made the Squad was an incredibly proud moment. I had spent so long prepping for those trials... I had spent all my money hiring lonely sports halls  at early hours on weekend mornings, I had trained relentlessly in the gym, I'd read pretty much every sports psychology book I could get my hands on. I'd gone all out to make the Squad. Knowing I would wear a Welsh jersey was incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Training for a National Team is a significant additional investment for a skater, on top of their existing league commitments. How did you manage the time needed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the time I was in the Squad, there was no balance in my life. It was Roller Derby, all in. I worked, I played derby and I cross trained. I mumbled 'sorry' to my brilliantly supportive partner as I disappeared every weekend, usually on both days, for League and Squad training. I spent my money on Roller Derby travel, the gym and physio. I missed the wedding of a close friend and countless nights out and weekend adventures.
At some point it stops being about you, and becomes about what you owe the Squad. You know that there were other skaters who would have done anything to have the spot on Squad you have, you owe it to them to go all out. You know that your team mates are missing birthdays and weddings and not seeing their kids in order to train, you owe it to them. And there is always the thought of not letting your Country down. You are going to skate out with a Welsh dragon on your chest, you want to show the World (and the Welsh) that we were serious about this sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the lead up to the World Cup, Wales played several other games, including a kind of home-series (Road To Dallas) against Ireland, Wales and the West Indies. What do you think you and the team gained from these games?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The games we played in the lead-up to the World Cup were an incredibly experience. I think the proliferation of European (and UK-based teams) really lifted the quality of derby that was played at the World Cup. By the time we got there we had played half a dozen games as a National Squad - that makes a huge difference.
Instead of working out kinks in our game at the World Cup, we had a squad who had skated together, understood each other and had developed our game. We also got to learn from the experiences of teams that had skated in the first World Cup. Scotland and Ireland had such strong, experienced Squads. Playing them beforehand gave us a chance to learn and adjust. The West Indies were great to play against as well... they were such a tough, hard-hitting Squad... it totally warmed us up (tenderised us??) for the hard-hitting play we experienced in Dallas.
It also gave us a chance to experience skating as Team Wales and the whole different set of nerves that comes with that. Finally, it meant that more players had the experience of playing for their country. Not everyone made the Squad in Dallas, so some great skaters who didn't get the chance in Dallas still had the incredible experience of skating for their country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representing Wales in Dallas, you played against New Zealand, South Africa, Norway and Puerto Rico. What was your favourite game, and why? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each game was a special and intense experience and created memories that will stay with my forever. South Africa were a great, physical side, having the time of their lives and their spirit was infectious. New Zealand were, well, HUGE! They were formidable and it was brilliant to have the chance to go up against them. Puerto Rico was a joy of a game - the final of the one we played at the World Cup and just a riot.
But my favourite... was Norway. They were skilled, strong and relentless, but we had a moment where Wales came together and realised that everything we had worked for was now and that this was our chance. We went back out on track with a vengeance, lifting our performance. We lost, but that switch in how we were operating on track was special. It was a moment of mental resilience and this incredible sense of skaters going out there for each other. We did each other proud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you planning on trying out for Team Wales again?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've retired now - full of dreams made reality! But to anyone considering it - go.
Try out.
Yes: you.
Imagine being able to say you were at trials for a National Squad... imagine being able to say you made it. Get your butt to training, get to the gym, get watching footage and grab yourself a derby dream. You will get something from any part of the process you go through. Go get it, skater!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We currently don't know much about the 2017 World Cup. If you had a choice, where would you like it to be (and who would you like to face on track?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd love to see it in Europe: the cost for so many teams to travel to North America was prohibitive. I'd love to have it closer to home, and see more European teams able to have all their skaters there and more skaters get the chance to have their moment on track.
Who would I like to see Wales face on track? It's got to be Norway. But this time with a different ending...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team wales</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/28/team-wales-skater-buccaneer-betty-fear/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 13:09:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Wales Manager Dorkmistress</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/24/team-wales-manager-dorkmistress/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, we interviewed the outgoing members of the Team Scotland Management and Coaching Team, in collaboration with the &lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UKRDA&lt;/a&gt;. In an ongoing collaboration with UKRDA, we're happy to present interviews with &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamwalesrollerderby/"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt;' Management and Coaching team, starting with Team Manager: &lt;strong&gt;Dorkmistress&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(You can apply to try out to skate for Team Wales here: &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform&lt;/a&gt; , with a FAQ concerning tryouts here: &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1"&gt;https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1 &lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dorkmistress has had a long and varied time in Roller Derby. Starting in 2011 with the Cardiff Roller Collective, as a skater and announcer, she has since moved to Swansea City Roller Derby (in 2013), and moved into refereeing for both Swansea and the South West Silures in 2014. She was Team Manager for Team Wales Roller Derby for the 2014 Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup, and continues in this role, having been re-elected in the post earlier this year. Her derby CV is extensive, including over 60 games refereed, and 100 announced, over her 5 year period in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full aligncenter" title="wp-1458819373825" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/wp-1458819373825.jpg" alt="image"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In common with other Team Wales roles, you're returning to the role of Manager from the last iteration of the National Team. What led you to decide to continue in the role? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a big decision - I loved the last two years but it's a fairly big commitment. We learnt so much in the last two years, starting the team from scratch and I wanted to make sure that I could see these lessons implemented. I know how I want to do things differently and think that I can do a much better job this time around. Plus, I'm not ready to watch Team Wales on track without being part of it! When I was thinking about how to answer these questions I looked back on the Team Wales Facebook page and seeing the support, encouragement and emotion on there made me remember what an incredible experience and honour it is to be part of Team Wales, and to be part of a team of such amazing people. And I still regularly look at the pictures of the Team Wales supporters gang - those crazy laydees from Neath Port Talbot, the supporters who travelled to Belgium and Dallas with their inflatables and daffodil hats, our own official leader of chants, Rhys Jones. Who wouldn't want to be part of that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managing a National team is quite a complex task, with many things to keep track of (and you've technically managed 2 Nations, what with Team Sealand). What do you think are the most important aspects of the job? (And coping with the workload?) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able and willing to keep all the plates you are spinning in the air is probably the key to success! And you can only achieve that with delegation and lots of communication. I worked with the skaters and other members of the management team to set up committees to cover key areas, like fundraising and events, and each group had an action plan and regular meetings. I did live on Facebook and Google Docs for the year, and ended up missing training a fair bit, but I wanted to make that commitment to make sure Team Wales was in the best place possible in Dallas. I have a busy real life job, but that's given me lots of time management and project planning skills, which were essential. Team Sealand was much easier, I just had to sort out travel and bout contracts ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last time around, a big part of the Management for most National teams was simply raising the funds to make it to Dallas. How did you guys go about managing the process, and finding new ways to get funds?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were really clear that fundraising was the responsibility of everyone in Team Wales, and everyone got involved. We had huge support from leagues from Newcastle to LRG to Severn Roller Torrent to Swansea City Roller Derby, giving us raffle proceeds, holding fundraising events and giving us stall space at their events. We had people donate money, we sold a LOT of t-shirts, we held kare-oke nights, we made loom bands, we had a baby picture competition, we had face painting at our games - literally any way we could get money out of people, we tried. We also decided to hold the fabulous Road to Dallas tournament in Newport in October 2014, hosting Teams Scotland, Ireland and West indies. Fundraising was constant - the challenge was to make it fun and to try and not just ask the same people all the time....same as most leagues face. It will be easier in some ways this time - we have our merch in place and an existing fan base - but harder in a sport where we have more leagues trying to fundraise from the same audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What've you learned from the last time around that you'll be applying this time, to improve Team Wales' management?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you got enough space in this blog? We're starting in a better position - we have a clear identity and design, so we will have t-shirts and merch available sooner and more options for our supporters. Do more on social media - keep everyone updated on our journey towards the World Cup. Delegate more and more completely - easier when you know what you are trying to achieve and know all the details and issues that need to be considered. Get the right partners and sponsors so things are as easy and cheap as possible for us. Play more games - we had 9 months from team selection to the World Cup last time and that wasn't enough - one reason we were keen to kick off the National Squad selection process in the UK. Everyone's going to freak out a bit on this journey - we are all allowed a freakout, just hopefully not at the same time. Sleep more and stop looking at Facebook messages at midnight and then again at 7am. Don't share a room with morning people if you are a night owl - probably the hardest and most important lesson I learnt.....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You've also announced in many places, including at the first Men's World Cup. How would you compare your two World Cup experiences?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very different experiences because they were very different sized events on very different continents. The Men's World Cup memories I have will last me a lifetime. It was my first taste of international roller derby and it was small and perfectly formed - the announcing team was incredible and the size of the schedule and event meant you could keep up with all of the action and see all of the teams and skaters sat next to you. I got to hang out with Team Japan and watch Team Argentina and nearly lost my voice shouting at Team Wales scoring points against Team USA - and those moments were all in the same room, right next to each other. It was the first time I got to introduce the Welsh National Anthem and I can still feel the hairs rising on the back of my neck. I also got to do the in-house announcement for &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; Wales V Australia game and the emotion in the venue at that last jam overwhelmed me so much I cried for 30 minutes at the end of the game - us announcers feed off that crowd emotion and I have never felt anything like it. It was such a personal experience I am not sure anything will ever really be the same as that. I'm desperately proud to have been part of the delivery of that event and I am more than a bit heartbroken that I can't go to Calgary this July - but I know Team Wales will make me and everyone else even prouder than they did that day in Birmingham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blood and Thunder World Cup was just so much bigger. When we arrived at the airport the customs guys said 'you here for the roller derby?'. Thats because they had already seen so many skaters and fans. 30 teams is a lot of people, three tracks in this massive room in a ginormous exhibition centre in America? Much bigger than the Futsal! If I went to the team room (each team had its own room! what?!) it was a good 5 minute walk, which, by the end of the day, felt like 5 miles. We'd gone to the European Roller Derby Tournament in Belgium and shared the underside of the bleachers seating with 7 other National teams and the next thing you knew we had a Team Support person, and a room and all sorts of things to make our time easier. I missed announcing though, you watch games in a different way and I didn't see a lot of other games as I was busy on the merch stall or sorting transport or one of the many other things that went on. And I missed being part of the team that showed you the event and explained what was going on. However, nothing in my life will ever compare to being able to walk out on the biggest Roller Derby stage in the world as part of Team Wales in the Parade of Nations. I can't even now, all this time later, put that experience and feeling into words. It's something I will forever be proud of and proud to have been part of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you were interviewed last time around, you noted that you were most looking forward to Team Wales playing "teams from far off places". In the event, Wales played South Africa, New Zealand, Norway and Puerto Rico, at least three of which probably count! If you could play any teams (announced or not) in the upcoming World Cup, what would they be?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Norway are going down this time ;-) It was almost impossible to watch the game  - seeing the team play out of their skins to claw back to within reaching distance for Norway to pull away just at the end. I'd love to see us play Argentina, they were incredible in Dallas and I think the South American teams are going to go to the next World Cup with a huge step up in skills and strategy. And there will be teams from new places - Iceland, definitely, maybe even Egypt, or Russia [where there are teams, but no established National infrastructure, yet]! We think and talk a lot about European Derby and Derby in North America, but the World Cup is the only place we get to see derby developing as a Global sport, and thats going to be really evident in the next World Cup for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(And if you have a place you'd like the World Cup to be, for any reason…)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would love it to be in Japan as I have always wanted to go there but even pretending I'd have to fundraise for that makes me want to cry! Very boringly I'd like it to be in Europe next - I think that showing as many people as possible international level derby inspires skaters and so would like to see it move around continents to give everyone that experience - watching it on the internet isnt quite the same. So next time Australia or New Zealand. Then South America or Asia or Africa. A true world tour!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team wales</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/24/team-wales-manager-dorkmistress/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 11:38:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interviews: UK and Ireland</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/20/world-cup-interviews-uk-and-ireland/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last week, our &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; tour covered The UK and Ireland. Over the weekend, Ireland, Wales and Scotland (and Team West Indies) played against each other in the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/724704624268299/"&gt;Road to Dallas&lt;/a&gt; tournament, with Scotland placing 1st, ahead of Ireland in second place, and the hosts, Wales, taking up the 4th place position, despite a close game against third-place West Indies.
If you missed any of our interviews, here’s a recap…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Ireland" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/14/world-cup-interview-team-ireland/"&gt;Team Ireland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Wales" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/15/world-cup-interview-team-wales/"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Scotland" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/16/world-cup-interview-team-scotland/"&gt;Team Scotland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team England" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/17/world-cup-interview-team-england/"&gt;Team England&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week we will be hopping over to Scandinavia to interview the teams from Norway, Denmark, Finland and Sweden!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team england</category><category>team ireland</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team scotland roller derby</category><category>team wales</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/20/world-cup-interviews-uk-and-ireland/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 09:50:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Wales</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/15/world-cup-interview-team-wales/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamwalesrollerderby"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt; will be making their &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;World Cup Debut&lt;/a&gt; in December 2014 and everyone is very excited to see them play. Liz Gibson also known as Talula Trouble, was able to answer some questions for me.
&lt;p&gt;Team Wales will also be competing in &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/724704624268299/?fref=ts"&gt;The Road to Dallas&lt;/a&gt; this weekend with Scotland, Ireland and West Indies, and are, in fact, the hosts of the event!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://caleykapowski.files.wordpress.com/2014/10/team-wales.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4" src="https://caleykapowski.files.wordpress.com/2014/10/team-wales.jpg?w=300" alt="Team Wales logo" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Team Wales logo by Dafydd Williams&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are your training sessions going, have you had to take time from your own league training for Team Wales training? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team Wales training sessions are very hard work but a lot of fun. We train about twice a month either in South Wales or Gloucester area .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel I have learnt so much from the coaches and the other skaters. Having such a range of skaters from different leagues provides us with such a great range of strategy and game play, we all get along great and have really bonded over the last few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My home league the Wirral Whipiteres are very supportive of my training commitment to team Wales. Sadly I have had to take time from training and bouts to try out and train, but my home league have been very accommodating .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In addition to Team Wales training, how have you been preparing for the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To prepare for the world cup I have been using ankle weights at my home league training to build up my endurance and power as well as skating out doors about twice a week (weather permitting).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also been trying to eat healthier as a result of doing more training. I am interested in doing cross training as a few of our Wales girls cross train by doing yoga/aerobics/gym/swimming etc but finding the time to do that has been difficult so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have you been fundraising and achieving sponsorship in order to help with the expense of travelling to Texas?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To raise funds for training/funds to attend the world cup I have recently held a cinema night, a mega raffle and coached some local leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cinema night was held at my home leagues local after party venue "Mistys", we had some footage from wwrd vs nwrd and Team Wales vs Blitz dames. Of course we had cake too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the mega raffle I sold tickets to lots of skaters from a whole range of leagues. Some awesome derby shops such as (bootlegbrawlers, rollerderbycity, grandslam and Queens of the sin bin) and local leagues were very keen to donate prizes to help. I really cant thank them enough!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next fundraising project is to auction off a fully signed Southern Discomfort t-shirt, which the lovely Rolling Thunder organised!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What teams are you most looking forward to playing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm really looking forward to playing team Germany. I recently saw them at the womens euro's in Belgium, their play was very technical and they worked well together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you most looking forward to about the World Cup this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am really looking forward playing some of the best skaters in the world. The world cup is the pinnacle of roller derby. To be a part of it is really amazing and I cant wait for the adventure, its a new chapter in my derby life which all skaters dream of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Manager Dorkmistress also told me the process involved for Team selection;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UKRDA ran an election process for our Head Coach, Assistant Coach, Lineup Manager and Team Manager. Candidates were asked to apply describing their experience and how they would approach the role. UKRDA member leagues then voted to elect the best candidates. The Management team were elected in two stages in 2013, and we unfortunately had to rerun the elections for Head Coach and Assistant Coach in 2014 as the initial coaches stepped down.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class="_37"&gt;
&lt;div class="_53"&gt;
&lt;div class="_3hi clearfix"&gt;
&lt;div class="_38 direction_ltr"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We worked with the UKRDA again to set in place the selection criteria and timetable for the skater selection so that it was comparable across the home nations. We had first round tryouts in South and north Wales in Jan 2014, and the second round tryouts were held in March.  We had 60 skaters try out and we selected 27 for the Training Squad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Team Wales roster&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baby Cheesus
Beatrix
Blaze of Gory
Buccaneer Betty Fear
Glenys the Menace
Gin n Sonic
Haman
Jen-Clawed Van Slamme
Jolly-Pop
Lockhart
Marie Bayonet
Mort
Ireste
Optimus
Snail
Steflon
Sleazy Rider
Talula Trouble
ThunderKat
Voodoo Ray&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Manager - D orkmistress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head Coach- Ben Phillips&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lineup- Professor Moriarty&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team wales</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/15/world-cup-interview-team-wales/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 09:11:38 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>