<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about team poland)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/team-poland.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 08:59:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Slavic Roller Derby Tournament grows into its second year, adds the Baltics!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/23/the-slavic-roller-derby-tournament-grows-into-its-second-year-adds-the-baltics/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, we &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/08/11/a-slavic-tournament-how-central-and-eastern-european-derby-exploded-in-just-3-years/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reported&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the first ever "Slavic Roller Derby Tournament", a three team round-robin hosted by Warsaw Hellcats, and featuring St Petersburg's White Night Furies, and Prague City Roller Derby B in addition to the hosts. At the time, we noted that the mere possibility of this tournament existing was a signal for just how fast Roller Derby is expanding into Eastern Europe...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and that expansion has continued into this year, so it is perhaps unsurprising that the tournament is back for a second year this October; bigger and more extensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27274" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/slavic_map_out.png?w=2048" alt="SLAVIC_map_out" width="1024" height="650"&gt; Competitors in Red, except the hosts (in Blue), and the three teams contributing to Team Czech (in Yellow). Men's Derby bout competitors in Black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poland have outdone expectations by doubling the number of contenders this time around, and extending the geographical inclusion to the southern Baltic states as well as Slavic nations. Fitting the resulting 6 team round robin into a single day is only possible with non-WFTDA rulesets (15 games would take 15 hours of WFTDA play, not including breaks), so this edition of the Slavic Tournament is being run as with Roller Derby Sevens rules. The reduced maximum roster size of Sevens also makes it more accessible for some of the newer competitors as an additional bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, this added accessibility has allowed several other firsts at this event:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riga Roller Derby, representing Latvia, have previous bout experience, as part of the Team Baltic Roller Derby who competed against Team Israel at the 2018 Roller Derby World Cup - but have never played as a team themselves. Their Sevens team will therefore represent multiple firsts here: the first time Riga have competed as a team, and the first time &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; team from the (south) Baltics have competed in a ranked event!
This is very good timing, as the Baltics have just gained their third official league - in Tallinn, Estonia - this week, showing the work done in Riga and Tartu paying off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Baltic is not the only connection to the Roller Derby World Cup, as Team Czech Roller Derby will be representing their country in Sevens form, with skaters from Prague's Prague City Roller Derby and Hard Breaking Dolls, joined by members of Roller Derby Brno. Brno's skaters on Team Czech will all be skating in their first public bouts at this tournament, giving them good experience to take back to their league. (We hope that next time Team Czech plays, they can also include skaters from the newly formed league in Ostravia, also announced this week!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27275" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/slavic_czech_map_out.png?w=2048" alt="SLAVIC_CZECH_map_out" width="1024" height="714"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Host country Poland will be exceptionally well represented, with not only hosts Warsaw Hellcats, and their fellow Warsaw team, Worst Warsaw, competing, but also Vratislavia (Wrocław)'s MadChix Roller Squad! All three teams have at least several games under their belt, and contributed skaters to Team Poland, (although Warsaw's teams are a lot more experienced!). Additionally, all are particularly used to Sevens tournaments, having competed in the 7th Heaven tournament in Poznań only a few months ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also returning to the tournament from last time are the only bouting team in Russia, St Petersburg's White Night Furies; although they are sending their newer B team, Ingria Rollers, to compete this time around. The Furies also gained a lot of experience from their members in Team Russia at the World Cup this year (as well as their continued participation in the Pohjola Cup), so we're expecting a strong performance from their B Team here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The restrictions of Sevens rostering make it difficult to predict the standings of the Slavic/Baltic tournament from FTS records (not least because several of these teams are playing for the first time!), but we'd be unsurprised by strong performances from the hosts, and the composite Czech team. Given the strong tournament experience gained by many of the competitors here in the past year, however, it's hard to rule anyone out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the main event, this edition of the Slavic/Baltic Tournament will also be showcasing two other contests:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another debut, this time in men's roller derby: Polish Men's Roller Derby, a collaboration of the Polish Eagles skaters based in Poland itself, play their first game on home soil, ever, against the might of London's Southern Discomfort B, Mild Discomfort!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, finally, a chance to see another fantastic sport on wheels, as Warsaw's Wheelchair Rugby team present their sport in an exhibition game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2079168135665222/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;first Slavic/Baltic Tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will be held on the 20th October in &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/XDcKWPs5wWN2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centrum Sportu Wilanów&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in Warsaw, Poland. Tickets and more information will be available on the Facebook Event in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>baltic roller derby</category><category>czech republic</category><category>hard breaking dolls</category><category>ingria rollers</category><category>international derby</category><category>poland</category><category>polish roller derby</category><category>prague city roller derby</category><category>riga roller derby</category><category>roller derby sevens</category><category>slavic tournament</category><category>southern discomfort</category><category>team czech</category><category>team poland</category><category>team poland men's roller derby</category><category>team russia</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>tournaments2018</category><category>vratislavia madchix</category><category>white night furies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/23/the-slavic-roller-derby-tournament-grows-into-its-second-year-adds-the-baltics/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 09:57:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Poland: New to the World Cup 2018</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/09/team-poland-new-to-the-world-cup-2018/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Returning to our series on the 11 teams new to the Roller Derby World Cup 2018 in Manchester, and we're staying in Europe for this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poland, despite having one of the largest populations in Central Europe, has only recently developed a significant Roller Derby population. We talked to one of Team Poland's organisers, Ewa Kaczyńska, about the formation of the National Team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-19856" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/screen-shot-2017-06-02-at-15-34-22.png?w=300" alt="Screen Shot 2017-06-02 at 15.34.22" width="300" height="188"&gt; The Polish Flag (standing in for Team Poland's logo)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Roller Derby having only come to Poland in 2013 - the first league in Poznań quickly followed by Warsaw, then Wrocław, Szczecin and Gdańsk - there was little possibility to compete in the 2014 World Cup. Since then, Polish Derby has grown considerably, to the point of holding their first &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1232048456872900/"&gt;Derby Sevens tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; this year, as well as hosting one of Scald Eagle &amp;amp; Lady Trample's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1852698681626181/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WinTourOpe bootcamp&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; dates. Whilst not all the leagues are huge at the moment (there's a preference for mixed team events and scrims to cover the numbers for the smaller teams), Polish derby is still growing and in a strong position in the Central European vanguard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is often the case, inline skating is more popular in Poland than Quads, although, Ewa notes: "[interest in quad skates] is growing, here is a better access to quads in shops. However, not that much luck with roller derby related skate shops, as there are just 3 or 4 with limited offerings." It's perhaps the growth of Chicks in Bowls, which also has a Polish branch, which is helping to drive this interest, helping out Roller derby with the cross-over, as it does elsewhere. "Yes, they definitely [help]. It's good that girls are taking over the skateparks!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more derby related help, the community surrounding has been supportive, with bootcamps and shared bouts popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Thanks to skaters from all over the World we are able to organize bootcamps led by experienced coaches," Ewa told us. "That is so much different from learning from the book - as we did at first! 'Roller Derby 101: The Fresh Meat Training Manual ' was our first derby bible... Now, we get a lot of help and support from Czech and German teams - I guess it's just the thing with neighbours! &lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We also get  lots of help from Polish (and other) skaters from all over the World.&lt;/span&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the intent to participate applications opened for the 2018 World Cup,  Poland were actually the last team to sign up, as Ewa notes: "There’s been a discussion about founding Polish National Roller Derby Team going on since November 2016 in Poland. [...]No decisions were made until the very last moment before the registration period ended. We formed a Founding Committee and acted!
I think [the decision] was just about not letting people miss the opportunity to represent Poland."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ewa also had personal reasons for pushing for the decision to commit, "I believe that sometimes people need to be pushed a bit. Sometimes no decisions are made simply because of the lack of courage, or ability to take responsibility for one's actions. I started derby three years ago and I started it to compete later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;At first I thought that Polish skaters are not yet ready to compete on such level as World Cup. Since last November, we had numerous discussions with more experienced skaters. We got a lot of encouragement and support and then it suddenly became clear to us: t&lt;/span&gt;hings like forming a National Team need to be done to push things further, to make teams grow, to create opportunities for development. We cannot just sit doing nothing!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the last-minute decision, Poland's size and population have immediately produced results, with more than 50 skaters registered to try out or otherwise be involved, with around 50% from the existing Polish teams, and the rest from across the World. Poland has many nationals, and descendants of nationals, spread across the world - in Europe and in the USA - and many of them feel just as much pride for their country as those who live there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"After we decided to found Team Poland we got a massive response from other parts of the World, which is just amazing; [...] it is truly touching when we get messages from people that 'want to do it for their Grandpa', although we would [also] love Team Poland to have lots of Polish girls living in Poland!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for all National Teams, and especially the newer ones, Team Poland are driven by more than simply patriotism. With National teams comes the chance of better visibility for Roller Derby as well - and a chance to combat myths and prejudice. "What really pushed us to form TP is a bigger picture," explains Ewa. "We know that all the teams went the same way at the beginning: rented vintage skates, no proper protection, no coaches, no places to skate. Also most of people think about roller derby as of 'rugby on quads' or an aggressive sport for punk girls with piercings and tattoos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely, we do have them, but taking a part in such a big event could be an eye opener for people here! We would love them to acknowledge this sport as an athletic discipline, not only for 'outcasts'..."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And part of growing that athletic image is, of course, better training. As we discussed with &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/26/team-austria-new-to-the-world-cup/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Austria&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the advantage of  National Teams is also in the sharing of experience and skills, and Ewa agrees. "We all think that apart from World Cup, the following months will let us all benefit from the joined training sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a big step for Polish roller derby, that's for sure!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no Team Poland website or Facebook page yet - interested people should email the team at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:team.Poland.roller.derby@gmail.com"&gt;team.Poland.roller.derby@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;or&lt;strong&gt; message Ewa Kaczyńska on Facebook.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2018</category><category>team poland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/09/team-poland-new-to-the-world-cup-2018/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 15:25:26 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>