<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about team nitemare)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/team-nitemare.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 11:56:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Derby Review 2014: Nitemare, Voodoo and Hades... and Bob.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/12/derby-review-2014-nitemare-voodoo-and-hades-and-bob/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A slightly unusual Review entry this time: not a league, but a collection of Derby Happenings all tied together by one common feature: Falkirk's own skate and roller derby store, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/intothe.nitemareclothing"&gt;Into The Nitemare&lt;/a&gt;. We thought that, what with having their own exhibition team, founding two others during the year &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; putting on a national tournament, they probably deserved an article to themselves...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/img_0002.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-3280" alt="img_0002" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/img_0002.png?w=614" width="368" height="553"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Titan and Raven, Into The Nitemare, at the end of Battle of Britain (Copyright: Sam Skipsey)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/img_0001.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3281" alt="Newcastle Roller Girls, winners of BoB." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/img_0001.png?w=614" width="614" height="408"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Newcastle Roller Girls, winners of BoB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This has been an eventful year for Into The Nitemare's derby involvement, with Team Nitemare holding their first exhibition bouts, the formation of Hades Roller Boys and Voodoo Roller Dollies, and the successful hosting of Scotland's second ever national tournament, Battle of Britain. What has been the standout experience for the two of you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve had an amazing year derby wise, and there are far too many highlights to name just one. Team Nitemare was just amazing, I remember welling up at the skateout. Just so proud to see two amazing groups of such talent under one roof. The Jakey Tayzers proved to be a force to be reckoned with and as it turns out, many of them have found themselves on their gender's National Team Scotland. That was also the day of the Hades debut, which was one of the most exciting bouts I’ve had the pleasure of experiencing…I got so wrapped up in the game I have since been sacked as Line Up…by my own husband no less, hehe. I am so not cut out for that position.
The Hades boys put together a charity bout in November, just the week before BoB, which got people coming from all over the UK, and we were chuffed to bits that all these people made such an effort to come, from Manchester Roller Derby, Blackpool Roller Derby League and Belfast Men's Roller Derby, not to mention representation from leagues all over Scotland. It was an amazing day.
Then we get to BoB…well that was a year in the making and we’d again like to pass along our thanks to all that made it possible. We had representation from wider Europe and even the good ole USofA. The only drawback of the day was not skating in it!
As for the Voodoo Roller Dollies, well you’ll have to keep your eyes peeled for our upcoming news but needless to say we’re training hard in preparation for an incredible first year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coming back to the events in sequence, last time we spoke, we talked about your plans for coed exhibition team, Team Nitemare. This year, they managed to bout for the first time, taking on the Jakey Tayzers for a narrow 174:215 loss and then travelling to play Middlesborough Milk Rollers' Milk Invaders away to a resounding 278:168 win! How was the experience of building to those two bouts?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beauty of Team Nitemare is that we have built on it throughout the year and we have expanded our ranks. There were a few hiccups in the the run up to the Jakey Tayzer bout, but in true roller derby fashion, it pulled together and ran smoothly on the day. The Tayzers were a formidable force and showed how well a co-ed team can work together. All of the lead up to the Milk Invaders (Middlesborough Milk Rollers and Teeside Skate Invaders Mash up) was all down to the lovely Terri Sudron and we the team. It was intense in the run up though, especially the first one, it was almost like Christmas, so much tension for an hour or so of watching it all come together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Nitemare's debut was also Hades Roller Boys', the second bout pitting them against Ireland's Men Behaving Derby, for a narrow win. Hades later played Wirral's men's team away in December. This is a bit of a reversal for the two of you, with Raven getting to cheer on Titan[Cronos?] for the first time! Tell us a bit about the experience…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit here, I was a very bad wife and abandoned Titan to go and have fun at Team Scotland Try-outs… The debut is the only bout I’ve seen of Hades, as their next one was over in Montpellier against the Kamiquads.
Although I will be at their next game, most definitely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A little after Hades was founded, the Falkirk area also gained its third women's team in Voodoo Roller Dollies. With Fierce Valley and Bairn City already in the region, how are Voodoo planning on distinguishing themselves?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We set ourselves apart from the two other big teams in the area by being small. We are not looking at expanding to league proportions but our initial aim is to gain a roster of 20. I’ve been a part of a big and fast growing league and found that it wasn’t for me. I like feeling that I know all of my team mates and we speak every day. We aim to conduct the team with as little of the traditional structure as is expected. So if you’re looking to become a new blood at Voodoo, you can expect to have fun , just skate and be a valued member of VRD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capping off the year for Into The Nitemare was the 6-way Battle of Britain tournament, pitting teams from across the UK (with a few last minute substitutions from the original lineup) against each other. With three teams in the event, Scotland did creditably, with Dundee finishing a strong second after Newcastle's Whippin Hinnies' first place.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; How was the experience of running your first big event? Anything you'd do differently next time [will there be a next time]?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoB as it was fondly known was a great day. We were so proud to see Scotland do so well, with Dundee rampaging home in silver position, Lothian Representing extremely well on the day despite injury and some brand new skaters and the Belters getting their first win.
Newcastle, having stepped in at the last minute, were valiant in their win, Belfast showing some massive hits and the Reapers playing their first open bouts and getting that first public win under their belts too. The day was fantastic and without the help of Teams, Refs, NSOs, Photographers, Announcers and event staff it would not have been possible. As I said before the nature of derby is to throw a spanner in the works and there were more than a few in the final weeks of preparation with two teams pulling out, venue issues and then on the day a minor mishap with a team bus..but it all came together in the end.
Special mention has to go to Head Ref: Ella Bella Bang Bang (ARRG) and our Head NSO [Crashing] Wookiee [Broken Zebra] (GCRG) without whom, I would have been pretty much a wreck.
Will we do another tournament? Maybe, you’ll just have to wait and see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With all that happening in 2013, Into The Nitemare must have plans for 2014. Is there anything you can reveal now, or is it all secret?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not secret, but it hasn’t been announced yet. We have a busy year ahead in all aspects, Hades, Voodoo and Team Nitemare , so you’ll just have to watch on the facebooks and twitters to keep abreast of all our happenings!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>battle of britain roller derby tournament</category><category>derby review 2014</category><category>hades roller boys</category><category>into the nitemare</category><category>team nitemare</category><category>voodoo roller dollies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/12/derby-review-2014-nitemare-voodoo-and-hades-and-bob/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 19:34:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Wee Raven's 'New Nitemare'</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/09/10/wee-ravens-new-nitemare/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, 15 September at 1:30pm, &lt;a title="Team Nitemare Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamNitemare" target="_blank"&gt;Team Nitemare&lt;/a&gt; will be hosting a double-header bout in Grangemouth Sports Complex. The first bout of the day will see Team Nitemare take on &lt;a title="The Jakey Tayzers Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/jakeytayzers" target="_blank"&gt;The Jakey Tayzers&lt;/a&gt;, then &lt;a title="Hades Roller Boys Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Hades-Roller-Boys/1387245968162894" target="_blank"&gt;Hades Roller Boys &lt;/a&gt;will come up against &lt;a title="Men Behaving Derby Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Men-Behaving-Derby/260450844088944" target="_blank"&gt;Men Behaving Derby&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h6&gt;So who are the teams?&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Team Nitemare&lt;/strong&gt; are a group of hand-picked male and female skaters from across the UK, chosen by &lt;a title="Into the Nitemare Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/IntoTheNitemare?fref=ts" target="_blank"&gt;Into the Nitemare,&lt;/a&gt; to represent co-ed roller derby. The double-header this weekend will be their debut appearance!
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Jakey Tayzers&lt;/strong&gt; originated in 2012 when &lt;a title="The Jakey Bites Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/TheJakeyBites" target="_blank"&gt;The Jakey Bites&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="Dundee Roller Girls Website" href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls' &lt;/a&gt;Silvery Tayzers chose to join forces in Scotland's first ever co-ed bout against The Silvery Bites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hades Roller Boys&lt;/strong&gt; appeared on the circuit in July this year as a male-only travel team. Similar to Team Nitemare, the skaters in this team originate from all over the UK and have been selected by the team founders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Men Behaving Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; are another 'exhibition' team - but their skaters hail from Ireland. Since their inception in February this year, MBRD have been busy recruiting new skaters; this bout will be their first public outing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets for the double-header bout are available online from &lt;a title="Buy Tickets Online" href="http://newnitemare.eventbrite.co.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;EventBrite&lt;/a&gt;, priced at £7. Since the Grangemouth Sports Complex is a small venue, they will be sold on a first-come, first-served basis online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see Team Nitemare's &lt;a title="Wee Raven's New Nitemare Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/147236675460398/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt; for further details on this double-header bout, or if you have any questions for the organisers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/teamnitemare.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2915" alt="Image courtesy of Team Nitemare" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/09/teamnitemare.jpg" width="599" height="900"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Team Nitemare&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>grangemouth</category><category>hades roller boys</category><category>men behaving derby</category><category>team nitemare</category><category>the jakey tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/09/10/wee-ravens-new-nitemare/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 12:11:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Interview with... Raven from Into The Nitemare</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/06/17/an-interview-with-raven-from-into-the-nitemare/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In every community, there are some individuals who, through dint of energy, enthusiasm or engagement, quickly become linchpins of activity. In Scottish Roller Derby, arguably the newest such persons are Raven and her husband Titan, co-owners of the Into The Nitemare skate store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to running the store, Raven has also been very much involved with Bairn City Rollers (who she skates for), but has also made inroads into tournament planning and even a little team creation of her own. I caught up with her at the Into The Nitemare base to talk about her discovery of roller derby, the newly revealed Team Nitemare, and other facets of her involvement in Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/06/carousel-item-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2702" alt="carousel-item-1" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/06/carousel-item-1.jpg?w=614" width="614" height="629"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a Friday evening, and I've just found the home of Falkirk's local Skate Store in a quiet residential area, thanks to the Queens of the Sin Bin tshirt gracing a torso dummy in the window. For now, Into The Nitemare runs its business from home, all of the stock carefully located out of the way of the two kittens who prowl the living room in that slightly uncoordinated way that immature cats do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm interviewing Raven on a Friday because the very next day, she and Titan are off south to attend a bout in England along with their stall. The wide travel for the business has become an increasingly common part of their lives, and has both fed into and from their list of contacts in UK Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"&lt;em&gt;We founded a book shop around 3 years ago, mainly because I love books; and because I discovered I hated working for other people. Heard of [&lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;], went to a fresh meat taster, but couldn't commit. Stayed involved in derby, started doing a range of clothes. Discovered Queens of the Sin bin, through FB, and started doing their clothes... and then &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; asked us if we wanted to have a stall at one of their fundraisers... and the travel didn't stop.&lt;/em&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, the lure of actually skating was never far away. With the business doing well, Raven was also in contact with Wee Zoomer (who had also tried out derby at Fierce Valley) and her husband Megabloker, who had just started with the Jakey Bites.
"&lt;em&gt;[Megabloker] really wanted a full, male, league to develop all the skills that the girls do [not just a constructed team like the Jakeys]. He asked if we could provide some sponsorship to start them off&lt;/em&gt;." And one thing led to another, and Scotland's first co-ed league, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;, was formed. Things started moving rapidly after that, with Raven herself putting on skates again:
"&lt;em&gt;I started skating in May last year; 5 days after my derby anniversary, I bouted [in Cherry Pop]. It was AMAZING.&lt;/em&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This drive seems to be shared by the whole of Bairn City (although Into The Nitemare also handle Bairn City's bout arrangements), as they have left the traps after their first bout at something of a sprint. One or more of the leagues' three teams (men's Skelpies, women's Central Belters, co-ed Belter Skelpers) is bouting every month for the next year, excepting December, an ambitious schedule even for a very established league, which Raven admits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"&lt;em&gt;We have pushed it hard and fast. But it's been good. Really Good. We're a very close knit community; there's some politics, but you get that everywhere. But we're a like a giant family - we socialise CONSTANTLY. Not arranged functions or events, we have an extended social support network. Some things that have happened recently, I wouldn't have gotten through without them. It's going to be a hard year, but I'm very excited.&lt;/em&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As perhaps with many roller derby players, enthusiasm for the sport pervades most of Raven's responses to questions, whether asked about meeting &lt;a href="http://www.viennarollergirls.com/"&gt;Vienna Rollergirls&lt;/a&gt; (who were put up by Bairn City's You Sayin' Bolt for their visit to play Auld Reekie); "&lt;em&gt;lovely lovely girls&lt;/em&gt;", or her feelings about fellow Scottish derby store &lt;a href="http://www.5thblockerskates.co.uk/"&gt;5th Blocker Skates&lt;/a&gt;; "&lt;em&gt;[owner Marshall] Lawless is awesome; she's just generally awesome, proper derby crush, I love the way she jams. We'd not want to step on her toes.&lt;/em&gt;", or &lt;a href="http://www.granitecityrollergirls.org.uk"&gt;Granite City Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;; "&lt;em&gt;Clinically Wasted, she's brilliant: legs everywhere.&lt;/em&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This enthusiasm has also seen its way into sponsorship of a number of teams across the UK, and even into Europe (&lt;a href="http://trondheimrollerderby.com/"&gt;Trondheim Roller Derby Norway&lt;/a&gt; are proud sponsorees). Perhaps a little more controversially, it's also seen individually sponsored skaters invited to join a co-ed exhibition team, Team Nitemare."&lt;em&gt;[Team Nitemare] kind of came about by accident. We'd been toying with how cool a 'Team Nitemare' would be, but we toyed with it and dropped it and toyed with it. And then Bob [Battle of Britain] came about. We were approached by Rollin Thunder of SDR, one of whom's fellow skaters is sponsored. So we made a list and asked various skaters we like, and thankfully they all said yes. […] They're not all really well known names, but they're talent we think should be pushed to the fore.&lt;/em&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obvious slippery slope argument of "corporate ownership" immediately rears its head as soon as private individuals start constructing their own teams, but Raven is adamant that Team Nitemare is somewhere between a bit of fun and a promotional tool for co-ed derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"&lt;em&gt;It's mainly…&lt;/em&gt;" she says, tailing off for a moment with surprise that someone might think she'd be making a team for self-aggrandising reasons, "&lt;em&gt;…the whole point behind it is, well women's derby is big and still growing at a massive rate. Men's derby is catching up fairly rapidly. Co-ed is fairly new… and we just think that it needs an extra push. It's mainly going to be exhibition stuff, 2 or 3 games at year, just to show how girls and boys can work together.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We're not going to ask to be on the rankings. And our players all play for other established leagues - we'd never expect them to come play for us over them! That would defeat the whole thing! It's all meant to be a bit of fun.&lt;/em&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the interview, another sponsored Co-ed team, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamDaring1"&gt;Team Daring&lt;/a&gt;, has been announced. It will be interesting to see how this aspect of derby evolves in the coming year…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun comes up a lot for Raven in other contexts as well. It's clear that while she loves roller derby, and takes the sport seriously, she's also quite committed to the need for the sport to be entertaining. This becomes clear when we get on to discussing some of the hot topics of roller derby, and after dealing with the issue of new mins, where she shows a serious side:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"You can't stay still. Every thing you do; every time you watch a video, go to a bout, go to a social skate, go to training, it's all about learning. Everything's a learning curve, a learning process. So, yeah, it's going ot be hard for some people, but at the same time, it's that progression, it's going to push people. I think it's a good thing, I do think it's a good thing. I think it's going to take a lot of people… I mean, I read some of the bits of it and I thought what, oh no! But when it comes around again, I think it'll be okay."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and a commitment to safety&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"And I like the fact that Derby is the only sport in the world where you have to take a written test! I think that's amazing, there's no other sport in the world that does it. But that's one of the selling points for people. You get asked, 'oh, well is it just punching people?' and you can say, well, no you have to set a full set of minimum skills tests, and a full written test about the rules. You can't just 'go up and lamp someone'!"&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but then almost immediately switches tack segueing into the topic of derby names and 'proper sport':&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"&lt;em&gt;… the rules test, the new minimums, the new blog on should derby names be your real name, I mean 'people won't take you seriously if you don't skate under your real name'(!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some of the greatest sports people… and performers like Madonna; Lady Gaga, she doesn't go by her real name!&lt;/em&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The awareness of the overlap between competition and performance (which is a part of most team sports) is also clearly deep in Raven's psyche, as we talk about what's special about roller derby, compared to other sports. "&lt;em&gt;It attracts people who don't feel to be comfortable in "mainstream" situations. Slightly alternative, a bit different, a bit geeky. it attracts the less confident, because you get to put ...on a set of skates, and the derby uniforms - I've never been excited about wearing a skirt before in my life before that Saturday.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's totally out of character - I'm a baggy jeans, doc martens and a big baggy jumper kind of girl. So for me to wear short shorts and a dress, and face paint; not only is it out of character, it also gives me that confidence to say "let's go and do this!&lt;/em&gt;" So is it a costume, or armour? "&lt;em&gt;For me… costume, definitely.&lt;/em&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I get on to the other big event in Into The Nitemare's future: their UK tournament at the end of the year. We don't have quite as much time to discuss the details of selection as either of us would have liked, but as with Team Nitemare, Raven's Battle of Britain features teams that she, well, gets on with. "&lt;em&gt;Obviously we sponsor Rainy City, the Reapers... Shoetown, oh, how could I forget my Shoetown girls, are also sponsored... but we have the Central Belters because I skate with them, and we asked the Lothian Derby Dolls because we thought they'd be at the right level to play the Belters and Belfast to challenge Rainy City. We've had a huge amount of help from the Scottish Roller Derby [community] in arranging things.&lt;/em&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organisation is understandably still under development, but as always Raven seems committed to making the tournament entertaining. A tournament is a process for finding the best team, in theory, but if there are no upsets, the brackets can be predictable. "&lt;em&gt;It's going to be 3 teams per group,&lt;/em&gt;" she says, speaking about her current concern, "&lt;em&gt;But just putting them in the right way to stop the result being predictable. The obvious final would be Rainy v Belfast… but we don't &lt;strong&gt;want&lt;/strong&gt; that, we want something a bit different.&lt;/em&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether she gets her wish or not, Raven will certainly make sure that the event is run in the derby spirit of hard work and a sense of humour, and perhaps that's the most important thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Nitemare: &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/TeamNitemare"&gt;http://www.facebook.com/TeamNitemare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battle of Britain: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/307235179377214/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/307235179377214/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Into the Nitemare Derby Store: &lt;a href="http://into-the-nitemare-roller-derby-store.myshopify.com/"&gt;http://into-the-nitemare-roller-derby-store.myshopify.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>interviews</category><category>team nitemare</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/06/17/an-interview-with-raven-from-into-the-nitemare/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 19:39:37 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>