<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about team belgium)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/team-belgium.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 08:59:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Road to TBC: Lessons from ERDT and the last World Cup!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Blood &amp;amp; Thunder still have yet to formally announce the location and date for the 2017 Women's Roller Derby World Cup, by the end of November we will have already seen two of the "lead up" events for next year's tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is the the already complete &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://euroderbytournament.eu/"&gt;European Roller Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, held in Mons, Belgium. The second will be Team Wales Roller Derby's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1224163900948144/"&gt;"The Road To TBC"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, scheduled for the &lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;27th&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;November&lt;/strong&gt; 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the two tournaments, we will get a good look at most of Europe's competitors in the Third World Cup, albeit at an early stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attending the European Roller Derby Tournament were &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Denmark&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Switzerland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Portugal&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Italy&lt;/strong&gt; and new team &lt;strong&gt;Iceland&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Road To TBC will bring you &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Wales&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Belgium&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt; again, with the addition of &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Sweden&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;West Indies&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; all showing their national team debuts at the event!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what can we predict, if anything, about The Road to TBC from what has come &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we can look at ERDT. Whilst only 50% of the lineup overlaps between ERDT and TRtT, we can judge some expectations about absolute strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the now-traditional Bayesian inferred strength charts from ERDT, with the top four teams also singled out in separate highlights [as usual, these charts are relative to the winner - in this case, France - and so they are not directly represented]. We've marked vertical lines to show the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/"&gt;performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (also relative to France) in the Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Women's World Cup 2014, for those teams who attended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="8997,9001,8998,8999,9000" type="slideshow" link="file"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is pretty clear, whilst Spain is just about separate from the top three, although closely competitive with Wales and Belgium; the distributions for Belgium and Wales are almost indistinguishable. While France was indisputably the strongest team at ERDT, it's reasonable to suggest that the tournament also showed that Belgium and Wales are almost identical in strength. (Wales was the victim of one of the classic problems with single elimination tournaments, being relegated to the consolation brackets by an early encounter with the eventual Champions, and achieved Third as their highest possible relegation place.)
It's also possible to see that, assuming France is still relatively similar in strength, that Wales, Spain and Portugal have all noticeably improved in strength from 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/2/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over the page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we'll talk about the teams at The Road to TBC in more detail...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we can expect the hosts to be strong competitors in November... but what about their challengers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9075" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14448951_1432178393465450_4812609206374398804_n.jpg?w=600" alt="14448951_1432178393465450_4812609206374398804_n" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/20/roller-derby-international-rankings-2014/"&gt;back at the last World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Sweden&lt;/em&gt; was one of the strongest teams in the tournament, reflecting the strength of Scandinavian Roller Derby even back then. Since then, Swedish roller derby has gone from strength to strength, with both Stockholm Roller Derby and Crime City Rollers in WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs this year!
A quick count of their recently published training team for 2016/17 [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamswedenrollerderby/photos/a.517256094957689.143365.224501220899846/1432139023469387/?type=1&amp;amp;theater"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] suggests that at least &lt;em&gt;13&lt;/em&gt; of the skaters from 2014 are returning as possible rosters (as several skaters were recorded under their legal names for the 2014 roster, and under their skatenames here, it's a little tricky to be 100% certain).
We expect, on the balance of this, and the general health of Swedish derby, for Sweden to be a contender for the top spot at The Road to TBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3901" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamfrance.png?w=570" alt="TeamFrance" width="285" height="300"&gt; Team France logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team France&lt;/em&gt; were a top 8 team for us in 2014 (although they narrowly missed the actual final 8 at the tournament itself. We see at least 12 skaters from 2014 in the 2016 roster so far, which is about an average rate of returns in Europe. Almost 50% of the roster is drawn from Paris and Toulouse (with the rest mostly from the other strong French leagues), and both teams have experienced strong growth since 2014. Paris Rollergirls, in particular, have rocketed up the WFTDA rankings in the last two years, currently at #77 in the World.
We would consider France to be one of our three contenders for 2nd place, with chance at taking on Sweden for the top spot too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Belgium&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Wales&lt;/em&gt;, as we mentioned above, statistically drew at ERDT. At the 2014 World Cup, Belgium was the stronger team, by some distance, so this represents a particular improvement on Wales's part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9087" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/1957831_642788809139747_4859931912064326634_o.jpg?w=600" alt="1957831_642788809139747_4859931912064326634_o" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the composition of 2016 &lt;em&gt;Team Wales&lt;/em&gt; is quite different to that in 2014, with only a handful of skaters shared betwen the two rosters. What is still true, however, is the dominance of Tiger Bay Brawlers and Swansea City Roller Derby in the training team, making up 18 of the 30 spots. Both teams have have exceptional years, with Swansea City particularly excelling at British Champs (where they defeated all comers in promotion to Tier 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-3897" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teambelgium.jpg?w=582" alt="TeamBelgium" width="291" height="300"&gt; Team Belgium logo: Anouk Paepen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Belgium&lt;/em&gt;, meanwhile have at least 14 skaters returning from the strong 2014 roster in 2016. Belgian Roller Derby has always been pretty strong, on the basis of Gent Go-Go Rollergirls and One Love Roller Dolls amongst their many teams. However, we've not seen, perhaps, the explosive performance increase that, for example, Scandinavia has. We'd say that Team Belgium is, indeed, about as strong as it was in 2014.
We expect Wales to be keen on taking on Belgium on their home turf, and cautiously predict a win for the hosts on this basis. Overall rankings are hard to predict, but there are some particularly strong teams competing in The Road to TBC, and we wonder if the battle here will be for 4th place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3842" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamspain.jpg?w=600" alt="Team Spain logo -" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2014, &lt;em&gt;Spain&lt;/em&gt; have clearly come on in leaps and bounds.
The 2014 Team Spain consisted almost entirely of skaters from Barcelona and Tenerife, along with a few from outside Spain. The 2016 Training Team contains 13 skaters from 2014, but a huge number of new faces. We expect that Barcelona and Tenerife will still be strongly represented, however, and note that both leagues have significantly improved their rankings in the last 2 years (Tenerife has a steadily increasing ranking on Flat Track Stats, with no drops at all over that period!). We'd say that Spain have a good chance of placing well, assuming no surprises - although the general strength of teams at The Road to TBC is also higher than ERDT, so another 4th place is unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3773" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamwestindies.jpg?w=424" alt="Team West Indies Logo" width="212" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team West Indies&lt;/em&gt; was new to the Roller Derby scene in 2014, and also had the aim of trying to promote the sport back in the West Indies itself, with all of the skaters being from leagues outside of the islands (and many from the UK). Two years later, it seems that they're planning even greater things - but there's no official roster published for the team to date. We gather that Birmingham Blitz Dames and London Rockin' Rollers are still the core of the UK branch of the team, however, and both teams have had strong years - the Blitz Dames in particular benefitting from a change of coaching style which has improved their performance. While we rated West Indies as a little weaker than Spain and Wales in 2014, we wouldn't rule out surprising things from the team after 2 more years to build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4007" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/team-ireland.jpg?w=600" alt="team ireland" width="300" height="300"&gt; Team France logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Ireland Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt; did pretty well at the 2014 World Cup - in fact, on some metrics, we considered them competitive with France! The 2016 iteration is totally unknown, however - they're literally recruiting and selecting as we write this. On the basis of the performance of Dublin Roller Derby (who recently had a US trip and came back even stronger), we wouldn't rule the new Team Ireland out of a top 3 spot in this tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-9080" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/14390622_1111812092237414_410042907831655880_n.png?w=600" alt="14390622_1111812092237414_410042907831655880_n" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we come to our local team: &lt;em&gt;Team Scotland&lt;/em&gt;!
Scotland performed very creditably in the 2014 World Cup, placing around 10/11th place by our calculations. In 2014, the Scotland team was strongly dominated by Glasgow Roller Derby and Auld Reekie Roller Girls, with only a few skaters from Granite City, 1 from Dundee, and 1 each from Seaside Sirens and London Rollergirls.
This time around, due to both changes at Glasgow, and the strong growth in strength at Dundee and Granite City, we have a more rounded mix of representation in the training team (5 skaters from Dundee, and one from Fierce Valley!); as well as more skaters from outside Scotland itself, with 2 from Wirral, 2 from Newcastle and 1 each from Hallam, Leicester, London Rockin' Rollers!
We're not sure how the team roster for Team Scotland has been selected for The Road to TBC, but we've seen the team in practice, and they look pretty cohesive already. We'd tip Scotland for a chance at upsetting Ireland's dreams of a Top 3 spot, if anyone does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the only way to actually see if we're right is to make your way to Cardiff for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1224163900948144/"&gt;The Road to TBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; itself. Ticket sales are open for the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;27th November,&lt;/strong&gt; and sales are going fast, we believe!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>european roller derby tournament</category><category>international derby</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>statistics</category><category>team belgium</category><category>team france</category><category>team ireland</category><category>team scotland</category><category>team spain</category><category>team sweden</category><category>team wales</category><category>team west indies</category><category>the road to tbc</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/02/the-road-to-tbc-lessons-from-erdt-and-the-last-world-cup/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 10:36:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interviews: Northern Europe</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/06/world-cup-interviews-northern-europe/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week our &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; tour covered Northern and Central Europe, including many of the competitors at the &lt;a href="http://euroderbytournament.eu/"&gt;European Tournament&lt;/a&gt; last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you missed any of the interviews, the links are below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team France" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/02/world-cup-interview-team-france/"&gt;Team France&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Belgium" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/30/world-cup-interview-team-belgium/"&gt;Team Belgium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Switzerland" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/03/world-cup-interview-team-switzerland/"&gt;Team Switzerland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Netherlands" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/29/world-cup-interview-team-netherlands/"&gt;Team Netherlands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/01/world-cup-interview-team-germany/"&gt;Team Germany&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week we jump across the Atlantic to cover the teams of South America, where Derby has been taking off like wildfire since the first Cup in 2011!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>an interview with...</category><category>blood and thunder world cup 2014</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team belgium</category><category>team france</category><category>team germany</category><category>team netherlands</category><category>team switzerland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/06/world-cup-interviews-northern-europe/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 09:50:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Belgium</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/30/world-cup-interview-team-belgium/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second up on our trip through the countries of Northern Europe attending the &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/30/world-cup-interview-team-belgium/rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup&lt;/a&gt;, and it's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamBelgiumRollerDerby"&gt;Team Belgium&lt;/a&gt;'s turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with Team Netherlands yesterday, Belgium is new to the World Cup this time around, and are pretty evenly matched with the former. In fact, Belgium placed 3rd in the &lt;a href="http://euroderbytournament.eu"&gt;European Championships&lt;/a&gt;, just ahead of Netherlands, after an extremely close bout. (We suspect that if they match up in Dallas, the Netherlands will be interested in reversing the situation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C.C. Titmouse was good enough to answer our questions on Team Belgium (these questions were received just before the Championships started).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teambelgium.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3897" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teambelgium.jpg" alt="Team Belgium logo: Anouk Paepen" width="517" height="533"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Team Belgium logo: Anouk Paepen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most of Team Belgium is derived from the plentiful Belgian leagues (excepting Scotland's Lilo and Stitches?). How was the selection process organized (did you have more expatriate skaters try out and not make the team, for example)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where did it all start ? On January 1st of 2012, Lolli Chop created a facebook group for all Belgian skaters, from an interleague point of view. Belgian leagues were this way, we were able to stay informed on Belgian roller derby events, to adjust our league’s calendars to other derby-events. Since we’re a small country, we’ve always wanted to support each other, so a forum was needed. In June 2012, SckrPnch (the local Belgian roller derby skate shop) organised « Derby Revolution », Europe's very own annual 4 day Roller Derby Convention. This event brought the best, international coaches and skaters to Belgium and gave the opportunity learn &amp;amp;  to challenge teams to scrimmage. It didn’t take long until the suggestion was made to set-up an unofficial « Team Belgium » delegation and challenge The Netherlands to set-up an All-star delegation, to play a challenge bout at Derby Revolution 2012. Before the bout, we wanted to have an opportunity to have at least one practice together, so on June 17th of 2012, the Blackland Rockin’ K-Rollers (Charleroi) hosted the very first national practice. The start signal was given and on June 28th, we (re-enforced by Kamikaze Kitten, who was eager to join us) played the Dutch All-star team, « The Bloody Oranges » at Derby Revolution and we took home the victory. At this point, we were all just seeing how and where things were going, but the idea of a national team started to get shape. We formed a little group with two representatives/league and started meeting on a regular basis. We started hosting regular national practices, open for all skaters who were linked to a Belgian league and learned from and with each other. Every league was encouraged to host at least one practice a year, which made 10 practices, since we were 10 leagues at the time. The main point on our meetings was how would we go forth in creating a national team/organization. The 2011 Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup, held in Toronto (Canada) from December 1st – 4rd, was the first international competition for national team. Different countries put together teams, but since the timing was rather short, not every set-up went as smoothly. This was exactly why we wanted to take advantage from our country being small and thus making it possible for us to meet and train together on a regular basis. We wanted to do it right from the start, creating a base that would last us a long way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took us from that first training in June 2012 until November 26th, when we announced our Belgian coaching team to the world !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there on out, things went very fast. We hosted a national practice every month and every month all Belgian reps (two reps/league) came together to discuss our next steps. The coaches started taking notes and putting together a selection of 35 skaters. June 2014, they selected a core of 20 skaters that will represent Belgium in the 2014 World Cup and we’re working up to the European Roller Derby Tournament in Mons, Belgium the upcoming weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With the majority of your skaters in Belgium, I guess this makes organizing practices easier than it might be? How have they been scheduled (avoiding conflicts with team practices etc)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Belgium, we’ve always had trouble finding venues, but if you gather forces with all the leagues, things go easier. It does take a lot of coordination, even if you’re relatively close together. We try to let every league host one practice, that way we split venue costs and we encourage Team Belgium’s practices and events to be run alongsides fixed training dates. Most of the Belgian leagues train on Sunday f.e., so we try to organize all Team Belgium-related events on Saturday. If it does conflict with other league’s practices, it’s up to the skaters to decide of course, but we asked on before hand to commit and Team Belgium promises to take every league into account as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Belgium is off to the European Derby Tournament in September. What are you aiming to get out of the tournament? (You've also had a few other pre-Dallas bouts, so how useful have you found them in general?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re really looking forward to the tournament! It’s the ideal occasion to meet other teams, on and off track! We want to play the best game we have in us and play together as a team. We want to win of course, but we’re merely in it for the experience and experiencing gameplay of other teams. We want to learn from it and use that knowledge to improve our own game for Dallas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve played Germany &amp;amp; The Netherlands a couple of months ago, and it has been a good experience. A good way to get to know the teams, but the ideal way to learn how individual skaters work together. Although we’re a small country, the team consists of players from out different leagues and it remains a challenge to play together as a team and not just a bunch of awesome individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What have you been doing to raise funds, awareness + sponsorship for the big expenses of getting to the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve been communicating quite some info on our skaters, coaches, practices, mostly on our website, facebook, Instagram &amp;amp; twitter account. We’ve organised 2 public games against other national teams, we’ve provided merch (that will be available at the European Tournament!) and we’re currently working on a Fundraising-plan to get more money for our skaters. So keep your eyes (and wallets! :p) open! ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are Team Belgium's aims for Dallas?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We haven’t set team goals just yet. Gameplay-wise we’re waiting for the European Tournament, since that’s the ideal occasion to set realistic goals for Dallas. Team spirit wise, we’ve been bounding since day 1. Belgium is small and has a lot of political issues, which has no place in derby. Whether we’re from the Dutch, French or German side of Belgium, we’re all Belgian and we’re proud to be! Our main goal is to be a front, to stick together off track,  so it translated on track as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus questions: Does the English language focus of derby make it harder for Belgian derby, or are English language skill (and the recent publication of the WFTDA rules in French) in Belgium sufficient to ease matters?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Belgium, we officially speak 3 languages; Dutch, French &amp;amp; German. But in reality, we’re mainly bi-lingual, speaking both Dutch &amp;amp; French. Most of us speak fluent English as well, so that can’t hold us back ;-).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some national teams are apparently switching to legal names for the World Cup (eg much of Team Scotland has, with some retaining their derby names). Is Team Belgium taking a position either way on this (or is it unimportant)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn’t take a general position within this matter, since a name is still personal. We have a couple of skaters who decided to play with their legal names, and that’s totally fine. Within Team Belgium, it’s an individual choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Team Belgium Roster is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aline Decat #6
Bhurt #88 (Namur Roller Girls)
Bicky Monkey #18
Bundy Nelson #1610 (Brussels Derby Pixies)
C.C. Titmouse #85 (One Love Roller Dolls)
Charlie McHell #829
Cherry Moshpit #07 (One Love Roller Dolls)
Daisy Destroy #8 (Blackland Rockin’ K-Rollers)
Eve’il X #13 (One Love Roller Dolls)
Evil Spin-Her #26 (Gent GO-GO Roller Girls)
FallWafal #90 (Gent GO-GO Roller Girls)
Guts’n Glory #68 (Gent GO-GO Roller Girls)
Hipshot #89 (One Love Roller Dolls)
Humpme Bogart #00 (One Love Roller Dolls)
Lilo &amp;amp; Stitches #626 (Auld Reekie Roller Girls)
Majin Buu #10 (One Love Roller Dolls)
Miss Miyagi #86 (Gent GO-GO Roller Girls)
Olga Volt #44 (Gent GO-GO Roller Girls)
Sandra ButtBlock #36 (Gent GO-GO Roller Girls)
Todestrieb #6 (Brussels Derby Pixies)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coach: Mister Grey
Lineup: Kadha&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>an interview with...</category><category>blood and thunder world cup 2014</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team belgium</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/30/world-cup-interview-team-belgium/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 09:00:32 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>