<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about team south africa)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/team-south-africa.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 09:36:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>South Africa's National Derby Fest 2018: three years of Festivals!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/31/south-africas-national-derby-fest-2018-three-years-of-festivals/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the final article in our series covering National and International tournaments which deserve more attention, we're coming to a continent which receives little attention from the Roller Derby community: Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The South African Roller Derby community has always been, by necessity, a tightly-connected group; the closest Roller Derby to them is at the other end of the continent to them (in Egypt), so the South African leagues have a feel more like those of the early North American and European leagues. That is to say, they're very much "leagues", and home-team games within each city's league are more common than travel team games between the leagues themselves.
(This is not to say that South Africa isn't engaged in the global community: they of course attended the 2014 and 2018 World Cups, and engage in much of the rest of the community itself.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, there's still a lot of appetite for a big National Tournament to raise the profile of the sport, so Golden City Rollers (previously C-Max Roller Derby) of Johannesburg started the "National Derby Fest" back in 2016. Back then, almost all the teams present were actually part of the C-Max league, with only Pretoria's P-Town making it to the contest from outside (with some skaters from Cape Town joining their team for the event).
As a result, the 2016 winners were a C-Max home team: the Thundering Hellcats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27680" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/zanational_sa.png?w=1024" alt="ZANational_SA" width="1024" height="813"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, with Golden City hosting again, the event was run as a triple header round robin between Johannesburg, Durban and Cape Town, with the hosts' travel team emerging victorious with a commanding lead over second place Cape Town, with a final score of 219:73!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, in the third year of the event, the tournament is hosted by the other large league in South Africa, Cape Town Roller Derby. The format has changed, providing a pair of Open To All mixed "scrimmage" bouts, featuring skaters from all three leagues which attended last year, followed by the Championship event face-off between Cape Town and Golden City!
As far as we know, the provision of OTA games is an innovation for this event; these bouts will provide track time for all the bout-ready skaters across South Africa, which is an important focus for the tournament as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of their community engagement, the one day event will have each bout separated by open skating for the audience (for which kit hire is available).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With interleague bouts between the leagues fairly rare, it's hard to be definitive about the expected result of the Championship event: however, given Golden City's history, we're expecting a continuation of their reign, albeit a closer one than in the past.
However, the real benefit will continue to be the South African Roller Derby community itself, regardless of who picks up the trophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Third National Derby Fest will be held on &lt;strong&gt;Nov 17&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Sunningdale Sports Complex&lt;/strong&gt;, Cape Town. The event is located at Facebook here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/179294086331874/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/179294086331874/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with all National Tournaments, you can see the history of winners at our page here: &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/NationalTournaments.htmlhttp://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/NationalTournaments.html"&gt;http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/NationalTournaments.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>golden city roller derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>south africa</category><category>team south africa</category><category>tournaments2018</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/31/south-africas-national-derby-fest-2018-three-years-of-festivals/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 11:19:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup 2014: Africa and Asia-Pacific Round-up</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/22/world-cup-2014-africa-and-asia-pacific-round-up/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're one week into our series of National Teams interviews, covering all of the teams entering the &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder 2014 Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, we covered the "Africa and Asia-Pacific" set of nations. If you missed the Interviews, you can read them here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Japan [ローラーデービーのワールドカップ：日本のチーム]" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/15/world-cup-interview-team-japan-%e3%83%ad%e3%83%bc%e3%83%a9%e3%83%bc%e3%83%87%e3%83%bc%e3%83%93%e3%83%bc%e3%81%ae%e3%83%af%e3%83%bc%e3%83%ab%e3%83%89%e3%82%ab%e3%83%83%e3%83%97%ef%bc%9a%e6%97%a5/"&gt;Team Japan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team South Africa" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/16/world-cup-interview-team-south-africa/"&gt;Team South Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team West Indies" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/17/world-cup-interview-team-west-indies/"&gt;Team West Indies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Australia" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/18/world-cup-interview-team-australia/"&gt;Team Australia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/19/world-cup-interview-team-new-zealand/"&gt;Team New Zealand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, we start our coverage of the European Teams, beginning tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team australia</category><category>team japan</category><category>team new zealand</category><category>team south africa</category><category>team west indies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/22/world-cup-2014-africa-and-asia-pacific-round-up/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 09:51:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team South Africa</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/16/world-cup-interview-team-south-africa/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Next on our series of &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;World Cup&lt;/a&gt; interviews is another team new to the World Cup this time around.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamSouthAfricaRollerDerby"&gt;Team South Africa&lt;/a&gt; is the only African team participating in the World Cup this time around (next time, we could hope for an Egyptian entry...), and could be one of the big disruptions in the tournament.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;We interviewed Szerdi Nagy (who skates as Julia Sieze-Her) on behalf of the team.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamza.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3758 aligncenter" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/teamza.jpg" alt="Team ZA logo" width="660" height="660"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Team ZA logo: Ilana van Lingen&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, firstly, Team selection.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It looks to me like all of the SA team are selected from SA-local teams. Did you choose the selection and eligibility criteria to encourage this, or was this just a natural consequence of the process and who submitted applications?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;When we initially put out the application it was open to any South African skaters the world over and we had applicants from the Texas Roller Girls, the Royal Windsor Roller Girls and the London Roller Girls as well as from the South African leagues of C-Max, Durban Derby and the Cape Town Roller Girls. For the first round of trials we accepted video submissions, but for the final round of trials we required skaters to attend a bootcamp in South Africa which logistically was a bit tricky for some of our foreign skaters. Despite this, we have skaters from both the Texas Roller Girls and the Royal Windsor Roller Girls who made it into our squad of 18.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you give me a brief background for how long derby's been going in SA, and what the scene is like? (Last World Cup, Australia and NZ were the big unknowns, with an active derby scene that just hadn't been visible outside of Oceania; I get the feeling SA is a bit like that?) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;That is exactly how it is! Derby came to South Africa in 2010, the first league was based in Johannesburg (C-max) and was started by Melinda Lotz and Candice van Niekerk, the following year a league was started in Cape town and in 2012 a league in Durban. (Since then we have leagues in various stage of development in Pretoria, Bloemfontein, Grahamstown and Nelspruit). Within the last two years there has been a significant jump in the level of derby being played in South Africa and this year saw our first inter-league skating. So while derby is pretty active within South Africa, internationally we are virtually unknown and one of only 2 leagues in Africa (the caiRollers in Egypt being the other league). Getting an opportunity to skate internationally at the end of the year we think is going to be eye opening not only for ourselves and our skaters, but for the rest of the world as well!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I see you've already got equipment and training sponsorship from some big names. How else are you raising money and awareness for the big travel and training expenses of getting to the World Cup in Dallas?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I think like in many parts of the world, derby is still a relatively unknown sport so attracting sponsors can be a bit tricky on the home front.  We have had an incredible amount of support from the international derby community who are keen to get us over to Texas! We have a gofundme campaign which is bringing in a bit of money (&lt;a href="http://www.gofundme.com/8etb18" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.gofundme.com/8etb18&lt;/a&gt;) and our skaters and leagues are really being super proactive in trying to raise money to send our our girls over. We have skaters doing ultra trail runs to raise money, bout fundraisers, band festival fundraisers and the list goes on. Unfortunately though with our currency being so weak to the US Dollar, it is likely our girls will have to partially fund their trips. We are lucky enough to have received some publicity from various online magazines and even an article in one of our national airlines in flight magazines. One of our main goals in going to the World Cup is to raise derby awareness in South Africa generally.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a relative unknown (from the perspective of the European/American focus of a lot of derby reporting), what are your aims coming into the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;South African roller derby is still in its early learning phases, our goal at the world cup is to learn as much as we can to bring back to our home leagues to improve South African derby as a whole and to improve the awareness of our sport. We are hoping that competing in international derby of this level will help legitimise our sport in the future and enable us to seek sponsorship to help some of our teams to be able to travel and skate internationally in the future.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Since this interview, Team South Africa have received sponsorship from &lt;a href="http://www.nistevousa.com/"&gt;Nistevo USA&lt;/a&gt; , and have a huge range of &lt;a href="http://www.teamzarollerderby.com/"&gt;merchandise&lt;/a&gt; available from their website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Team ZA roster is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MICHELLE DOSSON, Booty Queen 000
PHILIPPA VAN WELIE, Pippa 575
ROZANNE DU PREEZ, Betty Bone Crusher ak47
TERI ROBERTS, Gazelle 8
AIMEE PLANK, The Iron Tyrant 917
SAMANTHA SCHOLTZ, Slam-U-Well Jackson 25
JEANETTE VENSKE, Sugarfists 89
EMILIA DOMAGALA, Bug Off 001
CLAIRE HAYWARD, Miss C Malice 22
CANDICE VAN NIEKERK, Ling Vom Bot 33
SZERDI NAGY, Julia Seize-Her 11
LAURIE BAUER, Sookie Smackhouse 7
KELLY WOOLDRIDGE, Electri-Kell 900w
LAUREN BARKUME, Pit Bullet 50mm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reserves:
ZANI FOURIE, Red Mist 1981
JOLIZE JACOBS, G.I. JoJo 03
CHRISTL BOUWER, Ming Die-Nasty 888
ASHLEIGH PIENAAR, Ashtrix 225&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coach:
NICHOLAS CHALMERS, Coach Nic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team south africa</category><category>team za</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/16/world-cup-interview-team-south-africa/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 09:16:21 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>