<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about team puerto rico)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/team-puerto-rico.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Puerto Rico Men's Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/10/mrdwc-2016-team-review-puerto-rico-mens-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Completing our first week of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; team profiles, we have one of the teams new to the Cup: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamPuertoRicoMensRD/"&gt;Puerto Rico Men's Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7699" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/12794452_1968058606751881_850918363325886616_n.png" alt="12794452_1968058606751881_850918363325886616_n" width="526" height="690"&gt; The Team Puerto Rico logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teampuertoricorollerderby/"&gt;Women's Team Puerto Rico&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; attended the &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/33509"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup&lt;/a&gt; in 2014, there was not quite enough interest in Men's Derby for a similar team to form for MRDWC2014. This time around, Team Puerto Rico Men's Roller Derby has been pulled together from Puerto Rican nationals from around the world, as is increasingly the case for "new" National Teams from the smaller nations. There are some great teams providing skaters for Puerto Rico, but as always team cohesion will be the most important factor for a geographically distributed team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Puerto Rico is in &lt;strong&gt;Group Blue&lt;/strong&gt;, with returning teams Belgium, France, Netherlands and Australia. Belgium and Netherlands finished in the lower half of the table last time around; France and Australia did well enough to get through to the placement knockout, placing 4th and 5th in the tournament. With just two teams from each group going through to the knockout with a chance at 1st place, Team Puerto Rico is likely to miss out on the chance at higher rankings - but there's a lot of newer teams in this tournament, and they could place well in the lower half of the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James "Disaster Chief" Wargacki was kind enough to answer some questions for us on the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Puerto Rico are new to the Men's World Cup. What are your aims in the tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;
Our primary goal is proudly represent the island and culture of our families, which have had a particularly unique experience in contributing to the patchwork of the United States. In doing so, we hope that this will spark increased interest in the sport to encourage more Puerto Rican, as well as other Latino, men to put on skates and participate as competitors on the island, in the United States and throughout the Caribbean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: &lt;strong&gt;Your Group is full of strong teams, including Australia's Wizards of Aus and Team France (who were 5th and 4th place in 2014). Which teams are you most looking forward to playing (or seeing play)?&lt;/strong&gt;
A: We are looking forward to facing all of the teams in our group. We wish to neither overlook any team, nor subordinate ourselves to others' past performances. We respect the effort that each team has exerted to make it out to the tournament, and hope to bring our best to each game, as we expect from those lace up against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's the level of interest in roller derby in Puerto Rico?&lt;/strong&gt;
Currently, the ladies have several leagues on the island (i.e. Enchanted Island, Rumtown, Wicked Island), along with a team that represented in Dallas, TX at the 2014 World Cup. No men's teams have been formed, as of yet, but we hope that will change in the very near. Male participation in roller derby in Puerto Rico is, at this time, are gentleman serving as referees, along with the handful of skaters attending the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I guess that, like Women's Puerto Rico, you've recruited from Puerto Ricans across the world?&lt;/strong&gt;
We have. A couple of skaters and one of our bench coaches are living in Puerto Rico right now. We also have skaters from New York, New Jersey, Florida, and Arizona. Most of us here in the US still have friends and family living in Puerto Rico as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This year, MRDWC are promoting the lead up to the Cup with the "Road to Calgary" tag. In the spirit of this, what bouts and training have you been doing since the last selection?&lt;/strong&gt;
Due to our geographic limitations, those who get to practice regularly together are in the same league, such as the New York Shock Exchange. When the opportunity presents itself, some individual members have been able to travel and skate in practices and scrimmages with other teammates. This has proven valuable to give skaters the opportunity to become familiar with each other, prior to converging on Calgary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After the last World Cup, several nations saw increased awareness and interest in Roller Derby. What are your hopes for Roller Derby in Puerto Rico?&lt;/strong&gt;
We’re hoping to not only increase awareness about the sport but to also inspire others to give roller derby a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Puerto Rico's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/27/mens-roller-derby-world-cupschedule-timezone-adjusted/"&gt;first bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is against France, the likely Group winners, at 10am Calgary-local-time on Thursday on Track 2, followed by Belgium at 1pm on Track 1. [The official MRDWC schedule is located here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/"&gt;http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Team Puerto Rico roster is:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Samy Franco&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;CoAcH BoOm&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Bustelo, Angel (BUS-TELL-O)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Rivera, Hector&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;11&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;PapiChuleta (PAH-PEE CHU-LEY-TAH)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;18&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Madera (MA-DAY-RAH)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;24&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Flecha (fe-LAY-CHA)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;68&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Rosario, John&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;93&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Tio Danny (TEE-OH DAN-E)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;117&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Disaster Chief&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;275&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Martinez, Angel Andres (MAR-TEEN-EZ&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;414&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Ti-MAN (Tee-MAN)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;5280&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;David Miles Rios (Ree-Ohss)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Bench&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Officer Pain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Bench&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Pirate Booty&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Bench&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p class="layoutArea"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="column"&gt;Revelyn Sin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>roller derby world cup calgary 2016</category><category>team puerto rico</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/10/mrdwc-2016-team-review-puerto-rico-mens-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 11:02:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interviews: The Americas</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/03/world-cup-interviews-the-americas/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scottish Roller Derby has been profiling the teams who will bring lightning reflexes and torrents of talent to the Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup in Dallas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week saw the last of our interviews posted online - featuring four teams from the Americas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you missed them, here there are in one handy round-up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/28/world-cup-interview-team-usa/"&gt;Interview with Team USA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/29/world-cup-interview-team-puerto-rico/"&gt;Interview with Puerto Rico&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/30/world-cup-interview-team-canada/"&gt;Interview with Team Canada&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/31/world-cup-interview-team-mexico/"&gt;Interview with Team Mexico&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team canada</category><category>team mexico</category><category>team puerto rico</category><category>team usa</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/03/world-cup-interviews-the-americas/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 09:00:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Puerto Rico</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/29/world-cup-interview-team-puerto-rico/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Puerto Rico's flag – consisting of five stripes and one star – is almost tailor made for derby - as are the sensational skating senoritas who hail from this beautiful island paradise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first time at the World Cup for Team PR and the Latin American derby divas are aiming to make their debut in style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have been working hard in preparation for the World Cup – meeting every week to skate for three hours … and that’s on top of at least three weekly practices with their own leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the team aren’t tired – far from it - Dallas is going to be a fiesta, not siesta for &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teampuertoricorollerderby"&gt;Team Puerto Rico&lt;/a&gt;, with everyone determined to showcase how much derby means to their homeland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These awesome skaters are blazing a trail in Puerto Rico – raising awareness of derby, sourcing practice venues and even overcoming a vicious virus which causes more pain than a can-opener at full speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scottish Roller Derby caught up with skater Sindia Pérez Pérez – aka Miss Tumbacocos – and also Kristen Fink (Mala Suerte) to get the low-down on the Latin American aces.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/puerto-rico.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-4142" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/puerto-rico.png?w=300" alt="puerto rico" width="498" height="498"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Logo designed by Samuel Mojica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are preparations going for the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Kristen&lt;/em&gt;: Lately anxiety and pressure have been rising as we continue counting down to the big day. We’ve been giving our 100+% at our weekly practice! Administrative work such as merchandise, travel, filling out surveys, sending documentation to the organisers, getting uniforms done and a gazillion other things are taking up most of our non-practice time. So, roller derby 24/7 would sum it up. Oh, and making sure these interviews get completed and sent out, so people get to know Team Puerto Rico - let alone that it exists!
&lt;p&gt;Just recently we added an additional hour to our weekly Sunday practice and an extra two-hour practice on Thursdays. This is additional to each player’s individual team/league practices which meet between two-three times a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sindia&lt;/em&gt;: As TPR we practice once a week for three hours. Each skater has at least three practices with their league/team that lasts two hours. We skate in an extremely hot and humid environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In terms of the team - from which leagues have your players been drawn? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sindia&lt;/em&gt;: We are proud to say that we come from all the existing teams in Puerto Rico - Enchanted Island Roller Derby, Killer Dolls Roller Derby, Rumtown RollerPunks Roller Derby and Wicked Island Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the team's goal at the World Cup? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sindia&lt;/em&gt;: To represent our small island with dignity. We have many challenges, from having an almost non-existent skating culture, to lack of practice venues and, recently, a painful virus new to our Island called Chicunkunya - transmitted by mosquitoes (living in the tropics). That has affected many of our skaters and our different teams’ rosters (don’t worry, it doesn’t spread by touching or in the air). It has been a challenge because it causes extreme joint pain in the extremities. But when they have less pain, they come back and keep skating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kristen&lt;/em&gt;: We want to leave a lasting impression, let the world know we have been practising and studying derby very hard for the last four years. We also want to gather and build the largest derby contact list ever! This to us has been a constant learning process. I would say getting a selection together to participate in the World Cup is already achieving a goal, now we are just looking forward to absorbing and getting the experience of what it is to compete against top, elite teams and skaters from all around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fundraising and sponsorship - how are they going? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kristen:&lt;/em&gt; This to us has been a huge challenge. Trying to get the word out, working very hard on raising the funds to travel and cover as many derby-related expenses as possible has been an ongoing process, but not as successful as we would like. In Puerto Rico we are still lacking the resources roller derby needs to get the sport recognised by the general public. Therefore we have not received much support or help from outside or local companies for sponsorship. Our biggest sponsors to date have been our own skaters’ local businesses like Rolers Skateshop, The Parlour and a couple more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sindia&lt;/em&gt;: We have a fundraising schedule with different activities like bingos, discounts at restaurants, merchandise and a Go Fund Me page - &lt;a href="http://www.gofundme.com/7lqn6c"&gt;http://www.gofundme.com/7lqn6c&lt;/a&gt;. Visit &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teampuertoricorollerderby"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/teampuertoricorollerderby&lt;/a&gt; for merch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's the mood of the team - excited, proud, and determined? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sindia&lt;/em&gt;: All of the above!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kristen&lt;/em&gt;: We are a bit shocked we were chosen to do this, positive that we will do our best and determined to make this a derby lesson for eternity. And most of all very blessed to be able to represent our country! We are way excited and trying to balance each other’s feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* What will Puerto Rico be aiming to do at the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sindia&lt;/em&gt;: We are aiming to win! Gain knowledge and skills, win peers and hopefully win some games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kristen&lt;/em&gt;: Mainly gain experience, up the game, diversify the game and win or lose, we are not going home empty handed. We are also looking forward to expanding our competitiveness as we aim to organise more Latin American tournaments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Without giving away any secrets, who or what should people in Scotland keep their eyes out for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sindia&lt;/em&gt;: On the record - you should know that we play with a LOT of heart. We are very passionate nation. Off the record - you should definitely keep your eyes out for our dancing skills at the after party.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kristen&lt;/em&gt;: Our amazing Puerto Rican booty and feisty attitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;* Thanks to Maria for additional material and being awesome.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/pr.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-4146" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/pr.jpg?w=300" alt="pr" width="462" height="292"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by Jennifer Pabón&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Puerto Rico roster:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Miss Tumba Cocos (Sindia Perez Perez)
&lt;p&gt;Mala Suerte (Fink)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meli Pop Pins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dona Pela&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screaming Meme&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swayne&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chill, Cris!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caraballo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hernandez&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marquez&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goomba Toomba&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cleo Catimba&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tijeras&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jo Animal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mad-Lin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pertierra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capeles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manic Mayhem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loki Rhino&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miranda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coaches:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carmona&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AKA Staycee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team puerto rico</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/29/world-cup-interview-team-puerto-rico/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 09:00:27 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>