<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about the jakey bites)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/the-jakey-bites.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:17 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Derby Review 2014: Capital City Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/20/derby-review-2014-capital-city-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;When writing an &lt;a title="Roller Derby: It’s Not Just for Girls!" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/02/02/roller-derby-its-not-just-for-girls/"&gt;overview of the Scottish Men's Leagues&lt;/a&gt; last year, we spoke to Tequila Jammer from Edinburgh's Capital City Roller Derby to hear all about the league's formation and their plans for their first year. A lot has happened at CCRD since then; Sassenick has done us the honour of sharing their adventures with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. When we spoke in February 2013, you were planning your first Fresh Meat &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;taster for April, and then another took place in September. How have you found the  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;recruitment process? Can you introduce us to the new skaters at Capital City who  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;joined in 2013? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Recruitment has been a bit hit and miss. Each time we've advertised a new Fresh Meat session, we've initially received plenty of interest, but getting people to actually turn up, and more importantly, come back for a second and a third time, has been tough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;The April Fresh Meat was a bit of a false start due to low numbers, but the September program has been very successful, with a number of the newer skaters now very close to passing their Minimum Skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I think our biggest success story is HaJuken, who’s gone from absolute beginner back in February to skating in public bouts and, most impressively, helping his team into joint 3rd place in the Jakey Sur5al in December.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/hadjuken-sur5al.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3300" alt="HadJuken jamming at Sur5al 2013" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/hadjuken-sur5al.jpg" width="614" height="921"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; HadJuken jamming at Sur5al 2013 - Photo courtesy of Ian McCreadie
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. How are you finding the balance between training skaters at a beginner level, and also those at a more advanced level? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;It is very difficult to find the right balance of training for newer skaters, intermediates and advanced skaters, especially when we currently only have one training session a week. At the outset of 2013 this wasn't so much of an issue, but as the year progressed, and more inexperienced skaters joined the league, we found ourselves with a wide range of skating skills and levels to cater for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We knew that this is an issue that all new leagues face sooner or later, so we assessed all of our skaters and created a training plan that would cater for everyone’s needs. We now split our training session into two halves: the first half covering skating skills that are needed for Mins, which our intermediate and advance skaters join in to help our newer skater’s progress. The second is focused on the skills we all need for playing derby. It has worked out really well and all the boys here at CCRD really put everything into each session, so much so that you can visibly see them advancing every week.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Your range of merchandise is very impressive! Capital City stalls are regularly spotted at Auld Reekie Roller Girls bouts, and at many local men's bouts. How important is it for you to attend these events and chat to the spectators? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Everyone loves a unicorn! We try to get a presence at as many bouts in and around Edinburgh as we can. It helps us to not only to promote ourselves, but also men’s derby in general. There are plenty of guys who attend women’s bouts who know very little or nothing at all about the men’s game and leagues. We aim to inform them and hopefully recruit them. A few of our current skaters were recruited at bouts in this way and at the time didn't even know there were any men’s teams in Scotland. That said, it’s important to find a balance when we’re setting up shop at other teams bouts, because until we’re actually giving something back in the form of, you know, actually playing Roller Derby in public, we run the risk of looking more like a clothing brand than a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;As an aside, because I’ll never stop getting excited by this fact, every so often people submit picture to &lt;a title="CCRD on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/CapitalCityRollerDerby?fref=ts" target="_blank"&gt;our Facebook Page&lt;/a&gt; of themselves wearing our merch. Last September an ARRG skater (shout out to Terrifying Tink!) posted a pic, taken on a visit to &lt;a title="Five Stride Skate Shop Website" href="http://www.fivestrideskateshop.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Five Stride Skate Shop&lt;/a&gt; in New York, of her wearing Capital City t-shirt while standing next to Bonnie Thunders &amp;amp; OMGWTF of Gotham Girls Roller Derby! How cool is that!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/ccrd-merch.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3302" alt="CCRD merchandise at Meadowbank Stadium" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/ccrd-merch.jpg" width="614" height="460"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; CCRD merchandise at Meadowbank Stadium. Photo courtesy of CCRD.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. All of the Scottish Men's Teams have certainly put their stamp on the roller &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;derby scene and are no longer seen as the 'newbies' trying to catch up with the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;women's teams. Starting a roller derby league is a big enough challenge - never &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mind introducing another culture at the same time! Can you tell us about the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;challenges you faced along the way, and how you overcame them to rise to the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;position you are in now? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We were lucky here at CCRD that we were started by a group of &lt;a title="The Jakey Bites on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/TheJakeyBites" target="_blank"&gt;Jakey Bites&lt;/a&gt; skaters. They saw a gap for an Edinburgh-based team when other regional men’s teams were starting to appear, and so CCRD was born. This gave us a solid foundation and a wealth of experience to draw on, not only from their experiences with the Jakeys, but also with Women's leagues as well as some of them were previously (some of them still are) referees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Even with this we have ran into our fair share of challenges. Recruitment is always the big one, as are hall costs. Unfortunately these go hand in hand, as without skating members we can't pay for hall time. Hall costs are always a big hurdle for new leagues and we’re no exception. It seems everywhere we look is expensive! This has led us to make sure to maximise our time we have on track each week, which in turn has helped to focus all our skaters at training. We are planning more Fresh Meat intakes throughout 2014 to hopefully add to our ranks, whilst still looking at alternative training venues to help us reduce hall costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;On a more positive note, I think the biggest obstacle that 2013 raised for was the need to actually become a team, rather than just a group of guys that skated together. Strangely enough, I think that happened pretty soon after we decided on our logo. It’s surprising how readily grown men will rally around a unicorn without a hint of irony, but it’s definitely become ingrained in our culture now.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. It was very exciting to see the establishment of the Men's National Team - The &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Power of Scotland - last year. Are many Capital City skaters on The Power of &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scotland roster? What opportunities do you think a Men's National Team will bring &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;to the sport? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We were all very excited about the establishment of &lt;a title="Power of Scotland on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland" target="_blank"&gt;Power of Scotland &lt;/a&gt;as a bouting team. There’s 4 skaters representing CCRD skating with Power of Scotland, two of which were voted in as the captain and vice-captain for POS. There is Dafty, Tequila Jammer, Judderjam and WKDeid (aka V for Vieneta); names I am sure followers of Men's Roller Derby will recognise from the Jakey Bites bouts. Also Ginge, their line-up, has also been on the side-lines of CCRD since the beginning, so we’ve definitely got a lot of representation in the national team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/pos.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3303    " alt="Power of Scotland Team Photo" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/pos.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Power of Scotland - Photo courtesy of CCRD&lt;br&gt;Back row: WKDeid 4th from right; JudderJam 2nd from right.&lt;br&gt;Front row: Tequila 1st from left.&lt;br&gt;Very front row: Ginge!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;It’s hard to say what sort of effect a national team will have in Scotland though. We’re in the fairly unique situation of already having an all-star team with the Jakey Bites, so the benefits of a supra-league team have always in a way been visible within CCRD. That said, our coaches are already bringing back new tactics and ideas from Power of Scotland which are definitely having a positive effect on our team and our game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;On top of that, with not only the Men’s World Cup in March, but the Women's in December, hopefully there will be more exposure of the sport in general here in Scotland and throughout the UK. It would be really good if the attention the sport is getting on a national level could feed back to help leagues, not only in terms of promotion and recruitment, but also in bringing in new sponsors and representation in the national media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. What would you consider as Capital City's biggest achievement in 2013? Are &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;there any highlights that stand out from a very busy year? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;2013 was a very busy year for us, but we don’t have much in the way of visible achievements. Behind the scenes, our biggest achievement of 2013 has been the successful changing of the way we run our training to best help and suit every one’s needs. This has helped build a drive and determination at CCRD to get us ready and in shape for bouting in 2014. Everyone has put in so much hard work and has a fantastic focus of getting us bouting in 2014, to make 2014 the year of the unicorn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We had our first Fresh Meat pass their Mins which I think is a big sign of success for the league as a whole, but most of the things that I think reflect well on us, can be seen in the successes of our members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;There have been a few more highlights through the year such as a few new skaters playing in their first bout, CCRD being represented at the co-ed charity bouts last year and CCRD being represented in the POS line up to name a few.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. What would you consider as your personal biggest achievement with Capital &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;City in 2013? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;That’s a surprisingly tough question, because everything feels like a big achievement when I first master it, but after a few weeks it becomes just another skill. I think the best feeling though was when I managed to skate 28 laps in 5 minutes. My previous PB was 22, I was on new skates, only two weeks back after a two month absence, and the previous week I’d skated headfirst into a wall in the attempt! To actually get the laps I needed after that was such an amazing feeling, even if I had to sit down for the next half hour to avoid passing out!&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. And finally, what are Capital City's plans for 2014? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Bouting! We’ve already got a couple of dates pencilled in for scrimmages with other leagues, and we’re definitely on track to have a public bout by the end of the year. Recruitment is also going to continue to be a big focus, and the big aim there is to have enough numbers so that we can have additional training sessions to better accommodate a range of abilities. On top of that? We’re just going to keep having fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/ccrd.png"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3299" alt="Capital City Roller Derby" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/ccrd.png" width="614" height="227"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>sur5al</category><category>the jakey bites</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/20/derby-review-2014-capital-city-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 13:13:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Review 2014: The Jakey Bites</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/11/derby-review-2014-the-jakey-bites/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2013 saw lots of action from all of the &lt;a title="Roller Derby: It’s Not Just for Girls!" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/02/02/roller-derby-its-not-just-for-girls/" target="_blank"&gt;Men's Roller Derby teams in Scotland&lt;/a&gt;, who represent the main regional areas of the country. And in June 2013, our National Team - &lt;a title="Power of Scotland on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland" target="_blank"&gt;The Power of Scotland&lt;/a&gt; - was formed. But the team who brought Men's Derby to Scotland have also had a busy year: &lt;a title="The Jakey Bites on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/TheJakeyBites" target="_blank"&gt;The Jakey Bites&lt;/a&gt; have continued to bout all over the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WK Deid summarises The Jakey Bites past year by telling us, "The first half of the 2013 saw some new faces in our team line-up, and some old ones disappear. The second half of the year brought with it our first victory in an open bout (against Team Steve), in July. Our first win was closely followed by two more against Super Smash Brollers and Barrow Infernos later in the year. We took part in the second ever Men’s European Roller Derby Championships (we were the only Scottish team in the tournament!), and we closed the year by hosting our own SUR5AL tournament in December".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/marco.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3175  " title="The Jakey Bites vs. Barrow Infernos" alt="The Jakey Bites vs. Barrow Infernos" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/marco.jpg" width="614" height="495"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Jakey Bites vs. Barrow Infernos - WK Deid takes on the Barrow Infernos jammer. Photo Courtesy of Felix Fotography&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WK Deid shares the highlights from their very busy 2013, and how the team have grown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The Jakey Bites have seen a lot of changes to their roster over the last year. Can you introduce us to the new skaters that joined The Jakeys in 2013?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been a few new faces in our line ups this year, and unfortunately some people have left our ranks as well. The new names people will have seen on the track last year were rEd Barron, iHorror, Allota Blacken Blue and Deathworm Jim. We also drafted in The Real Scrim Shady to fill a last minute gap in line ups when we had our co-ed bout with FVRG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. When we spoke to Duff in last year's interview, the regional mens' teams had only just appeared on the scene. What is the relationship like between The Jakey's and these teams? How has their appearance impacted what you do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When The Jakeys started, one of our original goals was to bring the men in Scotland who were interested in playing derby together - and then increase the numbers interested - so Scottish Men's Derby could start to build up from there. As for our relationship with the leagues, all of the current Jakeys (and some former Jakeys) skate with, or are associated with, one of the regional men's leagues. This helps bring the regional leagues a bit closer together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The appearance of the regional leagues has meant more training and more derby for us all, which is a great. We also get to skate with different and new people at our respective regional leagues and help to train them up. There hasn't been much of an impact on what we do so far, but once all the regional league’s start bouting more I think thats when we will see it happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. In 2013, an official National Team - The Power of Scotland - was established. Are you concerned that you may not get as many bouting opportunites now, as the 'unofficial' national team? Are many of The Jakey's on the Power of Scotland roster?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, all of the current Jakeys who were eligible to try-out for Power of Scotland were lucky enough to make the team! This obviously means that we will all be continuing to bout together, which is great, but there is that possibility that there will be less bouting opportunities as The Jakeys for a while. Hopefully in the long run this won't be a problem and we can continue on. You never know, perhaps we may even see some of the other POS skaters joining The Jakeys ranks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. What would you consider as The Jakeys biggest achievement in 2013&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s really is hard to pick just one thing from 2013 that stands out for us as there were so many things. There was hosting Scotland's first all Men's Headline Bout, and also holding Scotland's first Men’s vs Women's bout (The Jakey Bites vs. Team Steve).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/jakeys-steve-060713-117.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3262 " alt="The Jakey Bites vs. Team Steve - Photo courtesy of Dave McAleavy" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/jakeys-steve-060713-117.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Jakey Bites vs. Team Steve - Tea Virus takes on Splat and Fight Cub. Photo courtesy of Dave McAleavy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We won our first bout (and went on to win 2 more by the end of the year). We also travelled down to Birmingham to compete in the Men’s European Roller Derby Championships and made it through to a semi-final!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think though a lot of The Jakeys would pick our last bout of 2013 against Barrow Infernos as a high point of the year as it was our first full length bout win against a mens team. It was a hard fought game from beginning to end in which we only played with 10 skaters the whole time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;2013 Bout Fixtures  &amp;amp; Summaries&lt;/h4&gt;
WK Deid has kindly supplied a summary of each of The Jakey Bites' bouts in 2013, in  case you missed them.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/04/2013: The Jakey Bites (126) vs. South Wales Silures (300)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was The Silures first public bout, although they had played in many scrims and some of their players were in The Expendables at last years MERDC. Although The Jakey's took the lead in the first few jams, The Silures fought hard and swung the lead round in their favour. The Silures took full advantage of The Jakeys' trips to the penalty box and racked up the points. In the end, they took the victory of the first Men's Roller Derby headline bout in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/07/2013: The Jakey Bites (177) vs. Team Steve (92)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who haven't heard of Team Steve before (where have you been hiding?), they are an exhibition team made up of skaters who didn't make it into the final cut of Team Scotland for the World Cup in 2011. Co-ed roller derby had been played before in Scotland, but this was the first time that an all-boys team faced off against an all-girls team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the first whistle, the girls didn't hold back and neither did we. We took a small lead which we maintained the first half. During the second half, we pulled out a bigger gap, but in the last quarter of the bout, Team Steve took advantage of our tiring team and started to close the gap. On the final whistle we took the victory - which was not only our first win - but the first win for any Scottish Men's team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13/07/2013: Of Fights and Men (115) vs. The Jakey Tayzers (185)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City Roller Girls approached us to play in a Co Ed bout, so we fielded some of our own skaters to join GCRG and lined them up against our Jakey/ Dundee Roller Girls team - The Jakey Tayzers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We saw this bout was as an opportunity to help us prepare for MERDC - and also to be a bit of fun - but neither side wanted to lose. The first half, and much of the second, saw a few lead changes,  but The Jakey Tayzers managed to take advantage of a couple of power jams, letting them pull out in front and win the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20/07/2013: MERDC (Men’s European Roller Derby Championships) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year we had wanted to play at MERDC, but unfortunately we were unable to get a team together in time. In 2013, we made it or goal to play at MERDC if our application was accepted. It was - and we made it onto the list of the 16 teams who would compete in the tournament. The majority of the teams were from England, with three from France, one from Wales, and ourselves from Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had prepared hard for the tournament with scrims and bouts every on the run up. We knew we were in for a very tough first game since the organisers announced who everyones first opponents were a few weeks before the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MERDC BOUT 1: New Wheeled Order (151) vs. The Jakey Bites (40)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winning against NWO was always going to be a tall order but we believed that we had a chance and put together a plan. Unfortunately, as hard as we tried and played, NWO were just too strong and their walls were so solid that our jammers struggled to make it through them. We did try to fight back near the end but the damage was done and NWO took the win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MERDC BOUT 2: &lt;/strong&gt;The Jakey Bites (105) vs. Super Smash Brollers (63)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the game that we secretly hoped we would get to play when we saw the sneak preview of the tournament's opening games. The reason being that a former Jakey - Danimal - had moved down south and joined Super Smash Brollers! But playing this game meant we would have lost our first bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went into this game knowing we had a good chance of taking the win, but from the first whistle, the Brollers put up a very fierce fight. For a while it looked like it was anyone's game to take until the Brollers racked up the fouls. With so many bin trips, we took advantage of the extra skaters on track and started to put in the points to take the win - our first against a men's team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MERDC BOUT 3: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Panam Squad (114) vs. The Jakey Bites (25)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both ourselves and Panam didn't know much if anything about each other before this game but spirits were high with both teams chatting, laughing, and wishing each other luck before the first whistle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We managed to take an early lead, even though Panam were playing hard. But soon after Panam found their rhythm and really dug in giving us all manor of problems. They soon took the lead and after a couple of power jams later they were comfortable in control. The final whistle ended our time at MERDC, but both teams who had beaten us that day (NWO &amp;amp; Panam) each went on to pick up trophies: Panam won the Plate Final in their next match, and NWO won the Bowl in theirs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/08/2013: The Violent Jakeys (147) vs. The Parma Bites  (277)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the success of our team up with DRG last year and then GCRG last month it was the turn of FVRG to get into some Co-Ed action. The first half of this bout was a very close, with nothing in it between the two teams. At half time the scores sat at 83 - 109 to the Parma Bites, with it anyone's game to win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second half started with The Violent Jakeys taking advantage of the first few jams and the game really heated up. It wasn't until the last 10/15 minutes of the game and with some power jams that the Parma Bites managed to build up a big points gap over the Violent Jakeys. At the final whistle the score stood at 147 - 277 to the Parma Bites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/11/2013: The Jakey Bites (199) vs. Barrow Infernos (121)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was our last bout of 2013 and one we really wanted to win to finish the year on a high. Unfortunately for us, we had a few injuries on the run up to this (WKDeid, Duff and iHorror), but Duff and WK Deid managed to get back on skates the week before and got back to training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our roster on the day only had 10 skaters to Barrows 14 and we knew from their bout against Mean City the previous month that they had progressed a lot since playing against The Skelpies earlier in the year. They were big guys and heavy hitters but we believed that even with less numbers we could fight for the win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a hard fought game from the start, with both sides skating very fast and hitting hard. We pulled together and worked as a team each jam, keeping our heads clear and concentrating on the job in hand. Which helped us lead the score the whole of the first half apart from a couple of jams half way through. The second half swung more our way with a few more power jams that helped us build up more of a lead. but throughout we stood firm worked together and played as a team to take the victory, which was our and Scotland's first Men's Derby Home win against a men's team, at long last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SUR5AL 2013 Tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year we held a &lt;a title="SUR5AL 2013: A Summary" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/12/29/sur5al-2013-a-summary/" target="_blank"&gt;SUR5AL tournament&lt;/a&gt; to say thank you to all the leagues that had helped us during our first year. We asked for 8 teams of 3 girls to sign up and each were given 2 Jakeys chosen at random. This year we wanted to host another one and make it a bit bigger. We asked for 20 teams to sign up, made up of a combination of 3 females and 2 males.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the run up to the event we had some teams pull out and we were left with just 16 so we changed the format of the event. It was organised into 4 group stages, with 4 teams in each group.  The team with the most wins at the end of the group would go through to the semi final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had teams not only from Scotland but a couple from England came up to take part as well. Unlike last time we also opened up the event to the public to come and watch, with all door takings going to the winning teams charity of choice. At the end of the day team Lamb 2.0 who emerged victorious but more than that everyone had a great day and there was a great atmosphere throughout the whole event as skaters from all over Scotland had travelled to take part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/12/final.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3094" alt="The Finalists - Festive Periods and Lamb 2.0" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/12/final.jpg" width="614" height="393"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Finalists - Festive Periods (in white) and Lamb 2.0 (in black) - Image courtesy of Ian McCreadie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>the jakey bites</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/11/derby-review-2014-the-jakey-bites/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 12:36:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SUR5AL 2013: A Summary</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/12/29/sur5al-2013-a-summary/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 14th December, The Jakey Bites &lt;a title="The Jakey Bites Host SUR5AL 2013" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/10/28/sur5al-2013/"&gt;hosted their second 'SUR5AL' Tournament&lt;/a&gt; at The Meadowbank Stadium in Edinburgh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16 teams of 3 females plus 2 males signed up to take part in the tournament, representing many of the Scottish Roller Derby leagues, as well as English teams: Barrow Infernos, Furness Firecrackers, and Blackpool Roller Derby. This year, the event was open to the public. All door takings plus each teams' entry fee was donated to the winner's charity of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 16 teams were split into 4 groups of 4 teams, with a variety of festive names! Each team played against the other three teams in their group, in 3 sets of 2 minute jams played back-to-back with no time-outs or call-offs. The team who won the most games from their Group then progressed through to the Semi Final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day ran extremely smoothly, with Dafty from The Jakeys guiding the teams through their group stages. The NSOs did a fantastic job of telling each team who was up next to play, and the Ref Crews were seamless in their switch-over between games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ian McCreadie - an independent photographer - was at The Meadowbank to capture all of the action from the day. He has kindly supplied all of the following images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group A Winner: Team 13&lt;/strong&gt;, representing Fierce Valley Roller Girls and Capital City Roller Derby. Their team skaters were Tiny Tearaway (FVRG); Maz-Manian Devil (FVRG); Fun Ghoul (FVRG); WK Deid (CCRD); HaJuken (CCRD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/12/k4z8886.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3090   " title="Group A Winner: Team 13" alt="Group A Winner: Team 13" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/12/k4z8886.jpg" width="614" height="371"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Tiny and Maz from Team 13 pictured - Image courtesy of Ian McCreadie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group B Winner: Team 6&lt;/strong&gt;, representing Granite City Roller Girls and Granite City Brawlermen. Their team skaters were Clinically Wasted (GCRG); Rock 'n Riot (GCRG); Fight Cub (GCRG); Pudz (GCB); and Jaffa Skates (GCB).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/12/group-b.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3093 " title="Group B Winner: Team 6" alt="Group B Winner: Team 6" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/12/group-b.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Jaffa Skates, Fight Cub, Pudz and Clincally Wasted from Team 6 pictured - Image courtesy of Ian McCreadie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group C Winner: Festive Periods&lt;/strong&gt;, representing Auld Reekie Roller Girls and MeanCity Roller Derby. Their team skaters were Bint Imperial (ARRG); Crazy Legs (ARRG); Unprotected Bex (ARRG); Tea Virus (MCRD) and Konanberg (MCRD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/12/img_7908.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3092  " title="Group C Winner: Festive Periods" alt="Group C Winner: Festive Periods " src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/12/img_7908.jpg" width="614" height="421"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Group C Winner: Festive Periods - Image courtesy of Ian McCreadie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group D Winner: Lamb 2.0&lt;/strong&gt;, representing Auld Reekie Roller Girls, Dundee Roller Girls, and Capital City Roller Derby. Their team skaters were Ginge (ARRG); Tequila Jammer (CCRD); Milky (DRG); Kiki (ARRG) and Dafty (CCRD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/12/k4z8740.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-3091  " title="Group D Winner: Lamb 2.0" alt="Group D Winner: Lamb 2.0" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/12/k4z8740.jpg" width="614" height="380"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Group D Winner: Lamb 2.0 - Image courtesy of Ian McCreadie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a hard-fought semi finals round, Festive Periods and Lamb 2.0 came head-to-head in the finals. Lamb 2.0 claimed the victory, and will be donating the takings from the event to a charity of their choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/12/final.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3094 " alt="The Finalists - Festive Periods and Lamb 2.0" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/12/final.jpg" width="614" height="393"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Finalists - Festive Periods (in white) and Lamb 2.0 (in black) - Image courtesy of Ian McCreadie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full line-ups of each team is as follows. Although there were a couple of changes on the day, this should give you an idea of the talent that competed in the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/12/sur5al-team.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3085" alt="The SUR5AL 2013 Teams" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/12/sur5al-team.jpg" width="614" height="399"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The SUR5AL 2013 Teams - Image courtesy of The Jakey Bites&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery type="slideshow" ids="3098,3099,3100,3101,3102,3103,3104,3105,3106,3107,3108,3109,3110,3111,3112,3113,3114,3115,3116,3117,3118,3119,3120,3121,3122,3123"]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bout reports</category><category>sur5al</category><category>the jakey bites</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/12/29/sur5al-2013-a-summary/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 11:47:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Jakey Bites Host SUR5AL 2013</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/10/28/sur5al-2013/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 14 December 2013, &lt;a title="The Jakey Bites Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/TheJakeyBites" target="_blank"&gt;The Jakey Bites&lt;/a&gt; will host a 'Sur5al' tournament in Edinburgh's Meadowbank Sports Centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Windsor Roller Girls' Website" href="http://windsorrollergirls.com/sur5al" target="_blank"&gt;Windsor Roller Girls hosted the first Sur5al challenge&lt;/a&gt; in April 2012, and now the format of a five-a-side, one-day tournament has spread all around the world. Skaters from all the Scottish leagues have been invited to form teams of 5 to take part in The Jakey's event, including co-ed teams. A few English, Welsh and Irish teams may even pop up on the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tournament will be open to the public with all profits going to the winning team's nominated charity. Join the &lt;a title="SURV5AL 2013 Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/317269091746500/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt; for the latest news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/10/jakey-sur5al.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2998" alt="Image courtesy of The Jakey Bites" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/10/jakey-sur5al.png" width="614" height="230"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of The Jakey Bites&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>meadowbank sports centre</category><category>sur5al</category><category>the jakey bites</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/10/28/sur5al-2013/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 13:18:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Jakey Bites vs Barrow Infernos</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/10/27/the-jakey-bites-vs-barrow-infernos/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 2 November, &lt;a title="The Jakey Bites Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/TheJakeyBites?fref=ts" target="_blank"&gt;The Jakey Bites &lt;/a&gt;will take on &lt;a title="Barrow Infernos Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/BarrowInfernos?filter=3" target="_blank"&gt;Barrow Infernos&lt;/a&gt; in Grangemouth Sports Complex, at 4pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both teams are keen to hold onto their recent winning streaks, with Barrow beating &lt;a title="Wirral Men's Roller Derby Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/ThePackAnimals" target="_blank"&gt;Wirral Men's Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="Bairn City Rollers Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers" target="_blank"&gt;Bairn City Rollers' &lt;/a&gt;Skelpies, where as The Jakey's have beaten &lt;a title="Team Steve Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Team-Steve/261667917252555?fref=ts" target="_blank"&gt;Team Steve &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a title="Super Smash Broller Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/supersmashbrollers" target="_blank"&gt;Super Smash Brollers&lt;/a&gt;. If you are yet to see any Men's Roller Derby, this will be a great first experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The November bout will be The Jakey's first outing since July, when &lt;a title="The Jakey Bites Take on Europe!" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/07/10/the-jakey-bites-take-on-europe/" target="_blank"&gt;they played in the Men's European Roller Derby Championships&lt;/a&gt;. The team played excellently in the tournament, and learnt a lot from the experience that they have taken back to the training room. Their hard work will hopefully pay off when they come face-to-face with the team from Barrow-In-Furness next weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are now available online through &lt;a title="Buy tickets online" href="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=6E973R82UPT76" target="_blank"&gt;PayPal&lt;/a&gt;. Join the &lt;a title="Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/577858578940889/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt; to keep up-to-date with the latest news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/10/jakey-bites-poster1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2995" alt="Image courtesy of The Jakey Bites" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/10/jakey-bites-poster1.jpg" width="614" height="867"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of The Jakey Bites&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>barrow infernos</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>jakey bites</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>the jakey bites</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/10/27/the-jakey-bites-vs-barrow-infernos/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 18:10:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Co-Ed Roller Derby: Violent Jakeys vs. Parma Bites</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/07/23/co-ed-roller-derby-violent-jakeys-vs-parma-bites/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Co-Ed Roller Derby has recently taken hold of the traditionally female sport, and &lt;a title="FVRG Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/FierceValleyRG" target="_blank"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; want a piece of the action!   Scottish Men's team, &lt;a title="The Jakey Bites Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/TheJakeyBites" target="_blank"&gt;The Jakey Bites&lt;/a&gt;, have already played with Dundee's Silvery Tayzers and Aberdeen's Granite City Roller Girls, but how will they fare playing against (or with!) FVRG's Parma Violents?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both teams will be taken out of their comfort zone as each line-up will feature male and female skaters. So what will these mixed teams be called? Violent Jakeys and Parma Bites, naturally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come along to The Peak in Stirling on Saturday 10th August for a guaranteed action-packed afternoon. Tickets are £7 on the door (under 12s go free with a paying adult). Doors open at 2pm for a 2:30pm start. Further details available on the &lt;a title="Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/FierceValleyRG?ref=hl#!/events/381912665243385/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/bout-poster.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2846" alt="Co Ed Bout Poster - image courtesy of Chaos Faerie" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/bout-poster.jpg" width="595" height="842"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Co Ed Bout Poster - image courtesy of Chaos Faerie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>the jakey bites</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/07/23/co-ed-roller-derby-violent-jakeys-vs-parma-bites/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 11:59:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Jakey Bites Take on Europe!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/07/10/the-jakey-bites-take-on-europe/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/merdc-logo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2762" alt="MERDC Logo" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/merdc-logo.jpg" width="250" height="250"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of MERDC
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="The Jakey Bites Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/TheJakeyBites" target="_blank"&gt;The Jakey Bites&lt;/a&gt; are gearing up for their debut appearance in the upcoming &lt;a title="MERDC Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/MensEuropeanRollerDerbyChampionships" target="_blank"&gt;Men's European Roller Derby Championships&lt;/a&gt;! The tournament will be spread over the weekend of Saturday 20th July and Sunday 21st July, hosted in Birmingham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only the second MERDC tournament, so the organisers are keen to pull out all the stops to make their mark. The number of teams participating between last year and this year has increased from 7 to 16, and from the discussions on Facebook, it looks like the venue will be jam-packed with team merchandise and stock from the tournament sponsors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2012 winners, &lt;a title="Southern Discomfort Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/southerndiscomfortrd" target="_blank"&gt;Southern Discomfort&lt;/a&gt;, will be back to guard their title from teams from France, Wales, England, and Scotland. &lt;a title="The Inhuman League Facebook Page" href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/inhumanleague" target="_blank"&gt;The Inhuman League&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="South Wales Silures Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/SiluresRollerDerby" target="_blank"&gt;South Wales Silures&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a title="Quad Guards Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/QuadGuards" target="_blank"&gt;Quad Guards&lt;/a&gt; from Toulouse, will be joining The Jakeys in putting up a strong fight to take home the Cup. As well as getting the chance to watch all of these fantastic teams in action, The Jakeys are hoping to come up against &lt;a title="Super Smash Brollers Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/supersmashbrollers" target="_blank"&gt;Super Smash Brollers&lt;/a&gt;, as former Jakey - Danimal - has recently joined their team after moving to England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday will set the tournament off to a flying start, with 20 bouts played over 2 tracks. From the line-up issued by the MERDC, The Jakeys will take on Manchester's &lt;a title="New Wheeled Order Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/NewWheeledOrder" target="_blank"&gt;New Wheeled Order &lt;/a&gt;in the third bout of the tournament. By the end of the day, only 8 teams will remain to fight it out for a place on the leaderbord. On Sunday, spectators can settle down to watch all the action from 1 track. They will be treated to the Semi-Finals, Third Place Play-offs, and then THREE Finals!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When asking The Jakeys how they are preparing for the tournament, team skater WK Deid told us, "At Jakey HQ we have been taking preparation for the Euros very seriously, which isn’t like us at all. In addition to our normal Jakey training sessions and our other leagues training (Capital City, Mean City &amp;amp; Bairn City Rollers) we are scrimming almost every week or bouting. We have recently played Team Steve (and celebrated our first win!) and will play &lt;a title="GCRG's Facebook Event" href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/232381250219767/" target="_blank"&gt;Granite City’s co-ed bout&lt;/a&gt; in the two weeks before the tournament".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/jakey-bites.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2792" alt="Jakey Bites vs Team Steve" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/jakey-bites.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Jakey Bites vs Team Steve - Image courtesy of Dave McAleavy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cult Friction from Dundee Roller Girls will be on the road with The Jakeys as their Line Up Manager. She has built a strong relationship with the men's team after training and skating with them since September 2012. Cult was Bench Manager for The Jakeys in their bout against the Crash Test Brummies in 2012, and her involvement has escalated from there. She told us that, "Skating with the guys every week has resulted in fantastic relationships and friendships with them, as a team and individually. I know how they all skate like the back of my hand so I guess becoming the Line Up Manager was a natural progression. They have taught me a lot in the last 10 months and always push me to up my game so it is an absolute pleasure to be their Line Up at MERDC. I think they will make us all proud at the MERDC tournament and will give a great representation of Men's Roller Derby in Scotland". We couldn't agree more, Cult!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/cult-friction.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2805" alt="Cult Friction at The Jakeys v South Wales Silures - Image courtesy of Claire Brunton" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/cult-friction.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Cult Friction at The Jakeys v South Wales Silures - Image courtesy of Claire Brunton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Buy MERDC on EventBrite" href="https://merdc2013.eventbrite.co.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;Tickets are available online&lt;/a&gt; until 17th July, priced at £20 for a day pass, or £30 for a weekend pass. Keep up to date with the latest tournament news by joining the &lt;a title="MERDC Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/MensEuropeanRollerDerbyChampionships#!/events/661336940559208/" target="_blank"&gt;MERDC Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>jakey bites</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>merdc</category><category>the jakey bites</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/07/10/the-jakey-bites-take-on-europe/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 11:24:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Jakey Bites vs. Team Steve</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/07/03/jakey-bites-vs-team-steve/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 6th July, The Jakey Bites will take on Team Steve at Grangemouth Sports Centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And "Who are Team Steve?", I hear you ask! They formed in 2011 with a 'Best of the Rest' line-up after the women's Team Scotland selection, and  have bouted against Team Scotland since the 2011 World Cup. With a few changes to the original team roster, skaters from &lt;a title="Dundee Roller Girls website" href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Auld Reekie Roller Girls website" href="http://arrg.co.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Glasgow Roller Derby website" href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="Granite City Roller Girls website" href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;Granite City Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; will return to take on The Jakeys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last Jakey Bites bout in Grangemouth was a sell-out, and this one looks set to be just as popular! Make sure to buy your &lt;a title="Buy Tickets from PayPal" href="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=R75N74BAWZNJG" target="_blank"&gt;tickets online&lt;/a&gt; for £6 to guarantee entry. Under 12s gain free admittance with a paying adult. Doors open at 2pm(ish) with the first whistle blown at 2:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/jakey-bites-poster.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2746" alt="Jakey Bites vs Team Steve Poster" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/07/jakey-bites-poster.jpg" width="614" height="868"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Jakey Bites&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>men's roller derby</category><category>the jakey bites</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/07/03/jakey-bites-vs-team-steve/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 11:59:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Jakey Bites: One Year On</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/04/the-jakey-bites-one-year-on/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the recent birthday of &lt;a title="The Jakey Bites on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/TheJakeyBites?fref=ts" target="_blank"&gt;The Jakey Bites&lt;/a&gt; - Scotland's first Men's Roller Derby team - we caught up with team skater, Duff McKeggar, to hear about their year so far and their plans for the future. The Jakeys will play their first headline bout at home this coming weekend, so this is a perfect opportunity to learn more about the team before heading along to Grangemouth to show them your support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In just over a year, The Jakeys have gone from being a "ragtag collection of male referees" from the existing female leagues, to a dedicated team of 22 skaters who travel all over the UK to compete.  They've come a long way since heir first training session in a cold airport hanger in Perth in January 2012!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/day-one.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2429 " alt="First Training Session" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/day-one.jpg" width="614" height="475"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; First Training Session: Alan Watt, Marco Vezzani, Martin Willox, Chris Riggeling, Iain Elstone, Dan Blake, Jazza Crawford, Gregg Pearson, Graeme Clark&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the news of a men's roller derby team in Scotland broke out, enthusiastic male skaters emerged from the derby community to join the 9 refs - a mixture of husbands of female skates, friends of skaters, or those who had watched a bout a thought "I want to try that!".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The newly-formed team didn't waste any time in lining up their first bout, despite having barely enough skaters to fill the roster and only recently having passed their minimum skills test. So on 21st April 2012, The Jakey Bites traveled to Newcastle to take on their men's team: &lt;a title="Tyne and Fear website" href="http://www.tyneandfear.co.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;Tyne &amp;amp; Fear&lt;/a&gt;. With their bright orange t-shirts, a Rab C. Nesbitt team logo, and a bus-load of supporters, The Jakeys made quite a first impression! The team never won their first bout but that didn't matter - this was their exploration into the unknown territory of Men's Roller Derby and getting a glimpse of what the future could hold for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/tyne-fear.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2425  " alt="Tyne and Fear vs The Jakey Bites, photo courtesy of Tyne and Fear" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/tyne-fear.jpg" width="614" height="342"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Tyne and Fear vs The Jakey Bites, photo courtesy of Tyne and Fear&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as the brightness of their uniforms that day, the team's merchandise for sale also raised a few eyebrows. Emblazoned across the back of the t-shirts were the words "Scottish All Stars". When I asked Duff McKeggar where this name came from, his answer was far less controversial than many had assumed! Duff explains, "It’s pretty much an in-joke. The Jakeys have always based ourselves on the featured team from the movie Rollerball (I must admit I've never seen it!) and apparently they are known as ‘The Houston All Stars’ so when we were designing our first t-shirt print run, Scottish All Stars was jokingly mentioned as a possible back print and it stuck!". Simple!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, there has been a lot of talk recently about standardizing National Team Selection on the &lt;a title="FAQ on UKRDA Website" href="http://ukrda.org.uk/?p=419" target="_blank"&gt;UK Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt; (UKRDA) website, so we were keen to hear if The Jakey Bites had any plans to live up to their All Star title and become the official national team. I must admit, I was disappointed when Duff said the The Jakeys would never be officially recognised as the 'Team Scotland' of men's derby, but he did reassure us that - when the time comes - the roster will hopefully feature a large number of Jakeys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before we look too far into the future, let's look back at what The Jakey Bites have achieved in their first year. By far their most memorable moment was playing in their first public bout against Tyne and Fear after only a few months in existence, explains Duff. The Jakeys also organised and hosted the hugely successful Sur5al tournament in December last year - a knock-out competition of mixed teams of 5 skaters from teams all over Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/sur5al.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2446" alt="Sur5al Tournament, photo courtesy of Claire Brunton of Zenspirations" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/sur5al.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Sur5al Tournament, photo courtesy of Claire Brunton of Zenspirations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a personal note for Duff, he recalls his biggest achievement with The Jakey Bites: "I was delighted to play in the Tyne and Fear bout after only a month of skating which was made all the sweeter by getting the Best Jammer award!  Playing in Scotland's first men's derby and co-ed bouts was also a great achievement".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After their first bout in April 2012, it was full steam ahead with The Jakeys playing 4 more bouts away from home; opening a double-header event for &lt;a title="Glasgow Roller Derby website" href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; in June; and joining force's with &lt;a title="Dundee Roller Girls website" href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Dundee Roller Girl&lt;/a&gt;s in the first co-ed bout in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/jakey-tayzers.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-2426  " alt="The Jakey Tayzers vs The Silvery Bites, photo courtesy of The Jakey Bites" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/04/jakey-tayzers.jpg" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Jakey Tayzers vs The Silvery Bites, photo courtesy of The Jakey Bites&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2013 already looks to be very busy for The Jakey Bites - and we're only in April! There is talk of a Men's &lt;a title="EuroDerby.org on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/euroderby.org?ref=stream" target="_blank"&gt;European Roller Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt; taking place later this year, and Duff hopes to see The Jakey Bites in the line-up to showcase the Scottish talent. If we know the The Jakeys, they should have a busy bouting calendar lined up, and hopefully more of these played at home. Duff also ranks their "elusive first win" as a huge priority for the coming year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With so many more bouts in the pipeline, the question on everyone gent's lips is: "How do I become a Jakey Bite"? The answer is simple: Duff recommends that you contact the team via &lt;a title="The Jakey Bites on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/TheJakeyBites?fref=ts" target="_blank"&gt;their Facebook Page&lt;/a&gt; to get more information about their training commitments. Even if you train with the team, your place still must be earned by a rigorous team selection process, with the final decision being with the Captain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the prospect of jumping right into a bouting team  isn't quite what you're looking for - any one of the regional men's teams would be happy to sign you up and put you through your paces. Duff explains that The Jakeys "have fully embraced the new leagues and are happy to see men's derby in Scotland growing so quickly. As the Jakeys are more of a collective than a league we've never really had a consistent fresh meat program whereas now the local leagues all have first rate fresh meat programs so ongoing we have a wider pool of talent to choose from". Duff himself is one of the founder members of &lt;a title="Capital City Roller Derby on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/CapitalCityRollerDerby?fref=ts" target="_blank"&gt;Capital City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; in Edinburgh, and many of his fellow Jakeys are involved with the new leagues in one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, Duff and his teammates are focusing all their efforts in organising and training for their first headline bout that will be played at home on Saturday 6th April.  We're intrigued to see The Jakeys in action again, especially since Duff lets on that "anyone who hasn't seen us for a while will be very pleased with how far we have come in such a short time". He is looking forward to having a loyal home crowd behind them, and hoping that they will put on a good show!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coming year promises to be very exciting for The Jakey Bites - and Men's Roller Derby in Scotland - and we can't wait!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Jakey Bites play South Wales Silures on 6th April in Grangemouth. Tickets are available to buy online - visit the &lt;a title="The Jakey Bites Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/122071404642449/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt; for more details so you don't miss out on the action!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>the jakey bites</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/04/the-jakey-bites-one-year-on/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 20:48:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lets hear it for the boys!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/08/lets-hear-it-for-the-boys/</link><dc:creator>thejammingpony</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A female perspective on Merby and CO-ED Roller Derby.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until the past couple of years Roller Derby has been a sport ‘rolled’ out on a predominantly female playing field. There have always been men around, be it in an official capacity or those of the infamous derby widow - ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However those who wished to play on a competitive level have taken the proverbial bull by the horns with Merby leagues are popping up all over the UK. Scotland in Particular has no less than 4 up and coming all male leagues. Their collective bouting team the Jakey Bites have been established for over a year now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arrival of Men’s Roller Derby has been met with mixed reaction on roller derby scene, some embracing it fully and others feeling a little put out that the male specimen are perhaps trying to steal our feminine thunder………God can’t they let us have anything!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being part of a league who have taken to Integrating with open arms, I have had a fantastic opportunity to skate and compete with the some of the Jakey Bites in the past year, skating in the Uk’s first ever CO-ED derby bout with The Jakey Tayzers last September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result I have become a keen supporter for CO-ED and men’s roller derby. The thought of this might seem a bit overwhelming for some but I believe it can make you a more rounded and skilled skater in the long run. I have skated for 2 years now, predominantly in all female training and bout situations and I thought I would take this opportunity to answer some of the questions or allay some of the fears people might have about Male and Co-Ed roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;DO THEY HIT HARDER?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate to emasculate anyone here but the answer to this is not really. I have found that taking a hit from a guy is no different from being hit by the girls. The fact that they don’t really have hips takes a bit of getting used to but the impact of the hit isn't as scary as it might seem.  Put it this way, if you have ever been hit by Cider from Auld Reekie then you have nothing to worry about and are fully prepared…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;ARE THEIR TACTICS DIFFERENT?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever we first started training for the CO – ED bout this was definitely one of our questions, in all honesty we thought for some reason they were going to be all offence and no discipline (not sure why, guess we were stereotyping). This wasn't the case at all; for the most part their tactics are exactly the same as what we are doing on the female side of things. They are definitely very skilled and know their stuff; I didn't find it any different from skating with my female team mates. They have had to adjust to the new rule set exactly the same as we have. From watching various Merby bouts last year there really wasn't much difference in the tactics played and there certainly wasn't any less glitter surprisingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;IS IT AWKWARD?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we all know, roller derby can be a very 'handsy' sport, it is full contact and I suppose it would be normal to wonder if it gets a bit awkward when playing CO-ED. This one is really in the eyes of the beholder to be honest, I personally haven’t ever felt awkward or anything likes that whilst skating. Whether that comes from knowing them quite well or from being in the zone on track I’m not sure but it certainly has never been an issue. You know the bond you have with your team mates on track, well that bond is completely possible in CO-ED as well and it is a pretty gratifying experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;ARE THEY BETTER THAN US?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer to this hangs on the word better; it’s not so much a case of better as different. Roller derby caters for differences; it’s one of the most appealing aspects of the sport which is known for celebrating individuality. In some cases they may be a little stronger and taller than us but……being a big player or a hard hitter isn't the be all and end all if you are smaller and faster. In truth they are as varied and unique as we are on the female side of things. Tall, small, fast, strong, hard-hitting, positional and/or agile everyone has strength it's just finding out how they compliment each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;ARE THEY JUST A BUNCH OF “LADS?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cracking dirty jokes and messing around? As for the dirty jokes I know some female skaters who could make them blush……….But in all seriousness the answer here is no. They are 100% dedicated to the sport and the progression of their regional leagues, the passion they have for the sport is no less than we have in the female leagues and the drive they have shown in starting from scratch has been nothing short of impressive. As a female skater they have always been nothing less than welcoming and supportive of me and since skating with them I have seen a real improvement in certain areas of my skating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a personal perspective I am fully in support of Merby in the UK. I would urge everyone to support their local Merby league alongside their local derby league, Capital City in Edinburgh, Mean City in Glasgow, The Skelpies in the Central Belt and The Tayminators in Tayside. I have had the pleasure of knowing people from most of these teams and can tell you they are a cracking bunch of guys, we should be proud to have them as a part of the Scottish Roller Derby scene. I hope to see a lot more CO-ED action in the future with my Jakey Tayzers. The Skelpies League, Bairn City are already establishing a Co -Ed league so it is onward and upward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to make up your own mind or have a male friend you’d like to wrangle into taking up the sport, the Jakey Bites (Comprising of members from 3 out of 4 of the aforementioned teams) have a bout coming up against The South Wales Silures on April the 6&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; in Grangemouth. Check their Facebook page for event details and ticket sales. The venue only holds 100 so buy in advance to avoid disappointment. Bairn City men’s team will also be playing South Wales the day after on the 7&lt;sup&gt;th &lt;/sup&gt;at the same venue, for more details and ticket sales check their Facebook pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.facebook.com/events/122071404642449/      (SKELPIES VS. SILURES)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.facebook.com/events/432929060108875/     (JAKEYS VS. SILURES)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a title="Jakeys VS. Silures" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/522492_342652352503139_928642489_n.png"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-2291 aligncenter" alt="522492_342652352503139_928642489_n" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/522492_342652352503139_928642489_n.png" width="506" height="567"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/10889_619537551396047_724006372_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-2292 aligncenter" alt="10889_619537551396047_724006372_n" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/10889_619537551396047_724006372_n.jpg?w=211" width="506" height="567"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>image</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>merby</category><category>roller derby</category><category>the jakey bites</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>the tayminators</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/08/lets-hear-it-for-the-boys/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 16:57:25 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>