<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about the skelpies)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/the-skelpies.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Roller Derby Is Back in Grangemouth in 2018</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/02/14/roller-derby-is-back-in-grangemouth-in-2018/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9205" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/bcr-banner.jpg" alt="bcr-banner" width="851" height="315"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby in 2018 has well and truly started after the Christmas break as we have just witnessed the Womens World cup in Manchester recently and still have the Men's world cup to look forward to in April. But this month sees the return of derby in Scotland, with the first games of 2018 taking place thanks to Bairn City Rollers. As they will be kicking of their 2018 by hosting a double header in Grangemouth Sports Complex on Saturday the 24th of February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a double header with a Geordie feel to is as BCR's Skelpies take on Tyne and Fears &lt;span class="_4n-j _fbReactionComponent__eventDetailsContentTags fsl"&gt;Inglorious B&lt;em&gt;Stars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for the first game of the day followed after there is an &lt;span class="_4n-j _fbReactionComponent__eventDetailsContentTags fsl"&gt;All Gender game made up of skaters from Newcastle.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="_4n-j _fbReactionComponent__eventDetailsContentTags fsl"&gt;The Skelpies and the BStars have faced off against each other three times to date, with the B*Stars taking the win each time, can the Skelpies take the win this time? Be sure to come along to find out.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="_4n-j _fbReactionComponent__eventDetailsContentTags fsl"&gt;Doors open 1.30pm and tickets are priced at £5 on the door. If you would like to know more &lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/587963344880848/"&gt;visit the facebook event page here&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bcr</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mens roller derby scotland</category><category>skelpies</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>tyne &amp; fear</category><category>tyne and fear</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/02/14/roller-derby-is-back-in-grangemouth-in-2018/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 11:15:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow ready to rock as British Champs T3 goes down to the wire</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/06/glasgow-ready-to-rock-as-british-champs-t3-goes-down-to-the-wire/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't stop believing&lt;/strong&gt; - that's the tune blasting out at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GlasgowMensRollerDerby/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; HQ where the Irn Brn are plotting a derby escape act which would make Houdini hop the apex with delight.
&lt;p&gt;This Saturday, GMRD play host to the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/133440747209468/?acontext=%7B%22ref%22%3A%222%22%2C%22ref_dashboard_filter%22%3A%22upcoming%22%2C%22action_history%22%3A%22%5B%7B%5C%22surface%5C%22%3A%5C%22dashboard%5C%22%2C%5C%22mechanism%5C%22%3A%5C%22main_list%5C%22%2C%5C%22extra_data%5C%22%3A%5B%5D%7D%5D%22%7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;final fixtures in the British Championships' Men's Tier 3 - Regional North group&lt;/a&gt; (at Glasgow's ARC Sports Centre).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD will be taking on their Celtic cousins, Men Behaving Derby (MBD), while Bairn City Rollers' Skelpies will be setting blasters to stun against Teesside Skate Invaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a decidedly Scottish-type twist, only a specific combination of results can now see GMRD qualify for the play-offs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the uninitiated, here's the short story:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April, GMRD travelled to Dublin to play the Skate Invaders, winning by 234 points to 167. GMRD were later denuded of victory due to an eligibility malfunction, with the score becoming 200-0 in favour of the Invaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD's next game against the Skelpies was then forfeited by the Falkirk team due to lack of numbers - a 200-0 win in favour of GMRD - leaving the table looking like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-20255 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/brd-table.jpg" alt="BRD table" width="1014" height="650"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, GMRD need to beat MBD on Saturday - that's a pre-requisite if GMRD want a play-off place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regardless of what flavour that victory lollipop is, the Irn Brn need to be sucking on it by Saturday evening.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Skelpies win against the Invaders then victory of any variety will be enough for the Glasgow mob.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if the Invaders win &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; GMRD win then the three top teams will be tied on six points and it goes down to scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD would need to have a better points differential than MBD to qualify for the play-offs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't worry about crunching the numbers, SRD Blog has done it for you - &lt;strong&gt;GMRD need to beat MBD by over 123 points to be certain of a play-off place.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That isn't going to be any kind of easy as MBD have already beaten both the Skelpies and the Skate Invaders this season, the latter with just 6 players!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's why Hugs &amp;amp; Kisses - GMRD's President - is sounding the rallying horn to the Irn Brn faithful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We need everyone in the West of Scotland and beyond to come out and support Saturday's double-header," he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-20254" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/18768309_10209728094985432_4231219290125343973_o.jpg" alt="18768309_10209728094985432_4231219290125343973_o" width="1600" height="1067"&gt; The Irn Brn - photo by Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"This is an amazing first for our city - a British Champs men's game at the home of Glasgow derby, the ARC sportscentre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"You are going to see two gallus games of roller derby, with the fate of three teams hanging in the balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Come out and support the Irn Brn as we attempt the great escape. We're confident we can put on a great show - don't stop believing, ken?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* Doors open at the ARC sportscentre, Glasgow, on Saturday (10 June) at 11.30am. Tickets cost £7. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/133440747209468/?acontext=%7B%22ref%22%3A%222%22%2C%22ref_dashboard_filter%22%3A%22upcoming%22%2C%22action_history%22%3A%22%5B%7B%5C%22surface%5C%22%3A%5C%22dashboard%5C%22%2C%5C%22mechanism%5C%22%3A%5C%22main_list%5C%22%2C%5C%22extra_data%5C%22%3A%5B%5D%7D%5D%22%7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Click here for more information.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teeside Skate Invaders vs Bairn City Skelpies - first whistle at 11:45&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby vs Men Behaving Derby - first whistle at 2pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>men behaving derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>teeside skate invaders</category><category>the skelpies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/06/glasgow-ready-to-rock-as-british-champs-t3-goes-down-to-the-wire/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 16:02:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bairn City's co-ed bout to celebrate their 4th birthday</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/05/bairn-citys-co-ed-bout-to-celebrate-their-4th-birthday/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bairn City Rollers became Scotland's first co-ed league back in 2012. Now as they approach their 4th birthday they are kicking of celebrations and ending their 2016 season in the best way they could, a co-ed game. Their opponents will be the Brawler Buddies, who are made up of skaters from &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/granitecitybrawlers/"&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GraniteCityRollerDerby/"&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/dundeerollergirls/"&gt;Dundee Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In change from the norm, there will be no advanced ticket sales for this event. Instead in celebration of their 4th birthday BCR are inviting spectators to pay what they want on the day. That's right, &lt;span class="_4n-j fsl"&gt;just turn up on the game and pay whatever you like.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game will take place at Grangemouth Sports Complex on Saturday the 15th of October, doors will be open from 2.15pm and first whistle will be at 2.40pm, for more information &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/527945357409228/"&gt;visit the event page here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/527945357409228/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-9205" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/bcr-banner.jpg?w=700" alt="bcr-banner" width="700" height="259"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bcr</category><category>central belters</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>grangemouth</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>skelpies</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/05/bairn-citys-co-ed-bout-to-celebrate-their-4th-birthday/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 19:38:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital City Host the Final SMRDN game of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/27/capital-city-host-the-final-smrdn-game-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year we saw the launch of the Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals (SMRDN), which saw Bairn City Rollers, Mean City and Capital City all fight for the bragging rights of being the top Scottish Men's team. With two games played and two wins to BCR's Skelpies they have taken the title of champions for this year. There is however still one more game left to play which is sure to be an exciting clash for more than one reason, which is Capital City vs Mean City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone wp-image-4863 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ccrd-banner-smrdfin.jpg?w=614" alt="ccrd-banner-smrdfin" width="614" height="227"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two teams have yet to met on track in a public game, with this their first encounter deciding who will take second place in this years SMRDN and the looser picking up 3rd and last place for 2015. With so much to play for, both teams will be fighting for every point from the first whistle to the last. And if this wasn't enough to tempt you along, Capital City have turned the event into a double header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get everyone ready for the main event, they are putting on a coed game first at which we will get to see some of the the Granite City Brawlermen in action for the first time as they join forces with some of the girls from Granite City Roller Girls as well as other guys and girls from the likes of Capital City, Mean City and Bairn City to form both of the coed teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This double header will take place at Meddowbank on Saturday the 19th of September, for more information visit the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/920630431323750/"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4864" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/ccrd-tall-smrdfin.jpg" alt="ccrd-tall-smrdfin" width="513" height="720"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>ccrd</category><category>coed</category><category>double header</category><category>granite city brawlermen</category><category>mcrd</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mens roller derby scotland</category><category>scottish men's roller derby nationals</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><category>smrdn</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/27/capital-city-host-the-final-smrdn-game-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 11:21:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BCR Skelpies vs CCRD Mighty Unicorns February 28th 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/02/02/bcr-skelpies-vs-ccrd-mighty-unicorns-february-28th-2015/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There has been a big buzz surrounding the British Roller Derby Champs which kicked off recently and grew out of the heartlands series. Many of the skaters from leagues taking part are now eagerly awaiting their first game in what is Europe's largest Roller Derby tournament, comprising 72 women’s leagues from England, Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland. Along with 10 men's leagues also competing in the men's side of the tournament. With all this going on you may be fooled into thinking that this is the next big new competition for women's and men’s derby, and you may be right. But here in Scotland we now have something new and very exciting to look forward to with our men's derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a considerable amount of discussions between Scottish Men's Derby Leagues over the last couple of years, there will be a brand new tournament taking place this year. The 28th of February 2015 will go down in Scottish derby history as the opening day and first ever game of the newly created &lt;a title="A run down on the Scottish Men’s Roller Derby League/Scottish Men’s Roller Derby (SMRD) Nationals" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/01/10/a-run-down-on-the-scottish-mens-roller-derby-nationals/"&gt;Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals (SMRDNs)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1528686777405809/"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4545 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/bout-bcr-vs-ccrd-280215.jpg?w=614" alt="Poster by Cara Scott (Beatrix Slaughter of BCR)" width="614" height="515"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Poster by Cara Scott (Beatrix Slaughter of BCR)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bairn City Rollers have the honor of hosting the first of the three games being played this year as part of the SMRDNs. This game will take place at Grangemouth Sports Complex on Saturday the 28th of February, doors are at 3pm and &lt;a href="http://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/skelpies-vs-capital-city-roller-derby-tickets-15110714554"&gt;tickets are now available online&lt;/a&gt;. For more information on this visit the event page over on Facebook here: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1528686777405809/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1528686777405809/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital City are a relatively new bouting team having played their first ever game in November of last year, whilst BCR have been bouting since 2013 and have six public bouts to their name.  It may be hard to believe, but this game will be only the second time that two Scottish Men's derby teams have played each other in a public bout. Out of all the three bouting Scottish men's leagues, only BCR and Mean City have played each other in a public bout. That encounter ended with BCR taking the win and the bragging rights.  So come the 28th, BCR will be making sure they will do everything possible to extend that undefeated run against Scottish men's derby opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both sides are expecting it to be an explosive encounter and great inaugural game for the SMRDNs. As starting with a win, will be the best way to be crowned the 2015 SMRDN champions, because both teams will only have 1 more SMRDN game to play this year. After the 28th, the two remaining games will be Mean City vs BCR and the East vs West line up of Capital City v Mean City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With it being the first game in the newly created SMRDNs there has been a lot of excitement and interest in the game and if BCR Skater Archibald Wreck would have us believe there has been a furore of excitement in Russia and Japan since the game was announced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/japan.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4546" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/japan.jpg?w=614" alt="BCR VS CCRD Advert in Japan" width="708" height="408"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image by Archibald Wreck (Graeme McPhail) of BCR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/russia.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4547" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/01/russia.jpg" alt="BCR VS CCRD Advert in Russia" width="707" height="466"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image by Archibald Wreck (Graeme McPhail) of BCR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bcr</category><category>capital city</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>ccrd</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby edinburgh</category><category>men's roller derby falkirk</category><category>mighty unicrons</category><category>scottish men's roller derby nationals</category><category>scottish mens roller derby</category><category>skelpies</category><category>smrdn</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/02/02/bcr-skelpies-vs-ccrd-mighty-unicorns-february-28th-2015/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 12:39:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>HIS-STORY IN THE MAKING FOR SCOTTISH ROLLER DERBY </title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/06/his-story-in-the-making-for-scottish-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/skelpies.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3135" alt="Skelpies vs. Mean City Roller Derby" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/01/skelpies.png" width="614" height="217"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Skelpies vs. Mean City Roller Derby - Image courtesy of Bairn City Rollers
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A guest post, written by journalist - and skater - Alan Muir.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SPORTING history will be made this month when two teams of home-grown heroes go skate to skate on the roller derby track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow's very own &lt;a title="Mean City Roller Derby on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby" target="_blank"&gt;Mean City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; will be taking on Falkirk's &lt;a title="Bairn City Rollers on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers" target="_blank"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; during an all-action bout in Grangemouth on Saturday, January 25. It will be the first time two men’s roller derby leagues in Scotland have gone head to head - with a rip-roaring day of reckoning in the offing. It's set to be a pulsating and punishing clash - showcasing a sensational sport which is sweeping Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Players from both leagues have been selected to represent their country's national team - &lt;a title="Power of Scotland on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland" target="_blank"&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/a&gt; - at the &lt;a title="MRDWC Website" href="http://mrdwc.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; in Birmingham this March. And Mean City also boast two of the most experienced skaters currently playing roller derby - Jason Crawford and Jim Whyte - who together have played in more than 40 bouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City are keen to start the New Year with a resounding victory over the Bairns' men's team - the Skelpies. Mean City Chairman and founder BruiseDog - aka Jason Crawford - said: "We're delighted to be helping to make history with our good friends and rivals from Bairn City Rollers. The Skelpies will be determined to get one over on Mean City, but we aim to beat the Bairns in their backyard. We hope our army of fans will be out in numbers for this very special, historic occasion. It promises to be an amazing advert for an awesome sport. Roller derby is fast-paced, skilful, athletic and all-action - offering a thrilling day out for all the family. Come and enjoy a sport that really has to be seen to be believed."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain and co-founder of the Skelpies, iHorror - aka Anthony Sweeney - said: "We can't wait to make history on January 25 and we want as many people are possible to come along and support their local team. Get your tickets now for what is sure to be a bruising, all-action bout. We will sell you a whole seat, but you won't need it - you'll be perched on the edge of it for the full 60 minutes."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skelpies vs. Mean City takes place on Saturday, January 25, at 2.30pm in Grangemouth Sports Complex, Abbots Road, Grangemouth. Tickets cost just £4. Visit the &lt;a title="Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby - which formed in 2012 - is the first male league in the West of Scotland and is the brother league to the all-female, all-conquering Glasgow Roller Derby. If you would like to join Mean City - male or female - as long as you're over 18 and ready for a new challenge this is your chance. Visit their &lt;a title="Mean City on Facebook" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/06/his-story-in-the-making-for-scottish-roller-derby/www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Page &lt;/a&gt;for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bairn City Rollers are Scotland's first - and so far only - co-ed roller derby league, meaning they have male and female skaters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>the skelpies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/01/06/his-story-in-the-making-for-scottish-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 21:18:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lets hear it for the boys!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/08/lets-hear-it-for-the-boys/</link><dc:creator>thejammingpony</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A female perspective on Merby and CO-ED Roller Derby.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until the past couple of years Roller Derby has been a sport ‘rolled’ out on a predominantly female playing field. There have always been men around, be it in an official capacity or those of the infamous derby widow - ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However those who wished to play on a competitive level have taken the proverbial bull by the horns with Merby leagues are popping up all over the UK. Scotland in Particular has no less than 4 up and coming all male leagues. Their collective bouting team the Jakey Bites have been established for over a year now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arrival of Men’s Roller Derby has been met with mixed reaction on roller derby scene, some embracing it fully and others feeling a little put out that the male specimen are perhaps trying to steal our feminine thunder………God can’t they let us have anything!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being part of a league who have taken to Integrating with open arms, I have had a fantastic opportunity to skate and compete with the some of the Jakey Bites in the past year, skating in the Uk’s first ever CO-ED derby bout with The Jakey Tayzers last September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result I have become a keen supporter for CO-ED and men’s roller derby. The thought of this might seem a bit overwhelming for some but I believe it can make you a more rounded and skilled skater in the long run. I have skated for 2 years now, predominantly in all female training and bout situations and I thought I would take this opportunity to answer some of the questions or allay some of the fears people might have about Male and Co-Ed roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;DO THEY HIT HARDER?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate to emasculate anyone here but the answer to this is not really. I have found that taking a hit from a guy is no different from being hit by the girls. The fact that they don’t really have hips takes a bit of getting used to but the impact of the hit isn't as scary as it might seem.  Put it this way, if you have ever been hit by Cider from Auld Reekie then you have nothing to worry about and are fully prepared…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;ARE THEIR TACTICS DIFFERENT?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever we first started training for the CO – ED bout this was definitely one of our questions, in all honesty we thought for some reason they were going to be all offence and no discipline (not sure why, guess we were stereotyping). This wasn't the case at all; for the most part their tactics are exactly the same as what we are doing on the female side of things. They are definitely very skilled and know their stuff; I didn't find it any different from skating with my female team mates. They have had to adjust to the new rule set exactly the same as we have. From watching various Merby bouts last year there really wasn't much difference in the tactics played and there certainly wasn't any less glitter surprisingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;IS IT AWKWARD?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we all know, roller derby can be a very 'handsy' sport, it is full contact and I suppose it would be normal to wonder if it gets a bit awkward when playing CO-ED. This one is really in the eyes of the beholder to be honest, I personally haven’t ever felt awkward or anything likes that whilst skating. Whether that comes from knowing them quite well or from being in the zone on track I’m not sure but it certainly has never been an issue. You know the bond you have with your team mates on track, well that bond is completely possible in CO-ED as well and it is a pretty gratifying experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;ARE THEY BETTER THAN US?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer to this hangs on the word better; it’s not so much a case of better as different. Roller derby caters for differences; it’s one of the most appealing aspects of the sport which is known for celebrating individuality. In some cases they may be a little stronger and taller than us but……being a big player or a hard hitter isn't the be all and end all if you are smaller and faster. In truth they are as varied and unique as we are on the female side of things. Tall, small, fast, strong, hard-hitting, positional and/or agile everyone has strength it's just finding out how they compliment each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;ARE THEY JUST A BUNCH OF “LADS?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cracking dirty jokes and messing around? As for the dirty jokes I know some female skaters who could make them blush……….But in all seriousness the answer here is no. They are 100% dedicated to the sport and the progression of their regional leagues, the passion they have for the sport is no less than we have in the female leagues and the drive they have shown in starting from scratch has been nothing short of impressive. As a female skater they have always been nothing less than welcoming and supportive of me and since skating with them I have seen a real improvement in certain areas of my skating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a personal perspective I am fully in support of Merby in the UK. I would urge everyone to support their local Merby league alongside their local derby league, Capital City in Edinburgh, Mean City in Glasgow, The Skelpies in the Central Belt and The Tayminators in Tayside. I have had the pleasure of knowing people from most of these teams and can tell you they are a cracking bunch of guys, we should be proud to have them as a part of the Scottish Roller Derby scene. I hope to see a lot more CO-ED action in the future with my Jakey Tayzers. The Skelpies League, Bairn City are already establishing a Co -Ed league so it is onward and upward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to make up your own mind or have a male friend you’d like to wrangle into taking up the sport, the Jakey Bites (Comprising of members from 3 out of 4 of the aforementioned teams) have a bout coming up against The South Wales Silures on April the 6&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; in Grangemouth. Check their Facebook page for event details and ticket sales. The venue only holds 100 so buy in advance to avoid disappointment. Bairn City men’s team will also be playing South Wales the day after on the 7&lt;sup&gt;th &lt;/sup&gt;at the same venue, for more details and ticket sales check their Facebook pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.facebook.com/events/122071404642449/      (SKELPIES VS. SILURES)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.facebook.com/events/432929060108875/     (JAKEYS VS. SILURES)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a title="Jakeys VS. Silures" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/522492_342652352503139_928642489_n.png"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-2291 aligncenter" alt="522492_342652352503139_928642489_n" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/522492_342652352503139_928642489_n.png" width="506" height="567"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/10889_619537551396047_724006372_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-2292 aligncenter" alt="10889_619537551396047_724006372_n" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/10889_619537551396047_724006372_n.jpg?w=211" width="506" height="567"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>image</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>merby</category><category>roller derby</category><category>the jakey bites</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>the tayminators</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/08/lets-hear-it-for-the-boys/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 16:57:25 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>