<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about tiger bay brawlers)</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/tiger-bay-brawlers.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:54:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Europe's First Continental Cup: the UK's next International Derby fixture in 2018</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/04/europes-first-continental-cup-the-uks-next-international-derby-fixture-in-2018/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By any account, 2018 has been a very good year for Roller Derby's international profile, in both Europe and the UK. From the third Roller Derby World Cup in Manchester this February, and the third Men's Roller Derby World Cup in Barcelona a few months later, we've gone on to host an MRDA Playoffs, in Halifax/hosted by Manchester Roller Derby, and a WFTDA Playoffs, in A Coruña.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pendulum is, inevitably, swinging back again from Spain to the UK, with the last event in this sequence: the first ever &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wftdaecc2018.com/"&gt;European WFTDA Continental Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, bringing up the rear in this inaugural year for the new format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the MRDA Playoffs (hosted by Manchester, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; Halifax), this is hosted by Birmingham Blitz Dames, but physically &lt;i&gt;located&lt;/i&gt; in Telford... but the hosts have done a lot to make the brand of the tournament their own. The distinctive diamond logo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-27531 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/blitzdamesdiamon.png" alt="BlitzDamesDiamon" width="245" height="240"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;has both a general connection to Birmingham's jewellery industry, and to the Blitz Dames themselves - and even references their ex-skater, goldsmith Isabella Day, who made the trophy for the tournament!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27532" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/continental_map_logos.png" alt="Continental_map_logos" width="1562" height="1070"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Continental Cups framework is a response to the increasing spread of Roller Derby, and particularly the increasingly global membership of WFTDA. With more than 400 member leagues, an ever decreasing fraction of travel teams can hope to compete in a WFTDA Playoffs (and travel costs become increasingly prohibitive if you just extend the cut-off for Playoffs, or extend the old Division 2). &lt;i&gt;Regional&lt;/i&gt; "Continental Cups" provide a WFTDA-certified tournament, for every region with enough teams, at a level just below that of Playoffs - but with much less travel costs. (Next year, there will also be a set of regional "Development Cups", providing a WFTDA-certified tournament option for regions who aren't competitive at the old "D2" level, with guest "seed" teams from more "connected" regions to help improve ranking accuracy.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe's Continental Cup, then, has a familiar set of teams (and countries) represented (order from WFTDA announcement):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Kallio Rolling Rainbow (Finland)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dublin Roller Derby (Ireland)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dock City Rollers (Sweden)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers (Wales)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Central City Roller Derby (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby (England)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
The current FTS Europe rankings (which include a different subset of games to WFTDA rankings; excluding games against teams outside Europe, but including unsanctioned games) disagree somewhat with this ordering - FTS thinks that some of these teams were strong enough to make Playoffs ahead of some of the European representation there! - but predict a rather close set of games, regardless. In fact, FTS currently rates the two "local" teams - hosts Birmingham Blitz Dames, and Central City Roller Derby - as being exceptionally close in strength - sadly, the bracket prevents them from meeting unless they both lose their first games, or meet in the final.
Similarly, FTS expects some surprisingly close matches in the first round of the elimination bracket, despite WFTDA's usual slaughter pairing setup: Kallio versus Middlesbrough should be a near-draw by European data; although WFTDA sanctioned ratings place Kallio much higher than the UK team. If you're playing the Bracket Challenge for this contest, that's your best chance for an early upset...
&lt;p&gt;Despite, or perhaps causing, of the possibility of so many upsets and ranking disparities, the European Continental Cup should continue the example of the two North American CCs, in having a higher than "usual" number of close bouts, despite the tendency of elimination tournaments to start with a round of blowouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bracket is available here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.wixstatic.com/ugd/590519_be81975ec1304fcf96b32590ddbe2d8a.pdf"&gt;BRACKET PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (note for those not in the UK - this event is on the weekend that the UK changes over from Daylight Savings Time, so be careful checking timings for the Sunday, in particular).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-27324" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/officials_eur_map.png?w=2048" alt="Officials_EUR_map" width="1024" height="768"&gt; Geographical distribution of European Officials at the ECC! Stars may represent more than one official from a given location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as for the competition, the Continental Cup is also a great chance for more representation for our highly skilled European Officiating community. Just at the Tournament and Crew Head levels, we have officials from Karlsruhe, Newcastle, Dublin, Nottingham, Paris/Lutece, London/Southern Discomfort, (and Michigan...) - including all of the other crew positions adds (deep breath) Amsterdam, Antwerp, Bath, Belfast, Birmingham, Brussels, Cambridge, Cardiff, Chelmsford, Copenhagen, Darmstadt, Devon, Dresden, Dundee, Essex, Falkirk, Frankfurt, Gothenburg, Kallio/Helsinki, Manchester, Metz, Mons, Nantes, Northampton, Oxford, Riems, Ruhrpott, Southend, Southampton, Vicenza, Vienna, Wiltshire, Wuppertal,  (and Rochester, NY; Monterrey County, CA; St Louis, MO; Boston, MA; USA... and Adelaide, SA, Australia)! Just as with the other international events in Europe this year, this kind of exposure, and opportunity to both officiate at a high level, and meet up with a wider-flung segment of the Derby Community is fantastic for Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not all, as there's also fantastic line-up of (mostly...) European announcers, from Head Announcer Biertrix (Rainy City Roller Derby), through a host of UK announcers from London through Manchester to Durham and Newcastle; and from Germany, Denmark, as well as the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, as with all WFTDA post-season events this year, there will be a genuine chance for all members of the community (WFTDA-members or no) to connect with WFTDA Membership via the co-hosted "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/772801099579539/"&gt;WFTDA World Summit Satellite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" event. We're very impressed by WFTDA's increased commitment to listening to the voices of the whole community, and would encourage the community to also make use of these opportunities in return: listening should be rewarded with dialogue. (On that note, WFTDA are also surveying every league which does derby and are not WFTDA-members - regardless of their gender policy etc - and we'd encourage everyone eligible to respond to this too, here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.org/surveys"&gt;WFTDA.org/surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The European Continental Cup will run from &lt;strong&gt;October 27th to October 28th&lt;/strong&gt; at The International Centre, Telford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WFTDA Continental Cup page: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/events/wftda-continental-cups/"&gt;https://wftda.com/events/wftda-continental-cups/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Facebook Event for European Continental Cup: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>birmingham blitz dames</category><category>central city roller derby</category><category>continental cup</category><category>dock city rollers</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>kallio rolling rainbow</category><category>middlesbrough roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>tournament</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/04/europes-first-continental-cup-the-uks-next-international-derby-fixture-in-2018/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 15:54:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash 2018: Newcastle Roller Girls' tournament expands beyond the "Euro".</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/26/euroclash-2018-newcastle-roller-girls-tournament-expands-beyond-the-euro/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Readers of the blog will remember our coverage of Newcastle Roller Girls' first European Tournament, &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/365884340424845/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, back in 2017. Newcastle's first WFTDA Recognised Tournament brought together teams across Europe for some high level action, and prefigured performances as far ahead as WFTDA Playoffs; as well as presenting a sneak peak at two of the National teams (Scotland and Ireland) as they worked towards the 3rd Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the ridiculously tournament-filled start of this year has delayed us, we're also going to be bringing you as much coverage as we can of the return of EuroClash this year... although, given one of the attendees this time, the tournament has already outgrown its name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this initial article, we're just going to introduce you to the competitors, and their current placements in the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst 2018's edition is slightly smaller than 2017's - 9 attendees (6 returning from last time), rather than 11 - their geographic distribution is &lt;em&gt;substantially&lt;/em&gt; wider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning from 2017's inaugural event are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls (hosts)
Auld Reekie Roller Girls (soon to &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/25/auld-reekies-10-anniversary-rebrand-with-your-help/"&gt;rebrand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; to Auld Reekie Roller Derby) [Edinburgh]
Central City Roller Derby (competed last year as Central City Rollergirls) [Birmingham]
Dublin Roller Derby
Middlesbrough Roller Derby (EuroClash2017 was their first fixture after rebranding)
Tiger Bay Brawlers [Cardiff]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joining them to make up the full nine are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames
Dock City Roller Derby [Gothenburg]
Steel City Roller Derby [Pittsburgh]!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-26639" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/euroclash2018.png?w=2048" alt="EuroClash2018" width="1024" height="768"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, EuroClash served as the first step for several of the attending teams' campaigns to get into WFTDA Playoffs - Auld Reekie, Bear City, Paris and Dublin all gaining valuable ranking points from their attendance, as all bouts are WFTDA Sanctioned games.
Whilst EuroClash itself is not arranged to provide a final ranking, or a tournament cup, we did analyse the tournament itself &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Our analysis was good enough to predict the results of Paris Rollergirls' subsequent two games against other attendees, so it's probably as good as any other attempt at rating the teams...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since last year, the returning teams have played a lot of Roller Derby, with varying stories; so we can expect some changes in the matchups this time around. [We're using the FTS "WFTDA" ratings here, as not all the teams can be rated with the usually-more-accurate Europe ratings.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the time of writing, the attending EuroClash 2018 teams span a 41 position zone within FTS's rankings - but a fairly closely rated one. (FTS's built in predictor tool expects only a 2:1 score ratio between the highest rated - Dublin - and lowest rated - Auld Reekie - teams if they played today.) We've also included, in parenthesis, the WFTDA Official ratings and rankings for the teams - despite the different ordering, the "range" in strengths is about the same for WFTDA's own ratings, perhaps slightly larger.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="3" rowspan="1"&gt;FTS "WFTDA" Ratings 23 April 2018 (WFTDA Rating 31 March)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rank&lt;/strong&gt; (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Rating (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;53&lt;/strong&gt; (46)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7775/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;745.2 (391.51)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;62&lt;/strong&gt; (65)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/29732/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dock City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;732.4 (318.9)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;63&lt;/strong&gt; (68)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7948/rankings/wftda"&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;729.4 (307.57)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;70&lt;/strong&gt; (94)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7763/rankings/wftda"&gt;Central City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;713.3 (242.58)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;83&lt;/strong&gt; (62)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7949/rankings/wftda"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;691.7 (323.67)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;86&lt;/strong&gt; (95)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/3417/rankings/wftda"&gt;Steel City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;683.0 (241.15)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;88&lt;/strong&gt; (88)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7736/rankings/wftda"&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;682.2 (259.63)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;93&lt;/strong&gt; (85)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7953/rankings/wftda"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;676.0 (262.62)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;94&lt;/strong&gt; (87)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/5912/rankings/wftda"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;674.9 (259.86)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
Auld Reekie and Middlesbrough both suffered ratings reductions against 2x4 Roller Derby during the latter's Jan-Feb tour of Europe, where the Argentine team outperformed expectations against almost &lt;i&gt;everyone&lt;/i&gt;. The jury is out as to how much of this is due to 2x4's general under-ranking, and how much is due to over-ranking of the teams they played - in general, we'd expect better-than-ranking performances from both teams at EuroClash.
Middlesbrough could potentially surprise the current #1 seeds, Dublin; the gap between their WFTDA ratings is entirely due to that loss to the under-ranked 2x4, and their European rating, by comparison, places them above the Irish team (and only just below Paris)!
Similarly, Auld Reekie's European rating places them in the middle of the field, rather than at the bottom, although their trajectory is in the same direction - however, some of this is due to their bout against Leeds Roller Derby, who are almost certainly under-ranked at this point in the year.
&lt;p&gt;Hosts Newcastle have also had difficult bouts, against EuroClash 2017 returnees Central City Roller Derby - given CCR's stronger-than-previous performance against other recent opponents, we consider this to be more of a reflection on CCR than Newcastle - and Leeds Roller Derby (who, again, are simply improving themselves, as they knit together as a team after their first year). We suspect Newcastle are somewhat underranked due to their choice of opponents, and as the hosts they'll be wanting to show that at EuroClash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remaining steady, Tiger Bay Brawlers have still had a pretty good year - and even their recent loss to Central City is not a bad sign, as their performance was near identical to that at EuroClash 2017; if CCR show signs of being back on the up, then this is actually good for the Cardiff team too. The recent transfer of Kid Block back to TBB from London can only improve their strength further - we expect strong performances from the team, beyond what their current rating implies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dublin Roller Derby have also had a pretty good 2017, continuing their upward trend in the FTS European ratings, and remaining steady in the WFTDA rating. Their current placement at the top of EuroClash 2018's rankings seems solid, barring improvements from Dock City, or Middlesbrough. This could all change this weekend, however, as Dublin play some competitive sanctioned games over in the USA at Southern Discomfort 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also remaining steady for the past year, Steel City Roller Derby - after losing around 100 rating points in 2016, the team had a very stable 2017, sticking around the 680-690 rating they still reside at entering EuroClash. A return to their 2016 high would make them easily the strongest team in the tournament, but we suspect their middle-table ranking is more likely, especially given the effects of trans-Atlantic travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gothenburg's second league, Dock City Rollers, continued their generally upwards climb over 2017 (and 2016), and show no particular signs of stopping this progress in WFTDA bouts. They're one of two teams which could challenge expected #1, Dublin if they play against them. Looking at the more plentiful data in the European FTS rankings, they've suffered a "correction" to their ranking as a result of their performance in last year's Swedish national tournament, but their trend is still upward - if we believe the European values, however, they'll be better matched against Auld Reekie than Dublin's finest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representing Birmingham, we have both Birmingham Blitz Dames and Central City Roller Derby, and both seeing upwards movement in the rankings over the past year - Central City in the past month or two, and BBD earlier in 2017 - although the more detailed European ratings show signs of a correction in the Blitz Dames rating at the start of this year, albeit again against the probably-underranked Leeds Roller Derby.  We'll see if the Blitz Dames still have more rating gains to come in the WFTDA rating, as they play in the 2018 K Town Shakedown this weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be back with some more articles, and a guide to the schedule when its published, closer to the event...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash 2018&lt;/a&gt; will be hosted at the &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/6NHQpKxP5Em"&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; on the &lt;b&gt;19th&lt;/b&gt; and&lt;b&gt; 20th May&lt;/b&gt; 2018 - less than a month away! Tickets are on sale, for &lt;b&gt;£30&lt;/b&gt; in advance (£35 on the door), or at a limited special group discount price of&lt;b&gt; £100 for 4&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>birmingham blitz dames</category><category>central city roller derby</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>dock city rollers</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>euroclash</category><category>middlesbrough roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>steel city roller derby</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/26/euroclash-2018-newcastle-roller-girls-tournament-expands-beyond-the-euro/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 13:04:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash Interviews: Tiger Bay Brawlers</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/07/euroclash-interviews-tiger-bay-brawlers/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As readers will be aware, we're quite excited about &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/newcastlerollergirls/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;' International Derby Tournament;  &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt; (25,26th March)&lt;/strong&gt;. So, we're running a series of interviews with all the attending teams to learn more about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, we're covering Wales' entry to the tournament, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tigerbaybrawlers.com/"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (who were also one of the first teams we ever interviewed for an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/26/brave-new-faces-the-writers-cut/"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, 6 years ago). TBB are certainly the strongest league in Wales, ranked #75 in the WFTDA rankings (they've been a member since 2013), and #16 in Europe by Flat Track Stats. They are also, understandably, a significant contributor of skaters to the Team Wales roster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Brawlers were an early adopter of international derby - attending the 2013 SKOD, and the 2014 ECDX in the USA - as well as the first season of British Championships in the Premier division. However, they had a relatively quiet 2016, track-time wise, for reasons we'll get into below...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13735 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tigerbay.jpg" alt="tigerbay" width="200" height="183"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers Captains, Thrill Collins and Steph Howarth, the former also a Team Wales rostered skater, gave us some insight into the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers had a short season in 2016, thanks to the significant threat of your usual venue being closed, and the effort to find a new one or save the existing venue. Despite this, you managed to fit in quite a lot of Derby into the first half of the year. What were your high points? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The campaign to save our training venue certainly took a lot of time and effort towards the end of last year, and still does now. It's frustrating that so many teams struggle to find a permanent venue to train in. We won't let that take the shine off last year though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Playing Crime City in Sweden was certainly a highlight. We really came together as a team. It was a huge test of everything we'd been working on and we felt like we rose to the challenge. We came away from that weekend feeling incredibly proud of our achievements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Unlike a lot of the competitors at EuroClash, TBB didn't fly across to the USA to play American teams (and work on their WFTDA rankings). Was this a conscious choice (it doesn't seem to have harmed your rankings much - you started 2016 at 93rd, and ended it in 75th place!)? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, it was very much a conscious choice. We've travelled to America twice over the last few years and it's placed a big financial burden on the team. On top of that, it's not easy to commit to long trips away if you have family or work commitments, like many Brawlers do. So we wanted to plan a season that avoided people having to make those difficult life vs roller derby decisions as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European roller derby has come a long way over the last few years so we decided to test ourselves against our Euro sisters in 2016 instead. It was good to show that you can still make progress in the WFTDA rankings without having to almost bankrupt yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;During and after EuroClash, Tiger Bay Brawlers have returned to British Champs, competing in the Premier Tier once more (and against two other EuroClash attendees) - what are your aims for this year's Champs? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our aim is to enjoy it! We want our teamwork and unity to shine through on track in every game that we play (cheesy, but true).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're really pleased that British Champs gives us the opportunity to play more UK-based games this year. We'll have games at home and some just over the Severn Bridge in Bristol. All too often, roller derby takes us far away from Cardiff, so it's great that our fans have got more chances to see us play closer to home this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As with the previous Team Wales, Tiger Bay Brawlers have contributed a significant number of skaters to the 2017/8 Roster. How does it feel to be such a big part of your national team, especially when their performance so far has been striking? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re so proud of all our skaters that are representing Team Wales in the current training squad. There’s such a massive pool of talent in the Welsh squad and it’s great to see how far roller derby in Wales has come these last few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also a great way for us to strengthen our links with other local teams so we can learn from each other and continue to push Welsh roller derby to the forefront of the UK derby scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With so many great teams attending EuroClash, which are you most looking forward to competing against (and have you been specifically training against their tactics)? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've never played Paris before, so we're definitely looking forward to that one. We saw some of them in action in the French national team recently at the Road to TBC tournament in Cardiff. They look in great form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're doing our research on them, obviously, but we train to play the best version of our game, not our opponent’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, in the downtime between bouts, you'll be having lots of time to watch the remaining teams - who are you most looking forward to watching?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many great games lined up that weekend, I honestly couldn't choose! It's a real testament to the quality and competitiveness of European roller derby right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re really excited to see what Leeds have to offer this year too. With such a big change to their line up after their merger I think they’ll be a force to be reckoned with this season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, what else is in Tiger Bay Brawlers' future?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can't wait to kick off our season on 26 February with the first round of British Champs. It's a home game too, so we're hoping for a great crowd at what might be our last game in our current venue (sniff).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're really focused on growing the league this year and welcoming more women to roller derby. We've been running an excellent beginners programme since May last year, which we'd like to build on in 2017. It's already produced game-ready skaters so we're looking for opportunities to get them some experience on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help with this, we've done something a bit different - we've set up a Tiger Bay challenge team. It's open to everyone in Tiger Bay as not only do we want to give our newer skaters some game experience, we also want to give them the chance to play side-by-side with our more experienced skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're reading this and you'd like to play our challenge team, then get in touch!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>euroclash</category><category>interviews</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/07/euroclash-interviews-tiger-bay-brawlers/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 10:55:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash 2017 - The Teams</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/12/euroclash-2017-the-teams/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;When Newcastle Roller Girls announced their intent to host a women's derby equivalent of the Men's European Cup (hosted by their sibling league, Tyne and Fear), there was understandable excitement... but the hosts have been remarkably secretive about the leagues involved, with the only hints being that the attendees were amongst the best teams in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Now, finally, the roster of competitors is announced, so we've made this quick guide to the teams (and will have individual features later on). EuroClash will be March 25th to 26th, at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Walker+Activity+Dome/@54.968707,-1.558266,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487e7068944e76d1:0xe1a6394d9f25325!8m2!3d54.968707!4d-1.556072"&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Newcastle. Tickets available &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.org.uk/buy-tickets/euroclash-2017"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-13774" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/euroclash.jpg" alt="euroclash" width="851" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, who are the teams competing in the first ever &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/365884340424845/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13711 alignleft" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/newcastlerg_1.png" alt="newcastlerg_1" width="122" height="250"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Starting with the hosts, we have &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;. British Championships 2016 Premier Tier Winners, and currently ranked 76th by WFTDA (13th in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/europe"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and 13th by &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;*), the Canny Belters have had a strong 2016 - competing in the USA for the first time, at Beach Brawl in Florida (losing only to the mighty Rainy City) almost immediately after taking that British Championships win. In fact, the Belters have only lost to two teams in the last year - Rainy City and Edinburgh's Auld Reekie (who they also defeated in a rematch). As the hosts, home team advantage will also help their performance, and it would be a mistake to underestimate their chances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13716 alignleft" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/leedsrollerderby-09.jpg" alt="leedsrollerderby-09" width="200" height="200"&gt;Staying within the UK, &lt;strong&gt;Leeds Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; are "technically" a new league, formed by merger of Hot Wheel Roller Derby and Leeds Roller Dolls at the end of 2016. Leeds Roller Dolls were ranked 65th by WFTDA, and their European Rankings were 23rd FTS, 22 SRD Rank; whilst Hot Wheel had Euro rankings of 31 and 25 respectively. We &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/19/by-their-powers-combined-they-are-leeds-roller-derby/"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on their merger at the time, and are excited to see what the combined pool of talent can accomplish in a single roster. Leeds Roller Dolls had their second trip to the USA in 2016, performing significantly above expectations; after placing solidly in the middle of the Champs Premier Tier rankings. Hot Wheel, by contrast, played their first European tournament in 2016, attending A Skate Odyssey, where they met surpassed expectations (beating their seeding by 4 places); they also managed to come second-from-top in British Champs Tier 2, clearly on the up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13765 alignleft" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/mmr1.jpg" alt="mmr" width="222" height="200"&gt;Middlesbrough Milk Rollers&lt;/strong&gt; are possibly the highest ranked English team attending Euro Clash, with an impressive 56th position on the WFTDA rankings (9th in Europe by FTS, and 4th by SRD Rank)! MMR declined to participate in British Champs in 2016, but had an absolutely impressive year of competition, defeating almost all comers (including Connecticut and New Jersey) despite playing away for each and every bout. The only team to defeat them was London B, the Brawl Saints, which is not a bad record at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13730 alignleft" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/central-city.png" alt="central-city" width="200" height="200"&gt;Central City Rollergirls&lt;/strong&gt; are the 83rd WFTDA ranked team (16th in Europe by SRD, and 20th by FTS), and one of the first Roller Derby leagues in the UK, representing Birmingham. CCR are the second team in this list to have spent their 2016 breaking into the USA via Beach Brawl, where they won more than they lost. They also defeated London B earlier on in the year, still a rare accomplishment for a UK team. The Birmingham team had quite a quiet year by comparison with the hectic adventures of some of the others in this list, and will have a lot of energy for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13735 alignleft" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tigerbay.jpg" alt="tigerbay" width="200" height="183"&gt;Moving outside England, Wales' &lt;strong&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/strong&gt; are the best that their country has, ranked 75th by WFTDA (14th FTS, 12th SRD Rank in Europe). Declining to compete in British Champs in 2016, TBB instead competed against a wide range of European opponents, defeating London B, but narrowly failing against the mighty Rainy City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;After a lull in 2015, the general feeling is that Cardiff's all-stars have regained their best performance and are ready to go further in 2017; they're also a strong component of the current, and very strong, Welsh National Team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13740 alignleft" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/arrg-logo.png" alt="arrg-logo" width="200" height="89"&gt;And representing the northern part of the UK, Edinburgh's &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; are the strongest team in Scotland, placing 60th in WFTDA (16th FTS, 20th SRD Rank in Europe). Auld Reekie made some waves last year by declining the offer to compete in WFTDA Playoffs, using the time to work more on their own performance - and they also declined British Champs 2016 as well. They did spend some time in the USA earlier in the year, competing at The Big O 2016, but had perhaps a more impressive start to 2016 where they defeated both our hosts Newcastle and Ireland's finest, Dublin. They'll be wanting to recapture that energy for the start of 2017... and will have a boost from their significant presence in the Team Scotland training squad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;For our remaining teams, we have to head outside the UK, so by distance, we first have...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13744 alignleft" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/drd-logo.png" alt="drd-logo" width="200" height="213"&gt;...&lt;strong&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;, ranked 86th by WFTDA (but 11th in Europe by FTS and SRD Rank). Dublin have had a very exciting 2016, playing their first bouts in the USA at (yes!) Beach Brawl and winning against everyone except Newcastle Roller Girls! This performance didn't slow them down at all, as they also had one of the busiest schedules of 2016 as well, playing 15 bouts over the year, 10 of them away! With strong representation in Team Ireland, the Dublin team is definitely a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13749 alignleft" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/paris.png" alt="paris" width="200" height="200"&gt;Moving a little further into Europe, &lt;strong&gt;Paris Rollergirls&lt;/strong&gt; are one of the two most exciting teams in France, ranked 71st by WFTDA, but 8th (or 9th) in Europe by FTS (SRD Rank). Hotly tipped for greatness in 2017 by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://thederbyapex.com/trending-french-roller-derby-56c5e691b036"&gt;The Derby Apex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the potential strength of Paris is also reflected in the performance of the French National Team, which they are a significant contributor to - Equipe de France is yet to lose a game with their current roster! Paris also burst onto the USA scene in 2016 at... (you've guessed it!) Beach Brawl, losing only the single bout. Much of the rest of their busy 2016 schedule was consumed by the French Nationale Elite Tier, which they topped, winning each and every bout in the 2015/6 season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13756 alignleft" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/bcrd-bear-city-roller-derby_0.png" alt="bcrd-bear-city-roller-derby_0" width="200" height="200"&gt;From Berlin, Germany, &lt;strong&gt;Bear City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; are also one of the older teams in Europe, established back in 2008 . Ranked 50th by WFTDA (and 12th in Europe by FTS, 14th by SRD Rank), the Berlin Bombshells are the only team in this competition to have competed in WFTDA (Division 2) Playoffs in 2016, placing a strong 5th out of the 10 competitors, and defeating 4th seed Cincinnati on the way. In fact, Bear City spent more time competing in the USA than anywhere else in 2016, as the majority of their remaining bouts were at the Midwest BrewHaHa, with only two bouts in Europe (against Kallio Rolling Rainbow and Glasgow Roller Derby). Whilst Bear City the league also won the German Nationals (the Bundesliga), we believe this was strictly an exhibition team which differed from BCRD's normal A roster...
EuroClash sees the Bombshells return to Europe to take on the other rising stars of the continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;But that's not all, as we also have the excitement of a National Teams bout as well!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13777 alignleft" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/ireland.jpg" alt="ireland" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13779 alignleft" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/scotland.png" alt="scotland" width="200" height="200"&gt;Teams &lt;strong&gt;Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; met at the Road to TBC in Cardiff this November, with the Irish taking the win... but neither team had finalised their roster at that point. This rematch is taking place after final selections for Team Scotland [their selection bout is February 11th], and the Scots will be keen to show what they can do with the team that will be heading to the World Cup in Manchester. Meanwhile, Team Ireland were exceptionally green at the Road to TBC, and they will be that much more experienced as a squad by March...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;We will be posting interviews with each of the teams competing at EuroClash over the next few weeks, to get into more depth about each of the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;* European rankings on SRD Rank computed from the set of all Women's Travel Teams in Europe known to the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bear city roller derby</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>euroclash</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>middlesbrough milk rollers</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>paris rollergirls</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/12/euroclash-2017-the-teams/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 19:15:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>"Brave New Faces" (The Writer's Cut)</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/01/26/brave-new-faces-the-writers-cut/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;An edited version of this article was published in Issue 2 (December 2011) of &lt;a href="http://www.insidelinemagazine.co.uk/"&gt;Inside Line Magazine&lt;/a&gt;. Reprinted with permission. Issue 3 of Inside Line will be on sale from March 1st.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Since this article was written, &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; have had their first (closed) bout, against Fair City Rollers' Fear Maidens, which Chasing Katy covered for the blog &lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2011/11/02/bout-report-fcr-fear-maidens-vs-fvrg-parma-violents-301011/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The final score was 170 FCR to 55 for FVRG. FVRG's first open bout is against Dundee Roller Girls' Silvery Tayzers on Feb 18th, in Dundee.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/yorkrollerderby"&gt;York Minxters&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://nastynessiesrollergirls.wordpress.com/"&gt;Nasty Nessies Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; are both still working towards being fully mins-passed and bout-ready. The Minxters have a weekly practise and an online blog from one member &lt;a href="http://www.oneandother.com/articles/diary-of-a-minxter-part-2/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, while the Nasty Nessies are gaining lots of attention in their local media.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="http://tigerbaybrawlers.com/"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/a&gt; are also going from strength to strength, having recently launched a junior league; while the &lt;a href="http://www.norfolkbrawds.com/"&gt;Norfolk Brawds&lt;/a&gt; have only this week relaunched a fantastic new website, and announced sponsorship from famous East Anglian rockers, The Darkness!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/team1-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-821" title="The Nasty Nessies!" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/team1-1.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since the roller derby revival in Texas, back in 2001, new leagues have been forming all over the world, perhaps especially in the UK. Now, with the increased exposure from the World Cup, and mainstream media starting to take an interest, the rate at which new leagues are incorporating is higher than ever.
Two such brand new leagues are the York Minxters, and Nasty Nessies Roller Girls, one of two Inverness-based leagues recently founded.
Fierce Valley Roller Girls, founded in the Forth Valley area of Scotland late last year, have been moving towards bouting standard ever since. Their first (closed) bout is imminent at the time of writing.
By contrast, the Tiger Bay Brawlers have been bouting for Cardiff since the start of the year, and the Norfolk Brawds since March.
I caught up with the leagues to try to get a good view of the process of becoming the next big thing in Roller Derby.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;There are many reasons you might have for starting a new league, rather than joining an existing one. Aby Falkingham founded the York Minxters with no knowledge of roller derby at all, drawn to the inclusive nature of the sport as exemplified by the London Roller Girls.
“It was something I was always interested in from buying tattoo magazines. I’d seen the London Roller Girls in the magazine, and I decided it was something I wanted to be part of. So, I found that there were teams in Leeds, Middlesborough, Manchester, but all of these were far away. So, I made it my mission to start a league in York…“
If distance was a factor for the Minxters, how much more for the Nasty Nessies: ”Try being 100+ miles from any of the other leagues and you'll soon understand why”, NNRG Secretary T-balls of Fire notes.
Whatever your reasons, making the choice to start a league is the easy bit.Once you’ve decided that you want to take on the challenge of creating a whole new roller derby league, you have to battle with all the problems of new skaters, as well as discovering what you’re supposed to be doing at the same time.
As well as potentially learning to skate, and learning the rules, there’s also the difficulty of finding practice space, getting word out to recruit fresh meat, and finding essential skilled roles in referees, coaches and the array of NSOs that every league needs to be successful, as well as the basic issue of funding.
&lt;p&gt;In many ways, it’s easier to face these challenges now than it was back in 2006 when London Rollergirls were just getting started. There’s a vast array of established UK leagues, all keen to help those starting out. Every league has nothing but praise for the support they received from the existing roller derby community. “I definitely could not have done it without them,” says Aby of the Leeds and Manchester leagues. “They came to our first session, and they’ve set us out a training plan to get all of us who haven’t skated before to a good level.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girls’ Cilla Block has been one of those helpful skaters for the Scottish leagues. “I think it can be quite daunting starting up, so ff there’s anything I can do to help, Scotland’s not all that big, you you’re only an hour or two away on the train. For Inverness, with [Irn-Bruzer, NNRG chair] at the moment, we’re looking at helping them with their mins.” She’s quick to note that even established leagues are always looking to improve, “Even now Dundee Roller Girls is always looking for people to come and help us, and I think it’s important for us to share that with other people as well.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even without being able to visit, the online roller derby community is a vital resource for information and advice. The Nasty Nessies are over 100 miles from their nearest league, but, according to Team Rep Cherry Bow “…the internet has been our life line! We have had support via Facebook, Twitter and emails from other leagues as well as individual skaters from as far afield as the USA...”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/dsc05260.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-824" title="SONY DSC" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/dsc05260.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="411"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to be a league, you have to have somewhere to skate. Practice space (and, later, a bouting venue) is often the first difficult problem that a new league faces. Many sports halls are reluctant to host skate-based sports, as they can mark the floors. One solution to this can be to find a hall that already hosts roller hockey; both the York Minxters and Dundee Roller Girls found their practice space by this method.
The first site is can often be the hardest, as Fierce Valley’s Grizabelta discovered: “As far as finding practice space goes, whilst we hit every obstacle we could to start with, once we'd been at Bo'ness a few months I wrote to all the other halls with a massive spiel about how great derby is (boosts self esteem, gets non-sporty types active, great camaraderie etc) and thankfully it worked!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paying for the space, and the equipment, can be a challenge, even for established leagues. Most set up a subscription fee for skaters, or practice sessions, and the community can be helpful in lending equipment at the outset.
Without access to funds from stalls at bouts themselves, however, sometimes you need to be more innovative. Fierce Valley recently held a concert as a fundraiser, and, as founder Kirk Jammett promises, they have plans for further action: “The novelty of the fundraisers tends to come from our own skaters' hobbies – we just try and sell what we're good at! Our next event is going to be a cabaret night!“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other advantage of big fundraisers is in spreading the word, although most leagues find that the enthusiasm of their members makes for the best medium.
Tiger Bay Brawlers’ Lola Coaster enthuses that “the majority of our advertising comes from word of mouth promotions through skaters and our friends and families and I think that’s where the roller derby community really shines. Those who do love it are so passionate about it and that passion is infectious, whether you’re directly involved or not.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also worth talking to your local skate shops and seeing if they’re prepared to offer you deals on the basic kit. Both the Minxters and the Nasty Nessies managed to arrange discounts for their skaters; the Nessies even managed to gain a coach in one of the owners.
Although as new to roller derby as the rest of the team, he is learning on the job, and applying his experience in teaching skateboarding to the role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can find someone with more coaching experience, however, it can work wonders: Fierce Valley have gained tremendously from initial coaching by Auld Reekie skater Ella-Bella Bang-Bang. As Grizabelta explains, “we were put in touch with the amazing Ella-Bella Bang-Bang by a mutual friend. Ella-Bella lives in our neck of the woods so helped us with our training right up until we passed our mins.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/roller-derby-newport-8-october-064tiger-bay-brawlerssimon-ayre.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-822" title="Roller Derby Newport 8 October 064Tiger Bay Brawlers,Simon Ayre" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/roller-derby-newport-8-october-064tiger-bay-brawlerssimon-ayre.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="511"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers have also benefited from having an experienced skater to help kickstart their coaching, BB Bombshell bringing experience from her time in Victorian Roller Derby League in Australia. “BB definitely pushed us as athletes which has contributed to how successful we’ve been so far” say coaches Billie Pistol and Judge Redd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have access to an experienced skater, it’s not the end of the world; the majority of TBB’s coaching team, including head coach Judge Redd, have built up their experience from scratch; “We get new drills from bootcamps, guest coaches and online and keep up to date with strategy by watching games both in the UK and online, quite often we'll see something we'd like to try and create an exercise around it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the point of those coaches is to bring you up to speed on the first challenge of all new skaters: minimum skills. Lola Coaster is keen to emphasize that they should be treated positively: “I think a lot of people are terrified by the ‘pressure’ of minimum skills, but I think they’re a really good way of measuring how far skaters have come since they first strapped on a pair of quads. They’re a really good way of identifying skater strengths and weaknesses so you know what you have to work on and have a defined focus and goal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not just your skaters you need to concentrate on, however; a new league can’t afford to ignore the need for training referees and NSOs. Fierce Valley and York Minxters might have lucked out by being co-founded by Referees-in-training, but not all leagues can be so lucky. NSOs, are a little easier to acquire, as the traditional role of injured or otherwise indisposed skaters. NNRG’s Cherry Bow is a case in point, “I am planning on starting a family soon and I know I can't skate when I'm pregnant so I want to train as a NSO and a ref so I will still be actively involved.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you do start to grow, there’s always the potential for drama; everyone knows at least one league that’s experienced some kind of major or minor conflict. The Norfolk Brawds’ Jessica Whackit advises: “Don't take it personally when people realise it's not for them.  We had a huge number leave us before Christmas and you just have to remember that whenever you get a large group of people together, personality clashes will happen. With this in mind, setting up a coherent committee structure will see you through absolutely ANYTHING.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/roller-derby-newport-8-october-113tiger-bay-brawlerssimon-ayre.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-823" title="Roller Derby Newport 8 October 113Tiger Bay Brawlers,Simon Ayre" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/roller-derby-newport-8-october-113tiger-bay-brawlerssimon-ayre.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="390"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When all your skaters have passed their mins, the next challenge for the league is the big one: the first bout. It’s understandable to be a bit nervous; despite it being a closed-bout, Fierce Valley’s Grizabelta admits: “we're still quite terrified! And yet really, really excited... I still struggle to get my head round what we've achieved – the bout will be 2 weeks short of our first birthday so it'll be the best celebration!” Kirk Jammett agrees “As one of the refs I'm terrified of messing up badly and also scared of some angry girls screaming at me! … And as Ella-Bella is being our Head Ref – we really don't want to let her down as she's been such a fundamental element to our success.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, if the nerves, and the inevitable disadvantage of facing much more experienced opponents gets to you, you shouldn’t be discouraged. The Norfolk Brawds’ first bout ended in a 23:188 loss, but Jessica Whackit took the best side to the experience: ”We were lucky enough to have a big loss, but still come out feeling on top. If you can lose well, you can win nicely. Towards the end of the game, a lot of the crowd were shouting for us, and we sold so many t-shirts! We came away with a lot of new fans, as well as our faith in our team intact. We played and lost as a team, so we won really.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, Tiger Bay Brawlers have had an enviably successful first year. Based on their experience, Lola Coaster offered this parting advice: “It’s really hard to give a single piece of advice; I could write a whole article on do’s or do not’s. If I am only allowed one then I think I would have to say “be positive”. Yes you’ll have bad sessions, yes you’ll have weeks/months where you feel roller derby is taking over your life, yes you’ll get hurt at some point, yes you’ll miss sessions, you’ll be left out of the game roster and a whole host of other things that can make you think negatively and wonder why you bother. But be positive and stick at it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>norfolk brawds</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>york minxters</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/01/26/brave-new-faces-the-writers-cut/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 20:28:55 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>