<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about tomodachi derby tournament)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/tomodachi-derby-tournament.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>EuroClash, Tomodachi and Quad Wars, Three Tournaments, One Weekend (stats)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outside of the USA, there were arguably three big "single date" tournament events last weekend:
Newcastle Roller Girls' &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;EuroClash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, hosting European leagues, a WFTDA Recognised Tournament
Okinawa and Japan's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, hosting East-Asia/Pacific and Alaskan leagues, with a WFTDA Sanctioned Tier
Mendoza, Argentina's Lado Oscuro Roller Derby's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quad Wars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, hosting B/C level Latin American leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of games in all of them, so there's plenty of meat for statistical inference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's start with EuroClash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-13774" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/euroclash.jpg" alt="euroclash" width="851" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuroClash was arranged as a pure invitational tournament, with structure set mostly by the participants' desires for opponents. As a result, EuroClash did not post a "winner" of the tournament. All bouts were WFTDA Sanctioned, as befits a WFTDA Recognised Tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participating teams for all but the last fixture were: Newcastle Roller Girls, Leeds Roller Derby, Middlesbrough Roller Derby, Tiger Bay Brawlers, Central City Rollergirls, Bear City Roller Derby (Berlin), Paris Rollergirls, Auld Reekie Roller Girls (Edinburgh) and Dublin Roller Derby. (Interviews with the teams can be found on this very blog here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/tag/euroclash/"&gt;https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/tag/euroclash/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scores (from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/89165"&gt;FlatTrack Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) are:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;TBB [Tiger Bay Brawlers]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;161&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;CCR [Central City]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;167&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BCRD [Bear City]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;228&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NRG [Newcastle]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;94&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARRG [Auld Reekie]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;194&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MRD [Middlesbrough]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;99&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;LeedsRD [Leeds]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;94&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;DRD [Dublin]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;312&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;238&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;BCRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;177&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;ARRG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;176&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;PRG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;192&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;DRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;85&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;ARRG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;301&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;LeedsRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;93&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TBB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;117&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;203&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;135&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CCR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;177&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MRD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;238&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BCRD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;89&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
As commentators have noted (including The Derby Apex), there's some significant departures from prediction here, which we've highlighted in two different ways. Bolded results are surprising in both European and WFTDA rankings terms, whilst Italic are surprising in terms of WFTDA rank only [in this sense, we mean explicitly "from the WFTDA rankings, not from FTS's ranking based on WFTDA Sanctioned play].
&lt;p&gt;It's pretty clear that there are several patterns here: two ranking errors in WFTDA (Leeds Roller Derby inheriting the ranking from Leeds Roller Dolls, and Paris Rollergirls' known underranking) are responsible for the majority of the `surprises' between them. Anyone who had seen LeedsRD play in British Champs would have expected the same high individual-skill, but teamwork needing more time to gel playstyle we saw in EuroClash - which is to say that there were moments of brilliance, particularly from their jammer rotation (Killaroo, Shin Pain and Little Dark One standing out for us, and in the stats), but there's still some place to go with the cohesion.
And Paris Rollergirls' determination to reach Division 2 playoffs this year is backed by considerable skill and effort in training over the last year - and a consciously constructed schedule of fixtures designed to gain them WFTDA ranking as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this context, then, the real surprises are: Tiger Bay Brawlers holding Paris Rollergirls to their expected performance [including holding them to zero points for the first half of the first period], Central City, in turn, 's surprising win over TBB in the first bout of the tournament, Auld Reekie Roller Girls matching their European expectations of tying Bear City to a 1-point win...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and the curious case of Middlesbrough Roller Derby. The MRD bouts are the only bouts which are a really surprising result in terms of FTS - in the one case, MRD massively underperforming versus Auld Reekie, and in the second MRD massively overperforming against Bear City! (And we mean massively in both cases - Middlesbrough might have been expected to beat Auld Reekie with that kind of points margin, not lose to them by it!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibility, exists, of course, that it was the other teams which were unpredictable... but we can test that with the power of statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We performed a standard linear regression against the results from EuroClash, using score ratios as our measure of performance. As we've explained before, this assumes that the strengths of each team are simply related to each other by their performance - so if Team A is twice as strong as Team B, and three times as strong as Team C, then Team B versus Team C should give a 2/3 ratio win for the B team. Of course, performance varies from game to game, but we can use an "R-squared" value to measure just how good the approximation is for our results. A value close to 1 indicates that the results are very well described by this kind of model, whilst a value close to 0 indicates that no such relationship exists at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running the regression against the full set of results above gives an R-squared&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; of &lt;em&gt;0.39&lt;/em&gt;, a disappointingly low value for Roller Derby tournaments in general (which tend to be around 0.7 or higher).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, given that we know that the MRD results are inconsistent, we can rerun the regression on the results, minus one or both of the MRD games. In this case, we get an pleasingly high R-squared of around &lt;em&gt;0.93&lt;/em&gt; - actually very high for a tournament.
This suggests that, whilst the results might have been surprising when compared with WFTDA rankings, the performance of the teams (other than Middlesbrough) across EuroClash was remarkably consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For interest, then, the relative power-rankings (which should be in the ratio of the points scored between two teams) are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;184&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Paris Rollergirls&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;100&lt;/strong&gt;
Middlesbrough Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;76&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/em&gt;
Berlin City Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;69&lt;/strong&gt;
Auld Reekie Roller Girls &lt;strong&gt;62&lt;/strong&gt;
Tiger Bay Brawlers &lt;strong&gt;51&lt;/strong&gt;
Dublin Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;50&lt;/strong&gt;
Central City Rollergirls &lt;strong&gt;47&lt;/strong&gt;
Newcastle Rollergirls &lt;strong&gt;32&lt;/strong&gt;
Middlesbrough Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;31&lt;/strong&gt; *
Leeds Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where the three entries for Middlesbrough represent their performance against Berlin (184), Auld Reekie (31) and the average of the two (76). That average is around where we would expect MRD to actually have performed if they were consistent, which is interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally matching the results against the existing rankings produces the best matches if we assume that Paris, Dublin and perhaps Auld Reekie, are underranked, and LeedsRD are overranked, with smaller shifts for the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also means that, if we were awarding a Championship to any team, it would be the entirely expected Paris Rollergirls!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paris will be competing against Bear City only this coming weekend, so this will be a good test of their true strength...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-
Of course, the final event at EuroClash was the Team Scotland Roller Derby versus Team Ireland Roller Derby bout.
A rematch of the game played at Road to TBC, where both teams were in their training roster (and Ireland had barely selected that), where Ireland won - this time Team Scotland's competition 20 were playing a more-experienced, but still training, Ireland. (Both teams had many skaters from Auld Reekie and Dublin's rosters, respectively, as well as other teams.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's fair to say that there was a significant difference in the result, with Road to TBC's tough-but-convincing Irish victory replaced by a tight even score in at the end of the first period, becoming a strong Scottish victory by the end of the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final result, &lt;strong&gt;209&lt;/strong&gt; Scotland : &lt;strong&gt;128&lt;/strong&gt; Ireland is stronger than the expected result if Dublin had played ARRG, emphasising the importance of the other leagues making up each National Team; however, at half time, the result was a near tie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;For the statistically inclined, this is actually the adjusted R-squared, not the bare R-squared. We're also using the F-statistic for these regressions, but it closely follows adj. R-squared here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click here: for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/2"&gt;Tomodachi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and here: for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/3"&gt;Quad Wars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over in Okinawa, the Tomodachi Derby Tournament had three tiers - a WFTDA sanctioned tier, an unsanctioned women's tier, and the men's tier (with just two competitors). Interviews with all the participants are available here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/tag/tomodachi-derby-tournament/"&gt;https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/tag/tomodachi-derby-tournament/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-14076" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/tomodachi.png?w=300" alt="tomodachi" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;WFTDA-Sanctioned Tier&lt;/h4&gt;
Competing in the Sanctioned Tier were: Okinawa Roller Derby, Tokyo Roller Girls, Devil Dog Derby Dames (the 3 Japanese leagues), Pacific Roller Derby (Hawai'i) and Fairbanks Rollergirls (Alaska, USA).
This was a full round-robin, for a total of 10 games between the 5 teams.
&lt;p&gt;The results were [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/88944"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D4 (Devil Dog Derby Dames)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;305&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FR (Fairbanks Rollergirls)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;156&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRG (Tokyo Rollergirls)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;167&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRD (Hawai'i Pacific Roller Derby)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;138&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ORD (Okinawa Roller Derby)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;124&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;232&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;138&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;188&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;164&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;170&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;126&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;127&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;251&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;174&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;D4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;167&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;169&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;172&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;108&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TRG&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;212&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
The most surprising result is highlighted - Okinawa Roller Derby (which renamed from Kokeshi Roller Dolls just before the tournament) are usually ranked around the same as their fellow Okinawans in Devil Dog Derby Dames.
&lt;p&gt;Running our statistical regression on the tournament, we get an R-squared value (our measure of how "consistent" the games all are) of &lt;em&gt;0.44&lt;/em&gt;, which suggests that there's definitely at least one team which was variable in performance over the two days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, whilst you might expect that removing results such as the ORD v D4 score from the set would improve the R-squared factor for our fit, this is not the case - there's very little change in the R-squared for single-bout changes for the Tomodachi. We believe that this reflects the difference in tournament-experience of the teams involved, versus the higher ranked teams at EuroClash (who are more used to managing their rosters and effort across a long event).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resulting strengths of the WFTDA tier of Tomodachi, then, are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tokyo Roller Girls &lt;strong&gt;100&lt;/strong&gt;
Devil Dog Derby Dames &lt;strong&gt;100&lt;/strong&gt;
Okinawa Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;82&lt;/strong&gt;
Hawai'i Pacific Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;60&lt;/strong&gt;
Fairbanks Rollergirls &lt;strong&gt;60&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where we would give the "unofficial championship", by a whisker, to Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your next chances to see some of these teams: Devil Dog Derby Dames will be competing in Hawai'i's Big Island Brawl against the rest of Hawai'i, and teams from the continental USA (June), where you will also find Pacific Roller Derby. Okinawa Roller Derby are off to Europe to play in a tournament hosted by Rollergirls of the Apocalypse, in Kaiserslauten, Germany. Fairbanks are concentrating on their Alaskan neighbours, with the UWR State Tournament coming up in May. And Tokyo Roller Girls are looking for people to play them, so do ask!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Unsanctioned Tier&lt;/h4&gt;
With two of the three competing teams in the unsanctioned tier essentially exhibition teams (Pan-Asian Spring Rollers representing the Chinese and Thai derby leagues, and Team Women's Roller Derby Japan an open team for skaters who wanted to compete), and the third a Tokyo Roller Girls' home team (Yokosuka Sushi Rollers), there were no expectations on the three bouts.
&lt;p&gt;The results were:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;YSR (Yokosuka Sushi Rollers)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;307&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PASR (Pan-Asian Spring Rollers)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;51&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;YSR (Yokosuka Sushi Rollers)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;307&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PASR (Pan-Asian Spring Rollers)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;51&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;YSR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;152&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WRDJ (Women's Roller Derby Japan)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;167&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WRDJ&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;218&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PASR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;157&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
With just three teams and three bouts, there's not really much point in running statistical tests on the performance, as there's not enough data to produce a reasonable result. (The R-squared statistic is fairly poor for the set, due to the visibly wide variation in the teams' performance.)
&lt;p&gt;In fact, within statistical error, Yokosuka Sushi Rollers and Women's Roller Derby Japan are inseparable in performance, with the Spring Rollers' lack of time to train together evidence in their lower placing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establishing a winner really isn't the point of the unsanctioned tier, however - it's to give the teams a chance to get good experience against people they'd never reasonably be able to play. And, in particular, for the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers, this will be a great learning experience for them to take back to their home leagues in Hong Kong, Shanghai, Beijing and Bangkok.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Men's Tier.&lt;/h4&gt;
Glenmore Reservoir Dogs and Team Japan Men's Roller Derby (NinJapan Rollers) played each other twice over the tournament, with scores:
&lt;p&gt;GRD 273 : TJMRD 113
GRD 288 : TJMRD 138&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it should be fairly evident that, despite the Canadians winning both bouts, there's a close-to-significant improvement in NinJapan Rollers even in the second bout. (In both Men's Roller Derby World Cups, NinJapan have noticeably improved over the tournament, so this is in keeping with their character.)
These were Japan's first men's games since the last World Cup, in fact, and were more significant for the training opportunity, perhaps, than the resulting scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click here: for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/1"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and here: for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/3"&gt;Quad Wars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over to Argentina now, for the Quad Wars 2017 tournament, which saw teams from Argentina and Chile compete in a "B-tier" tournament (in the sense that Argentina uses "B", which is different to Europe - most of these teams are not actual B-teams).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-17011 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/qw.png" alt="QW" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competing were: hosts Lado Oscuro Roller Derby (LORD); Sailor City Rollers' B team, the Tsunami Bombs; Metropolitan Roller Derby's B team, the Bayonetas; Dirty Fucking Dolls; Brutal Lips; and the Sarcasticats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quad Wars has a Star Wars theme, fitting for a host league whose name is "Dark Side" in Spanish, and the teams were arranged in bracketed light and dark side groups, with a playoff for the championship at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results (from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/91785"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) are:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;LORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DFD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;215&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BRUTAL_LIPS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;51&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NERD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;203&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SARCASTICATS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;122&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BAYONETAS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;177&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NERD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DFD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;58&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;LORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;91&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BRUTAL_LIPS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;124&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BAYONETAS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;114&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TSUNAMI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;142&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;LORD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;57&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NERD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;209&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SARCASTICATS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TSUNAMI&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;157&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BRUTAL_LIPS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;34&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DFD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;131&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;BAYONETAS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;37&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;NERD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;247&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;DFD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;143&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;TSUNAMI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;78&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;BAYONETAS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;47&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;TSUNAMI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;63&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;NERD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;155&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;DFD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;27&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
The last four bouts (in red) represented a final playoff for the championship, which was won by NERD. We can't highlight surprising results using Flat Track Stats, as they do not have a Latin American ranking... but we can use our own &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to do this instead. In general, the big surprise here is the performance of Sailor City B, the Tsunami Bombs, which we rated as close to the winners, NERD in strength... but performed below expectations.
&lt;p&gt;NERD won the tournament overall, but we can provide the same analysis of the team ratings (and how consistent they were) as before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running the regression over all of the scores gives us a very good R-squared value of 0.8, suggesting that the tournament was well-run, and all the teams managed their schedules and fitness well over the multiple days of competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The estimated strengths of the teams from the regression are (with some confidence):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No Excuses Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;100&lt;/strong&gt;
Dirty Fucking Dolls &lt;strong&gt;41&lt;/strong&gt;
Tsunami Bombs (SCR B) &lt;strong&gt;21&lt;/strong&gt;
Brutal Lips &lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt;
Bayonetas (Metropolitan B) &lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt;
Lado Oscuro Roller Derby &lt;strong&gt;14&lt;/strong&gt;
Sarcasticats &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting feature here is the close grouping of most of the teams: we'd suggest that NERD and DFD could reasonably consider themselves high-B/low-A teams (in Latin American terms), rather than the B/C level of the other closely placed competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in seeing more Latin American Derby, then Metropolitan and Sailor City's A teams are competing at the Violentango 5, WFTDA Recognised Tournament in just a few weeks (13-15th April).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click here for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/1"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and here for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/2"&gt;Tomodachi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>euroclash</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>lado oscuro roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>quad wars</category><category>statistics</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 13:20:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tomodachi Cup: NinJapan Rollers (Men's Roller Derby Japan)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/24/the-tomodachi-cup-ninjapan/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; kicks off in Okinawa, we have one final team interview to post, even as scores come in from the first bouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started our coverage with Canada's entry into the men's tier, Glenmore Reservoir Dogs, and so it is only fitting to finish with their opponents: the Japanese Men's National Team, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/mrdj.web/"&gt;NinJapan Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NinJapan Rollers burst onto the derby scene at the first ever Men's Roller Derby World Cup, back in 2014, where they captured the hearts of the audience, and the other teams with their spirit on track. Returning in 2016, after devoting the intervening two years to actively promoting and growing men's derby in Japan (where they are still the only active league of Japanese nationals), NinJapan improved on their performance in 2014 with two victories. This is the first outing of what may become the 2018 iteration of the national team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14038 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/japan-logo-232x300.jpg" alt="japan-logo-232x300" width="193" height="250"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Spectators and teams were both very impressed by the improvement in the NinJapan Rollers from 2014 to 2016. How did you feel about your performance in the 2016 Men's Roller Derby world cup, and what was your high-point?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Japan, there are not so many people playing the Roller Derby, and we knew that the level was different in the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could only watch games from aronnd the world on the Internet, and we played only one game against a men's team between the 1st and 2nd [Men's] World Cup... only 1 day before 2nd World Cup itself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When World Cup started, it was different feeling from what we imagined, in terms of tactics, contact, speed. However, we are satisfied with our performance, the increase in what we can achieve, and our victories!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;One of the reasons for your success has been your active recruiting policy - trying to build Men's Roller Derby in Japan between the World Cups. Can we talk about how this is continuing?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the Internet to disseminate activities. Roller Derby is not known yet in Japan. We want to do activate more  if we have two teams and be more popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;★&lt;b&gt;At the Tomodachi Tournament, you will be playing Glenmore Reservoir Dogs. What are your aims, and preparation for playing them?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're very glad that we get to play another men's team, before the 3rd World Cup! First of all, we thank Glenmore for playing us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this game is checking our level before World Cup, our roster was changed. Of course, we also want to win!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the derby also evolves, we are researching the world standard and practicing to meet it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;And when you are not competing, which Teams and games are you looking forward to watching?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing the Alaskan and Hawai'ian teams; some members were playing in Japan and we have great memories of practicing with them at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What are NinJapan Rollers plans for 2017?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's just one year to the next World Cup, so our World Cup project will start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will practice again from the basics, to team we will be sharing to raise awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;★&lt;b&gt;Heading towards the MRDWC in 2018, what are NinJapan Rollers aiming for at the next World Cup?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were able to get our first victory and the second victory [at MRDWC2016], thanks to the cooperation and encouragement of lots of people. Next time we want to get even more wins, that just equal what we have already done. We will exceed what you can imagine,  and keep achieving all of our expectations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our ongoing coverage of the Tomodachi Tournament can be &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/tomodachi2017.html"&gt;tracked here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, with scores updated as they are announced, and video when available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>ninjapan rollers</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/24/the-tomodachi-cup-ninjapan/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 08:30:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tomodachi Cup: Team Women's Roller Derby Japan [トモダチダービートーナメント:チームWRDJ]</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/09/the-tomodachi-cup-team-womens-roller-derby-japan-tomodachidabitonamentochi/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; approaches, we're interviewing another team - the last team in the non-Sanctioned tier of the tournament. This article will be in both Japanese and English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14030 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/teamwrdj-sm.jpg" alt="teamwrdj-sm" width="250" height="154"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/WRDJapan/"&gt;Women's Roller Derby Japan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Team WRDJ] is a mixed subscription team, which was open to anyone applying to join. It was organised by Women's Roller Derby Japan, the body which organises the Japanese Women's National Team. チームウィメンズローラーダービージャパン[チームWRDJは]への参加を適用する誰にでも開かれていた混成チーム、です。 これは、日本女子代表チームを組織しているウィメンズローラーダービージャパンが主催したものです。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its roster consists of:
名簿には次のものが含まれます：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From (Tokyo Roller Girls Home Team): Neon Roller Monsters (Yokohama)
[横浜のローラーダービーチーム から]
・Thunder BELL #950
・Where's The Fire #75
・Inga Knee'her #235
・Rice Rocket #278
・Savage Dragon #5360
・Lisa Slamtimes #413
From Tokyo Three Rollers (Tokyo)
[東京のローラーダービー・チーム Tokyo3Rollersから]
・Red Eye #88
From Kokeshi Roller Dolls (Okinawa)
[沖縄のコケシローラードルスから]
・Loveless #0
・Lil N. Gin #9
・Lemmy Killmisstress #1975
・PurpleHaze #21
・Atomic Jenny #88
From Devil Dog Derby Dames (Okinawa)
[沖縄のデヴィゥドグダービダメスから]
・Madam Vice #7
・Christine Westbrook
・Mermaid Mayhem #20
From Echo City Knockouts (Hawaii)
[ハワイのエコシチノクアウツから]
・Bandit Angel #18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Captain Thunder BELL was good enough to answer questions for us.　チームキャプテンThunder BELLが私たちの質問に答えて&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="popup" title="くれる - to give"&gt;くれた。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did the idea for Team WRDJ occur? (チームWRDJのアイデアはどうやって起こったのですか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tomodachi Tournament originally had only a method to participate with full teams, and we felt this was a little sad. We looked for a good way to allow the opportunity for domestic skaters who can't join as their team, or players from foreign countries who are visiting without their team, to participate. We hit on the idea of making Team WRDJ. We hope that this team will help enjoyment of the tournament.
当初トモダチトーナメントにはチーム単位で参加する方法しかなく、それはとても限定的だと少し残念に思いました。トーナメントに参加しないチームの国内選手や海外から来日する選手達など、もっと沢山の人達に日本でダービーをプレイできる機会を作りたくて、Team WRDJを作るアイディアを思いつきました。このチームがより多くの人が友達トーナメントを楽しむ為に役に立つ事を願ってます。
&lt;strong&gt;The Women's Roller Derby Japan Team contains a lot of skaters from Neon Roller Monsters - Tokyo Roller Girls' "Japanese" team. With the experience you have playing the Sushi Rollers already, do you think this will be an advantage in the tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(Team WRDJには、東京ローラーガールズの「日本人」チームであるネオンローラーモンスターのスケーターがたくさん含まれています。すでに寿司ローラーを経験している経験があれば、これがトーナメントで有利になると思いますか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team WRDJ is a mixed team, so I think it is stronger than Neon Roller Monsters. If there is something to be advantageous, if we use Japanese language during the game, they can't understand our strategy...But Sushi Rollers is smart and very strong team, so it might not matter!
Team WRDJはミックスチームなので、ネオンローラーモンスターズよりも強いと思います。有利になる事があるとしたら、私達が日本語を使用すれば作戦が彼らにバレない事です。しかしスシローラーズはとても強いチームなので、そんな事は関係ないかもしれません…笑
&lt;strong&gt;With skaters from Honshu, Okinawa and Hawai'i, how have Team WRDJ been practising together before the Tomodachi Tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(本州、沖縄、ハワイの選手と一緒に、チームWRDJはTomodachiトーナメントの前にどのように練習していましたか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can not practice together as Team WRDJ. We will think about our strategy.
チームWRDJとして皆んなで一緒に練習する事出来ません。これから作戦を考えます。
&lt;strong&gt;Outside of your own division, there's a lot of other Roller Derby to watch at the tournament: which teams, or games, are you most looking forward to seeing?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(自身の部門外には、トーナメントで観戦できる多くのローラーダービーがあります。どのチームや試合が最も楽しみですか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I'm looking forward to the Pan-Asian match. I'm very interested in how Asian players will play derby. WRDJ would like Roller Derby to spread further across Asia in the future.
Pan-Asianの試合が最も楽しみです。
アジアの選手達がどんなプレイをするのかとても興味があります。これからもっとアジア全域にローラーダービーが広がっていってほしいです。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After the Tournament, will Team WRDJ continue in other events? &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(トーナメント終了後、WRDJチームは他のイベントを続行しますか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is undecided right now, but we would like to do it again if we have good opportunities.
今のところ未定ですが、良い機会があればまたやりたいです。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Women's Roller Derby Japan also has a mandate to manage the National Japanese team. Looking towards 2018's Roller Derby World Cup, how is this going, what are your plans?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(ウィメンズローラーダービージャパンには、日本人のチームを統括する権限もあります。 2018年のローラーダービーワールドカップを目指していかがですか、予定はどんな感じですか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started new Team Japan for World Cup 2018. Twenty-five skaters from all over the world have applied for this time. Last time, our major goal was [just] participation in the World Cup, but this time, our new major goal is getting &lt;em&gt;victories&lt;/em&gt; at the World Cup! Team practice has started in Japan. We need figure out how we work together with overseas skaters, but we are sure that new Team Japan will be stronger than last time. Please expect the Team Japan 2018!!
私達は2018年の為のチームジャパンを結成しました。今回は世界中から25人の選手達が応募をしてきました。前回はワールドカップに出場する事が私達の大きな目標でしたが、今回は勝つ事を大きな目標において、チーム作りをすると決めています。日本国内ではチーム練習が始まりました。パワーアップしたチームジャパンを是非期待していて下さい。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tomodachi Derby Tournament will be held between the 24th and 26th of March, in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/%E6%B2%96%E7%B8%84%E7%9C%8C%E7%B7%8F%E5%90%88%E9%81%8B%E5%8B%95%E5%85%AC%E5%9C%92+%E4%BD%93%E8%82%B2%E9%A4%A8/@26.3104722,127.8208903,18.72z/data=!4m8!1m2!2m1!1sOkinawa+Comprehensive+Park!3m4!1s0x0:0xd83f29f95619b3f0!8m2!3d26.3106488!4d127.8200047"&gt;Okinawa Comprehensive Sports Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Okinawa.トモダチダービートーナメントは３月２４日から３月２６日まで&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/%E6%B2%96%E7%B8%84%E7%9C%8C%E7%B7%8F%E5%90%88%E9%81%8B%E5%8B%95%E5%85%AC%E5%9C%92+%E4%BD%93%E8%82%B2%E9%A4%A8/@26.3104722,127.8208903,18.72z/data=!4m8!1m2!2m1!1sOkinawa+Comprehensive+Park!3m4!1s0x0:0xd83f29f95619b3f0!8m2!3d26.3106488!4d127.8200047"&gt;沖縄県総合運動公園 体育館&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;で開催されます。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>team wrdj</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>women's roller derby japan</category><category>日本語</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/09/the-tomodachi-cup-team-womens-roller-derby-japan-tomodachidabitonamentochi/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 12:03:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tomodachi Cup: Kokeshi Roller Dolls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/01/the-tomodachi-cup-kokeshi-roller-dolls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the second ever international tournament in Okinawa, Japan grows ever closer, we're bringing you another interview with a team attending the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;March 24&lt;/strong&gt;th to &lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt;th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last of our interviewees in the WFTDA Sanctioned tier of the tournament, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.okinawarollerderby.com/"&gt;Kokeshi Roller Dolls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are one of the two "local" leagues, based in Okinawa itself. KRD can contest with Tokyo Roller Girls for the title of "oldest league in Japan", both being founded around the same date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Japan Open, Kokeshi were the only Japanese team to defeat the might Juneau Roller Derby. Previously to that, the team has also played international roller derby away, at The Big O in 2014. KRD skaters also contributed to the teams competing at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/"&gt;first ever public&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; roller derby bout in China!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14036 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/kokeshi.png" alt="kokeshi" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRD were happy to answer some questions for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As the host league, and member of the organising Japan Derby Tournament Committee, what are you most proud of about the Tomodachi Tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRD: We’re technically not the host league; we’ll be hosting a revamped tournament next year called the Far East Face Off, but this year our role on the JDTC was solely to cover the marketing aspect of tournament preparation. One of our league members is a graphic designer, and was able to design the logo, banners, tees, and tournament program, which was a massive bonus for the JDTC. We're impressed that the committee, which first formed in September, was able to overcome a language barrier and pull off the planning of a tournament in under six months. Many of us worked overwhelmingly hard to make that happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the last tournament, Kokeshi played the three visiting A teams from outside Japan, pulling off a win against Juneau in their last bout of the tournament. What lessons are you taking into the Tomodachi, when facing Fairbanks and Pacific in particular?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRD: We’ve been practicing specific defensive strategies and better communication, and even increasing our endurance and strength training off skates. I think last year, our energy was focused on running the tournament, rather than practicing effective strategies. This year, our athletic staff isn’t involved in the tournament operations, and can focus on leading the team. Additionally, we were caught off guard by the slippery floor surface; the arena floors had recently been resealed and polished, and many of us did not have grippy wheels that first day. Lesson learned! We’ll be prepared for any surface this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You've played both Tokyo and D4 [Devil Dog Derby Dames] fairly regularly, of course (and D4 are particularly close by…). How are you feeling about your rematches against them this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRD: We didn’t bout either of these leagues last season, and with the high turnover rate due to military relocation, many of our skaters have never played against these leagues. We have had opportunities within the past season to play fun informal mixed scrimmages with members of TRG and D4, so keeping a competitive mental focus might be challenging since we’re used to having fun on the track. Both leagues have some very skilled skaters that we’re excited to go up against. Our goal is to practice effective communication and teamwork now that our skaters have had a whole season to train together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outside of your division, what teams and bouts are you most looking forward to at the Tomodachi?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRD: We're interested to see the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers play together. KRD was given the opportunity to skate with many of them in Beijing last summer at the HeForShe roller derby expo, which was a phenomenal experience. It sounds challenging to have a team comprised of women from different leagues all skating together for the first time, and we’re excited to see how they adapt to working together on the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's next for Kokeshi, after the Tomodachi?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KRD: KRD is undergoing an exciting rebranding campaign! We are renaming the league “Okinawa Roller Derby” to better represent our location when we venture off island to play in tournaments. We are heading to Kaiserslautern, Germany for a tournament this June. We want to expand our horizons, challenge ourselves, and see what we can accomplish as a travel team. Then we’ll take the summer off to refocus on recruitment and, of course, put in some hours at the beach!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>kokeshi roller dolls</category><category>okinawa roller derby</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/01/the-tomodachi-cup-kokeshi-roller-dolls/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 10:15:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tomodachi Cup: Tokyo Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/23/the-tomodachi-cup-tokyo-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And your second look at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; attendees this week are a two-for-one interview. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/TokyoRollerGirls/"&gt;Tokyo Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are not only attending the WFTDA Sanctioned division of the tournament with their travel team, but have also entered one of their home teams, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YokosukaSushiRollers/"&gt;Yokosuka Sushi Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, into the non-Sanctioned division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the first Roller Derby league in Japan, Tokyo Roller Girls have been a full WFTDA member league since 2013,  and are strong contributors to Women's Roller Derby Japan, the governing body of the National team. As well as playing in Japan, Tokyo have played in Hawai'i (in 2014). Home team, the Yokosuka Sushi Rollers were TRG's original home team, and are based in and around the Yokosuka Naval Base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="14028,14026" type="square" columns="2"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TRG and Sushi Rollers' coach, Ms. Judgment, was good enough to answer our questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tokyo Roller Girls have always been strongly involved in the development of Roller Derby in Japan - indeed, your skaters have formed the backbone of Team Japan, and contributed strongly to the founding of Women's Roller Derby Japan. How do you think the sport of Roller Derby plays in Tokyo - and how have you been recruiting? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby in Japan is unique, and Tokyo Roller Girls is no exception to this. Playing roller derby within our league and against NinJapan Rollers has helped us grow as skaters and form new bonds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traveling outside of Japan is difficult because of the expense and the approval process some of our players have to navigate. Inviting teams to come bout against us here has also proved to be difficult. There are many more rules and regulations when it comes to fundraising, advertising, and reserving venue space here in Japan than in the United States (largely due to our military affiliations). With all of these factors challenging us, our love for the sport helps to keep it going, and helps to continue growth here in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our home teams spread throughout mainland Japan and the majority of our members attached to the U.S. military we have a very high turnover rate. Each home team is responsible for its own recruiting, which is largely accomplished through social media and recruiting events. We have also been lucky enough to have a few transfer skaters from the States. Our Japanese counterparts who are not on military bases have a more difficult challenge - they try to recruit friends, family, exchange students and co-workers. If we can attract a larger Japanese fan base here our recruiting efforts will be made easier, but it is difficult to get the word out to the Japanese public about roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You're also part of the newly minted Japan Derby Tournament Committee - what changes has this made to the organization of this tournament from last time? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Japan Open is planned for every two years. The last one was in 2016 and the next one will be in 2018. The Tomodachi Derby Tournament is the alternate year tournament. It’s taking place in the same venue, but that’s really all it shares with the Open. The Tournament Committee is entirely different from the Japan Open Committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re trying to make this year’s tournament much more home-grown, with each of the Japan leagues working with Ninjapan to host this year’s tournament. So you will see us skating, NSOing, taking care of the venue (and each other!), and hopefully all having a great time as we get a chance to skate for WFTDA rankings for the first time this year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the last tournament, Tokyo played all of the visiting A teams from outside Japan, and came off worse (although pretty closely against Juneau). What lessons are you taking into the Tomodachi, when facing Fairbanks and Pacific, in particular? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that our isolation here works against us, but we are working hard on both skating fundamentals and team play. We were fortunate to have Sausarge Rolls here for a clinic in November – he certainly taught us quite a bit and left us with plenty to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I skated previously with Monterey Bay Derby Dames (another small league), so I have been trying to bring a lot of our lessons learned about skating with a small roster to use here. We have a great group of skaters that have a lot of desire to learn and improve – attitude really matters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sushi Rollers have, until now, only played as a home team (notably against [fellow home team] Neon Roller Monsters many times in the last year). How are they preparing to play not just their first away game, but also their first bouts against new skaters? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the Sushi Rollers participated in the Sausarge Rolls clinic and that was a great introduction to new skills and skating with others. We also hosted Season’s Beatings, which was a day-long mash-up of seven mini-bouts that challenged us by changing the roster for each game. A few of our transfer skaters have some tournament experience, so we are sharing as many tips and tricks as we can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have played against many of the members of the Women’s Roller Derby Japan team (and love playing with and against them!), but we are really looking forward to meeting and skating with the members of the Pan Asian Spring Rollers team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Speaking of the Neon Roller Monsters, they're strongly represented in Team WRDJ - does this help to plan how to take on the team, or are you expecting new challenges from the other skaters?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does help. Thunder BELL is an active member and skater in TRG, NRM’s head coach, and WRDJ’s head. While we much prefer playing &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; her, we respect her on the track and look forward to seeing what she has put together with Team WRDJ for this tournament!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's next for Tokyo Roller Girls, after the Tomodachi? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will continue to skate and practice, and hope to help prepare both the men’s and women’s world cup teams. Unfortunately, we have no travel scheduled at the moment – if you have a tournament you think we would be a good fit for, please let us know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other than your fellow TRG team, which teams are you most looking forward to watching at the Tomodachi, when you're not playing? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frankly, we are just really excited to be in a tournament environment! I’m sure we’ll be watching ALL of the teams, but I am really looking forward to watching our US challengers, as well as the Glenmore Reservoir Dogs – you never know where you will pick up new skills and strategies!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>tokyo roller girls</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>yokosuka sushi rollers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/23/the-tomodachi-cup-tokyo-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 14:52:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tomodachi Cup: Fairbanks Rollergirls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/22/the-tomodachi-cup-fairbanks-rollergirls/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And after covering a EuroClash team yesterday, today it's time to meet another of the attendees at Okinawa's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, also 24th to 26th March, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today's interviewee is the team travelling the furthest to attend the tournament, from northern Alaska, it's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fairbanksrollergirls.org/"&gt;Fairbanks Rollergirls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Dating back to 2009, Fairbanks joined WFTDA in the 2011 cohort, and have maintained a pretty solid regular season, mostly competing against other Alaskan leagues. They will be competing in the WFTDA sanctioned tier of the Tomodachi Tournament, against the host leagues and Pacific Roller Derby of Hawai'i.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14024 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/fairbanks_rollergirls.png" alt="fairbanks_rollergirls" width="200" height="240"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fairbanks Rollergirls President, Jaime Lynn Smears, answered some questions for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alaskan Roller Derby has, necessarily, always been a very close-knit community, with all of the Alaskan leagues playing each other frequently… but perhaps not getting the chance to play teams from the rest of the USA (or Canada) as often, let alone the rest of the World. How do you feel about the state of Alaskan Roller Derby?&lt;/strong&gt;F&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel really great about the state of Alaska Roller Derby. It is steadily growing and the teams are eager to learn and getting better every season. It's nice to have a small feeling community of skaters, which I think a lot of places might not have. Many of us are friends with each other and are able to develop long-lasting friendships because of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as playing the rest of the US, there are teams that do travel to the lower 48 for game play. Rage City All-Stars travel to get higher-level sanctioned games and tournaments, as well as their B-Team Orange Crush went to Spokarnage last year. Denali Destroyer Dolls from Wasilla made a trip to a Colorado tournament last summer. Sitka Sound Slayers are bringing up a Rat City home team, Throttle Rockets, for a game in February as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fairbanks themselves have hosted the annual United We Roll tournament for Alaskan derby. Can you tell us a bit about the tournament, how it came to be (and if it will be running this year)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fairbanks Rollergirls were the original creators of the United We Roll Tournament in 2013 and haven't hosted since. Financial burdens had us cancel our portion in 2015 and a working group between the leagues saved that years tournament, being hosted by Denali Destroyer Dolls in Palmer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tournament is meant to be a traveling tournament within the state, but it was decided amongst the leagues that the best place for it would be in the Anchorage, Wasilla areas because it is a more central location, making it much easier for teams to travel. Fairbanks is 400 miles north of everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Boom Town Derby Dames have been the hosts the past 2 years in Wasilla, and have done a great job with it we're all anxiously awaiting the details!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fellow Alaskans Juneau Rollergirls made something of a splash in the first Japanese tournament last year… is this something that Fairbanks are intending to live up to at the Tomodachi?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who doesn't aspire to be the Juneau Rollergirls? They went last year with 6 or 7 people? Thats crazy! AND they did amazing!! We love them and definitely have them in our thoughts while we prepare for this year's tournament. We hope to be a remembered force in the tournament, for sure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As far as we can tell, Fairbanks have only played one of the Tomodachi competitors before - Hawai'i's Pacific Roller Derby back in 2010! - how are you planning for taking on so many new teams, and so far away?
&lt;/strong&gt;
We often have a full season and play many tough games throughout which have helped us. We just got back from a mini 3-team tournament with full-length bouts that was a good indicator for us to see what we need to focus on or what we are getting right. Two of our games were literally back to back with 10 minutes in-between and we did pretty well, losing by just 10 points. We are very good at adapting on the fly and playing our game, so I think that will help us at the Tomodachi Tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, in the downtime between bouts, what are you most looking forward to seeing in the other divisions at the tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking to see some great gameplay by everyone involved! Roller derby is a fantastic sport to watch on all levels and we look forward to cheering everyone on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's next for Fairbanks, in 2017, after the Tomodachi?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Tomodachi, we will turn our focus on the UWR State Tournament which is May 5-7 this year. We are also chatting with another team about a June game, but after that will be our summer break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alaska Derby typically runs September through May-ish because of the short summer season in which a lot of people travel for work fishing, etc. It's hard to get people to practice when its near 24 hour daylight, there's just so much to do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are already booking for next season and that kicks off with our Breast Bout Ever, a mashup game that benefits the Breast Cancer Detection Center of Alaska. Skaters get to choose breast-related names and there's a lot of pink and tons of fun! It's a nice shake-up to skate with people from all-over the state as your team!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fairbanks rollergirls</category><category>international derby</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/22/the-tomodachi-cup-fairbanks-rollergirls/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 15:09:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tomodachi Cup: Devil Dog Derby Dames of Okinawa</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/16/the-tomodachi-cup-devil-dog-derby-dames-of-okinawa/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we've discussed, the second ever international tournament in Japan is coming in March; with the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; hosting teams from Japan, the Asia-Pacific region, Alaska and Hawaii.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're interviewing each of the attending teams in the run up to the tournament itself, and this week we're talking to one of the two leagues from Okinawa itself, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.devildogderbydames.com/"&gt;Devil Dog Derby Dames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (or D4).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14034 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/devil_dog_300.png" alt="devil_dog_300" width="200" height="199"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Devil Dog Derby Dames' President, Honey Badger, answered some questions for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a member of the organising Japan Derby Tournament Committee, what are you most proud of about the Tomodachi Tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to assisting with the Tomodachi Tournament, we are most proud of having the opportunity to collaborate with the Leagues and Officials. The collaboration allows the opportunity to communicate and experience different views and perceptions when it comes to the inter workings of establishing and running a Roller Derby Tournament in Japan. Having a role in the Tournament Committee allows us the opportunity to showcase our strengths in our organization off of the track, as well as, learn from our surrounding Japan Roller Derby Leagues and Organizations.
&lt;strong&gt;In the last tournament, D4 played all of the visiting A teams from outside Japan, and came off worse (although pretty closely against Juneau). What lessons are you taking into the Tomodachi, when facing Fairbanks and Pacific, in particular?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Japan Open Tournament was a valued learning experience for the Devil Dog Derby Dames. Being on the track with A teams outside of Japan allowed us the opportunity to experience the way Roller Derby is played from different parts of the world. Experiencing the different ways of game play on the track erupted our love and passion for the sport of roller derby; thus fuelling us with motivation to train harder and always push for that 110% , mentally and physically. The lessons that the Devil Dog Derby Dames received from training camps utilizing the knowledge shared from Ninjapan, Vito Ramon, and Carmen Getsome will be applied in every aspect of game play going into the Tomodachi Tournament.
&lt;strong&gt;Against the other Japanese leagues, D4 have a strong record, and you're the favourite of the three teams competing. How are you feeling about your rematches with Tokyo and Kokeshi?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are extremely excited and honored to bout both Tokyo and Kokeshi once again. It has been a long time since we have had the opportunity to play against either team. It will feel like a completely new team due to some of us having the high turn over rates from our military affiliations. D4 is confident in our strengths and abilities as a team to perform at our highest level of play when it comes to each of these Bouts. We are humbled with the amount of support in the roller derby community and strive to work hard to earn the support we receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outside of your division, what are you most looking forward to at the Tomodachi?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Devil Dog Derby Dames are the utmost excited to witness and cheer on all of the teams participating in the Tomodachi Tournament. We can hardly wait to witness the Ninjapan vs Glenmore bouts, due to the extreme talents both teams showcase. We are looking forward to the opportunity for further networking and continuing to build relationships all around the globe for the growth of Roller Derby in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's next for D4, after the Tomodachi?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the Tomodachi Tournament, D4 is continuing our roller derby endeavours by participating in the 1st Annual &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BigIslandBrawl/"&gt;Big Island Brawl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in June of 2017. The Big Island Brawl is being hosted by Paradise Roller Girls in Hilo, Hawaii. We can hardly anticipate the opportunity to play teams from Hawaii, as well as Colorado and New Zealand, at the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>devil dog derby dames</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/16/the-tomodachi-cup-devil-dog-derby-dames-of-okinawa/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 11:05:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tomodachi Cup Teams: Pan-Asian Spring Rollers!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/08/the-tomodachi-cup-teams-pan-asian-spring-rollers/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;Next in our coverage of teams attending the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Okinawa, March 24th to 26th, is one of the entrants into the "B" tier of the tournament.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;The Pan-Asian Spring Rollers are a hybrid team, consisting of members from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.beijingrollerderby.com/"&gt;Beijing Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/shanghairollerderby/"&gt;Shanghai Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hongkongrollerderby.com/"&gt;Hong Kong Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BangkokRollerDerby/"&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, representing the East-Asian derby communities outside Japan. (Several of these teams previously combined forces to stage the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/04/beijing-roller-derby-and-un-break-ground-in-china-derby-for-equality-with-heforshe-derby-invitational/"&gt;first ever Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; bout in China last year.)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;At the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the Spring Rollers will be competing against the exhibition team Team Women's Roller Derby Japan, and Tokyo Roller Girls' Sushi Rollers.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;Sarah Cason gave us this history of how the team formed.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14040 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/pan-asian.jpg" alt="pan-asian" width="223" height="200"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt;The Pan-Asian Spring Rollers, a fusion of derby teams from Beijing, Shanghai, Hong Kong and Bangkok, merged in November 2016 to form a joint league for the upcoming Tomodachi Derby Tournament in Okinawa, Japan this Spring. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt;As individual teams, all had recieved the invitation to join the tournament as much as a year ago, but the challenges of sustaining a roller derby team outside in this particular region meant that it was seen as nothing more than an extremely beautiful pipe dream.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt;Until, that is,  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Shanghai's Lauryn Kill met one of the Beijing players completely by chance while in Beijing for an unrelated work event. The two of them got talking. The Beijing player mentioned the tournament and that they didn't have enough players to compete, and the idea to form a mixed team was born!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt;Shanghai contacted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Beijing and Hong Kong and put forward the idea of forming a joint team - an idea that both teams immediately got on board with! Beijing suggested bringing Bangkok into the mix, the teams having recently joined forces for Beijing's successful Roller Derby Invitational in partnership with UN Women's HeForShe campaign. Bangkok were keen, and from four small teams, the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers were born!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span class="m_-8209972237915141599m_-5168947352590846932m_-972164390001973434m_4531940457047869190m_-4727285666428833042m_-3965224260262558723m_-8989229780971231211m_-7401372700082996779gmail-_5yl5 gmail_msg"&gt;&lt;span class="gmail_msg"&gt;Unity of purpose was what really brought the teams together into a unified whole. Roller derby is still catching on in many parts of Asia and hasn't yet gained the popularity it has in many western countries. For the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; skaters of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers, the tournament is about the game (always!) - the opportunity to scrimmage can be a rare one in places where roller derby is struggling to take hold - but it's also and importantly about raising awareness of our sport in our region, about building thriving relationships with our sister teams, and about working together to promote and develop the thrilling and empowering sport of roller derby across the region.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="gmail_msg" dir="ltr"&gt;We feel that it's only by uniting, sharing skills, knowledge and ideas, and working together to overcome the challenges we face that we can build a self-sustaining and successful roller derby community in our delicious little corner of the globe.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/08/the-tomodachi-cup-teams-pan-asian-spring-rollers/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 09:43:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tomodachi Cup: A Chat with Pacific Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/26/the-tomodachi-cup-a-chat-with-pacific-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In our second interview of our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; series, covering each of the teams competing in Okinawa from the&lt;strong&gt; 24th &lt;/strong&gt;to the&lt;strong&gt; 26th March&lt;/strong&gt;, we're with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/PacificRollerDerby/"&gt;Pacific Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, of Honolulu, Hawai'i.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14022 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/pacificrollerderby.png" alt="pacificrollerderby" width="200" height="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pacific Roller Derby were O'ahu’s first modern-day roller derby league founded back in 2008, and joining WFTDA the following year. As Pacific have grown, they have shifted from their early "All-Star" team, drawn from across Hawai'i, to fielding their own O'ahu-sourced A-Team, the Hulagans.
Pacific Roller Derby are very proud of their Hawai'ian culture, and make a point of bringing Aloha with them when they travel for tournaments, or host their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hulagans will be competing in the WFTDA Sanctioned tier of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, against host leagues Kokeshi Roller Dolls, Tokyo Roller Girls and Devil Dog Derby Dames, as well as Alaska's Fairbanks Rollergirls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To hear our chat (with rather a lot of Pacific Roller Derby on the other end of the line)...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[soundcloud url="https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/304626708" params="auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true" width="100%" height="450" iframe="true" /]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>pacific roller derby</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/26/the-tomodachi-cup-a-chat-with-pacific-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 15:00:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tomodachi Cup Teams: Glenmore Reservoir Dogs</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/25/the-tomodachi-cup-teams-glenmore-reservoir-dogs/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As promised last week, we'll be spending some time up to the &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;in Okinawa (24th to 26th March) introducing you to the teams competing there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, competing in the Men's event, we'd like to introduce Calgary's own Men's team, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chinookcity.ca/"&gt;Glenmore Reservoir Dogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strictly, the men's team of Chinook City Roller Derby, the Reservoir Dogs are named for both (of course) Quentin Tarantino's film, and the Glenmore Reservoir, not far from their original practice space. Currently ranked at 17th position in the MRDA Rankings, and 65th in the world (men and women) by SRD Rank, the team has been competing since 2011, and an MRDA member since 2013. As well as hosting their own tournament (Flat Track Fever), Chinook City were also the hosts for the 2016 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Glenmore Reservoir Dogs will be playing the Japanese National Men's Team, NinJapan Rollers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14032 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/grd_logo_cmyk.png" alt="grd_logo_cmyk" width="200" height="102"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team's only remaining original founder member, Dev Null, was happy to answer some questions from us.
&lt;strong&gt;The Reservoir Dogs had a pretty busy 2016, at the O-Town Throwdown and the Mayday Mayhem - taking second place at the latter to the formidable Ground Control. Can you talk us through your high-points of the last season?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ground Control game was a high point I think for 2016. Stelly is an incredible jammer and we thought without him, we would have had a much better outcome for us in that game. Still, it was such an incredible game and our jammers and blockers did everything we could at the time to face them. At O-Town playing against the Hooligans, it was great for us to go up against a top 15 team and our standing against them and Montreal proved that we belong in the top 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You also hosted Argentina's ThunderQuads - probably the strongest Men's team in Latin America. How did you arrange that (possibly one of the longest distances they've travelled away), and how did it feel to be playing that kind of truly international Derby at home?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of team Argentina were ThunderQuad skaters at the time so putting the game together was pretty easy. Playing that game at home was awesome and as a precursor to MRDWC it got the whole team involved. It's incredibly difficult to get teams here because of distance and international travel, so having the community come to us we could really show our hospitality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As joint hosts of MRDWC 2016, you saw your opponents at the Tomodachi, Ninjapan Rollers, compete against some of the best skaters in the world. How are you planning for your own bouts against them?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're going to be bringing our best defensive game and coupled with the strength of our jamming crew we feel we should have some success against Team Japan. Our practises are also getting better because we've added skaters this year and have a deeper bench. We're really excited for the 2017 MRDA season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With the schedule as it is, the Reservoir Dogs are going to have a lot of derby to watch. Are there any teams you're looking forward to seeing in action?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The teams are really well matched in the WFTDA division, and I think the Tokyo vs Kokeshi game will be the one to watch. Fairbanks vs the Devil Dogs and Devil Dogs vs Tokyo will also be great games. Most of us just love watching new teams and hopefully new strategies. We'll see where we are when we get there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, after the Tomodachi, What's in Chinook's future for 2017?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 2017, we plan to build on our past success and have scheduled games at the Big O and another MRDA event prior to the end of June. Our games at O-Town Throwdown, which worked out nicely for us, and our games at Big O will hopefully see us seed well in Vancouver. In a perfect world, we'd want to come up 1 to 2 spots in MRDA for the June rankings so that we seed in at 4th or 5th place for playoffs but realistically our goal is just to make that 8 from North America. I think having 3 teams from Canada in the top 20 in MRDA is really saying something for Canadian Men's roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>glenmore reservoir dogs</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/25/the-tomodachi-cup-teams-glenmore-reservoir-dogs/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 14:31:13 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>