<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about torneo brutal)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/torneo-brutal.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>A Brutal kind of Derby: Chilean Men's short-derby tournament.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/04/a-brutal-kind-of-derby-chilean-mens-short-derby-tournament/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of exciting things happen in Roller Derby without getting the attention they deserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these has been the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Torneo-Brutal-709201495857174/"&gt;Torneo Brutal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a unique short-format-derby tournament which has been held by the Chilean leagues for the last few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to organiser Lola Paranoia about the genesis of the tournament, and the currently completed Third Edition of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"In August 2015 was the first edition of the Torneo Brutal. The idea was copied from a similar tournament in Argentina, where a friend participated and told us the experience. At that time, we had little competition in the country, few leagues, so the format of the tournament seemed perfect."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking for a host, Vina del Mar's men's league - Tacones Bandidos - were most excited and agreed to be hosts for the first ever Torneo Brutal , and the two sequels so far!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way, Lola's artist friend Picota, and Rambla and Mr. Sokram, joined the project as organisers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The format is similar to the European "Derby Sevens", with 6-skater teams (plus a bench) playing 30 minute games, otherwise according to WFTDA/MRDA Rules. Like many Sevens tournaments, the teams are CoEd/Open-To-All (or "Roller Derby mixto"), which is also a more popular approach in Latin America in general, and are essentially "exhibition teams" created for each edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third edition of the Tournament sees 11 teams compete in a single-elimination bracket, which is easily managed with the smaller format games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Teams - Zicod'lia, La Mafia Del Sur, Virutas, Mujeros, Emoticon Team, Cosmopolitan, Team Sexy, Cousins Power, Chalabota, Malbec Madness, and Jurassic Quad - draw skaters from across Chile, as well as across the border from Mendoza, Argentina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An intense tournament resulted in a win for Emoticon Team over Viruta, with a narrow 119-94 scoreline, with Viruta finishing the 30 minutes with only 2 players on track. (The reduced starting roster means that Torneo Brutal does not have a minimum-roster to continue competing after injury or foul-outs.) The exciting footage is available here, via Facebook Live: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/709201495857174/videos/1126079294169390/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/709201495857174/videos/1126079294169390/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this edition of the tournament complete, the intent is definitely there for a 4th edition - possibly incorporating elements from other short-format roller derby around the world. We'll keep you informed about details as they emerge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-17398" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/04/17505208_10155115703413766_6259473394845813480_o.jpg?w=768" alt="17505208_10155115703413766_6259473394845813480_o" width="768" height="1024"&gt; The Torneo Brutal Trophy - the "Trofeo Brutal" - made by Picota and other artists&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>articles</category><category>chile</category><category>international derby</category><category>latin american derby</category><category>short format tournaments</category><category>torneo brutal</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/04/a-brutal-kind-of-derby-chilean-mens-short-derby-tournament/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 15:04:50 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>