<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about tournaments)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/tournaments.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 18:18:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 19 October 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-19102019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a surprisingly really exceptionally busy weekend, so we're definitely going to split this update into two bits (and even then, we'll be unable to cover all the things deserving of highlights this Saturday.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're not even mentioning the Short Track Roller Derby events this weekend to save space - they're all in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/shorttrack-102019/"&gt;this roundup post&lt;/a&gt; if you want to catch up with them (although we've marked them on the map). They're all highlights, but this is a super busy weekend, so something has to give.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 3rd fixture of the Chilean national tournament happens this weekend, as does the final of the New Zealand Top 10 Championshops 2019; as well as a number of large tournament events (perhaps the largest being in Sydney, Australia, and Lille, France). There's charity derby in Teesside, and even an international roller derby bootcamp up north in Iceland!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've bent the rules a bit this time, because it's important to highlight derby in regions which need more attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/19Oct-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-19102019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentine roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>austrian roller derby</category><category>belgian roller derby</category><category>bootcamps</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>chilean roller derby</category><category>czech roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>icelandic roller derby</category><category>korean roller derby</category><category>national tournaments</category><category>new zealand roller derby</category><category>northern irish roller derby</category><category>short track roller derby</category><category>south african roller derby</category><category>swedish roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-19102019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rollercon Nations Tournament 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/08/RNT-2019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the last few years, the National teams bouts have become a fixture of Rollercon.
Founded in 2017, before the last Roller Derby World Cup, they've been a great way for newer, or less visible National teams to be seen; and for raising awareness of the globally diverse nature of Roller Derby in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year was a particularly important point in the tournament's history, as two borderless nations - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/teamindigenousrollerderby/"&gt;Team Indigenous Rising&lt;/a&gt; (link to Facebook), and the new &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/jewishrollerderby/"&gt;Jewish Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; - competed in the tournament, and even played each other. (In fact, even the styling of the series of games as a true, all-day, tournament was a change this year, as previously there had not been enough competitors to realise this.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking for Team Indigenous, Jumpy McGee explained the importance of this to both teams:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Team Indigenous is extremely grateful to have this platform to bring our teams together and highlight that not all humans are defined by borders or citizenship.  There are centuries of displacement, violence, and oppression that have occurred causing people indigenous to their homeland to create home elsewhere.  We believe it was critical then to create a space where players identifying as a member of a nation had a place to belong.  And when WE talk about nation, we're talking about nation in the sense of a collection of humans who have the same cultures, beliefs, languages and traditions who cannot be contained or defined by borders.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2019 Nations tournament was run as an efficient double-elimination bracket, with seedings voted on by the competing teams. This means that each team could lose once in the tournament - that loss knocking them out of the "winners" bracket, and into a sudden-death bracket against other teams with a single loss. The eventual survivor of that sudden death bracket, having proven themselves the best of the teams, other than sole unbeaten team, gets to play in the final against that undefeated remainder. In this case, for time, all games were single period WFTDA-rules bouts, except for the final, run as a full-length WFTDA-rules game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as the two borderless nations, there were also three Asian nations represented: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/teamphilippines_rollerderby/"&gt;Team Philippines&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/teamkorearollerderby/"&gt;Team Korea&lt;/a&gt;, and Team "Japan-fam" (so named because they did not have a tryout and offered this opportunity to all skaters of Japanese heritage). This is also an important aspect of the event, and has been since it began, with Philippines and Korea founding members in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Action from the Korea / Philippines game, Philippines jammer on inside line passing blocked Korea jammer in pack." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/09/TristanKing-KoreaPhilippines.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Action from Korea versus Philippines (Photo: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/TKvisualarts"&gt;Tristan King&lt;/a&gt; [see link for license])&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As ShortStop noted for Korea, in particular:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
As a small nation, with relatively low representation in Roller Derby, [we] submitted an initial roster that included 8 Koreans, two skaters from OH Roller Derby Team (the only roller derby league in South Korea), and skaters from China, Vietnam, Thailand and Hong Kong. All of our non-Korean Asians are currently involved in building their own nations teams, and we thought it was a wonderful way to include them as start to gather their own teams.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Philippines' Electric PIRANHA, it's an equally strong, and personally important opportunity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
I have played sports throughout my whole life and have been playing roller derby now for four years. I never once in my life thought I would be able to represent a national team, a team that represents my heritage and culture. I had the opportunity to represent Team Philippines at the World Cup in Manchester and just recently in the Nations Tournament at RollerCon. Words cannot describe the feeling I get skating for Team Philippines. I am surrounded by smart, beautiful, athletic Filipinas. When we are together, there is an extraordinary and undeniable bond we have, like we've been skating together as a team for years when we only have had the chance to skate together a handful of times. We represent a country that has gone through colonization, war, and the fight for independence. I skate for my cultural heritage and I skate for my family. #pamilypirst #poweredbylumpia #poweredbyrice&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even for Japan, where there has been derby in some form for more than a decade, visibility is low, as we've discussed before on this blog.
Kris Rago, for Japan-fam noted to us that this was a factor in their participation here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Japan Fam was unique in the sense that roller derby is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/rdjapan/photos/a.316960268326566/2053816941307548/?type=3&amp;amp;permPage=1"&gt;present in Japan&lt;/a&gt; and that some of our skaters from both Japan and Hawaii were able to fly over and join our U.S. Japanese skaters. It was really wonderful to be able to come together and work together to represent our heritage and do amazing things on the track. My hope is more opportunities like this will help to strengthen the relationship between our U.S. Japanese skaters and skaters and leagues in Japan.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/08/RNT-2019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>international roller derby</category><category>jewish roller derby</category><category>team canada roller derby</category><category>team indigenous rising</category><category>team indigenous roller derby</category><category>team korea roller derby</category><category>team philippines roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/08/RNT-2019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 20:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chaos returns to Glasgow after 6 years.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/chaos2019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arguably one of the high points of roller derby in Glasgow was way back in August 2012, when Glasgow Roller Derby hosted their first
tournament event, &lt;em&gt;Chaos on the Clyde&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/884747741612081/"&gt;FB&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/17770"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120829101350/https://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/bouts-events/bouts-eventschaos2012/"&gt;WEB&lt;/a&gt; ). (This was also around the time that the National Museum of Roller Derby was getting going, and
so, as well as the international competition, the NMRD stall also helped to develop derby in different senses.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, thanks to the venue used being closed not long after, and other suitable venues being inaccessible, it's been 6 years now until Glasgow Roller Derby have been able to bring back the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Image of flyer for Chaos on the Clyde 2." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/07/Chaos2019flyer.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, back it is, with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/854543498244493/https://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/events-calendar/2019/8/17/chaos-on-the-clyde-2"&gt;Chaos on the Clyde 2&lt;/a&gt; hosted in GRD's regular venue of the ARC in late August this year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read on for more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/chaos2019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>chaos on the clyde</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/chaos2019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 07:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chilean National Championships 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/chile2019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, as part of our &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/tournaments2018/"&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; on National Tournaments around the World, we brought you up to date with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/26/chilean-national-championships-2018-torneo-x-returns/"&gt;Chile&lt;/a&gt;'s Championships, the Torneo X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the 2019 edition of the Torneo arriving very soon now, we thought it was time to catch you up on events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="map of Chile with teams competing in the two playoffs for Torneo X 2019" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/07/chile-2019-teams.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Chile's Torneo X teams for 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/chile2019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>chilean roller derby</category><category>national tournaments</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/chile2019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mexican National Championships 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/mexico2019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, as part of our &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/tournaments2018/"&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; on National Tournaments around the World, we brought you up to date with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/18/mexican-national-championships-2018/"&gt;Mexico&lt;/a&gt;'s Championships and ratings - one of the longest running
national tournaments in Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the 2019 edition of the Championships arriving very soon now, we thought it was time to catch you up on events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, Mexico City Roller Derby held the #1 spot for the WFTDA-gender division, with Baja California's Baja Roller Derby coming a close second... can this year shake up the dominance of the Mexico City teams?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="map of mexico with teams competing in the Division 1 and Division 2 tournaments for 2019 marked with stars." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/07/mexico-2019-teams.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Mexico Division 1 (red) and Division 2 (yellow) teams for 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/mexico2019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mexican roller derby</category><category>national tournaments</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/mexico2019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 20 July 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-20072019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend (and the week leading to it) is pretty dominated by the world's largest annual Roller Derby event, Rollercon. With people travelling across the world to attend, the schedule elsewhere is a little sparse, but there are still exciting things happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've also included a bonus section in this week's roundup highlighting sessions at Rollercon itself which we think are either interesting, or important, or both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This list was updated on Thursday 18th to include late announced bouts on Sunday in Mexico and Argentina&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/07/20Jul-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-20072019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentine roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>brazilian roller derby</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>mexican roller derby</category><category>national tournaments</category><category>new zealand roller derby</category><category>roller derby sevens</category><category>rollercon</category><category>short track roller derby</category><category>spanish roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><category>weekend highlights</category><category>WFTDA Officiating Clinic</category><category>WFTDA World Summit</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-20072019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WFTDA's Playoffs and Continental Cups - the costs for non-North Americans</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/nonNAchamps2019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last few days, the brackets and confirmed attendees for the WFTDA post-season events - WFTDA Division 1 Playoffs, and the WFTDA Continental Cups - have been announced.
This year continues the trend of increasing "worldwide" participation of teams in the post-season - which also means increasing average costs for the sport!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst we would like to congratulate all the teams on making Playoffs or CC, this article isn't just to celebrate them (even though we made a map to drive home the distribution)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We thought that providing some hard-ish numbers on costs might be useful, so we did a bit of calculation to feed discussion. More after the break...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="world map with WFTDA 2019 Playoffs and Continental Cup teams outside NA marked, coloured by the contest." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/07/WFTDA2019EndofSeason.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Our non-North-American teams for WFTDA Playoffs and Continental Cup, coloured by event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/nonNAchamps2019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>international derby</category><category>statistics</category><category>tournaments</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/nonNAchamps2019/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Guest Post: SKIR Golden Edition</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/skir2019-hazzard/</link><dc:creator>hazzard</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last month, Italy's largest Roller Derby tournament, Skate Im Ring (SKIR) held its Golden Edition, as always in Bolzano. Luckily for us, New Town Roller Derby's Hazzard
was attending, and has been good enough to provide us with this guest article!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 22nd and 23rd of June, 8 Italian roller derby teams and a swathe of officials had arrived at Arena Ritten, just outside of Bolzano in the North of Italy. They were to participate in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/423438998225036/"&gt;Skate Im Ring (SKIR) Golden Edition&lt;/a&gt; [link to Facebook] hosted by the Alp’n Rockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Image of the venue (Arena Ritten)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/07/ArenaRitten.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The fantastic Arena Ritten, host venue for SKIR 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weekend was the 4th edition of the SKIR and was its biggest edition so far.
The tournament consisted of a day of single-period ranking games and a day of full games. The teams were split into two groups and then seeded to go head to head with their counterparts in the other group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meeting with two of the organisers of SKIR, Betty Burp and Billi, we chatted about the previous editions of SKIR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/skir2019-hazzard/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>guest posts</category><category>italian roller derby</category><category>national tournaments</category><category>skate im ring</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/07/skir2019-hazzard/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BCR Host the final game day of Champs Tier 2 North</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/bcr_host_final_game_day_bct2nm/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/bairncityrollers"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; started off their 2019 and their champs campaign in the best way possible (you can read more about that here) . Their two wins in their first two Champs games saw them sit third in their group with six points despite having played one less game than the two teams above them, who had played three each. Their next two games came against those two teams: first they took on North Wales Mens and then T&amp;amp;F: Inglorious B*Stars. Both opponents took the wins in very hard fought games ending their 2019 Champs season 1st and 2nd in the group, 2 weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="British Champs Tier 2 M N leaderboard, showing the current state of play, including BCR at the middle of the table." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/MRDAside2-2019.png"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst those two teams have finished their champs season, the other teams in the group still have one more game and each team still has everything to play for. The last game day of Tier 2 North takes place on Scottish ground, with BCR hosting this fantastic battle at Grangemouth Sports Complex on the 29th of June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This double header could not have been set up more perfectly for the final set of games, as each match is a decider and will see the teams involved fighting for their final position against their opponent. Hosts BCR will be taking on The Inhuman League, with the winner of that game finishing 3rd in the group and the loser coming 4th. Whilst the other game will see Knights of Oldham play Teesside Skate Invaders, with the loser unfortunately ending up with the wooden spoon for the tier, and facing potential relegation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both games are shaping up to be quite a close battle as by their results so far each are evenly matched. So every team will be pulling out all the stops to get that final win in this years champs competition to finish above their opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors are at 1.15pm and tickets are only £5 on the door, find out more and keep up to date on the Facebook event page &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/2402082363156371/"&gt;https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/2402082363156371/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Flyer for the final fixtuer in British Champs Tier 2 M N; 29th June, 2019 at Grangemouth Sports Complex." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/06/BCR-flyer.png"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>british championships</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/bcr_host_final_game_day_bct2nm/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 11:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 16 June 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-16062019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the Sunday addendum edition of the highlights, for 16 June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're slightly breaking our usual rule this Sunday to allow two events for France. The French schedule of events is so dense, we end up overlooking many of them each weekend in only picking one, so we're selecting two equally important fixtures for this Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sun-toowoomba-qld-australia"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sun: Toowoomba, QLD, Australia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/403135743749698/"&gt;[FACEBOOK LINK]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.toowoombacityrollers.com/"&gt;Toowoomba City Juniors&lt;/a&gt; host a double scrimmage day for JRDA level 2 and 3 skaters: one scrim will be level 2 and one level 3. Skaters will also be encouraged to
try officiating the scrim they're not competing in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event starts: 1000 Sunday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venue: Gowrie Junction Progress Association and Community Hall, 24 Old Homebush Road, Gowrie Junction, QLD, Australia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sun-adelaide-sa-australia"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sun: Adelaide, SA, Australia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2092645010826971/RockabellasSausageSizzlefundraiserCristie'sBeach,SA,Australia"&gt;[FACEBOOK LINK]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/rockabellasrollerderby/"&gt;Rockabellas Roller Derby League&lt;/a&gt; host that most Australian of fundraisers, a Sausage Sizzle, to help raise funds for their Juniors and Officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event starts: 0800 Sunday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venue: The Original Open Market inc, 121 Beach Rd, Christies Beach, SA, Australia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sun-helsinki-finland"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sun: Helsinki, Finland&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/844404225893619/"&gt;[FACEBOOK LINK]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.helsinkirollerderby.com/"&gt;Helsinki Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; (or at least, those of them not in Canada) are part of "Jam in the Box"'s Skate Together open outdoor skate events, of which the first this year is today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event starts: 1700 Sunday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venue: Jam in the box, Vaasankatu 6, Helsinki, Finland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sun-nijmegen-netherlands"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sun: Nijmegen, Netherlands&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1998238140479360/"&gt;[FACEBOOK LINK]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://roadkillrollers.nl/"&gt;Roadkill Rollers&lt;/a&gt; host their inaugural "Small Teams Tournament", a one-day event aimed at giving smaller teams more opportunities to play in a tournament environment. This is an 8 team tournament, organised as 2 groups of 4, into a final between the top team in each group (for a total of 13 games in the day). Each game is 20 minutes long, based on the schedule. The tournament is OTA, but not all teams are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teams (Group A)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Market Gardeners (Eindhoven, Arnhem and Nijmegen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thunder &amp;amp; Lightning (Groningen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jammer Slammers (Arnhem??)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roller Derby Twente&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Group B)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roadkill Rollers (Nijmegen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keytown Roller Derby (Leiden-based exhibition team)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pink Peril Roller Derby (Limburg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blacksheep Honey Rollers (Middelburg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Games are not listed in FTS, as they are too short. (We'd still love to know the results, though)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event starts: 1200 Sunday (first game)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venue: Sporthal de Horstacker, Horstacker 1401, Nijmegen, Netherlands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sun-dunkirk-france"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sun: Dunkirk, France&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2080633558732883/"&gt;[FACEBOOK LINK]&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/110239"&gt;[FTS LINK]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://rollerderbydunkerquois.fr/"&gt;Sirènes Hurlants&lt;/a&gt; of Dunkirk host a triple header of Roller Derby on the French coast, with two scrimmages (one MRDA-gender and one WFTDA-gender), and a full game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Les Sirènes Hurlantes (Dunkirk) versus Les Nasty Pêcheresses (Montreuil B)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MRDA-gender Open Scrimmage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WFTDA-gender rookie Open Scrimmage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FTS lists only the first game, as scrimmages cannot be rated&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event starts: 1100 Sunday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venue: Lycée de l'Europe, 809 Rue du Banc Vert, Dunkirk, France&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sun-limoges-france"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sun: Limoges, France&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2292261411047390/"&gt;[FACEBOOK LINK]&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/110457/overview"&gt;[FTS LINK 1]&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/110458/overview"&gt;[FTS LINK 2]&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/110459/overview"&gt;[FTS LINK 3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limoges' &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.limogesrollerskating.info/roller-derby/"&gt;Porcelain Dolls&lt;/a&gt; host a triple header of French roller derby for a less-than-quiet Sunday. This is a round-robin tournament between Limoges, Quads de Paris, and Toulouse!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rainbow Furies (Toulouse C) versus Porcelain Dolls (Limoges)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;La Carcasse (Quads de Paris C) versus Rainbow Furies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Porcelain Dolls versus La Carcasse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event starts: 1000 Sunday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venue: Gymnases Municipaux Beaubreuil Hau, 84 rue Rhin et Danube, Limoges, France&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sun-loughborough-uk"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sun: Loughborough, UK&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/298862214339252/"&gt;[FACEBOOK LINK]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.dollyrockitrollers.co.uk/"&gt;Leicestershire Dolly Rockit Rollers&lt;/a&gt; are also helping to give people more games, with their "Love at First Fight", a WFTDA-gender policy rookie &amp;amp; intermediate tournament.
This is a three-team round-robin tournament with teams mixed up from the skaters signed up, with the three 30 minute games ending in a 40-minute final (presumably a rematch between the two highest ranked teams).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event starts: 1200 Sunday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venue: Loughborough Leisure Centre, Browns Lane, Loughborough, UK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sun-miramar-argentina"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sun: Miramar, Argentina&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2724617440913290/"&gt;[FACEBOOK LINK]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/atlantico_srd/"&gt;Atlántico Sur&lt;/a&gt; . &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cobraquadsrollerderby.com.ar/"&gt;Cobra Quads&lt;/a&gt; . &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/mdqueens_roller_derby/"&gt;MDQueens&lt;/a&gt; . &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/rebeldesdelasfalto"&gt;Rebeldes del Asfalto Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/sudestadard/"&gt;Sudestada Roller Derby Necochea&lt;/a&gt; are collaborating on a series of "Officials on the Atlantic Coast" referee and NSO clinics, designed to build and strengthen the officiating community along the Necochea to Mar del Plata area. (This is necessary to enable the proper support of Roller Derby in this area of Argentina, where, as you can see, there's a lot of teams already!). This first edition is hosted by Atlántico Sur in Miramar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event starts: 1700 Sunday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venue: Club Defensores, Miramar, Argentina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Sun:
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -

`[FACEBOOK LINK]`__
`[FTS LINK]`__

.. __:
.. __:

`Name`_ ...

.. _Name:

Event starts:

Venue: --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentine roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>dutch roller derby</category><category>finnish roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>officiating clinics</category><category>small teams</category><category>tournaments</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-16062019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>