<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about tournament)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/tournament.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:34:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>National Champions 2018 - a Review of the Year.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/01/09/national-champions-2018-a-review-of-the-year/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor's note: due to burn-out, and the increasingly obnoxious changes on the Wordpress backend, our end of year feature content has been delayed. We'll be releasing it over the next few weeks as we complete it. This is the first item in this content. We apologise for the delays incurred, and will update you all on the future of SRD when we know what that is.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the growth of Roller Derby worldwide, there has also come increasing regional organisation. Since 2010, and especially since the first Roller Derby World Cup in 2011 focussed thoughts on National structures, a number of nations, and nation-like entities, have begun organising various "National Tournaments" within themselves. At SRD, we consider these to be as important as any other large scale tournament - such as WFTDA or MRDA events - especially as they can also be more inclusive than such series due to reduced travel costs and membership requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, we'd like to highlight the winners of each such tournament series we're aware of in 2018 - and briefly cover the tournaments themselves. As a historical resource, we also host a summary of all of the winners of the tournaments (and some references for them) here: &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/NationalTournaments.html"&gt;National Tournaments (2010-)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;We'll start with the two largest such events (it's hard to judge which is larger, as they have exchanged places on various metrics year to year):&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;UK&amp;amp;Ireland ("&lt;a href="https://www.britishchamps.com/"&gt;British Championships&lt;/a&gt;")&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;British Champs has been running since 2015, and has made various changes to its structure over the years (the most recent to improve inclusion and accessibility). It is structured as a multi-tiered divisional system, with each "skill level" tier divided into one or more geographical "divisions"; teams promote/relegate between tiers between seasons. Since 2016, Champs has officially run parallel tournaments for WFTDA- and MRDA- conforming teams, and has also allowed competition from non-A teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, the WFTDA-side tournament winners, topping Tier 1 convincingly were: &lt;strong&gt;Central City Roller Derby (Birmingham), &lt;/strong&gt;not only winning every game against their opponents, but also achieving a significantly higher points difference than the second spot team, Liverpool.
2018 has been a good year for Birmingham teams, as the city's other team, Birmingham Blitz Dames, also hosted the first ever WFTDA Continental Cup in Europe later in the season.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MRDA-side tournament  was topped extremely impressively by &lt;strong&gt;New Wheeled Order (Manchester M)&lt;/strong&gt;, also delivering a huge points-difference advantage over second place Tyne and Fear. New Wheeled Order have had a very good few years, and we expect even more from them in 2019.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;France ("Championnat de France Roller Derby")&lt;/h4&gt;
The French National tournament series is, like the similarly sized British Champs, organised into Tiers by strength, and also loosely divided into geographical regions. (Unlike British Champs, there is competition across regions within a tier; also unlike BC, the Championnat is run directly as part of the French NGB, the FFRS.) The Championnat de France has &lt;em&gt;Feminin&lt;/em&gt;- and &lt;em&gt;Masculin&lt;/em&gt;- parallel tournaments; some leagues submit teams to the tournament which differ from their Travel teams, and the relaxed structure of the tournament also allows for "combined" team submissions from cooperating leagues. Unusually, compared to many of the other tournaments listed here, the French Championnat is fitted to the French sporting season (roughly following the European school year), and so starts in the previous winter, and finishes in the early summer each year.
&lt;p&gt;Repeating their victory in 2017, &lt;strong&gt;Nothing Toulouse (Roller Derby Toulouse)&lt;/strong&gt; retained the French Championship this year. They remain one of the few non-WFTDA member leagues to hold a Championship position in their home country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Undefeated champions since the Championnat started in 2016, &lt;strong&gt;Quad Guards (Toulouse M)&lt;/strong&gt; continued their streak for another year in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Whilst the French and British tournaments are the largest, they are not the longest running National tournaments. Next, we're going to cover the longest running tournaments in modern Derby, the four which started in 2012:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Sweden (Swedish Roller Derby Seriespel)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Swedish National Tournament,  . Like larger tournaments, the Series is split into tiers ("serien"), with the Eliteserien being the top tier. More recently, Elite tier teams have been allowed to differ from the Travel teams for their league. There is only a WFTDA-gender tournament in Sweden, to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Crime City Rollers (Malmö)&lt;/strong&gt; retained their Championship title for the third year running, placing them one more victory behind Stockholm's streak of 4 wins (from 2012 to 2015).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Finland (Suomi Cup)&lt;/h4&gt;
Finland's National Tournament is structured rather like the Swedish version, including the tendency of Elite tier leagues to submit non-Travel team rosters to the tournament. For the first time, in 2019 the Suomi Cup will be open to non-Finnish teams (making it an interesting extension of "National"), as St Petersburg Roller Derby A, the White Night Furies, compete.
&lt;p&gt;For the first time in 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Oulu Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; achieved the Championship title, breaking a run of alternating wins by Helsinki and Kallio over the previous 6 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Northern Finland also holds its own tournament - the Pohjola Cup - which started the tradition of welcoming non-Finnish participants in previous years via St Petersburg. So, in some ways, it sets the trend for its higher-profile southern relative.]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Mexico (Torneo Nacional de Roller Derby)&lt;/h4&gt;
Mexico's National Tournament series has been organised by their national governing body, the Asociación Mexicana de Roller Derby, since it began in 2012. We've covered the leadup to the current season on the blog previously here: &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/18/mexican-national-championships-2018/"&gt;Mexican National Tournament article&lt;/a&gt;. The series consists of a series of playoffs, selected by rating/ranking in the Mexican league tables (which work using the WFTDA rating scheme), with two divisions. As with many other nations, there are "varonil" and "femenil" parallel tournaments, corresponding to WFTDA- and MRDA- policies.
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Mexico City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; retained their title for a three-year streak of victories, despite&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Varonil side of the tournament, &lt;strong&gt;Disorder Roller Derby (Mexico City M)&lt;/strong&gt; also began a streak, retaining their title from 2017.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Colombia&lt;/h4&gt;
Whilst Colombia has run a National Tournament since 2012, the series has had a somewhat more complex past than the others in this category, with a couple of restructurings, and a hiatus from 2015 to 2016. In its current form, the Tournament consists of two parallel series - a multi-fixture tournament for Bogotá's many leagues (the "Torneo Distrito"), and a separate one for teams in the rest of Colombia (the "Western Region" tournament), with the top teams from both then competing at the Torneo Nacional finals. (&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/01/the-5th-colombian-national-tournament-2018-so-far/"&gt;We've written more about the 2018 series here.&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;p&gt;2018's Champions, &lt;strong&gt;Bogotá Bone Breakers&lt;/strong&gt;, also retained the Bogotá title in 2018, as well as continuing a three win streak in the national series (albeit across that 2 year gap).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Slightly less venerable than the oldest tournaments, but not in the size rank as Britain and France, our next grouping also covers a large geographical area.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Brazil (Brasileirão de Roller Derby)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brazil's national Championship, the Brasileirão, is a single-fixture event at present, which started as least as long ago as 2013 (there's some evidence it started earlier). Due to the distribution of teams in the country, it's semi-invitational, although the highest rated teams in Brazil always attend. (&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/11/the-brasileirao-brazils-national-championships-at-8/"&gt;We've written more about the history of the tournament here.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018's Brasileirão winners were &lt;strong&gt;Gray City Rebels (São Paulo)&lt;/strong&gt;, retaining the title from 2017 (and resisting Ladies of Helltown's attempts to take back the title from 2016).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Chile (Torneo X / Torneo X-Men)&lt;/h4&gt;
Chile has one of the youngest National Tournaments in Latin America, with the first Torneo X beginning in 2015. Year on year, it has gained more participants, and has had to change structure multiple times to accommodate this, currently using a playoffs and finals structure. For the first time in 2018, B teams have been allowed to compete, enabling Chile's strongest (and only WFTDA-member) league, Metropolitan Roller Derby, to compete with its Bayonetas.
Since 2017, there has also been a MRDA-gender tournament, the Torneo X-Men, run in parallel, and loosely associated with the original WFTDA-gender event.
(&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/26/chilean-national-championships-2018-torneo-x-returns/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We've covered an intro to this year's Torneo X earlier on the blog.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;p&gt;For the first time ever, 2018's winners are a B-team: &lt;strong&gt;Bayonetas (Metropolitan B | Santiago)&lt;/strong&gt;, taking a fairly commanding win in the final bout.
In the Torneo X-Men, which finished earlier in the year, &lt;strong&gt;Terror S-Quad (Santiago M)&lt;/strong&gt; were victorious for a second time in a row.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Germany (Bundesliga Roller Derby)&lt;/h4&gt;
The German National Tournament, or Bundesliga, formally started in 2015, as a multi-tier tournament run by the German NGB, Roller Derby Deutschland (RDD). In this form, its history has been tracked by Derbyposition.de since the beginning; the structure is much like the much larger French and British tournaments, but without the need for multiple geographical divisions, due to its smaller number of teams. (There were two previous events which might count as "German National Tournaments", in 2010 and 2013, but they are not part of the modern event.)
As with several other National series in nations with very high rated WFTDA-member leagues, those leagues have begun sending "non-Travel teams" to represent them in the tournament.
&lt;p&gt;For the first time in the tournament's history, &lt;strong&gt;Dresden Pioneers&lt;/strong&gt; comprehensively won the Bundesliga Division 1 in 2018.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Australia (Australian National Tournament &amp;amp; Australian Men's Nationals)&lt;/h4&gt;
Unusually, Australia has not had a formally denoted "National Tournament" for WFTDA leagues (although you could claim that the Great Southern Slam counts, given the scope of its attendance). The Australian Men's Roller Derby organisation, on the other hand, has organised an Australian Men's Nationals since 2015, as a single fixture tournament towards the end of the year.
More recently, an unusual "State-teams" style National Tournament has been launched (for the first time in 2018), with WFTDA- and MRDA- gender legs, but we're not sure if this counts as a National tournament in the same sense as the other events in this list.
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Victoria Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; won the Australian Men's Nationals, having lost it for the first time ever in 2017 (to Tasmania!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;For our final grouping, we have another eclectic selection of Nations, all united in having run a National series for 3 years or less.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;New Zealand (Top 10 Championships)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Zealand's "Top 10 Championships" have been running since 2016, although information on the second year of their organisation is a little patchy due to website bitrot. In general, the series is a flat round-robin style event, distributed across the year, with no tiering or geographical structure. As far as we are aware, there's only a WFTDA-gender version of the tournament so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Dead End Derby (Christchurch)&lt;/strong&gt; won the Top 10 Championships for the first time (ending Wellington's Richter City's streak of 2 years).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Spain (Campeonato Nacional de Roller Derby)&lt;/h4&gt;
The Spanish National tournament is a single event affair, due to the relatively small number of potential competitors in Spain at present. Organised by the Spanish National Governing body, the single tournament sees the top teams in the country play for victory in a single elimination structure. The event has run since 2016, with an additional MRDA parallel event introduced in 2017.
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Roller Derby Madrid&lt;/strong&gt; continued their unbroken win streak since the start of the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, 2018's winners in the other division were &lt;strong&gt;MadRiders (Madrid M)&lt;/strong&gt;, also continuing an unbroken win since last year.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Austria&lt;/h4&gt;
Austria's National tournament only started in 2017; before then, there was effectively only one sufficiently developed team in the country (Vienna Roller Derby), and so no way to hold such an event. Due to the small number of teams, the Austrian National Championship is a single fixture event; and due to the dearth of MRDA teams, it has only a WFTDA leg.
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Vienna Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; retained their title from 2017, although competition within the rest of the teams was strong, Vienna have a significant experience advantage in their country.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;South Africa (National Derby Fest)&lt;/h4&gt;
South Africa have held a National Championship event since 2016, although that first event included "home teams" from some of the leagues involved. As South Africa has very few leagues with travel teams, this event is a single fixture which also focuses on developing the sport within the nation. (&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/31/south-africas-national-derby-fest-2018-three-years-of-festivals/"&gt;We've written more about the history of the event here.&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, Johannesburg's &lt;strong&gt;Golden City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt; retained their win streak since the dawn of the tournament.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Belgium (Roller Derby Belgium National Tournament)&lt;/h4&gt;
Finally, we come to the newest National tournament in our list: Belgium. The Belgian national tournament, organised by rd.BE, the Belgian NGB, ran for the first time this year, as a year-long series of round-robin fixtures within tiers. (Initial tiers were drawn from FTS Europe ratings.) From the start, the rd.BE event has had a WFTDA- and an MRDA- leg.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antwerp Roller Derby (One Love Roller Dolls)&lt;/strong&gt; are the first ever holders of the rd.BE Championship title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the MRDA leg, Brussels' &lt;strong&gt;Manneken Beasts&lt;/strong&gt; achieved the first ever Championship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Special mention:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Japan (Derby Nights 4x4)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst it's structure is rather different to every other event in this list, we should note that Japan has also had a Tokyo-series first for the first time in 2018. The Derby Nights 4x4 ("DN4x4") series was a multi-fixture event with "womens" and "mens" legs, open to leagues of all affiliations in Japan. (As such, the women's division included both the World Skate/FIRS affiliated Spiral Cats, and all of the WFTDA-affiliated leagues in the Tokyo metropolitan area, from Tokyo Roller Derby to the independent Kamikaze Badass.) This was a unique ruleset, with, we believe, 4 skaters per competing team, and very short period and jam lengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Neon Roller Monsters&lt;/strong&gt; (the submitted team from Tokyo Roller Derby) won the women's division.
The new-in-2018 team, &lt;strong&gt;Tokyo Bar Hoppers&lt;/strong&gt;, won the men's division (which had only 2 teams this year!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're excited to see what happens with this tournament format, and if it expands beyond the Tokyo region to the rest of Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>asociación mexicana de roller derby</category><category>australian men's nationals</category><category>austrian nationals</category><category>brasileirão de roller derby</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>bundesliga</category><category>campeonato nacional de roller derby</category><category>championnat de france</category><category>derby nights 4x4</category><category>international derby</category><category>national derby fest</category><category>rd.be</category><category>suomi cup</category><category>swedish seriespel</category><category>top 10 championships</category><category>torneo nacional de roller derby</category><category>torneo x</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/01/09/national-champions-2018-a-review-of-the-year/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 16:53:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-US/Canadian Derby Roundup: 22nd December to end of year Edition</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/18/non-us-canadian-derby-roundup-22nd-december-to-end-of-year-edition/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;We’re bringing you another roundup of the upcoming Roller Derby this weekend from across the world. As always, we’re using &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/" data-mce-href="http://flattrackstats.com/"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for much of this information – for regions with less good coverage, we also do a bit of intensive searching using a tool which scans the Facebook events of Roller Derby leagues known to &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://derbylisting.com/dl/grid/" data-mce-href="http://derbylisting.com/dl/grid/"&gt;Derby Listing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Predictions of bouts are from FTS, if possible, and from our own &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRankv2.html" data-mce-href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRankv2.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; where FTS cannot make predictions (for example: Latin America, or non-MRDA men’s bouts). (SRDRank also has recent WFTDA rankings, including the 31st June ranking, as well as SRDRank, and allows you to make predictions from them.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;If we’ve missed you from our roundup, please let us know! [Or add yourselves to FTS and/or Derbylisting]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We're trying a new colour coding this week, to differentiate &lt;span style="color:#800000;" data-mce-style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;BOUTS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; from &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;RECRUITMENTS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style="color:#993300;" data-mce-style="color: #993300;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;OPEN SCRIM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;s, and &lt;span style="color:#008000;" data-mce-style="color: #008000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BOOTCAMP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;s.
&lt;p&gt;This roundup is our end of year roundup, so covers everything until the new year (also because there's just not much stuff happening).&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/EUR_map-1.png?w=1024" alt="EUR_map" width="1024" height="768" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27893"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Scotland&lt;/h3&gt;
Scotland is still pretty full of skating this weekend before Christmas, with the Last Scrim of 2018 on Friday...
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Wed, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edinburgh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Edinburgh's first Junior Derby team, the Boardwalk Bombs  practices and recruits at The Boardwalk, every Wednesday [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/264021497777923/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/264021497777923/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;strong&gt;Dumbarton&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicks in Bowls Scotland host Quad Meet sessions [6-10pm, Unit23 Skatepark][&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/571664849967506/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/571664849967506/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Glasgow Men's Roller Derby's ongoing new skater intake continues every Friday, for the foreseeable future! [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/538450946579720/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/538450946579720/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#993300;" data-mce-style="color: #993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Glasgow Men's Roller Derby also see out the year with The Last Scrim of 2018, an Open To All scrimmage event [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2058400910894339/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2058400910894339/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grangemouth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Bairn City Rollers rolling recruitment continues in their Friday sessions. Open to all genders. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/290765008244029/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/290765008244029/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edinburgh&lt;/strong&gt;: The Boardwalk hosts a "Special Christmas Roller Disco" for all ages [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/340885586687429/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/340885586687429/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Resistance Roller Derby, Glasgow's Junior Roller Derby club for queer and trans young people continue their training sessions open to new skaters and existing. [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ResistanceRDG/posts/2188691664720225" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/ResistanceRDG/posts/2188691664720225"&gt;EVENT Flyer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kirkwall&lt;/strong&gt;: Orkney ViQueens host a festive Family Roller Disco for all ages. Fancy dress encouraged. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1288092327997647/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1288092327997647/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicks in Bowls Scotland host a Sunday Skate followed by a park skate outside [Transition Extreme Sports] [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/235245817133829/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/235245817133829/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Next Sat (29th), &lt;strong&gt;Edinburgh&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicks in Bowls Scotland host a Skatemanay Quad Skate night at the Transgression Park. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/797604653910341/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/797604653910341/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/h3&gt;
Christmas in the UK means... the final scrimmage of the year.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;span style="color:#993300;" data-mce-style="color: #993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carlisle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Border City Roller Derby host an Open Christmas Scrim, Open To All genders. Fancy dress encouraged. Referees and NSOs welcome. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2185180175028358/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2185180175028358/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;Scarborough&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Scarborough Slammers host a Christmas Roller Disco open to all ages. Fancy dress encouraged. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/454162931775690/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/454162931775690/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Europe&lt;/h3&gt;
Europe is still pretty busy, with both France and Belgium hosting public bouts (in Belgium's case, the last fixture in their first ever Championships!).
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prague&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Czech Republic: the Hard Breaking Dolls host the second of 5 open training sessions, for interested potential competitive skaters, referees or NSOs. (Skaters limited to WFTDA-gender policy.) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/536798893399081/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/536798893399081/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;Tallinn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Estonia: Tallinn Roller Girls continue to host their open training sessions on Fridays for all interested attendees. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2130649673675124/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2130649673675124/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tartu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Estonia: Tartu Roller Derby also continue their open training sessions for all interested attendees. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2102606236669992/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2102606236669992/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#993300;" data-mce-style="color: #993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Groningen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Netherlands: Roller Derby Groningen host an Open Scrimmage, Open To All genders (and ages, including juniors), both for the Holiday season, and also to bid farewall to their current hall space. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/341700253046775/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/341700253046775/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#993300;" data-mce-style="color: #993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rotterdam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Netherlands: Rotterdam Roller Derby host an "Open Holiday Scrimmage", the third of three (one each Friday before Christmas). We think these are OTA, and are also open to NSOs. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/316023082321334/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/316023082321334/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vienna&lt;/strong&gt;, Austria: Vienna Fearleaders present their release party for their current calendar, as well as an excuse to see them perform live! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1945031492200598/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1945031492200598/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;" data-mce-style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Melrand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: Roller Derby La Ferraille host a Christmas match [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/474210783103734/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/474210783103734/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;La Ferraille versus Les Sabordeuses (Brest B) [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a data-mce-href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/106158" href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/106158"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;" data-mce-style="color: #800000;"&gt;Antwerp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Belgium: Antwerp Roller Derby host the final Belgian Championship fixtures of the year, deciding Division 1 W.  [&lt;a data-mce-href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/104124/overview" href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/104124/overview"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2083881251922264/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2083881251922264/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;One Love Roller Dolls (Antwerp) versus GO-GO Gent Roller Derby [rd.be champs d 1]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Open scrimmage. (Against Antwerp B?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#993300;" data-mce-style="color: #993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lleida&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Spain: The Mediterranean Rollers (Barcelona O) and the Sicarias del Cierzo host an Open To All genders and abilities Christmas Open Scrimmage [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/307896600066112/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/307896600066112/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Mon, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warsaw&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Poland: Worst Warsaw's Open recruitment continues for interested potential members in any roles! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2024174427621904/?" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2024174427621904/?"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Wed, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ostrava&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Czech Republic: Trojhali Ostrava Roller Derby continue their open training and rolling recruitment? [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1139929732833996/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1139929732833996/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pacific&lt;/h3&gt;
It seems very quiet in the Asia-Pacific region before the end of year.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Next Sat (29th), &lt;strong&gt;Eltham&lt;/strong&gt;, VIC, Australia: Diamond Valley Roller Derby Club host a "Sausage Sizzle and Bake Sale". [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1935206959861597/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1935206959861597/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/LA_map-5.png?w=1024" alt="LA_map" width="1024" height="768" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27894"&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Latin America&lt;/h3&gt;
The Latin American region is always the hardest for us to find things in. We'd appreciate any heads-up about things we've missed!
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sat, &lt;strong&gt;Bahía Blanca&lt;/strong&gt;, Argentina: Brujas Roller Girls are either holding or attending a Truco tournament (Truco being an Argentinean card game) today. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BahiaRD/photos/a.1053885397961848/2514381115245595/?type=3&amp;amp;theater" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/BahiaRD/photos/a.1053885397961848/2514381115245595/?type=3&amp;amp;theater"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT Flyer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#993300;" data-mce-style="color: #993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;San Salvador de Jujuy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Argentina: Mortal Kollas and Coquena's Fighter co-host a "Roller Derby Christmas" bout. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/305007883441118/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/305007883441118/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Quienes () versus Grinchs (exhibition/open subs game)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Africa and Middle East&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>weekly roundup</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/18/non-us-canadian-derby-roundup-22nd-december-to-end-of-year-edition/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 15:11:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-US/Canadian Derby Roundup: 15th/16th December Edition</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/12/non-us-canadian-derby-roundup-15th-16th-december-edition/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;We’re bringing you another roundup of the upcoming Roller Derby this weekend from across the world. As always, we’re using &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for much of this information – for regions with less good coverage, we also do a bit of intensive searching using a tool which scans the Facebook events of Roller Derby leagues known to &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://derbylisting.com/dl/grid/"&gt;Derby Listing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Predictions of bouts are from FTS, if possible, and from our own &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRankv2.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; where FTS cannot make predictions (for example: Latin America, or non-MRDA men’s bouts). (SRDRank also has recent WFTDA rankings, including the 31st June ranking, as well as SRDRank, and allows you to make predictions from them.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;If we’ve missed you from our roundup, please let us know! [Or add yourselves to FTS and/or Derbylisting]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We're trying a new colour coding this week, to differentiate &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;BOUTS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; from &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;RECRUITMENTS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;OPEN SCRIM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;s, and &lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BOOTCAMP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;s.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/12/non-us-canadian-derby-roundup-15th-16th-december-edition/eur_map-32/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-27859"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter wp-image-27866 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/EUR_map.png?w=700" alt="" width="580" height="435"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scotland&lt;/h3&gt;
Scotland is surprisingly busy this close to Christmas, with Glasgow Men's Roller Derby hosting their MRDA-policy rookie skater game on the Saturday, and also their returning mini-bootcamp series.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Wed, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edinburgh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Edinburgh's first Junior Derby team, the Boardwalk Bombs  practices and recruits at The Boardwalk, every Wednesday [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/264021497777923/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;strong&gt;Dumbarton&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicks in Bowls Scotland host Quad Meet sessions [6-10pm, Unit23 Skatepark][&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/571664849967506/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Glasgow Men's Roller Derby's ongoing new skater intake continues every Friday, for the foreseeable future! [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/538450946579720/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grangemouth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Bairn City Rollers rolling recruitment continues in their Friday sessions. Open to all genders. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/290765008244029/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grangemouth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Bairn City Rollers combine the above with an Open Scrim (presumably Open To All genders), with a Christmas theme [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2240785815966781/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Resistance Roller Derby, Glasgow's Junior Roller Derby club for queer and trans young people continue their training sessions open to new skaters and existing. [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ResistanceRDG/posts/2188691664720225"&gt;EVENT Flyer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grangemouth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Glasgow Men's Roller Derby host an MRDA-policy centred Debut Skater game, aimed at encouraging and developing the MRDA side of the sport in Scotland. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/258084504904639/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicks in Bowls Scotland host a Sunday Skate followed by a park skate outside [Transition Extreme Sports] [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/235245817133829/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tues, &lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicks in Bowls Scotland host a regular Quad Meet (Transition Extreme) [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1770144559760410/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tues, &lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edinburgh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Glasgow Men's Roller Derby host the 8th edition of Jammer Club, their irregular series of Jammer "mini-bootcamp"s, coached by Optimus Grime. Open To All genders. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/286597728865042/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/h3&gt;
Christmas in the UK as a whole means "scrimmage", and there's a huge number of open scrims of various gender policies across the country. The only actual public bout we know of is in Halifax, however.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Wed, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swansea&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Wales: Swansea City Roller Derby host a Christmas Open Scrim, open to WFTDA gender policy conforming skaters (and all referees, NSOs). [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/327947104668678/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leeds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Leeds Roller Derby host a Christmas Guest Skater night (essentially an open scrim and training), open to WFTDA-gender-policy conforming skaters. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1138538202970912/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;Middlesbrough&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Middlesbrough Roller Derby host a Christmas themed Open Scrimmage (team Santa v team Elf). No gender policy stated. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1935495183197611/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;Barrow-in-Furness&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Furness Roller Derby host a Christmas Roller Disco to close out the year. Appearance by Santa Claus guaranteed for the children attending. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1493371527462878/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;Stratford&lt;/strong&gt;, England: London Rockin' Rollers host a "meet the Rookies" event, as a social welcome to the league. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/359700001265488/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basingstoke&lt;/strong&gt;, England: The Basingstoke Bullets host a Xmas Fun Skate, open to all skaters of all abilities, fancy dress encouraged. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/252961858706066/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leeds&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Double Threat Skates host another of their regular Pop Up Shops "Up North", with a free open skate too. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1988543731179375/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lincoln&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Lincolnshire Bombinos host a Junior Derby open mixed scrim (open to Junior skaters, entry fee applies) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/280014262645530/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lincoln&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Lincolnshire Bombers also host a Christmas Roller Disco, raising funds for SANDS (Sillbirths And Neonatal DeathS) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/767019970314204/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nottingham&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Nottingham Hellfire Harlots host a Christmas Craft Fair (with free entry), supporting homemade and local crafts. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2212063269007184/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oldham&lt;/strong&gt;, England: The Knights of Oldham host a "Saturday Knight Fever" Roller disco... [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/263121284546342/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grimsby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Grimsby Roller Derby host "Home Alone" an Xmas Charity Scrim event. (Actually two scrims, both raising funds for the charity "Not Home Alone"). [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/257304228305240/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;WFTDA-gender-policy scrim&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;OTA genders scrim.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Halifax&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: The Bruising Banditas host a double header "Snow Brawl" [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/749425978734851/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;WFTDA-aligned Skater Debut bout: Jingle Belles versus Candy Canors&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Bruising Banditas (Halifax) versus Spa Town Roller Derby (Harrogate) [FTS]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;Manchester&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Manchester Roller Derby host their End of Year, Mixed Level, Open To All genders Open Scrim! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/555927811509741/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nottingham&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Nottingham Hellfire Harlots follow up their Fair with an Open Christmas Scrim, open to WFTDA-gender-policy conforming skaters. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1408727432563803/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oadby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Leicestershire Dolly Rockit Rollers host "Propeh Scrimbo", an Open To All genders Open Scrim. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1108734799293052/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wallasey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Wirral Roller Derby and the Pack Animals co-host a Super Sunday Scrim, a scrim event Open To All genders, with WFTDA-gender and MRDA-gender policy lineups for max inclusivity [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/339395616808792/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tues, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sheffield&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Sheffield Steel Rollergirls host their December Megascrim, 90-minutes of Open scrim, open to WFTDA-gender-policy conforming skaters. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/279606026224237/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Europe&lt;/h3&gt;
Europe... and especially France... is very much still in bouting mood this close to Christmas. There's a huge number of tournaments (and single headers) across the continent, including Belgian Championship games and German Bundesliga fixtures.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prague&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Czech Republic: the Hard Breaking Dolls host the first of 5 open training sessions, for interested potential competitive skaters, referees or NSOs. (Skaters limited to WFTDA-gender policy.) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/536798893399081/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toulouse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: Roller Derby Toulouse host the last of their Recruitment days for their Men's Derby component (QuadGuards et al). [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/330799877471861/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;Tallinn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Estonia: Tallinn Roller Girls continue to host their open training sessions on Fridays for all interested attendees. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2130649673675124/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tartu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Estonia: Tartu Roller Derby also continue their open training sessions for all interested attendees. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2102606236669992/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rotterdam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Netherlands: Rotterdam Roller Derby host an "Open Holiday Scrimmage", the second of three (one each Friday before Christmas). We think these are OTA, and are also open to NSOs. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/316023082321334/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Coruña&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Spain: As Brigantias host a Recruitment / Intro To Roller Derby outreach event, with the assistance of the City Council [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2401301499943991/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oulu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Finland: Oulu Roller Derby celebrate the festive season with a B teams single header [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/298449800779543/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Oulu B versus Tampere B [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/106216"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;Anglet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, France: Roller Derby Côte Basque host a Happy Derby Christmas event... [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/272417090081897/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Valient Bitchiz (Bayonne) versus Botxo Killers (Bilbo) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105359"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charleroi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Belgium: The Blackland Rockin' K-Rollers host a quadruple header as part of the Belgian Championships. [FTS tournament][&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/569425380158917/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Blackland Randy Devils (Charleroi M) versus RATM (Arras M) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/106008"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Atomium Kittens (Brussels B) versus Blackland Rockin K-Rollers [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/104125/overview"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RD.be D 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Brussels Derby Pixies (Brussels) versus Namur Roller Girls [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/104124/overview"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RD.be D 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Atomium Kittens versus Holy Wheels Menace (Leige) [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/104125/overview"&gt;RD.be D 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bordeaux&lt;/strong&gt;, France: Roller Derby Bordeaux Club co-hosts a weekend of open skating events, with skating from 2pm on Sat, and all day on Sun [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2364285910312090/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: B.M.O Roller Derby Girls host a single header for Xmas [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2170289309658658/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Toutes Étoiles (Brest) versus Les Duchesses (Nantes) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/106119"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;Cholet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, France: Cholet Roller Derby host an recruitment day as part of the Cholet Decathlon, including a demonstration [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/294801631133456/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clermont-Ferrand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: the Auver'Niaks host a festive double header("Le Père Noël est une jammeuse."). [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/304956910344529/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Auver'Niaks B (Clermont-Ferrand B) versus Bloody Angels (Melun) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105896"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Auver'Niaks A versus Reaper's Crew (Epinal) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105895"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sat+Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dijon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: The Velvet Owls host a weekend of Roller Derby, "Jammer is Coming". [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/260656024622294/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Namur Glorious Basterds (Namur M) versus La Raclée (Dijon M) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105689"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Zombeers (Calais M) versus Namur Glorious Basterds [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105690"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;La Raclée versus Zombeers [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105691"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dead Dragibus (Calais J) versus Les P'tits Bou'Niaks (Clermont-Ferrand J) [FTS?]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Velvet Must'Hard (Dijon B) versus Black Tagada (Calais) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/106215"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sainte Geneviève des Bois&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: The Psyko'Quads host a single header event with little fanfare [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2105784676150794/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Psyko'Quads (Sainte Geneviève des Bois) versus Knock'n'Roll Cannibals (Creil) [FTS]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sat+Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strasbourg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: Hell's Ass Derby Girls and Les Menneles co-host Bretz'Hell Battle, a "Coed" Grand Tournament, with several OTA teams competing. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/293310274785376/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Le Peine Capitale (Paris O) versus Strasbourg Roller Derby (Hell's Ass + Les Menneles | Strasbourg O)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;UB (open subs OTA team) versus Orcet (Orcet RD + Wolfgang | Orcet O)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;La Peine Capitale versus UB&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Strasbourg versus Orcet&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Le Peine Capitale versus Orcet&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Strasbourg versus UB&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;"final" and "3rd place?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;The Hague&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Netherlands: The Parliament of Pain host "The Fight Before Christmas: Onion Edition". This is a triple header of OTA derby, with open-subs teams, and a raffle! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/265162317599269/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;X-Mas Circus versus X-Mas on Ice&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;X-Mas on Ice versus X-Mas at Iron Mist's&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;X-Mas at Iron Mist's versus X-Mas Circus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sat-Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Candeán&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Spain: Lobishomes Men's Roller Derby host their first mixed tournament, Full Moon Showdown. There's not much public info about the teams attending, however. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/994366180754996/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Teams Attending:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jabatas Roller Derby (Ourense)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Lobishommes (Galicia/Vigo M)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;"Spanish mash-up team"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geneva&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Switzerland: Genève Roller Derby United host "Les Matchs del la marmite" (referring to the pot, not the savoury spread), a double header event. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/169854680568961/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Les Taxider'Biches (Léman A) versus Mères Royaume (Geneva) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105984"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Cannibal Marmots Cééé (Grenoble C) versus Black Votchkas (Neuchâtel + Fribourg mix)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Braine-le-Comte&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Belgium: Manneken Beasts host a triple header of MRDA derby games in the return of their "Merry Hitmas" event [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1805380902894444/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Manneken Beasts (Brussels M) versus Panam Squad (Paris M) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105154"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tampere Rollin' Bros (Tampere M) versus Panam Squad [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105155"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Manneken Beasts versus Tampere Rollin' Bros [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105153"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;Dijon&lt;/strong&gt;, France: Roller Derby Dijon (we assume) host a Round Table on the future of Junior Roller Derby in France. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/266594554206929/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ligugé&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: Les Broyeuses du Poitou host the third edition of their winter tournament, Winter is Rolling. This edition is a triple header [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/685226385198076/permalink/709059599481421/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Marcheuses Blanches versus La Garde de Nuit ("White Walkers" versus "Night's Watch"), mixed teams.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Broyeuses du Poitou (Poitiers) versus Pirnanas (Chateauroux) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/106159"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Grandes Goulges (Poitiers O?) versus Royales Mandales (Rennes O?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lille&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: Lomme Roller Girls host a triple header event to close the season, against all of Paris! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/283433205498718/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tétons Flingueurs (Lomme C) versus San Culottes (Paris C) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105090"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Glorious Bâtardes (Lomme B) versus Quedalles (Paris B) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105091"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Bad Bunnies (Lomme A) versus Paris All-stars (Paris A) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105092"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
&lt;p id="u_1z_0" class="_52c9"&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;Montpezat-sous-Bauzon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, France: The Criminal Nurses of Aubenas host a Christmas double-header, the 4th edition of "Track's Anatomy". [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/120149342195197/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Criminal Nurses (Aubenas) versus Head Hunters (Narbonne) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105804"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;White v Black UB (open subs) game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sainte Geneviève des Bois&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: The Psyko'Quads return with a second fixture, a Scrimmage/Friendly game  [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/197917064430842/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Psyko'Quads (Sainte Geneviève des Bois) versus Channibals Lecters (Creil B) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105844"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;?}&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karlsruhe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Germany: The rocKArollers host one of the last sets of Bundesliga Div 2 fixtures in this season [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/99250/overview"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS Tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/551235075329922/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Delta Quads (Mannheim) versus Riot Rollers (Darmstadt) [Bundesliga D 2]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;rocKArollers (Karlsruhe) versus Demolition Derby Dolls (Hannover) [Bundesliga D 2]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Västerås&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Sweden: Västerås Roller Derby host "All I Want for Christmas is a Roller Derby Double Header"... a Roller Derby Double header. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/261405811190480/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Västerås Roller Derby versus LKPG Go'Rullaz (Linköping) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/106141"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Västerås Roller Derby versus Sundsvall Demolition Rollers [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/106136"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Mon, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warsaw&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Poland: Worst Warsaw's Open recruitment continues for interested potential members in any roles! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2024174427621904/?"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Mon, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zürich&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Switzerland: Zürich City Roller Derby host their next open tryouts for those interested in joining the team, in any capacity. Open To All genders. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2086866721375900"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tues, &lt;strong&gt;A Coruña&lt;/strong&gt;, Spain: As Brigantias follow up their open recruitment day with an outreach event at Centro Social A Comuna [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2210725422538195/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Wed, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ostrava&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Czech Republic: Trojhali Ostrava Roller Derby continue their open training and rolling recruitment [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1139929732833996/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/?attachment_id=27860#main" rel="attachment wp-att-27860"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27860" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/anz_map1.png?w=700" alt="" width="580" height="435"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pacific&lt;/h3&gt;
It... seems... very quiet in Australia, New Zealand and the Asia-Pacific region this weekend, but it's also possible we're missing events. Do let us know if we've missed you.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;Westbury&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, TAS, Australia: Devil State Derby League host their regular Monthly Scrim, Open To All skaters. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/804779056567723/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;California Gully&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, VIC, Australia: Dragon City Roller Derby host "Wreck the Halls", a Christmas Scrimmage event. Open to WFTDA-gender-policy conforming skaters, 16+ age. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/342318496574482/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Low contact Scrimmage&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full contact Scrimmage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/12/non-us-canadian-derby-roundup-15th-16th-december-edition/la_map-26/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-27861"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter wp-image-27885 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/LA_map-4.png?w=700" alt="" width="580" height="435"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Latin America&lt;/h3&gt;
The big event in Latin America is the Huiñas returning tournament Quad Beer II, covering teams across Argentina!
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Córdoba&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Argentina: Insubordinades Roller Derby Disidente host their third intraleague game with almost no notice (event announced the day before) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/InsubordinadesRD/photos/a.334590297032649/498266763998334/?type=3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT Flyer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sat+Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bariloche&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Argentina: The Huiñas Roller Derby host their second Tournament, Quad Beer II. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/261378434507283/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Teams:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Huinas Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Hijas de Pantano&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ambulatory Derby Team&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Barderas Insurrectas (Neuquen)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Hienas de la Calle (Neuquen)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Moron Roller Derby (Moròn)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Zapala Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Day 1 schedule:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Huiñas versus Moron [FTS]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ambulatory versus Zapala&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Moron versus Barderas Insurrectas&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Zapala versus Hienas de la Calle&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Barderas Insurrectas versus Huiñas&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Hienas de la Calle versus Ambulatory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;Rio de Janeiro&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Brazil: Avas Roller Derby host a recruitment day for interested new skaters. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/avasrollerderby/photos/a.334188037153430/387727361799497/?type=3&amp;amp;theater"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valdivia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Chile: Roller Derby Valdivia celebrate their 3rd birthday with a triple header event! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/352057925558568/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Indomitas RD (Valdivia) vs Diosas Volcánicas (Puerto Montt)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Indomitos RD (Valdivia O) vs Coed Chillan (Chillan O)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Colusion Austral (Valdivia? M) vs Chillanrrolleros (Chillan M)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bogota&lt;/strong&gt;, Colombia: Rock N Roller Queens celebrate their 9th birthday with a "Tropical Queens" party event! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/931973800335033/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="_6int"&gt;
&lt;div class="_6f1m"&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class="_6euq"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;San Jose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Costa Rica: Panties Dinamita Roller Derby host an international game to finish their year! There's only a mysterious instagram post to confirm this... [&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BqYLu7FAUIx/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT Flyer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Panties Dinamita (Costa Rica/San Jose) versus Burdel Zombie (Mexico City) [FTS]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ciudad Juarez&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Mexico: Medias Rotas Juniors host their final home-teams game of the year [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Mediasrotasjunior/photos/a.1035789499791411/1971728366197515/?type=3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Grinch versus Santa Claus (Junior home teams)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;Buenos Aires&lt;/strong&gt;, Argentina: Kamikazes Roller Derby celebrate their 6th birthday with a party - which is also raising funds for local animal shelters. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/352726782181610/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;São Paulo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Brazil: the Ladies of Helltown are hosting an "open training" session for any interested potential members who want to experience the sport. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2014103785337063/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;San Joaquín&lt;/strong&gt;, Chile: Unión Subversiva Roller Derby host a "Roller Derby Flea Market" as a fundraiser and source of unique festive gifts [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1999206777046397/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mexico City&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;?, Mexico: Jaibronas Roller Derby are hosted for triple-header "friendly" against two of Mexico City Roller Derby's teams, which is a &lt;em&gt;debut&lt;/em&gt; for the Jaibronas! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/264684001065739/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jaibronas (Tampico Madero) versus Quadtlicues (Mexico City)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jaibronas versus Catrinas (Mexico City)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Quadtlicues versus Catrinas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Africa and Middle East&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>upcoming events</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/12/non-us-canadian-derby-roundup-15th-16th-december-edition/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 16:13:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-US/Canadian Derby Roundup: 8th/9th December Edition</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/05/non-us-canadian-derby-roundup-8th-9th-december-edition/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;We’re bringing you another roundup of the upcoming Roller Derby this weekend from across the world. As always, we’re using &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for much of this information – for regions with less good coverage, we also do a bit of intensive searching using a tool which scans the Facebook events of Roller Derby leagues known to &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://derbylisting.com/dl/grid/"&gt;Derby Listing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Predictions of bouts are from FTS, if possible, and from our own &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRankv2.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; where FTS cannot make predictions (for example: Latin America, or non-MRDA men’s bouts). (SRDRank also has recent WFTDA rankings, including the 31st June ranking, as well as SRDRank, and allows you to make predictions from them.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;If we’ve missed you from our roundup, please let us know! [Or add yourselves to FTS and/or Derbylisting]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We're trying a new colour coding this week, to differentiate &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;BOUTS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; from &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;RECRUITMENTS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;OPEN SCRIM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;s, and &lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BOOTCAMP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;s.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/?attachment_id=27824#main" rel="attachment wp-att-27824"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27824" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/eur_map.png?w=700" alt="" width="580" height="435"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scotland&lt;/h3&gt;
Scotland is a little quieter this weekend, as Christmas approaches. There's still a chance to get some track time in Aberdeen on Thursday though.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Wed, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edinburgh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Edinburgh's first Junior Derby team, the Boardwalk Bombs  practices and recruits at The Boardwalk, every Wednesday [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/264021497777923/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Granite City Roller Derby host an Open (WFTDA-gender) Scrim, free for first time attendees. Visiting officials also welcome. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/240321319974597/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;strong&gt;Dumbarton&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicks in Bowls Scotland host Quad Meet sessions [6-10pm, Unit23 Skatepark][&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/571664849967506/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;Dundee&lt;/strong&gt;: Dundee Roller Derby host their annual Christmas Party, celebrating the end of the year and season, including a quiz! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/179830772945510/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;Edinburgh&lt;/strong&gt;: Auld Reekie Roller Derby host their end of year Awards Night for 2018! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/267718480551007/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Glasgow Men's Roller Derby's ongoing new skater intake continues every Friday, for the foreseeable future! [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/538450946579720/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grangemouth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Bairn City Rollers rolling recruitment continues in their Friday sessions. Open to all genders. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/290765008244029/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Resistance Roller Derby, Glasgow's Junior Roller Derby club for queer and trans young people continue their training sessions open to new skaters and existing. [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ResistanceRDG/posts/2188691664720225"&gt;EVENT Flyer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicks in Bowls Scotland host a Sunday Skate followed by a park skate outside [Transition Extreme Sports] [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/235245817133829/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tues, &lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicks in Bowls Scotland host a regular Quad Meet (Transition Extreme) [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1770144559760410/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/h3&gt;
Across the rest of the UK, there's a host of bouts, even a week into December, even if most are charity style events.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle upon Tyne&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Newcastle Roller Girls host a Christmas Movie Pub Quiz  [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/302177010636302"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;Lincoln&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Lincolnshire Bombers Roller Derby also host a festive event, with their Christmas Party closing out the year [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/565759020546410"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;Bridgend&lt;/strong&gt;, Wales: Bridgend Roller Derby host a "Christmas Family Skate" [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/919677955087456/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oxford&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Oxford Roller Derby host their "Grinchmas Games", a pair of open-subs games, raising funds for SAFE [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/343567029779677/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;WFTDA-gender Rookie game&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;OTA Intermediate/advanced game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Portsmouth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Portsmouth Roller Wenches host their last fixture of the year, an A/B double header &lt;strong&gt;[&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/283656325810711"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Portsmouth Roller Wenches A versus North Devon Roller Derby A [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105656"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Portsmouth Roller Wenches B versus North Devon Roller Derby B [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105657"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;Merthyr Tydfil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Wales: Merthyr Roller Derby host a pre-Christmas Roller Derby Sevens tournament to close out the year. (No real details on teams yet...) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/250373965604599/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;teams?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;Wrexham&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Wales: North Wales Roller Derby complete the year with their regular Christmas Scrim event, a double header of scrims [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1894207003973627"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;OTA Rookie Scrim&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;WFTDA-gender Intermediate/Advanced Scrim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;Birmingham&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, England: the Crash Test Brummies host "A Smashing Good Time", a festive open scrimmage, Open To All genders. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/329969860921266/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cambridge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Cambridge Rollerbillies have a stall at the Last Gang's Alternative Xmas Market, a closed market supporting local and home-grown vendors. [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/241780883175105"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eastbourne&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England:  Eastbourne Roller Derby host their annual Christmas Scrim, with three different scrim types &lt;strong&gt;[&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/490458304789711"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;OTA scrim&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;WFTDA-gender scrim&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Juniors scrim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;Guildford&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Surrey Roller Girls host their 7th Birthday Bash, especially open to all people in the community who've played SRG this year. Event includes roller disco, party games, stalls, potluck picnic and more! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2107087602877908/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tues, &lt;strong&gt;Whitchurch&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Basingstoke Bullets host a Tuesday Xmas Fun Skate event, Open To All, fancy dress encouraged [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2160423160866100/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Wed, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swansea&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Wales: Swansea City Roller Derby host their Christmas open scrim, open to WFTDA-gender-policy, mins-passed skaters [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/327947104668678"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Europe&lt;/h3&gt;
The French National tournament continues to roll on, with the second Nationale 1 fixture of the current season this weekend. There's also huge amounts of Roller Derby across all of Europe, especially in Helsinki and Stockholm... a German Bundesliga fixture, and a pair of Belgian Champs fixtures. There's even two big bootcamps! [And Derby in Moscow is recruiting!]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prague&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Czech Republic: the Hard Breaking Dolls host the first of 5 open training sessions, for interested potential competitive skaters, referees or NSOs. (Skaters limited to WFTDA-gender policy.) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/536798893399081/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;strong&gt;Helsinki&lt;/strong&gt;, Finland: Chicks in Bowls Helsinki host a Shred Day in collaboration with Helsinki Roller Derby. This includes multiple sessions, with beginners' and more advanced workshops, gear talk, and "games and competitions". [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/343282643097194/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moscow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Russia: Rollerciraptor Roller Derby Moscow host their first open-recruitment into a training series! Open under WFTDA-gender to all interested skaters. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/RolleciraptorDerbyMoscow/photos/a.1825736977458578/2182608395104766/?type=3&amp;amp;theater"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT Flyer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;Tallinn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Estonia: Tallinn Roller Girls continue to host their open training sessions on Fridays for all interested attendees. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2130649673675124/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tartu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Estonia: Tartu Roller Derby also continue their open training sessions for all interested attendees. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2102606236669992/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karlsruhe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Germany: Roller Derby Karlsruhe host the last of their Scrimmage Nights, open to "female only" skaters. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/352947422199002/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;Rome&lt;/strong&gt;, Italy: the She-Wolves of Roller Derby Roma are giving a demonstration at the Love 80s 90s 00s event hosted by Free Unicorns events. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/196451087937457/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rotterdam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Netherlands: Rotterdam Roller Derby host an "Open Holiday Scrimmage", the first of three (one each Friday before Christmas). We think these are OTA, and are also open to NSOs. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/316023082321334/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Farsta&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Sweden: Stockholm Roller Derby host their Christmas home teams finale, with a Harry Potter theme [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1732096483584898"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Death Eaters versus Aurors (home teams)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;Vienna&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Austria: Vienna Roller Derby host an A/B Doubleheader to close their season and year &lt;strong&gt;[&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/279002802737560"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Vienna Beasts (Vienna B) versus Liverpool Roller Birds B [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/104972"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Vienna Oysters (Vienna A) versus Liverpool Roller Birds A [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/104971"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Belgium: Go-Go Gent host a single header event, as part of the Belgian Championships! [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/104124/overview"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/261394164576251/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Go-Go Gent versus Holy Wheels Menace (Liège A)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prague&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Czech Republic: Prague City Roller Derby host their regular pre-Christmas open charity event. As always, Open To All genders, and to all skill levels (mins-passed). [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/707013669699059/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Santas versus Grinch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;Aalborg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Denmark: Aalborg's Combat Bullies bring a festive double header to celebrate the season and a new venu [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2250303785039959/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;WFTDA-gender open-subs bout : All The Jingle Ladies versus The Fa La La La La Llamas&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;OTA open-subs Sevens game: Pain Deers versus The Tree Rex´s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helsinki&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Finland: After their ramp work on Thursday, Helsinki Roller Derby host an end of year Tournament, the Best Hits 2018! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/179568609659795/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Helsinki ALpakka (Helsinki X) versus Åbo B-ajas (Dirty River B | Turku) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/106108"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Helsinki Juniors (Helsinki J) versus Vakaat aikuiset ( )&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Åbo B-ajas versus HC Ässat (Kallio Rolling Rainbow + Lappeenranta)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Helsinki ALpakka versus HC Ässat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sat-Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grenoble&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: The Cannibal Marmots host the next Championnat de France Nationale 1 fixture [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/105093/overview"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/441671236237683/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Cannibal Marmots (Grenoble) versus Faux Soyeuses (Lyon United)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Bloody Skulls (Marseille) versus DDCLM All Stars (Montpellier)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Les Harpies Braqueuses (Pibrac) versus La Horde (Orcet)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Cannibal Marmots versus Bloody Skulls&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Faux Soyeuses versus DDCLM All Stars&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Bloody Skulls versus Les Harpies Braqueuses&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Cannibal Marmots versus La Horde&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;"Demo and signup for Handi-hockey"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sat-Sun, &lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saint-Etienne&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: The Green Harpies and Green Go host the "Green Winter Bootcamp", a two-day bootcamp with intermediate skater sessions (coached by Pepe Le Punch and Paris' YAS), NSO beginners sessions (coached by Paris' Polo Kiwi), and Referees intermediate sessions (coached by Paris' Watze).  [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2148209608530652"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nancy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: Wheel Spirit Roller Derby host a festive double header [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1012544235584748"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Wheel Spirit (Nancy) versus Les Flèches Revêches (Dijon) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105777"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Roller Derby Metz Club versus Les Baronnes von Schlass (Lille B) [&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Darmstadt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Germany: Riot Rollers Darmstadt host a Double Header, including a Bundesliga Division 2 bout [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/99250/overview"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS tournament]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/530751487396081"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Riot Rollers Darmstadt A vs Zombie Rollergirlz (Münster) [Bundesliga D 2]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Riot Rollers Darmstadt B vs Splatter Fairies (Marburg) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105084"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frankfurt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Germany: Bembel Town Rollergirls host an OTA, Advanced-level, bootcamp, run by Glasgow Men's Roller Derby's Rosie Peacock and Optimus Grime! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/521357111623975"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;Stuttgart&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Germany: Stuttgart Valley Roller Derby host a single header to finish the year [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/819934618202889"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Bad Seeds (Stuttgart B) versus Bloody Wheels (Torino/Turin) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105013"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Padova&lt;/strong&gt;, Italy: The Criminal Bullets co-host their regular "Festival of the Madonna" event with ASD Quadrato Meticcio Women's Football. This is a party event but also includes a debate on "women for sport, sport for women", and celebrates feminist sport in general. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/308350699795021/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;Vicenza&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Italy: The Anguanas host a double header to finish their season,  with two games for their B team in one event! This is also being run as a Pride event. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2140853552898275"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The AnguanASS B-side (Vicenza B) versus Fearless Bruisers (Innsbruck) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105738"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The AnguanASS B-side versus Bone-Crushing Hyenas (Bologna) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105739"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heerlen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Netherlands: Roller Derby Liège and Les Vî-Kings host a Belgian Championships Men's tier fixture across the border... [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/105833/overview"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS Tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/988090958057941/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Vî-Kings (Liège M) versus Manneken Beasts (Brussels M)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Farsta&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Sweden: The Royal Swedish Roller Derby host their final fixtures of the season, with both intra- and inter-league games [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1219621908175614/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The Royal Brigade (Royal Swedish B | Stockholm) versus Nerike Knockouts (Örebro) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/105709/overview"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Brass Knuckle Harlots versus The Slayer Sisters (home teams)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Halmstad&lt;/strong&gt;, Sweden: Chicks in Bowls Halmstad host a Meet Up at the Halmstad Skateboardkubb [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/287077575263254/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aix-en-Provence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: Les Amazones host a festive double-header "Star pass ou ça casse" &lt;strong&gt;[&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2168594863353214"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Les Amazones (Aix A) versus Lutéce Destroyeuses (Lutéce B | Paris) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/105917"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Les Valkyries (Aix B) versus Gap/Montpellier mixed team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;Angers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, France: Anjou Derby Girls host Jingle Beigne, a Roller Derby Sevens tournament, with four festive teams [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/667445406961123"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;teams:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Besançon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: The Voodoo Vixens host a "Bootcamp à la fresh" - that is, a bootcamp aimed at pre-mins and rookie skaters &lt;strong&gt;[&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1766039813522580"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L'Houmeau&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: Roller Derby La Rochelle host a triple-header event to end the year [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/780336528964885/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Cheeky Dolls (La Rochelle A) versus UB (open subs team)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sombres Héros ( ) versus Rillettes Chili Peppers (Le Mans) [FTS]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Charogne Maritime ( ) versus Mortale Condate (Rennes B) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/106140"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;Paris&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, France: les Gueuses de Pigalle host an open scrimmage event with extras for the season [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/738563823173376/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;Arnhem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Netherlands: Arnhem Fallen Angels host a double header event  [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/273683013216912"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Arnhem Fallen Angels versus Rockcity Rollers High Voltage (Eindhoven B) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/106199/overview"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Black v White mixed teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Mon, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warsaw&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Poland: Worst Warsaw's Open recruitment continues for interested potential members in any roles! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2024174427621904/?"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Wed, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ostrava&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Czech Republic: Trojhali Ostrava Roller Derby continue their open training and rolling recruitment [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1139929732833996/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/?attachment_id=27825#main" rel="attachment wp-att-27825"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27825" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/anz_map.png?w=700" alt="" width="580" height="435"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pacific&lt;/h3&gt;
Australia and New Zealand host mostly Christmas events, with Japan also hosting their regular seasonal scrim.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;North Hobart&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, TAS, Australia: Convict City Roller Derby League host the 7th and final home season bout for the year. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/192308081647757/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Debut skaters game?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tauranga&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, New Zealand: Moana Roller Derby host their Christmas Open Scrim, limited to WFTDA gender policy (and with Christmas costumes encouraged).  Donations to Tauranga Women's Refuge will be collected. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/693229111063795/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Urangan&lt;/strong&gt;, QLD, Australia: the Red Hot Chilli Rollers host a family Christmas skate party with "very special guest", and all the accoutrements of an Australian party (including sausage sizzle). [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1957510230997816/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Devonport&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, TAS, Australia: Van Diemen Rollers host "Wreck The Halls", a double header to bring the season to a close [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2188686864703752"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;United Tasmanian Roller Derby Mixed-gender (OTA) bout&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Gangster Wrappers versus Ho Ho Hos (Van Diemen Home Teams bout)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Melbourne&lt;/strong&gt;, VIC, Australia: Chicks in Bowls Melbourne host the third of their Beginners Ramps Workshops. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1960821247344684/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Albany&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, WA, Australia: Albany Roller Derby League end their season with a single header and fun [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/348779469229200"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;"Potluck" open-subs WFTDA-gender game&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Food, bar, awards (end of year awards?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;Gladstone&lt;/strong&gt;, QLD, Australia: Gladstone Roller Derby host a relaxed season closer with BBQs heavily featured. &lt;strong&gt;[&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/733564756995322"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun,&lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Carrum Downs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, VIC, Australia: South Sea Roller Derby host their Christmas Special edition of Derby &amp;amp; Chill, their regular multi-level open scrimmage and social skate events [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/320127221872635/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Christmas-themed social skate&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Red (no-contact) scrimmage&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Amber (low-contact) scrimmage&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Bouting full-contact scrimmage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zushi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Kanagawa, Japan: Yokosuka Sushi Rollers host the 2018 Season's Beatings, their annual scrimmage / mini-bouts event for the end of the year! Open to All genders [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/250850952449983/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/?attachment_id=27826#main" rel="attachment wp-att-27826"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27826" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/la_map.png?w=700" alt="" width="580" height="435"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Latin America&lt;/h3&gt;
There's derby in Costa Rica, Brazil and Argentina this weekend, at least (we find it hardest to keep up with events in Latin America, so we appreciate being told what we've missed].
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;San José&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Costa Rica: Roller Derby Costa Rica host their Último Partido (Final game) for the year.  [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/255203441834309"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Reindeer versus Elves themed bout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sat+Sun, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;Río&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;Gallegos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Argentina: Fénix Roller Derby host a two-day open bootcamp and scrimmage. The Bootcamp is on Saturday, the Scrimmage on the Sunday. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/361355604631531/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buenos Aires&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Argentina: Buenos Aires Conspiracy, and Chat Noir, co-host a quadruple header! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/344694809445650/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Buenos Aires Conspiracy (Buenos Aires M)  vs Facones Galacticos (Buenos Aires M)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;"Low calorie" mixed scrimmage&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Space Jam (?) vs Buenos Aires Conspiracy&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Chat Noir intraleague: Black versus White&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blumenau&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Brazil: the Iron Ladies of Blumenau host an exciting challenge bout [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/318010738792066/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Iron Ladies (Blumenau) versus Brasil Roller Derby Masculino (Brasil M) !&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Santos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, São Paulo, Brazil: Thunder Rats Derby Squad host a single header to close 2018 [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1204891753009008/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;CANCELLED DUE TO RAIN STORMS&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thunder Rats (Santos, São Paulo) versus Sugar Loathe Roller Derby (Rio de Janeiro) [FTS]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morelia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Mexico: Roller Derby Morelia play Amour Roller Derby in a "friendly" [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/1020573958109634/photos/a.1020653411435022/1184517068381988/?type=3&amp;amp;theater"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT Flyer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Africa and Middle East&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>european derby</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>roller derby bootcamps</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>upcoming events</category><category>weekly roundup</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/05/non-us-canadian-derby-roundup-8th-9th-december-edition/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 16:31:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Brasileirão - Brazil's National Championships at 8!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/11/the-brasileirao-brazils-national-championships-at-8/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby in Brazil has been developing as long as it has in Mexico or Argentina, but the Brazilians were the first to develop a National Championship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first Roller Derby "&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/brasileiraorollerderby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brasileirão&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;", in fact, took place back in 2012; only a year after Team Brazil made its debut in the first ever World Cup appearance. Details of the first few years of the tournament are a little hard to find (part of the general problem with the volatility of content on the Internet), but since 2015 there's been a consistent social media presence for the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 6th edition of the tournament, held last year in Curitiba, saw 7 teams compete, from across 6 cities and 5 states. As with Colombia, where the East is low population due to the Amazon Rainforest, the North of Brazil is similarly sparse, so most of the teams are fairly coastal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27158" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/brasileiro2017.png" alt="Brasileiro2017" width="1920" height="1440"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;2017 Competitors:&lt;/h4&gt;
Ladies of Helltown - São Paulo, São Paulo
Gray City Rebels - São Paulo, São Paulo
Iron Ladies Roller Derby - Blumenau
Sugar Loathe Roller Derby - Rio de Janeiro
Meat Machine Roller Derby - Campo Grande
Thunder Rats Roller Derby - Santos, São Paulo
Blue Jay Rollers - Curitiba (Hosts)
&lt;p&gt;2017 hosts, Blue Jay Rollers, improved massively from their performance in the 5th Brasileirão (where they placed 6th) to take the 2nd place position overall, knocking the usually high-placed Ladies of Helltown down a peg in a surprising upset. In general Blue Jay Rollers have been having a good couple of years, but with the tournament host baton passed on this year, it will be interesting to see if they can maintain their position without home team advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obvious favourites for this year's Brasileirão, of course, are the 4-time winners, and current Champions, São Paulo's Gray City Rebels. Whilst their winning streak was broken in 2016 by Ladies of Helltown (in a close game, relegating the Rebels to 2nd), the Rebels regained the Championship in 2017 with a very convincing (226 : 107) win against the hosts.
Strikingly, no team from outside São Paulo has won the Brasileirão since the very first in 2012, the dominance of Gray City and Helltown being pretty solid from their posted scores on FTS. (Although, given the sparsity of records on Flat Track Stats from Brazilian roller derby, this is hard to judge in detail.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27572" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/brasileirao7.png" alt="Brasileirao7" width="1640" height="624"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;strong&gt;7th Brasileirão&lt;/strong&gt; hosted by &lt;strong&gt;Ladies of Helltown&lt;/strong&gt; in São Paulo, from the 2nd to the 4th of November, the advantage will be back with those strongest teams, and it would be a significant upset for a non-São Paulo team to take the Championship in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this stage, the competing teams have not been announced - although it is anticipated that, in addition to the hosts, Gray City Rebels, Blue Jay Rollers and the Iron Ladies of Blumenau will be returning as regulars.  Camp Grande's Meat Machine, Piracicaba's Capivaras, and new league Avas Roller Derby (Rio de Janeiro) are also possible attendees, in addition to third São Paulo area team, the Thunder Rats, and original Rio team, Sugar Loathe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This edition of the Brasileirão will also adopt a different format to previous events, adopting a 3 day structure, where two groups of (three?) teams play round-robin in the initial stages. The top teams in each group play for the 1st Place in the tournament (whilst the middle ranked teams play for 3rd, and the bottom teams from the groups play for 5th). Seeding for the groups will be done by boustrophedon alternation* across the estimated ranks for the competitors (selected purely because the WFTDA "S-curve" is this method), which is one of the two fairly good ways to seed groups like this - although the lack of strong Brazilian rankings (due partly to poor recording of game results) means that the seeds here are drawn from rankings at the previous year's Brasileirão.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This 7th edition of the Brasileirão will also host an Officiating Clinic, with WFTDA Level 2 Certified referee, Peter ParkHer attending from Germany; and Diego Rosan hosting the NSO component, and representing Oficiais RD Brasil, the organisation for Roller Derby officials in Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The 7th Brasileirão will be hosted in São Paulo, from the 2nd to the 4th of November 2018.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[EDIT (22 October): the current attendees are: Ladies of Helltown &amp;amp; Gray City Rebels (São Paulo), Thunder Rats (Santos), Blue Jay Rollers (Curitiba), Iron Ladies (Blumenau) and Capivaras (Piracicaba). ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*that is, the groups are seeded with ranks 1,4,5 in one group and 2,3,6 in the other - you can imagine this as filling in a pair of columns, from left-to-right, then right-to-left, then left-to-right as you go down. The alternate, uniform, seeding, would put 1,3,5 in one group, and 2,4,6 in the other (this can be better if you suspect that strength differences aren't that uniform across your competitive field) - you go "left-to-right" across each row, and don't alternate directions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>brasileirão de roller derby</category><category>brazil</category><category>brazilian roller derby</category><category>gray city rebels</category><category>international derby</category><category>ladies of helltown</category><category>national tournament</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming events</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/11/the-brasileirao-brazils-national-championships-at-8/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 10:11:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Europe's First Continental Cup: the UK's next International Derby fixture in 2018</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/04/europes-first-continental-cup-the-uks-next-international-derby-fixture-in-2018/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By any account, 2018 has been a very good year for Roller Derby's international profile, in both Europe and the UK. From the third Roller Derby World Cup in Manchester this February, and the third Men's Roller Derby World Cup in Barcelona a few months later, we've gone on to host an MRDA Playoffs, in Halifax/hosted by Manchester Roller Derby, and a WFTDA Playoffs, in A Coruña.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pendulum is, inevitably, swinging back again from Spain to the UK, with the last event in this sequence: the first ever &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wftdaecc2018.com/"&gt;European WFTDA Continental Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, bringing up the rear in this inaugural year for the new format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the MRDA Playoffs (hosted by Manchester, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; Halifax), this is hosted by Birmingham Blitz Dames, but physically &lt;i&gt;located&lt;/i&gt; in Telford... but the hosts have done a lot to make the brand of the tournament their own. The distinctive diamond logo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-27531 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/blitzdamesdiamon.png" alt="BlitzDamesDiamon" width="245" height="240"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;has both a general connection to Birmingham's jewellery industry, and to the Blitz Dames themselves - and even references their ex-skater, goldsmith Isabella Day, who made the trophy for the tournament!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27532" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/continental_map_logos.png" alt="Continental_map_logos" width="1562" height="1070"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Continental Cups framework is a response to the increasing spread of Roller Derby, and particularly the increasingly global membership of WFTDA. With more than 400 member leagues, an ever decreasing fraction of travel teams can hope to compete in a WFTDA Playoffs (and travel costs become increasingly prohibitive if you just extend the cut-off for Playoffs, or extend the old Division 2). &lt;i&gt;Regional&lt;/i&gt; "Continental Cups" provide a WFTDA-certified tournament, for every region with enough teams, at a level just below that of Playoffs - but with much less travel costs. (Next year, there will also be a set of regional "Development Cups", providing a WFTDA-certified tournament option for regions who aren't competitive at the old "D2" level, with guest "seed" teams from more "connected" regions to help improve ranking accuracy.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe's Continental Cup, then, has a familiar set of teams (and countries) represented (order from WFTDA announcement):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Kallio Rolling Rainbow (Finland)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dublin Roller Derby (Ireland)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dock City Rollers (Sweden)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers (Wales)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Central City Roller Derby (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby (England)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
The current FTS Europe rankings (which include a different subset of games to WFTDA rankings; excluding games against teams outside Europe, but including unsanctioned games) disagree somewhat with this ordering - FTS thinks that some of these teams were strong enough to make Playoffs ahead of some of the European representation there! - but predict a rather close set of games, regardless. In fact, FTS currently rates the two "local" teams - hosts Birmingham Blitz Dames, and Central City Roller Derby - as being exceptionally close in strength - sadly, the bracket prevents them from meeting unless they both lose their first games, or meet in the final.
Similarly, FTS expects some surprisingly close matches in the first round of the elimination bracket, despite WFTDA's usual slaughter pairing setup: Kallio versus Middlesbrough should be a near-draw by European data; although WFTDA sanctioned ratings place Kallio much higher than the UK team. If you're playing the Bracket Challenge for this contest, that's your best chance for an early upset...
&lt;p&gt;Despite, or perhaps causing, of the possibility of so many upsets and ranking disparities, the European Continental Cup should continue the example of the two North American CCs, in having a higher than "usual" number of close bouts, despite the tendency of elimination tournaments to start with a round of blowouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bracket is available here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.wixstatic.com/ugd/590519_be81975ec1304fcf96b32590ddbe2d8a.pdf"&gt;BRACKET PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (note for those not in the UK - this event is on the weekend that the UK changes over from Daylight Savings Time, so be careful checking timings for the Sunday, in particular).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-27324" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/officials_eur_map.png?w=2048" alt="Officials_EUR_map" width="1024" height="768"&gt; Geographical distribution of European Officials at the ECC! Stars may represent more than one official from a given location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as for the competition, the Continental Cup is also a great chance for more representation for our highly skilled European Officiating community. Just at the Tournament and Crew Head levels, we have officials from Karlsruhe, Newcastle, Dublin, Nottingham, Paris/Lutece, London/Southern Discomfort, (and Michigan...) - including all of the other crew positions adds (deep breath) Amsterdam, Antwerp, Bath, Belfast, Birmingham, Brussels, Cambridge, Cardiff, Chelmsford, Copenhagen, Darmstadt, Devon, Dresden, Dundee, Essex, Falkirk, Frankfurt, Gothenburg, Kallio/Helsinki, Manchester, Metz, Mons, Nantes, Northampton, Oxford, Riems, Ruhrpott, Southend, Southampton, Vicenza, Vienna, Wiltshire, Wuppertal,  (and Rochester, NY; Monterrey County, CA; St Louis, MO; Boston, MA; USA... and Adelaide, SA, Australia)! Just as with the other international events in Europe this year, this kind of exposure, and opportunity to both officiate at a high level, and meet up with a wider-flung segment of the Derby Community is fantastic for Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not all, as there's also fantastic line-up of (mostly...) European announcers, from Head Announcer Biertrix (Rainy City Roller Derby), through a host of UK announcers from London through Manchester to Durham and Newcastle; and from Germany, Denmark, as well as the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, as with all WFTDA post-season events this year, there will be a genuine chance for all members of the community (WFTDA-members or no) to connect with WFTDA Membership via the co-hosted "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/772801099579539/"&gt;WFTDA World Summit Satellite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" event. We're very impressed by WFTDA's increased commitment to listening to the voices of the whole community, and would encourage the community to also make use of these opportunities in return: listening should be rewarded with dialogue. (On that note, WFTDA are also surveying every league which does derby and are not WFTDA-members - regardless of their gender policy etc - and we'd encourage everyone eligible to respond to this too, here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.org/surveys"&gt;WFTDA.org/surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The European Continental Cup will run from &lt;strong&gt;October 27th to October 28th&lt;/strong&gt; at The International Centre, Telford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WFTDA Continental Cup page: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/events/wftda-continental-cups/"&gt;https://wftda.com/events/wftda-continental-cups/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Facebook Event for European Continental Cup: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>birmingham blitz dames</category><category>central city roller derby</category><category>continental cup</category><category>dock city rollers</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>kallio rolling rainbow</category><category>middlesbrough roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>tournament</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/04/europes-first-continental-cup-the-uks-next-international-derby-fixture-in-2018/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 15:54:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Silver City Cup: Scotland's first MRDA Tournament</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/14/the-silver-city-cup-scotlands-first-mrda-tournament/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would be remiss of us to run a series on Tournaments which deserve more attention without covering Scotland's own example of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst there have been many tournaments run in Scotland, there have been relatively fewer "Men's Derby" focussed events. Given the lack of MRDA member leagues in Scotland until almost a year ago, when Granite City Brawlers were accepted, it was also impossible for there to have been any "officially" sanctioned tournaments at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, though, with two MRDA member teams (Glasgow Men's Roller Derby having quietly unofficially joined a few months ago, in June, although only officially announced by MRDA this week), the time is right for an international Men's Roller Derby tournament, and where better than the home of the first MRDA members in the country, Aberdeen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Silver City Cup - named for the poetic description of Aberdeen as the "Silver City, with the Golden Sands", possibly dating to an early guide to the city* - will host 6 teams from across Europe, in a group+placement format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we reported on the Men's European Cup, we noted that several of the teams involved were also facing each other in other MRDA sanctioned events this year. Conversely, the Silver City Cup seems to have attracted all the teams who aren't appearing as much elsewhere... so this is a great opportunity to see some matchups you can't get elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27437" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/09/silvercity_map_out.png" alt="Silvercity_map_out" width="1332" height="1436"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;England: Super Smash Brollers (Nottingham), Crash Test Brummies (Birmingham)
Finland: Tampere Rollin' Bros (Tampere)
France: Kamiquadz (Montpellier)
Scotland: Granite City Brawlers (Aberdeen)
Wales: South Wales Silures (Cardiff)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Structure&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;GROUP 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;GROUP 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Granite City Brawlers [661]{2.94}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Crash Test Brummies [618]{2.92}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;South Wales Silures [706]{3.24}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;KamiQuads [737]{3.8}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Tampere Rollin' Bros [777]{2.9}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Super Smash Brollers [612]{2.5}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="2"&gt;[FTS MRDA rating**]{SRDRank May 2018 rating}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
Within each group of 3, the teams will play round-robin (3 games per group), to produce a final group-ranking.
The 1st place winners in each group will play each other for Tournament 1st Place, whilst the 2nd places in each group will play for overall Tournament 3rd, and the bottom teams in each group will play for Tournament 5th.
&lt;p&gt;Looking at Flat Track Stats' "MRDA" ratings (which are derived only from MRDA sanctioned games played by teams), there's a pretty wide spread in predicted strength across the groups - second-highest-rated contenders, DCCLM's Kamiquadz are expected to beat lowest-rated contenders, Super Smash Brollers, by around a three-to-one points ratio! Ironically, the hosts have given themselves the harder of the two groups, based on prediction: they will be playing FTS' 1st and 3rd ranked teams of the tournament, as FTS' 4th ranked team themselves. In order to achieve their "rightful" position, they'd need to defeat the fearsome SWS in their group, before taking on the 2nd place team from Group 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at pure history, rather than ratings, the Kamiquadz are really the wildcards here. Most of their past bouts on record are, understandably, given the geography, against French men's teams, or teams from nearby Barcelona in Spain. As far as we can tell from their FTS record, the Kamiquadz have never played outside of mainland Europe before, so this will be a big change for them - the weather in Aberdeen will be a bit of a change to Montpellier! On the basis of their performances in France, however, we have no hesitation in considering them the favourites to take the 1st place in this tournament overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only slightly less of an historical wildcard for the other teams, Tampere Rollin Bros actually did play the Kamiquadz - way back in 2015 - but also have a more extensive set of travel experiences under their belts (being based in Finland forces that upon you, to some extent). In recent years, Tampere's bouts have not been MRDA-sanctioned (according to FTS), and so have not factored into their estimated strength*** - we'd actually say Tampere are somewhat overranked at present, going by their performance in their last tournament in 2017. [On the other hand, that tournament was in Barcelona, one of the most distant places Tampere have played, so it almost certainly represents a lowest bound on their expected strength at the time.]
The SRDRank ratings, which do include those games from 2017, tend to agree, placing Tampere in the same "closely-competitive" group as the rest of the field excluding KamiQuads and SWS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the UK based teams, Wales's South Wales Silures have had the strongest, year to date, although far from the busiest. Despite losing 2 of their three games in May (to Manneken Beasts, and, by 2 points only!, Gothenburg Salty Seamen), their incredibly strong first game performance against the Crash Test Brummies has kept their overall performance estimate high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aforementioned Brummies have, along with Nottingham's Super Smash Brollers, been extremely busy this year - with fixtures in British Champs MRDA-side (Tier 1 for the Brummies, and 2 for the Brollers) at the start of the year, and MRDA Qualifiers for the Super Smash Brollers as well. Fittingly, perhaps, the most recent bout for the two teams to date is against each other, a narrowish win for the higher-rated Brummies (162 to 199). The two teams will get to repeat that match-up again in their Group 2 bouts, almost certainly deciding which plays for 3rd and which for 5th overall in the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the hosts, Granite City Brawlers, have been stepping on the gas in terms of bout scheduling since getting MRDA membership - meeting the activity requirements to be ranked in the official rankings is a strong incentive for all members of official governing bodies. They, also, have played one of the other contenders most recently: a repeat matchup with the Super Smash Brollers resulting in a second win in a row for the Aberdeen team. FTS's MRDA rating for them, based on their past 4 games, is still trending upward, but it's not clear if it is "really" above the 700-odd mark needed to beat the Silures in their group - however, if Tampere really is as overranked as we think, the Brawlers may only need to be slightly stronger than they're currently rated to be to take their groups' 2nd place spot, and play for a likely 3rd overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Silver City Cup will be held at &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/3fr8ugyweUs"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Beach Leisure Centre, Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;; &lt;strong&gt;22-23 September&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
Event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/616684768693015/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/616684768693015/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Tickets are available from Brown Paper Tickets: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/3446103https://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/3446103"&gt;https://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/3446103&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The "Silver" here is generally considered a reference to the "silver darlings", the herring which formed the basis of Aberdeen's historic fishing industry.
&lt;strong&gt;Flat Track Stats' MRDA Rating as of &lt;span class="lighter smaller notbold"&gt;9/4/18 [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/mrda/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/mrda/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;Only &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; of Tampere Rollin Bros' bouts are listed as MRDA Sanctioned, both in 2016, and those are the only source for FTS's MRDA rating for them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>crash test brummies</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>kamiquadz</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>silver city cup</category><category>south wales silures</category><category>super smash brollers</category><category>tampere rollin' bros</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/14/the-silver-city-cup-scotlands-first-mrda-tournament/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 19:30:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Silver City Cup - A Brawling Interview</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/06/silver-city-cup-a-brawling-interview/</link><dc:creator>davidlewis8891</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen, September 2018&lt;/strong&gt; - Granite City Brawlers are making history with their very own MRDA sanctioned tournament called 'Silver City Cup'. Whilst MRDA has Champs and Playoffs, there has never been a sanctioned tournament held in Scotland. Granite City Brawlers, Super Smash Brollers, Crash Test Brummies, Kamiquadz, South Wales Silures and Tampere Rollin' Bros are all looking to take the inaugural 'Silver City Cup'. With the Brawlers hoping to make their mark in the MRDA rankings, we took some time to speak to GCB's Co-Captain, Pudz (Chris Mathieson) about the upcoming tournament.
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27393" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/09/34909209_2057023227701408_2544234365819289600_o.jpg" alt="34909209_2057023227701408_2544234365819289600_o" width="1920" height="1280"&gt;
Photo by: Len Rizzo&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Straight off the bat, tell us how this tournament came about?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We joined the MRDA last September and as part of this the team is required to play 5 sanctioned games a year in order to gain ranking. The bigger teams can get their games quite easily in a tournament weekend through Champs and Playoffs, however there wasn’t much opportunity for the lower seeded teams. So we put our organisational heads together and decided to put on a tournament weekend for those below 40 or unranked in the MRDA. This allows 6 teams (including Brawlers) to gain 3 of their games in a single weekend!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does it feel to be able to host/create the first MRDA tournament in Scotland as well as it having quite the international flavour to it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are over the moon at having 6 teams coming from 5 countries to our little tournament in Aberdeen. We even been working with some local bodies to promote the tournament and the city. VisitAberdeenshire have even put together a web portal (&lt;a href="https://www.visitabdn.com/cp/silver-city-cup"&gt;https://www.visitabdn.com/cp/silver-city-cup&lt;/a&gt;) full of information to help our tourist friends. A lot of people see Aberdeen as this grey city with not much going on but there is such a history to it! Three top things to check out on your visit would be Dunnottar Castle (for the Game of Thrones fans), Footdee (a small area of quirky houses, 5 minutes from the venue) and Slains Castle (the backdrop of our fab logo, you might even see one of the ghouls).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As for this being the first MRDA tournament in Scotland we are delighted to showcase to the rest of our international association just what Scotland has to offer and that we can put on one hell of a tournament!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think we all want to know, how do you think GCB will fair given the tough competitors and the grueling nature of a tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is GCB’s first ever tournament and as such we’re going to need to bring our A game up against some tough opponents! With a few Scotland skaters at the helm, we have some tournament experience that will hopefully help the rest of the team prepare mentally and physically. We’ll be aiming for the win and to keep the Silver City Cup in the Silver City but every team has a good chance of taking that trophy home, the very nature of a tournament weekend is that anything could happen!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You say you’ve been preparing for the tournament, how have you done this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last month we hosted a double scrim with skaters from almost every league in Scotland. This allowed us to prepare for back to back games against some high level skaters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We also have our weekly outdoor fitness sessions with Intrepid PT, these have worked doubly as both exercise and team bonding. Though its been a year and we all still hate burpees!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Should the tournament fair well, could we be seeing an annual Silver City Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ask me when its over! Maybe not an annual tournament in Aberdeen but we’d love to see a division two type structure appear within the MRDA as it continues to grow. Obviously our end goal is MRDA Champs but that’s a few years away yet!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any final words that you would like to share with us?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We really want to put on a good tournament, representing all of Scotland and we’d love a big Scottish home crowd behind us – get your tickets now - &lt;a href="https://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/3446103"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/3446103&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some inspiring words from Granite City Brawlers own, Pudz. From the sounds of it, this will be an exciting weekend of roller derby so make sure you get your tickets and be a part of Scottish history on &lt;strong&gt;September 22-23 at the Beach Leisure Centre in Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;! You can check out further information at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/616684768693015/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/616684768693015/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27394" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/09/35151282_840046892864311_5399712130972778496_n.jpg" alt="35151282_840046892864311_5399712130972778496_n" width="810" height="450"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Article written by Brawlers correspondent HaJuken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>crash test brummies</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>kamiquadz</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mrda</category><category>silver city cup</category><category>south wales silures</category><category>super smash brollers</category><category>tampere rollin' bros</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/09/06/silver-city-cup-a-brawling-interview/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 11:21:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Slavic Roller Derby Tournament grows into its second year, adds the Baltics!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/23/the-slavic-roller-derby-tournament-grows-into-its-second-year-adds-the-baltics/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, we &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/08/11/a-slavic-tournament-how-central-and-eastern-european-derby-exploded-in-just-3-years/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reported&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the first ever "Slavic Roller Derby Tournament", a three team round-robin hosted by Warsaw Hellcats, and featuring St Petersburg's White Night Furies, and Prague City Roller Derby B in addition to the hosts. At the time, we noted that the mere possibility of this tournament existing was a signal for just how fast Roller Derby is expanding into Eastern Europe...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and that expansion has continued into this year, so it is perhaps unsurprising that the tournament is back for a second year this October; bigger and more extensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27274" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/slavic_map_out.png?w=2048" alt="SLAVIC_map_out" width="1024" height="650"&gt; Competitors in Red, except the hosts (in Blue), and the three teams contributing to Team Czech (in Yellow). Men's Derby bout competitors in Black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poland have outdone expectations by doubling the number of contenders this time around, and extending the geographical inclusion to the southern Baltic states as well as Slavic nations. Fitting the resulting 6 team round robin into a single day is only possible with non-WFTDA rulesets (15 games would take 15 hours of WFTDA play, not including breaks), so this edition of the Slavic Tournament is being run as with Roller Derby Sevens rules. The reduced maximum roster size of Sevens also makes it more accessible for some of the newer competitors as an additional bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, this added accessibility has allowed several other firsts at this event:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riga Roller Derby, representing Latvia, have previous bout experience, as part of the Team Baltic Roller Derby who competed against Team Israel at the 2018 Roller Derby World Cup - but have never played as a team themselves. Their Sevens team will therefore represent multiple firsts here: the first time Riga have competed as a team, and the first time &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; team from the (south) Baltics have competed in a ranked event!
This is very good timing, as the Baltics have just gained their third official league - in Tallinn, Estonia - this week, showing the work done in Riga and Tartu paying off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Baltic is not the only connection to the Roller Derby World Cup, as Team Czech Roller Derby will be representing their country in Sevens form, with skaters from Prague's Prague City Roller Derby and Hard Breaking Dolls, joined by members of Roller Derby Brno. Brno's skaters on Team Czech will all be skating in their first public bouts at this tournament, giving them good experience to take back to their league. (We hope that next time Team Czech plays, they can also include skaters from the newly formed league in Ostravia, also announced this week!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27275" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/slavic_czech_map_out.png?w=2048" alt="SLAVIC_CZECH_map_out" width="1024" height="714"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Host country Poland will be exceptionally well represented, with not only hosts Warsaw Hellcats, and their fellow Warsaw team, Worst Warsaw, competing, but also Vratislavia (Wrocław)'s MadChix Roller Squad! All three teams have at least several games under their belt, and contributed skaters to Team Poland, (although Warsaw's teams are a lot more experienced!). Additionally, all are particularly used to Sevens tournaments, having competed in the 7th Heaven tournament in Poznań only a few months ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also returning to the tournament from last time are the only bouting team in Russia, St Petersburg's White Night Furies; although they are sending their newer B team, Ingria Rollers, to compete this time around. The Furies also gained a lot of experience from their members in Team Russia at the World Cup this year (as well as their continued participation in the Pohjola Cup), so we're expecting a strong performance from their B Team here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The restrictions of Sevens rostering make it difficult to predict the standings of the Slavic/Baltic tournament from FTS records (not least because several of these teams are playing for the first time!), but we'd be unsurprised by strong performances from the hosts, and the composite Czech team. Given the strong tournament experience gained by many of the competitors here in the past year, however, it's hard to rule anyone out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the main event, this edition of the Slavic/Baltic Tournament will also be showcasing two other contests:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another debut, this time in men's roller derby: Polish Men's Roller Derby, a collaboration of the Polish Eagles skaters based in Poland itself, play their first game on home soil, ever, against the might of London's Southern Discomfort B, Mild Discomfort!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, finally, a chance to see another fantastic sport on wheels, as Warsaw's Wheelchair Rugby team present their sport in an exhibition game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2079168135665222/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;first Slavic/Baltic Tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will be held on the 20th October in &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/XDcKWPs5wWN2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centrum Sportu Wilanów&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in Warsaw, Poland. Tickets and more information will be available on the Facebook Event in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>baltic roller derby</category><category>czech republic</category><category>hard breaking dolls</category><category>ingria rollers</category><category>international derby</category><category>poland</category><category>polish roller derby</category><category>prague city roller derby</category><category>riga roller derby</category><category>roller derby sevens</category><category>slavic tournament</category><category>southern discomfort</category><category>team czech</category><category>team poland</category><category>team poland men's roller derby</category><category>team russia</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>vratislavia madchix</category><category>white night furies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/23/the-slavic-roller-derby-tournament-grows-into-its-second-year-adds-the-baltics/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 09:57:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The 5th Colombian National Tournament: 2018 so far!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/01/the-5th-colombian-national-tournament-2018-so-far/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For our third important, but easily missed, tournament this year, we're heading north to Colombia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In common with Brazil and Mexico, Colombia began large scale national series relatively early.  From 2012 to 2014, a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TorneoRollerDerbyColombia/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colombian National Tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was organised, awarding wins to Bogotá's Rock N Roller Queens and Bone Breakers. Since then, however, things have been less consistent: whilst there has been a "Western Region" tournament every year since (the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/597182954013880/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Torneo Regional de Occidente&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ), and a "District Tournament" for the huge number of teams in the capital of Bogotá (the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TorneoDistritalRollerDerby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Torneo Distrital Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ), there was not an overall National Championship in 2015 or 16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2017, however, things have been getting more on track, with Bogotá Bone Breakers winning both the 4th Distrital (for qualification), and the resulting &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/4nacionalrollerderby/"&gt;Torneo Nacional&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in mid-November, the first since 2014, to take the overall Championship for the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The previous Championship set up continues for 2018, and we're already deep into the Qualifying Tournaments, so there's plenty for us to catch you up on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the uneven distribution of teams across Colombia, the two qualifiers have very different geographical extents - although they have similar numbers of eligible competitors. From &lt;em&gt;each&lt;/em&gt; qualifier, the top &lt;em&gt;three&lt;/em&gt; teams are then passed onto the Championship itself, to play for the cup, so that six teams play overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the teams competing this year, the most experienced are Bogotá's Bone Breakers (Bx3), who date back to 2009. Only slightly younger are also a Bogotá based team, Rock N Roller Queens, who date from just a year later. These two are also the only WFTDA member leagues in Colombia - with the Queens having joined as early as 2013, and Bx3 waiting until 2016. Before and after WFTDA membership, both leagues' A teams have always been well travelled within Latin America (for example, attending several of 2x4 Roller Derby's Violentango tournaments in Buenos Aires).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside Bogotá, Manizales' Valkyrias are easily the oldest team, founded in 2010 as well. Valkyrias have also travelled fairly widely in recent years, having attended the 5th Sailor City Rollers hosted &lt;em&gt;Piratas en el Asfalto&lt;/em&gt; tournament in 2017, also in Buenos Aires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the other end of the scale, we believe that Bogotá's youngest team in the tournament is Fugitivas Roller Punk, founded in 2016, whilst Cali's Silver Lynx Roller Derby are probably the youngest outside the capital region, dating from 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most geographically distributed Qualifier is the &lt;em&gt;Torneo Regional de Occidente&lt;/em&gt;, covering the entire West of Colombia. (The East of Colombia has a very low population density, being mostly covered by those parts of the Amazon rainforest in the Colombian borders). &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/597182954013880/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This year's tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the 6th, was hosted by Medellín's Spring City Rollers, from the 9th to 11th June as a single event - a round robin tournament with 5 competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valkyrias Roller Derby, of Manizales, gave a very impressive performance, taking the top of the leaderboard, just above the hosts Spring City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silver Lynx Roller Derby, and Bucaramanga's Pink Sucks Roller Derby, were unable to prevent Violet Attack, of Ibague, from taking the third qualifying spot. This is a significant improvement in Violet Attack's performance from last year, although the absence of several teams from the tournament may have helped them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the results available to us, it appears that Valkyrias have significantly improved on last year, with only new-this-year Spring City causing them any particular challenge. (We've been unable to source complete scores for the tournament, however, so we can't be certain about the relative strength of third place holders Violet Attack.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27149" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/torneoregional3.png?w=1024" alt="TorneoRegional" width="1024" height="768"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second Qualifier, the &lt;em&gt;Torneo Distrital&lt;/em&gt;, is centred entirely on the large capital city, Bogotá, and run as a round-robin with multiple fixtures throughout the year. Last year's District tournament was a huge affair with multiple divisions, and a packed structure (each fixture was a triple-header to accommodate all the teams).
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TorneoDistritalRollerDerby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This year's Distrital&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the 5th, is a much more compact affair, with all of the "B" teams, and the men's derby division, removed entirely.  Instead, the five big leagues of the capital area are all competing with their A teams only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the first round of play, the current standings in the Distrital are:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Bogotá Bone Breakers&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Combativas Revoltosas&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Rock N Roller Queens&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Central Derby D.C. Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fugitivas Roller Punk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
This is also the ordering of the same teams at the end of the last National Tournament, so we're not expecting any particular upsets going forward.
&lt;p&gt;The final phase of the tournament, in this year's design, will see the top 4 seed into a slaughter-pairing elimination tournament, to decide the winner, second and third places. As such, it is impossible for the Fugitivas to qualify for a top 3 position, and thus impossible for them to qualify for a place in the Torneo National this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27144" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/torneodistrital.png?w=1024" alt="TorneoDistrital" width="1024" height="768"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 5th Torneo Nacional will be hosted, in &lt;strong&gt;November 2018&lt;/strong&gt;, by the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ValkyriasRollerDerby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valkyrias&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, who gained the rights by qualifying first in June. There is no precise date announced yet, although we'd expect around the second week of the month, based on the previous tournament schedules. This is the first time the event has been held in Manizales, with three of the last 4 having been hosted in the capital, and the other (in 2013) in Medellín.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are guaranteed changes to the finishing order from 2017, even at this early date: the three Regional teams qualifying this year are entirely different to 2017 (when Pink Sucks, Ibague's Pain Dealers, and the Titanias of Cali were the qualifiers).
Even so, the SRDRank ratings for the current top 3 Distrital division teams are all noticeably higher than those for the Regional qualifying teams (we place current-4th-position Central Derby D.C. as competitive with the Valkyrias, at last estimate).  All four previous Torneo Nacionals have seen the same top three teams, in fact, with various combinations of Bx3, Rock N Roller Queens and Combativas in each position; although for the first time last year, the Rock N Roller Queens were relegated to third place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible, then, that this could be the first year that the Valkyrias - who have the best form of any of the Regional teams - might make bronze, especially with home team advantage!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particular thanks to Central Derby D.C. Roller Derby for their assistance in writing this article; and to the 5th Nacional hosts, Valkyrias.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>colombia</category><category>distrital</category><category>international derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>regional occidente</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/01/the-5th-colombian-national-tournament-2018-so-far/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 09:34:48 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>