<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about tournaments2018)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/tournaments2018.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:41:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>South Africa's National Derby Fest 2018: three years of Festivals!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/31/south-africas-national-derby-fest-2018-three-years-of-festivals/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the final article in our series covering National and International tournaments which deserve more attention, we're coming to a continent which receives little attention from the Roller Derby community: Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The South African Roller Derby community has always been, by necessity, a tightly-connected group; the closest Roller Derby to them is at the other end of the continent to them (in Egypt), so the South African leagues have a feel more like those of the early North American and European leagues. That is to say, they're very much "leagues", and home-team games within each city's league are more common than travel team games between the leagues themselves.
(This is not to say that South Africa isn't engaged in the global community: they of course attended the 2014 and 2018 World Cups, and engage in much of the rest of the community itself.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, there's still a lot of appetite for a big National Tournament to raise the profile of the sport, so Golden City Rollers (previously C-Max Roller Derby) of Johannesburg started the "National Derby Fest" back in 2016. Back then, almost all the teams present were actually part of the C-Max league, with only Pretoria's P-Town making it to the contest from outside (with some skaters from Cape Town joining their team for the event).
As a result, the 2016 winners were a C-Max home team: the Thundering Hellcats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27680" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/zanational_sa.png?w=1024" alt="ZANational_SA" width="1024" height="813"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, with Golden City hosting again, the event was run as a triple header round robin between Johannesburg, Durban and Cape Town, with the hosts' travel team emerging victorious with a commanding lead over second place Cape Town, with a final score of 219:73!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, in the third year of the event, the tournament is hosted by the other large league in South Africa, Cape Town Roller Derby. The format has changed, providing a pair of Open To All mixed "scrimmage" bouts, featuring skaters from all three leagues which attended last year, followed by the Championship event face-off between Cape Town and Golden City!
As far as we know, the provision of OTA games is an innovation for this event; these bouts will provide track time for all the bout-ready skaters across South Africa, which is an important focus for the tournament as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of their community engagement, the one day event will have each bout separated by open skating for the audience (for which kit hire is available).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With interleague bouts between the leagues fairly rare, it's hard to be definitive about the expected result of the Championship event: however, given Golden City's history, we're expecting a continuation of their reign, albeit a closer one than in the past.
However, the real benefit will continue to be the South African Roller Derby community itself, regardless of who picks up the trophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Third National Derby Fest will be held on &lt;strong&gt;Nov 17&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Sunningdale Sports Complex&lt;/strong&gt;, Cape Town. The event is located at Facebook here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/179294086331874/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/179294086331874/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with all National Tournaments, you can see the history of winners at our page here: &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/NationalTournaments.htmlhttp://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/NationalTournaments.html"&gt;http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/NationalTournaments.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>golden city roller derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>south africa</category><category>team south africa</category><category>tournaments2018</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/31/south-africas-national-derby-fest-2018-three-years-of-festivals/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 11:19:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Brasileirão - Brazil's National Championships at 8!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/11/the-brasileirao-brazils-national-championships-at-8/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby in Brazil has been developing as long as it has in Mexico or Argentina, but the Brazilians were the first to develop a National Championship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first Roller Derby "&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/brasileiraorollerderby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brasileirão&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;", in fact, took place back in 2012; only a year after Team Brazil made its debut in the first ever World Cup appearance. Details of the first few years of the tournament are a little hard to find (part of the general problem with the volatility of content on the Internet), but since 2015 there's been a consistent social media presence for the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 6th edition of the tournament, held last year in Curitiba, saw 7 teams compete, from across 6 cities and 5 states. As with Colombia, where the East is low population due to the Amazon Rainforest, the North of Brazil is similarly sparse, so most of the teams are fairly coastal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27158" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/brasileiro2017.png" alt="Brasileiro2017" width="1920" height="1440"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;2017 Competitors:&lt;/h4&gt;
Ladies of Helltown - São Paulo, São Paulo
Gray City Rebels - São Paulo, São Paulo
Iron Ladies Roller Derby - Blumenau
Sugar Loathe Roller Derby - Rio de Janeiro
Meat Machine Roller Derby - Campo Grande
Thunder Rats Roller Derby - Santos, São Paulo
Blue Jay Rollers - Curitiba (Hosts)
&lt;p&gt;2017 hosts, Blue Jay Rollers, improved massively from their performance in the 5th Brasileirão (where they placed 6th) to take the 2nd place position overall, knocking the usually high-placed Ladies of Helltown down a peg in a surprising upset. In general Blue Jay Rollers have been having a good couple of years, but with the tournament host baton passed on this year, it will be interesting to see if they can maintain their position without home team advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obvious favourites for this year's Brasileirão, of course, are the 4-time winners, and current Champions, São Paulo's Gray City Rebels. Whilst their winning streak was broken in 2016 by Ladies of Helltown (in a close game, relegating the Rebels to 2nd), the Rebels regained the Championship in 2017 with a very convincing (226 : 107) win against the hosts.
Strikingly, no team from outside São Paulo has won the Brasileirão since the very first in 2012, the dominance of Gray City and Helltown being pretty solid from their posted scores on FTS. (Although, given the sparsity of records on Flat Track Stats from Brazilian roller derby, this is hard to judge in detail.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27572" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/brasileirao7.png" alt="Brasileirao7" width="1640" height="624"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;strong&gt;7th Brasileirão&lt;/strong&gt; hosted by &lt;strong&gt;Ladies of Helltown&lt;/strong&gt; in São Paulo, from the 2nd to the 4th of November, the advantage will be back with those strongest teams, and it would be a significant upset for a non-São Paulo team to take the Championship in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this stage, the competing teams have not been announced - although it is anticipated that, in addition to the hosts, Gray City Rebels, Blue Jay Rollers and the Iron Ladies of Blumenau will be returning as regulars.  Camp Grande's Meat Machine, Piracicaba's Capivaras, and new league Avas Roller Derby (Rio de Janeiro) are also possible attendees, in addition to third São Paulo area team, the Thunder Rats, and original Rio team, Sugar Loathe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This edition of the Brasileirão will also adopt a different format to previous events, adopting a 3 day structure, where two groups of (three?) teams play round-robin in the initial stages. The top teams in each group play for the 1st Place in the tournament (whilst the middle ranked teams play for 3rd, and the bottom teams from the groups play for 5th). Seeding for the groups will be done by boustrophedon alternation* across the estimated ranks for the competitors (selected purely because the WFTDA "S-curve" is this method), which is one of the two fairly good ways to seed groups like this - although the lack of strong Brazilian rankings (due partly to poor recording of game results) means that the seeds here are drawn from rankings at the previous year's Brasileirão.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This 7th edition of the Brasileirão will also host an Officiating Clinic, with WFTDA Level 2 Certified referee, Peter ParkHer attending from Germany; and Diego Rosan hosting the NSO component, and representing Oficiais RD Brasil, the organisation for Roller Derby officials in Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The 7th Brasileirão will be hosted in São Paulo, from the 2nd to the 4th of November 2018.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[EDIT (22 October): the current attendees are: Ladies of Helltown &amp;amp; Gray City Rebels (São Paulo), Thunder Rats (Santos), Blue Jay Rollers (Curitiba), Iron Ladies (Blumenau) and Capivaras (Piracicaba). ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*that is, the groups are seeded with ranks 1,4,5 in one group and 2,3,6 in the other - you can imagine this as filling in a pair of columns, from left-to-right, then right-to-left, then left-to-right as you go down. The alternate, uniform, seeding, would put 1,3,5 in one group, and 2,4,6 in the other (this can be better if you suspect that strength differences aren't that uniform across your competitive field) - you go "left-to-right" across each row, and don't alternate directions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>brasileirão de roller derby</category><category>brazil</category><category>brazilian roller derby</category><category>gray city rebels</category><category>international derby</category><category>ladies of helltown</category><category>national tournament</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments2018</category><category>upcoming events</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/11/the-brasileirao-brazils-national-championships-at-8/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 10:11:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Europe's First Continental Cup: the UK's next International Derby fixture in 2018</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/04/europes-first-continental-cup-the-uks-next-international-derby-fixture-in-2018/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By any account, 2018 has been a very good year for Roller Derby's international profile, in both Europe and the UK. From the third Roller Derby World Cup in Manchester this February, and the third Men's Roller Derby World Cup in Barcelona a few months later, we've gone on to host an MRDA Playoffs, in Halifax/hosted by Manchester Roller Derby, and a WFTDA Playoffs, in A Coruña.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pendulum is, inevitably, swinging back again from Spain to the UK, with the last event in this sequence: the first ever &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wftdaecc2018.com/"&gt;European WFTDA Continental Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, bringing up the rear in this inaugural year for the new format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the MRDA Playoffs (hosted by Manchester, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; Halifax), this is hosted by Birmingham Blitz Dames, but physically &lt;i&gt;located&lt;/i&gt; in Telford... but the hosts have done a lot to make the brand of the tournament their own. The distinctive diamond logo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-27531 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/blitzdamesdiamon.png" alt="BlitzDamesDiamon" width="245" height="240"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;has both a general connection to Birmingham's jewellery industry, and to the Blitz Dames themselves - and even references their ex-skater, goldsmith Isabella Day, who made the trophy for the tournament!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27532" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/continental_map_logos.png" alt="Continental_map_logos" width="1562" height="1070"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Continental Cups framework is a response to the increasing spread of Roller Derby, and particularly the increasingly global membership of WFTDA. With more than 400 member leagues, an ever decreasing fraction of travel teams can hope to compete in a WFTDA Playoffs (and travel costs become increasingly prohibitive if you just extend the cut-off for Playoffs, or extend the old Division 2). &lt;i&gt;Regional&lt;/i&gt; "Continental Cups" provide a WFTDA-certified tournament, for every region with enough teams, at a level just below that of Playoffs - but with much less travel costs. (Next year, there will also be a set of regional "Development Cups", providing a WFTDA-certified tournament option for regions who aren't competitive at the old "D2" level, with guest "seed" teams from more "connected" regions to help improve ranking accuracy.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe's Continental Cup, then, has a familiar set of teams (and countries) represented (order from WFTDA announcement):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Kallio Rolling Rainbow (Finland)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dublin Roller Derby (Ireland)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dock City Rollers (Sweden)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers (Wales)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Central City Roller Derby (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby (England)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
The current FTS Europe rankings (which include a different subset of games to WFTDA rankings; excluding games against teams outside Europe, but including unsanctioned games) disagree somewhat with this ordering - FTS thinks that some of these teams were strong enough to make Playoffs ahead of some of the European representation there! - but predict a rather close set of games, regardless. In fact, FTS currently rates the two "local" teams - hosts Birmingham Blitz Dames, and Central City Roller Derby - as being exceptionally close in strength - sadly, the bracket prevents them from meeting unless they both lose their first games, or meet in the final.
Similarly, FTS expects some surprisingly close matches in the first round of the elimination bracket, despite WFTDA's usual slaughter pairing setup: Kallio versus Middlesbrough should be a near-draw by European data; although WFTDA sanctioned ratings place Kallio much higher than the UK team. If you're playing the Bracket Challenge for this contest, that's your best chance for an early upset...
&lt;p&gt;Despite, or perhaps causing, of the possibility of so many upsets and ranking disparities, the European Continental Cup should continue the example of the two North American CCs, in having a higher than "usual" number of close bouts, despite the tendency of elimination tournaments to start with a round of blowouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bracket is available here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.wixstatic.com/ugd/590519_be81975ec1304fcf96b32590ddbe2d8a.pdf"&gt;BRACKET PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (note for those not in the UK - this event is on the weekend that the UK changes over from Daylight Savings Time, so be careful checking timings for the Sunday, in particular).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-27324" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/officials_eur_map.png?w=2048" alt="Officials_EUR_map" width="1024" height="768"&gt; Geographical distribution of European Officials at the ECC! Stars may represent more than one official from a given location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as for the competition, the Continental Cup is also a great chance for more representation for our highly skilled European Officiating community. Just at the Tournament and Crew Head levels, we have officials from Karlsruhe, Newcastle, Dublin, Nottingham, Paris/Lutece, London/Southern Discomfort, (and Michigan...) - including all of the other crew positions adds (deep breath) Amsterdam, Antwerp, Bath, Belfast, Birmingham, Brussels, Cambridge, Cardiff, Chelmsford, Copenhagen, Darmstadt, Devon, Dresden, Dundee, Essex, Falkirk, Frankfurt, Gothenburg, Kallio/Helsinki, Manchester, Metz, Mons, Nantes, Northampton, Oxford, Riems, Ruhrpott, Southend, Southampton, Vicenza, Vienna, Wiltshire, Wuppertal,  (and Rochester, NY; Monterrey County, CA; St Louis, MO; Boston, MA; USA... and Adelaide, SA, Australia)! Just as with the other international events in Europe this year, this kind of exposure, and opportunity to both officiate at a high level, and meet up with a wider-flung segment of the Derby Community is fantastic for Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not all, as there's also fantastic line-up of (mostly...) European announcers, from Head Announcer Biertrix (Rainy City Roller Derby), through a host of UK announcers from London through Manchester to Durham and Newcastle; and from Germany, Denmark, as well as the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, as with all WFTDA post-season events this year, there will be a genuine chance for all members of the community (WFTDA-members or no) to connect with WFTDA Membership via the co-hosted "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/772801099579539/"&gt;WFTDA World Summit Satellite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" event. We're very impressed by WFTDA's increased commitment to listening to the voices of the whole community, and would encourage the community to also make use of these opportunities in return: listening should be rewarded with dialogue. (On that note, WFTDA are also surveying every league which does derby and are not WFTDA-members - regardless of their gender policy etc - and we'd encourage everyone eligible to respond to this too, here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.org/surveys"&gt;WFTDA.org/surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The European Continental Cup will run from &lt;strong&gt;October 27th to October 28th&lt;/strong&gt; at The International Centre, Telford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WFTDA Continental Cup page: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/events/wftda-continental-cups/"&gt;https://wftda.com/events/wftda-continental-cups/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Facebook Event for European Continental Cup: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>birmingham blitz dames</category><category>central city roller derby</category><category>continental cup</category><category>dock city rollers</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>kallio rolling rainbow</category><category>middlesbrough roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments2018</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/04/europes-first-continental-cup-the-uks-next-international-derby-fixture-in-2018/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 15:54:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Slavic Roller Derby Tournament grows into its second year, adds the Baltics!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/23/the-slavic-roller-derby-tournament-grows-into-its-second-year-adds-the-baltics/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, we &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/08/11/a-slavic-tournament-how-central-and-eastern-european-derby-exploded-in-just-3-years/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reported&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the first ever "Slavic Roller Derby Tournament", a three team round-robin hosted by Warsaw Hellcats, and featuring St Petersburg's White Night Furies, and Prague City Roller Derby B in addition to the hosts. At the time, we noted that the mere possibility of this tournament existing was a signal for just how fast Roller Derby is expanding into Eastern Europe...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and that expansion has continued into this year, so it is perhaps unsurprising that the tournament is back for a second year this October; bigger and more extensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27274" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/slavic_map_out.png?w=2048" alt="SLAVIC_map_out" width="1024" height="650"&gt; Competitors in Red, except the hosts (in Blue), and the three teams contributing to Team Czech (in Yellow). Men's Derby bout competitors in Black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poland have outdone expectations by doubling the number of contenders this time around, and extending the geographical inclusion to the southern Baltic states as well as Slavic nations. Fitting the resulting 6 team round robin into a single day is only possible with non-WFTDA rulesets (15 games would take 15 hours of WFTDA play, not including breaks), so this edition of the Slavic Tournament is being run as with Roller Derby Sevens rules. The reduced maximum roster size of Sevens also makes it more accessible for some of the newer competitors as an additional bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, this added accessibility has allowed several other firsts at this event:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riga Roller Derby, representing Latvia, have previous bout experience, as part of the Team Baltic Roller Derby who competed against Team Israel at the 2018 Roller Derby World Cup - but have never played as a team themselves. Their Sevens team will therefore represent multiple firsts here: the first time Riga have competed as a team, and the first time &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; team from the (south) Baltics have competed in a ranked event!
This is very good timing, as the Baltics have just gained their third official league - in Tallinn, Estonia - this week, showing the work done in Riga and Tartu paying off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Baltic is not the only connection to the Roller Derby World Cup, as Team Czech Roller Derby will be representing their country in Sevens form, with skaters from Prague's Prague City Roller Derby and Hard Breaking Dolls, joined by members of Roller Derby Brno. Brno's skaters on Team Czech will all be skating in their first public bouts at this tournament, giving them good experience to take back to their league. (We hope that next time Team Czech plays, they can also include skaters from the newly formed league in Ostravia, also announced this week!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27275" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/slavic_czech_map_out.png?w=2048" alt="SLAVIC_CZECH_map_out" width="1024" height="714"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Host country Poland will be exceptionally well represented, with not only hosts Warsaw Hellcats, and their fellow Warsaw team, Worst Warsaw, competing, but also Vratislavia (Wrocław)'s MadChix Roller Squad! All three teams have at least several games under their belt, and contributed skaters to Team Poland, (although Warsaw's teams are a lot more experienced!). Additionally, all are particularly used to Sevens tournaments, having competed in the 7th Heaven tournament in Poznań only a few months ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also returning to the tournament from last time are the only bouting team in Russia, St Petersburg's White Night Furies; although they are sending their newer B team, Ingria Rollers, to compete this time around. The Furies also gained a lot of experience from their members in Team Russia at the World Cup this year (as well as their continued participation in the Pohjola Cup), so we're expecting a strong performance from their B Team here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The restrictions of Sevens rostering make it difficult to predict the standings of the Slavic/Baltic tournament from FTS records (not least because several of these teams are playing for the first time!), but we'd be unsurprised by strong performances from the hosts, and the composite Czech team. Given the strong tournament experience gained by many of the competitors here in the past year, however, it's hard to rule anyone out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the main event, this edition of the Slavic/Baltic Tournament will also be showcasing two other contests:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another debut, this time in men's roller derby: Polish Men's Roller Derby, a collaboration of the Polish Eagles skaters based in Poland itself, play their first game on home soil, ever, against the might of London's Southern Discomfort B, Mild Discomfort!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, finally, a chance to see another fantastic sport on wheels, as Warsaw's Wheelchair Rugby team present their sport in an exhibition game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2079168135665222/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;first Slavic/Baltic Tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will be held on the 20th October in &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/XDcKWPs5wWN2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centrum Sportu Wilanów&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in Warsaw, Poland. Tickets and more information will be available on the Facebook Event in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>baltic roller derby</category><category>czech republic</category><category>hard breaking dolls</category><category>ingria rollers</category><category>international derby</category><category>poland</category><category>polish roller derby</category><category>prague city roller derby</category><category>riga roller derby</category><category>roller derby sevens</category><category>slavic tournament</category><category>southern discomfort</category><category>team czech</category><category>team poland</category><category>team poland men's roller derby</category><category>team russia</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>tournaments2018</category><category>vratislavia madchix</category><category>white night furies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/23/the-slavic-roller-derby-tournament-grows-into-its-second-year-adds-the-baltics/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 09:57:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The 5th Colombian National Tournament: 2018 so far!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/01/the-5th-colombian-national-tournament-2018-so-far/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For our third important, but easily missed, tournament this year, we're heading north to Colombia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In common with Brazil and Mexico, Colombia began large scale national series relatively early.  From 2012 to 2014, a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TorneoRollerDerbyColombia/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colombian National Tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was organised, awarding wins to Bogotá's Rock N Roller Queens and Bone Breakers. Since then, however, things have been less consistent: whilst there has been a "Western Region" tournament every year since (the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/597182954013880/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Torneo Regional de Occidente&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ), and a "District Tournament" for the huge number of teams in the capital of Bogotá (the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TorneoDistritalRollerDerby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Torneo Distrital Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ), there was not an overall National Championship in 2015 or 16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2017, however, things have been getting more on track, with Bogotá Bone Breakers winning both the 4th Distrital (for qualification), and the resulting &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/4nacionalrollerderby/"&gt;Torneo Nacional&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in mid-November, the first since 2014, to take the overall Championship for the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The previous Championship set up continues for 2018, and we're already deep into the Qualifying Tournaments, so there's plenty for us to catch you up on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the uneven distribution of teams across Colombia, the two qualifiers have very different geographical extents - although they have similar numbers of eligible competitors. From &lt;em&gt;each&lt;/em&gt; qualifier, the top &lt;em&gt;three&lt;/em&gt; teams are then passed onto the Championship itself, to play for the cup, so that six teams play overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the teams competing this year, the two most experienced are Bogotá's Bone Breakers (Bx3), who date back to 2009, and fellow Bogotá based team, Rock N Roller Queens, who date from the same period. These two are also the only WFTDA member leagues in Colombia - with the Queens having joined as early as 2013, and Bx3 waiting until 2016. Before and after WFTDA membership, both leagues' A teams have always been well travelled within Latin America (for example, attending several of 2x4 Roller Derby's Violentango tournaments in Buenos Aires).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside Bogotá, Manizales' Valkyrias are easily the oldest team, founded in 2010 as well. Valkyrias have also travelled fairly widely in recent years, having attended the 5th Sailor City Rollers hosted &lt;em&gt;Piratas en el Asfalto&lt;/em&gt; tournament in 2017, also in Buenos Aires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the other end of the scale, we believe that Bogotá's youngest team in the tournament is Fugitivas Roller Punk, founded in 2016, whilst Cali's Silver Lynx Roller Derby are probably the youngest outside the capital region, dating from 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most geographically distributed Qualifier is the &lt;em&gt;Torneo Regional de Occidente&lt;/em&gt;, covering the entire West of Colombia. (The East of Colombia has a very low population density, being mostly covered by those parts of the Amazon rainforest in the Colombian borders). &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/597182954013880/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This year's tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the 6th, was hosted by Medellín's Spring City Rollers, from the 9th to 11th June as a single event - a round robin tournament with 5 competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valkyrias Roller Derby, of Manizales, gave a very impressive performance, taking the top of the leaderboard, just above the hosts Spring City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silver Lynx Roller Derby, and Bucaramanga's Pink Sucks Roller Derby, were unable to prevent Violet Attack, of Ibague, from taking the third qualifying spot. This is a significant improvement in Violet Attack's performance from last year, although the absence of several teams from the tournament may have helped them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the results available to us, it appears that Valkyrias have significantly improved on last year, with only new-this-year Spring City causing them any particular challenge. (We've been unable to source complete scores for the tournament, however, so we can't be certain about the relative strength of third place holders Violet Attack.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27149" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/torneoregional3.png?w=1024" alt="TorneoRegional" width="1024" height="768"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second Qualifier, the &lt;em&gt;Torneo Distrital&lt;/em&gt;, is centred entirely on the large capital city, Bogotá, and run as a round-robin with multiple fixtures throughout the year. Last year's District tournament was a huge affair with multiple divisions, and a packed structure (each fixture was a triple-header to accommodate all the teams).
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TorneoDistritalRollerDerby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This year's Distrital&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the 5th, is a much more compact affair, with all of the "B" teams, and the men's derby division, removed entirely.  Instead, the five big leagues of the capital area are all competing with their A teams only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the first round of play, the current standings in the Distrital are:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Bogotá Bone Breakers&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Combativas Revoltosas&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Rock N Roller Queens&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Central Derby D.C. Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fugitivas Roller Punk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
This is also the ordering of the same teams at the end of the last National Tournament, so we're not expecting any particular upsets going forward.
&lt;p&gt;The final phase of the tournament, in this year's design, will see the top 4 seed into a slaughter-pairing elimination tournament, to decide the winner, second and third places. As such, it is impossible for the Fugitivas to qualify for a top 3 position, and thus impossible for them to qualify for a place in the Torneo National this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27144" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/torneodistrital.png?w=1024" alt="TorneoDistrital" width="1024" height="768"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 5th Torneo Nacional will be hosted, in &lt;strong&gt;November 2018&lt;/strong&gt;, by the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ValkyriasRollerDerby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valkyrias&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, who gained the rights by qualifying first in June. There is no precise date announced yet, although we'd expect around the second week of the month, based on the previous tournament schedules. This is the first time the event has been held in Manizales, with three of the last 4 having been hosted in the capital, and the other (in 2013) in Medellín.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are guaranteed changes to the finishing order from 2017, even at this early date: the three Regional teams qualifying this year are entirely different to 2017 (when Pink Sucks, Ibague's Pain Dealers, and the Titanias of Cali were the qualifiers).
Even so, the SRDRank ratings for the current top 3 Distrital division teams are all noticeably higher than those for the Regional qualifying teams (we place current-4th-position Central Derby D.C. as competitive with the Valkyrias, at last estimate).  All four previous Torneo Nacionals have seen the same top three teams, in fact, with various combinations of Bx3, Rock N Roller Queens and Combativas in each position; although for the first time last year, the Rock N Roller Queens were relegated to third place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible, then, that this could be the first year that the Valkyrias - who have the best form of any of the Regional teams - might make bronze, especially with home team advantage!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particular thanks to Central Derby D.C. Roller Derby for their assistance in writing this article; and to the 5th Nacional hosts, Valkyrias.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>colombia</category><category>distrital</category><category>international derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>regional occidente</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments2018</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/01/the-5th-colombian-national-tournament-2018-so-far/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 09:34:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chilean National Championships 2018 - Torneo X returns!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/26/chilean-national-championships-2018-torneo-x-returns/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chile's National Tournament, the mysteriously named &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TorneoX/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Torneo X&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, has been running for as long, or longer, than many of the better-known European tournaments, having begun in 2015. (The Men's Derby equivalent in Chile, Torneo X-MEN, started 2 years later.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the 4th event coming up at the start of next month, we're giving you a quick overview of the tournament and the players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Chile is a long, thin, country, as the tournament has expanded, it has done so mostly north/south, following the areas of highest population density. A bit like Scotland, Chile has a band of high population (in this case, roughly in the middle of the country), surrounded by low density rural areas to the north and south. Torneo X 2018 fills this entire high density area, for the first time in its history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26980 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/torneox_map.gif" alt="TorneoX_map" width="600" height="568"&gt; Torneo X's growth over time since inception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, Chillán's Chillanrolleras retained the title from the previous year, maintaining an unbroken streak since they joined the tournament. However, Viña del Mar's Tacones Bandidos pushed them until the very last bouts for that title, so a repeat performance in 2018 is definitely not assured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is especially true as, with 2018's tournament growing to become the biggest yet, there are even more challengers for the cup. Especially likely to want to make a big splash are Santiago's Metropolitan Roller Derby, the only WFTDA-member league in the tournament, although it's their B-team, the Bayonetas, who are competing here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Torneo X 2018 will consist of 4 fixtures across the coming months, spread across the competing regions:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1st&lt;/strong&gt; Fixture: Osorno (Deskarriadas) &lt;strong&gt;4-5 August [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/212354766088268/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2nd&lt;/strong&gt; Fixture: Santiago (Adrenaline) &lt;strong&gt;8-9 September&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd&lt;/strong&gt; Fixture: Viña del Mar (Tacones Bandidos) &lt;strong&gt;6-7 October&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final&lt;/strong&gt; Puerto Montt (Diosas Volcanicas) &lt;strong&gt;9-10 November&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-26981" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/torneox_map.png?w=602" alt="TorneoX_map" width="602" height="1024"&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;The historical rankings for the previous editions of the tournament are: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rank&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2015&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nativas RD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chillanrolleras&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chillanrolleras&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deskarriadas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deskarriadas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tacones Bandidos&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Diosas Volcanicas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nativas RD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Diosas Volcanicas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Diosas Volcanicas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deskarriadas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A Sangre Fría RD (Osorno)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adrenaline&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;RD Valdivia / Cuello Negro [as "Indomitas" 2018]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chillanrolleras Derby Club&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chíllan's premier team, and twice winners of the Torneo X, Chillanrolleras were bouting as early as 2013, although we have a gap in our records in 2015. From 2016, they've hosted multiple tournaments - including fixtures for the 2017 Torneo X itself - and have rarely lost a bout. SRDRank's current (unpublished) rating places them as the favourites to win the Torneo X title, and maintain their streak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chillanrolleras, as with many teams in Chile, have a brother league - Chillanrolleros - who share resources with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tacones Bandidos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tacones Bandidos are based in the coastal region of Vińa del Mar, Valparaíso. In their current form, they date from 2014, as a partnership with men's team, Bototos Bandidos.
The Tacones have had a pretty busy year to date - playing not just Chilean teams, but also Buenos Aires' Sailor City Rollers B, who they fought to a near-draw within the last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd rate the Tacones as likely to strongly contest the second place with the tournament newcomers from Santiago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diosas Volcánicas Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puerto Montt &amp;amp; Puerto Varas's Diosas Volcánicas are one of the older teams in Chile, dating back to 2012, founded by Dahmenatrix from San Diego Derby Dolls. They're one of the most southerly teams in Roller Derby (and certainly in Latin America), with only a few teams in southern Argentina and New Zealand much more to the south.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They've had a difficult time finding practice space, and have had periods where most training was outside (in one of the wetter regions of Chile!). This year, they've finally achieved stable training space - in a local prison gym! - and have been working on recruitment and training more intensively since then.
Their aim for 2018 is to qualify for the finals (in the top 4 of the table)... and then who knows how high in 2019?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deskarriadas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deskarriadas are the largest team in Osorno, founded in May 2014. They're the hosts of the first fixture of this year's Torneo X, in the first weekend in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Deskarriadas have been working towards the Torneo X all year, aiming to improve on their performance last year (where they placed 4th). In the first two years, they managed 2nd place, which is, we assume, their target for 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adrenaline Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adrenaline Roller Derby, one of two Santiago-based teams in the tournament, are the youngest contestants, founded in 2016. This relative youth has counted against them in ratings, and we'd consider them likely to be contesting in the same position as last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As hosts of the second fixtures in the tournament, home team advantage may well help them to beat expectations, in a fairly close lower half of the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indomitas RD Valdivia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby Valdivia consists of two member teams - the men's team, Indomitos, and the women's team, which used to be called Cuello Negro ("Black Swans"), but rebranded to Indomitas this year, whilst keeping the same logo. This rebrand was triggered by a complete rebuilding of the team, with the new "Indomitas" very different to the old 2015-2017 Cuello Negro in terms of skaters.
The Indomitas told us that they have spent the past year in intensive drilling, so that all their tactics are instinctive. They are prepared to demonstrate the heart, tenacity and perseverance that they can bring to the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nativas Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Temuco's first team, the Nativas date back to 2013. As with many of the teams here, they have "womens" and "mens" teams - although we can't find a name for the women's team except "Nativas Roller Derby". As one of the oldest teams in Chile, the Nativas competed in the first ever Torneo X, although they skipped the 2017 edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to a sparsity of bout data for the Nativas in FTS, we consider the returning team to be something of a wild card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metropolitan Roller Derby B, Bayonetas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santiago's Metropolitan Roller Derby are the only Chilean members of the WFTDA, with their travel team currently ranked at 122 (May 31 ranking release) by WFTDA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their B-team, the Bayonetas, have existed since 2014, and are one of the few teams in this tournament to have played extensively internationally - at least within South America. Out of the Chilean leagues, they've played nearby Valparaíso's Tacones Bandidos most often, with wildly different results - beating them 2 to 1 early in 2017, and losing by a similar ratio by the end of that year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>chile</category><category>international</category><category>international derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>torneo x</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments2018</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/26/chilean-national-championships-2018-torneo-x-returns/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 12:07:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mexican National Championships 2018</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/18/mexican-national-championships-2018/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Mexican Torneo Nacional de Roller Derby, run by the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/AsociacionMexicanaDeRollerDerby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asociación Mexicana de Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is one of the longest running continuous national tournaments in Roller Derby. Since 2012, the tournament has selected teams from across Mexico for multiple fixtures to determine a champion; and in more recent years, a full ranking system (derived from WFTDA rating calculations) has been applied for cut-offs into the Division 1 and 2 categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tournament proper begins in August of each year, and so we are rapidly approaching the 2018 edition. In anticipation of this, we're bringing you a quick overview of the event, and the teams involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top 12 teams in the AMRD ranking, at the time of selection, are sorted into Division 1, with the chance to play for the Championship. In this case, one team (Ovejas Negras) was forced to withdraw from the competition this year - allowing the 13th ranked team to replace them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Division 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is run as two "playoff" fixtures, each with 6 teams, selecting the top placed teams from each in the Final fixture, to play for the top spot. This year, the Playoffs will be hosted in Monterrey (by Monterrey Roller Derby), and Juárez (by Medias Rotas Roller Derby).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26947 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/mexico_playoffs20181.png" alt="MEXICO_Playoffs2018" width="900" height="675"&gt; Division 1 Playoff Teams for AMRD Nationals 2018, coloured by Playoff location&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Division 1 teams cover almost all of Mexico, except the extreme East, with their distribution roughly matching the population of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monterrey Roller Derby and Mexico City Roller Derby have both won the Championship at least twice over the past 6 Nationals, with Mexico City's wins in both 2016 and 2017. However, at this point in the season, fellow Mexico City based team, Quimeras (of Liga Cuidad de Mexico Roller Derby, LCMRD) are just pipping them in the rankings, making this a pretty contested championship. The alternating seed placement for Playoffs has placed the Quimeras in Monterrey's group, and outside MCRD's group, which will give the current champions some breathing room until the finals themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third in the rankings so far, All-Stars Juárez, have never won the Championship to date, and will be hoping to pick up a win for the northernmost city in the AMRD. Their placement in a group with Quimeras, Monterrey and another former Champion, Minervas, will make this a tough battle. Their fellow Juárez team, Medias Rotas,  have relatively less experience, and a weaker season (we have only 2 bouts on record this year in Flat Track Stats, against fellow D1 teams Division del Norte and Minervas).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the remaining teams, Baja California's Baja Roller Derby and Guadalajara's Minervas are the only other teams to have won the championship, and are seeded into different groups. Minervas have the challenging group with a total of three former champions (including themselves), whilst Baja face the most Mexico City centric group - although at least their travel costs will be moderated, given the closer proximity of Juárez. With Baja currently the second lowest rated and ranked team in Division 1, it will be a big ask for them to make the qualifier for the Finals - Minervas are having a much better year (in a close 5th place), but qualification will require them to defeat All-Star Juárez in their home city...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should not forget the currently fourth-place Division del Norte, of Chihuahua - whilst they haven't won the Championship yet, their current rating places them close to Juárez All-Stars in third (and just ahead of former Champions Minervas). As the second strongest team in their group, they are very likely to qualify - but could easily cause disruption in the finals if they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unexpected addition to the Division 1 list, Fugaz Roller Derby, of Toluca+Mexico City, replace Ovejas Negras, effectively getting a free promotion from Division 2 for the tournament. We assume that they'll be anxious to capitalise on the opportunity to prove themselves against their group - as a relatively new team (formed in the past year from Animas [Toluca] and Valkirias [Mexico City]), they have everything to prove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Playoffs (Division 1)&lt;/strong&gt;: August 11th-12th (Monterrey) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1713274988787386/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;], August 25th-26th (Juárez) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/630219864011209/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;strong&gt;Final&lt;/strong&gt;: 18th-20th November (EMEXRD, Mexico City).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Division 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, meanwhile, sees the next 5 [14 to 19 rank] teams fight it out in a single fixture to determine the top of their group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26991 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/division2mexico_map1.png" alt="Division2Mexico_map" width="960" height="720"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Division 2's teams cover the extremes of Mexico's geography, from Tijuana's Vipers, on the USA/Mexico border to the extreme West, to Cancùn's Reinas Rojas, to the Eastern extent of the country. The remaining three teams are clustered in the densely populated central region of Mexico; Tamaulipas, Nebulosas of Queretaro, and Furiosas of San Luis Potosí.
Tamaulipas Roller Derby, as well as being one of the newer teams to the Nationals (being formed in March this year, as a collaboration between Fairy Dust Roller Derby and Jaibronas Roller Derby), is also hosting Division 2 this year, in October. So far, their performance has placed them at the bottom of the rankings for Division 2, but they have been improving rapidly as their team and coaching gels. With the home-team advantage, they could be a wild-card here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short of an upset, however, the safer money is on a very close battle between Cancún's Red Queens and Queretaro's Nebulosas' space-adventurers for the top spot in the Division. The two teams are exceptionally closely rated in the official AMRD ratings - although FTS has very little data about the Red Queens to day - and so this should be an exciting matchup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Division 2&lt;/strong&gt;: October 6th+7th, hosted by &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TamaulipasRollerDerby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tamaulipas Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>asociación mexicana de roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>mexico</category><category>national tournament</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments2018</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/18/mexican-national-championships-2018/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 14:14:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Torneo Violentango 6: Argentina's biggest tournament goes B/C</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/22/torneo-violentango-6-argentinas-biggest-tournament-goes-b-c/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we reported &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/29/violentango-5-latin-americas-continental-tournament-returns/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;last year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Torneo Violentango, 2x4 Roller Derby's yearly tournament, has taken various forms over recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting as a smaller scale tournament, Violentango 4 (2016) was already a Latin America-wide event, with teams from Argentina, Brasil, Chile, Peru and Uruguay in two divisions. Violentango 5 (2017), which we reported on for the first time, was similarly large in scope, with only Uruguay missing, and more teams from the other regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1774791899244174/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Violentango 6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is changing things up a little again - driven by the demands of WFTDA rankings, 2x4 Roller Derby's Team OSOM will be taking a pass from the tournament for the first time, as the event is remoulded into a "B/C" level tournament, with teams from Argentina and Uruguay attending the two divisions. We're especially happy to see Uruguay returning to the tournament, given the general lack of Uruguayan derby in the popular eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26862" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/violentango_map_crop1.png" alt="Violentango_map_crop" width="2160" height="1893"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In the B-tier, competing are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Pibas (&lt;em&gt;2x4 B&lt;/em&gt;, Buenos Aires)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Alianza Rebelde Roller Derby (La Plata)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Mandrágoras Roller Derby (General Roca)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Wonderclan (Buenos Aires Norte)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;MDQueens (Mar del Plata)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Desalmadas Roller Derby (Piñeiro, Buenos Aires)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The C-tier is a little larger, and also slightly more diverse in origin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Team C (&lt;em&gt;2x4 C&lt;/em&gt;, Buenos Aires)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Fawkes Roller Derby (Merlo, Buenos Aires)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Morón Roller Derby (Morón, Buenos Aires&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Sarcásticats Roller Derby (Mendoza)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Atomic Bombs Roller Derby (Lanús, Buenos Aires)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Centellas Rayo Naranja Roller Derby (San Miguel de Tucumán)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Hienas de la Calle (Neuquén)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class="p1"&gt;Pájaros Pintados (Montevideo, &lt;strong&gt;Uruguay&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With just 6 teams in the B Tier, this will be organised as a 2 groups of 3, feeding into a 4 team single elimination from the top 2 teams in each group. (With unseeded teams, this is the second best possible arrangement to guarantee accurate final placements, and the best using a single elimination phase. It also guarantees a minimum of 3 games per team.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;B Tier: Group 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;B Tier: Group 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2x4 B: Las Pibas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Desalmadas Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alianza Rebelde Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MDQueens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mandrágoras Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wonderclan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="2"&gt;B Tier Elimination Structure&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Round 1 (Semifinal)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Round 2 (Final)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Group 1 Winner&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="2"&gt;Winner (1,2)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Group 2 Second&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Group 1 Second&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="2"&gt;Winner (3,4)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Group 2 Winner&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
Meanwhile, the 8-team C Tier will run as a standard 3 round single elimination, with consolation/repechage bouts for teams knocked out in round 1. (Guaranteeing either 2 or 3 games for each team.)
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="3"&gt;C Tier Tournament Structure&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Round 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Round 2 (Semifinal)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Round 3 (Final)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Centellas RN&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="2"&gt; Winner (1,2)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hienas de la Calle&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sarcásticats Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="2"&gt;Winner (3,4)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fawkes Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Atomic Bombs Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="2"&gt; Winner (5,6)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="4"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pájaros Pintados Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2x4 C: Team C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td rowspan="2"&gt; Winner (7,8)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Morón Roller Derby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Consolation 1: Losers Game 1 v 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Consolation 2: Losers Game 2 v 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
It's hard to make predictions for the tournament, due to the relative sparsity of data in Latin American derby, especially for teams which play infrequently, however, we expect a strong showing from the home teams, &lt;strong&gt;Las Pibas&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Team C&lt;/strong&gt;.
With the limited bout data we have available, we expect strong showings from &lt;strong&gt;Mandrágoras&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Desalmadas&lt;/strong&gt; in particular in the B Tier.
The C Tier is very hard to predict, with 4 teams having too little data in public records to predict (Hienas de la Calle, Atomic Bombs and Team C don't have recent enough public bout results, and Morón can only be rated with a small subset of the Argentinean teams). Of the teams we can try to rate, we expect a strong performance from the &lt;strong&gt;Sarcásticats&lt;/strong&gt;, in particular (who we rate higher than some of the teams in the B Tier...).
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Violentango 6 will run from &lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;9 July&lt;/strong&gt; 2018,  at &lt;strong&gt;Martín Fierro&lt;/strong&gt; Oruro 1310, &lt;strong&gt;Buenos Aires&lt;/strong&gt;, Argentina. Tickets available online &lt;a href="https://articulo.mercadolibre.com.ar/MLA-719453253-torneo-de-roller-derby-violentango-6-pase-completo-_JM"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2x4 roller derby</category><category>alianza rebelde</category><category>articles</category><category>atomic bombs roller derby</category><category>desalmadas</category><category>fawkes</category><category>hienas de la calle</category><category>international derby</category><category>latin american derby</category><category>mandrágoras</category><category>mdqueens</category><category>morón</category><category>pájaros pintados roller derby</category><category>rayo naranja</category><category>sarcásticats</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments2018</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>violentango</category><category>wonderclan</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/22/torneo-violentango-6-argentinas-biggest-tournament-goes-b-c/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 10:20:42 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>