<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about training)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/training.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 10:58:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>COVID-19 and Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/03/COVID19/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's hard not to be aware of the effect that the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic is causing on all human activity, globally, and Roller Derby is not exempt. COVID-19, the disease caused by
SARS-CoV-2, is stretching the health services of several nations. In order to control its spread, an increasing number of internal and external travel and gathering restrictions are being applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Italy and China, where all non-essential gatherings are currently banned, Roller Derby has stopped along with everything else. The Chinese leagues have not been able to practice since the lockdown in their
country in February (with restrictions now slowly being lifted); in Italy since the increasingly escalating actions in the last week or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An increasing number of tournaments are now beginning to cancel. In Italy, the Anguanas' March and April Sanctioned triple-headers have been cancelled; but even in countries with less internal restrictions, there are cancellations. Copenhagen Ladybugs have had to cancel their upcoming Sevens extravaganza due to the Danish advice, for example; and there are a host of cancellations across the continental USA, despite their government's lacklustre response to ongoing events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are yet to see changes to the status of the Men's Roller Derby World Cup or Rollercon, both highly-international events this year, but given the breaking news restrictions placed by the US President on travel from Schengen countries in Europe, it seems increasingly likely that there will be &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; knock-on effect. (They are both scheduled far enough in the future that it is &lt;em&gt;possible&lt;/em&gt; that we could have a pandemic peak before they happen; but once an infectious disease goes pandemic, it becomes much harder to eradicate quickly.) [Edited after initial publication to note: MRDWC have announced that they will be following all local and international advice; but this has not yet resulted in an actual change to their schedule.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://resources.wftda.org/covid-19/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt; has published risk-management guidelines for reducing the spread of SARS-CoV-2 infections if you do hold public games during this period. They essentially reduce to the usual advice that minimising physical contact, and maintaining proper hygiene standards is the most effective way to reduce the spread of the virus, along with recommendations to cancel non-essential events and follow your country's own guidelines and restrictions. (As with other examples of force majeure, WFTDA will not penalise members for cancelling Sanctioned events due to public health concerns around COVID-19.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're hoping to chat to some of the most affected regions and at least help keep their Roller Derby in the public eye a bit, even if they can't play...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...but if you want to help track all the effects on Roller Derby (or just see the results of this), we're linking to Axis of Stevil's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1mZhFN7i7s1vTUCE5g0gfy_YqFNDaUq0sAvWhI0nT1so/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;public Google Doc&lt;/a&gt; for this purpose. Stevil is part of WFTDA's "COVID19 Taskforce", who are working in managing the response to the pandemic and its medical and political effects relating to the sport and its participants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>cancellations</category><category>covid19</category><category>epidemiology</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>oronaviruses</category><category>roller derby</category><category>statistics</category><category>tournaments</category><category>training</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/03/COVID19/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 07:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Directory: a new (UK-focused) resource for growing the sport.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/21/derby-directory-a-new-uk-focused-resource-for-growing-the-sport/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A perennial question from people starting derby: from rookies joining a new team, through to the most scary challenge, people starting an entirely new league or team, is "how do I do this?".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst there are actually a lot of resources out in the wild concerning various aspects of roller derby, they're often fairly disorganised and dispersed, or strewn across various Facebook and other social media groups which aren't necessarily the easiest to find. (The original roller derby leagues in the UK created a newsgroup for this, which eventually evolved into UKRDA, but things have moved on since then.) Additionally, there's a big problem with link-rot and social media decay in modern resources, which can easily lead to a given source of information vanishing, becoming stale, or otherwise more useless over time. (We wrote a little about this issue &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;earlier this year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26888 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/derbydirectory.jpg" alt="DerbyDirectory" width="426" height="426"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://derbydirectory.info/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derby Directory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aims to solve all of this, at least in the UK; although its resources are mostly useful regardless of where your league is based. The brainchild of two of Border City Roller Derby, Carlisle's members - coach, referee, and founder Schrödinger's Phat #1691, and coach and skater Hoolia #2122 - this website aims to collect together, and organise, all the information you need to start up a league, or start off as a newbie skater. As Border City has only very recently transitioned to the state of being a "bouting" league, the issues of beginning skaters, and beginning leagues, are very fresh in the minds of all involved.&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps as a result, the site's organisation is really very good, with categories from the Rookie Corner (a step-by-step guide to the frequently asked questions of people new to derby), and Kit (including an itemised list of the mandatory kit items, with suggested products, ordered by price), through a comprehensive guide to Skate Care, links to Bootcamps and Coaches who are available to run sessions, and even a guide on Starting a New League.
In all cases, the clean, simple style, and clearly defined categories help to get to the information you need, quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with all projects like this, the proof of the pudding will be in the longer term - but both of the founders seem committed to maintaining and updating the site - both expanding it, and fighting the entropic forces of link rot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They're also still collecting offers of additional information - and especially Coaches available to run sessions for their mini-classified section there. If you're a Coach whose time is available for other teams, do let the Derby Directory team know!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coaching</category><category>communication</category><category>derby directory</category><category>in the news</category><category>reviews</category><category>training</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/21/derby-directory-a-new-uk-focused-resource-for-growing-the-sport/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 10:15:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Big Blether: Scotland Together</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/18/the-big-blether-scotland-together/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's often been commented that Scotland has seen some of the more dramatic growth (and changes) in Roller Derby, with respect to its population. Since the first league started in Glasgow in 2007, Roller Derby has spread across the Nation - but not always uniformly, or consistently. Whilst there's certainly a lot of Roller Derby in Scotland now - with 19 leagues in existence (by one count) now - communication and organisation across the community has not always been as good as it could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;October 7th&lt;/strong&gt;, in Edinburgh's Charteris Centre, three people aim to change this. Auld Reekie Roller Girls' Crazylegs and (Steph) Skinner, and Glasgow Roller Derby's head referee Candy Moho, are organising what they hope will be the first of a regular series of gatherings of the Scottish Roller Derby Community in one place and one time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-24409 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/screen-shot-2017-09-13-at-16-17-08.png" alt="Screen Shot 2017-09-13 at 16.17.08" width="335" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Big Blether&lt;/em&gt;, as it's now known, aims to bring together all of the extant leagues and clubs in Scotland, as well as others in the sport, in order to share and discuss the future and present of the sport. Every active league in Scotland has been invited to the event as part of the organisation process,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to two-thirds of the Organisers - thrice Team Scotland skater,  founding Roller Derby Nations Committee rep, and founding Auld Reekie Roller Girls member, &lt;em&gt;Crazylegs&lt;/em&gt;; and long-standing Glasgow Roller Derby Head Referee and organiser of the Scottish Roller Derby Events Spreadsheet, &lt;em&gt;Candy Moho&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crazylegs was inspired to kickstart this idea at the last European Rollerderby Organisational Conference, as she told us. "I guess for me the inspiration came from EROC - I love attending that event, and I guess the more I go to events like that and attend sessions, and deliver talks,  I kind of think, we've got such a compact community in Scotland - and I don't think we take advantage of it enough.
Our league [ARRG] gets so much out of events like EROC in terms of knowledge and new ideas to refresh you. It's so much easier for us to get together in Scotland - the leagues in Australia might find it harder to all meet up, for example - but we're so close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chatted to Candy at the end of EROC, and she mentioned that she'd been thinking of something similar, so it was in my mind from then."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candy, meanwhile, had a slightly different perspective. "My main focus was the Officials side, off of the back of a project I'd done for the Open Uni. And also being in the Event Organising Group, the Interleague Liasion group, a lot of the issues there - it just seemed it would be easier to get people in the same room to talk to each other!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;One of the things I am planning to do at The Big Blether is to present the findings from my OU project, which focussed on Scottish Derby Officials - I've not had a chance to pass on the results of that to the community, and I thought this is the perfect forum to do it, and make the results public after. That took in feedback from Officials as well as skaters from leagues. A lot of the stuff from that is still very relevant, and it's relevant to UK officials as well."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Unlike EROC's speaker-centered sessions, The Big Blether is intended to foster a less hierarchical approach - each topic will have a "facilitator" to moderate, but will emphasise communication and discussion between peers, not a top-down dissemination of from on-high.&lt;/p&gt;
Topics on the agenda currently cover the spectrum of community concerns and interests, from best practice in Training, through the creation of better links for interleague support and with local communities, and how to move the sport on in terms of recognition on both local and National/International scales; however, in keeping with the design of the event, there are no topics which are out of bounds if attendees wish to discuss them.
&lt;p&gt;Speaking to the organisers, again, they each have their own favourite areas from the menu presented. For Crazylegs, a key topic is governance and organisation, on all scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We want to cover topics like League Governance - so: the legalities of how you set up a league, how you structure a league, what works for different leagues, of different sizes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I guess leading on from that you'd look at&lt;span class="Apple-converted-space"&gt; sports &lt;/span&gt;governance - as in governing bodies, as in the national teams, UKRDA, WFTDA [MRDA], just I think maybe putting a bit of information out there for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I think there's a lot of myths out there concerning the various bodies - but we also need to talk about what Scotland itself needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;I know Stef's driving force for this comes from her job, she's a community sports officer, and she's been has been doing a lot of research around the growth of sport, how we can better use Sport Scotland, and have better links with them for funding and support. We were also discussing working on having clear pathways, to show people how they can get to where they want to go - if that's high level competition, or having fun - from where they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;And I think training as well - what support setups different leagues need, if we feel that there needs to be more information out there about training and structures, and how to set things up from beginning to getting wherever your league or team wants to go."&lt;/p&gt;
Candy, with her other hat on, is most concerned with another topic. "On the Events side: getting a Scottish Tournament (doing another "Highland Fling", perhaps) but also the topic of if we need to look into a League structure - as they have in Germany  and France. I think you tend to find that when you have that kind of structure, and people working well together, then you also drive the sport, and the level of competition as well. "
&lt;p&gt;But, most of all, the event is about everyone meeting up and building the community links that can make Scottish Derby stronger together. As Crazylegs notes, "having a relaxed chat to people that you don't know, but you've heard of their leagues - if you get that kind of face-to-face conversation with people you've only interacted with on social media, then you make better connections, and everyone learns something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The venue's amazing, it's close to town, we'll get some nice stuff going on in the breaks to build connections - and we'll be providing a delicious lunch!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Charteris Centre can be found &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Greyfriars+Charteris+Centre/@55.9455414,-3.1817633,19.53z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x104319695d91d9d9!8m2!3d55.9456793!4d-3.1812937"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here on Google Maps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
Sign up for leagues (who are already contacted) is for the &lt;strong&gt;23rd September&lt;/strong&gt;, with potential for other slots for non-league attendees after the initial numbers are known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All questions can be sent to the event organisers at &lt;a href="mailto:scottishderbyevent@gmail.com"&gt;scottishderbyevent@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial shortlist of topics is:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Training: Creation of clear pathways and sharing best practice&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sport recognition (Leagues, National/International Governing Bodies and National Teams)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Club governance; sharing best practices / resources / contacts, league support.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Scottish Events Scheduling: game scheduling, events, opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Partnership working, local communities&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Officiating: recruitment and retention, development pathways, national association&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Volunteering (development, pathways, recruitment, training)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
The organisers would like to thank Auld Reekie Roller Girls for funding both the event, and travel subsidies for the more distant leagues.&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>interviews</category><category>news</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>the big blether</category><category>training</category><category>upcoming events</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/18/the-big-blether-scotland-together/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 07:09:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lannthrax Talks to: Wintourope Glasgow edition</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/16/lannthrax-talks-to-wintourope-glasgow-edition/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So if you were at the Glasgow edition of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1717432861812471/"&gt;Wintourope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, you should probably by now, know your Toe Stop Pop from your Zip Zap Zop. If not, then I'm sorry, all I have for you is an interview with the lovely coaches. Scald Eagle and Lady Trample took the time to chat with me and I must admit, I felt like a fan-girl. These guys are two of my favourite skaters to watch and I'm so glad I got this opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13937 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/wintourope.jpg" alt="wintourope" width="960" height="354"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lanna&lt;/strong&gt;- “ How do you guys deal with the fame attribution that comes along with being at the top level within the sport?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scald&lt;/strong&gt;- “First of all, Fame is fleeting. What might be hot now might be day-old news next week. Saying that, I will always do my best regardless of status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The derby fame is something that you just have to deal with; I can still walk into a 7/11 and no one knows who I am, but you wouldn't see Lebron James walk into a 7/11. However, if I walk in to Rollercon, that’s a different story. Sometimes it’s hard to just make it to the bathroom and back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what I've really worked on is to put time aside and do what needs to be done but also make sure I have time to do what I need to do. It's great though: I am more than happy to have those interactions and I love it. It feels just like yesterday for me that I was waiting in line to get stuff signed and having people that I looked up to. I have a lot of patience for it and I love to do it”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trample&lt;/strong&gt;- “ One of the interesting things about, it is there is a level of responsibility, you have to be careful about what you put in the public eye. You are so accessible through social media. However, it also gives you a chance to do things for the community and opportunities to travel and share your knowledge, which I think Isn't really a thing you would see in other sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lanna&lt;/strong&gt;- “ Mental resilience is something that I personally have struggled with, how do you guys switch off that part of your brain and just get the job done?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trample&lt;/strong&gt;- “It’s something that comes with time; I had a really great coach this year and the main thing he would say to me is to back myself, so much so that I actually got a tattoo of it. It’s a nice memento that I can take with me to remind myself that I've worked hard and to trust my instincts, my pack, my offence, defence and my coaches. If your team are putting you on the line, they believe in you. It takes a little bit of self belief: I played some of my hardest games last year and once I got on that line I just had to remind myself that I've done all the training and to just let it all come into motion”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scald&lt;/strong&gt;- “I think that's where I'm at. In gameplay my cognitive part switches off and my instincts take over, I let my muscle memory do its thing. I don't know how often I have to actually tell myself to continue because it’s more like that's what I have to do, it's instinct. When I think about mental fortitude it’s about getting through practice week to week and living through the dynamics of my team at that level. When you're at that level you don't have the choice to just switch to the next team across town. If you want to play at that level I think the hardest part in my opinion is not figuring out how to deal with your opponents but how you can work well with your team mate”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lanna&lt;/strong&gt;- “ What have your highlights of the Winter Tour been so far ?”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scald&lt;/strong&gt;- “ (adopts an awkward Scottish accent) Shcotland! Och aye ye wee lass, We're in the land of Ootlander an' its ma favourite show and a cannae wait to be here. Its gonnae be a great time. (Back to American) I am super excited to be up here, I've been once before and I loved it. In the US we spent a lot of time re-visiting leagues that I had already been to so it was a lot about going and seeing old friends. We spent our time on the south west but I anticipate that next time round we will head along the east. As far as for the Wintourope Tour, my last name is Buschovik, so I’m really excited to go to Poland. I don't know much what it’s going to be like but it’s going to be an experience. The point of life is to experience new things so...”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trample&lt;/strong&gt;- “ I'm super excited to be in Europe because I've never been on this side of the world. I have a little bit of heritage in Scotland so it was cool to come and explore this place a little bit. Everywhere we are going is exciting to me and there's people who I've been talking to online for the past few years who I'm now getting to meet. They are all coming to our ramp camps and people are travelling all over the world to get to the different bootcamps. Chicks in Bowls is at close to 250 Chapters and it’s amazing I get to meet so many of the Chapter admins and members”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lanna&lt;/strong&gt;- “ And finally, What advice would you give to skaters who want to improve their game?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scald&lt;/strong&gt; - “I think that off skates training is really important, mostly from an injury prevention standpoint. You may not like going to the gym, but going to the ER is much less fun. Having strong quads helps you have strong knees and as women we have naturally weak knees so it's imperative that we strengthen the muscles around them so that they can withstand the torque we put them under. Same with ankles, there's so many baby ankle muscles and foot muscles that we need to look after. If you want to be a kick ass skater and be better than the person next to you then you need to start doing some squats with weight and different things like that. At Rose specifically one of the keys to our success, I believe, is that we have a required gym hour 2 hours a week where we all train together in the gym.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trample&lt;/strong&gt;- “ I don't really do off skates, I know, I'm bad. But I have recently been convinced by Scald that I should be hitting the gym especially to do Pre-hab. I rolled my ankle a while back and I'll do the rehab until its better but then I'm straight back on skates, and it’s not good because a few months later I'll roll my ankle again and it’s because I didn't build up the strength that I needed to help the muscles fully recover and be strong enough to stop the injury from happening again. So I am in a position now where I'm going to push myself to do it”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, there you have it. It was an absolute pleasure to interview these lovely ladies and hopefully you all take something away from my questions. Huge thanks to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GlasgowMensRollerDerby/"&gt;GMRD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for hosting a fantastic event and making sure the day was super fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Till next time
Much Love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next WinTourope is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1852698681626181/"&gt;WinTourope Poland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, this weekend (21-22nd Jan), followed by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/227698337655754/"&gt;Netherlands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/381880268819988/"&gt;France&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and finally &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/146844349126661/"&gt;England&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>chicks in bowls</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>training</category><category>wintourope</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/16/lannthrax-talks-to-wintourope-glasgow-edition/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 19:25:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Guest Post: Mental Strength with Power of Scotland's Optimus Grime</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/07/guest-post-mental-strength-with-power-of-scotlands-optimus-grime/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The recent &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/753462044787328/"&gt;Power of Scotland Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was a huge success, but unfortunately time pressure meant that &lt;strong&gt;Optimus Grime&lt;/strong&gt;'s &lt;em&gt;Mental Strength&lt;/em&gt; presentation (a complement to his &lt;em&gt;Physical Strength&lt;/em&gt; seminar) was cut.
For posterity, and to provide everyone with its benefits, Grime has written it up and graciously allowed us to publish it.
The below is all Optimus Grime's work (including selection of images, although the images themselves are the work of others, and credited appropriately).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;WARNING&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is best consumed with epic 80's motivational soundtracks from such films as the Rocky series, Karate Kid or Commando [The editor would also like to recommend &lt;a href="http://powergloveaudio.bandcamp.com/album/ep-1"&gt;PowerGlove's EP1&lt;/a&gt; for a similar effect]. The author intent was for it to be spoken aloud &amp;amp; PROUD. Side effects may include feelings of Getupandgoitis, motivationarrhoea &amp;amp; goosebumposis!! You have been WARNED!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1460021054231.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="wp-1460021054231" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1460021054231.jpg" alt="image" width="699" height="400"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Unknown copyright: please let us know if this is your image.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mental Strength:
It starts with a dream:
Conceive - A dream to achieve a goal. A dream to become something you can be proud of. Whether the goal is big or small is not important, as long as it IS important. It must mean something significant to you.
Believe - Thoughts .....become.....things. You must think about what it is you want and believe 100%, without any doubt that it is achievable. Doubts......will .......delay ......dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Achieve - For a goal to be a successful, a plan on how to achieve that goal must be made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions need to be asked. How do I get there? What must I do? How long will it take? Who do I need to learn from? IT IS ABOUT THE REMOVAL OF VARIABLES. Variables lead to detriment, distraction &amp;amp; even destruction. Questions are variables and once all the questions are answered, the journey can begin.
It's about creating a foundation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a body to become proficient at something it must be practiced &amp;amp; built up from a foundation. The same applies to the mind. Treat your mind like a wall or building. The first brick in your foundation is a dream. It is the root of achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This initial brick in your foundation must be strong. To do this a decision has to be made. You have to decide to commit to this dream and with that endeavour to not quit on it until it is completed. Decision is an extremely difficult thing to do. It is scary, new and takes a huge effort, but in a way it is wonderfully frightening. Once the decision is made, the rest is much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decision is incision. To decide is to cut off the chance of being deterred or distracted away from completion of your goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So just DECIDE. (Variable eliminated).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1460021066618.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="wp-1460021066618" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1460021066618.jpg" alt="image" width="960" height="540"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Photo: &lt;a href="http://lauramacd.co.uk/roller-derby-photography/"&gt;Laura MacDonald&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mind of a Building:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this point on you must think in a certain way. Think of the following metaphorically.
This starts with outlook and the words you use. It progresses with building on your foundation using metaphorical bricks. This ends with success &amp;amp; achievement. Each brick represents a new skill and/or success. Each brick is a new happiness. Once a brick has been laid, it is enduring, immovable and timeless. It is here to stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outlook:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forget the terms positive and negative. Nothing is negative. There is only learning &amp;amp; growing. All "negative" experiences are now lessons. "Every failure can only teach me. Every success will only make me grow and become more than I was". Adding "yet", changes everything. "I can't do that.....yet!".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Forget the little feelings" - little feelings are the pieces of inner monologue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have that tells us, "we're tired, we can't be bothered, we can do it later". Identification of the little feelings is very hard. We as humans live by feelings that our body and mind perceive; hunger, thirst, pain, cold, warm, sadness, excitement etc. Our lives are dictated by our sensations. So learning to prioritise the essentials and ignore the non-essentials is key to keeping my mind as strong as a building.
Identify and don't listen to the little feelings. (Variable eliminated)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scenario-ize:
Think of all the things that scare you with regards to your dream. List them. Think about all the things that can go wrong with regards to your goals. List them. Feelings of negativity &amp;amp; emotional turmoil arise happen...through shock of the unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we Scenario-ize. We go through the list of what we fear and what can go wrong;
Injury, defeat, abuse, pain, losing, ineffectiveness, anger - and we pretend internally that it has really happened. We go over the situation and tell ourselves how we want to behave/react.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"If someone hits me illegally, i will keep my cool and keep on track with my team"
"If someone yells at me, i will not take it personally nor let it effect me"
"If someone does better than me, it doesn't mean I was in anyway bad. It only means I have more to do"
"If I foul out, I will respect the decision and not argue it. Then analyse my performance after I have supported my team and been respectful to those around me".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mental preparation and practice, prevents poor performance and promotes positive prognosis. (Variables eliminated)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1460021074061.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="wp-1460021074061" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1460021074061.jpg" alt="image" width="1080" height="720"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Photo: &lt;a href="http://lauramacd.co.uk/roller-derby-photography/"&gt;Laura MacDonald&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning &amp;amp; Growing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not if....but when these negative situations occur &amp;amp; you have successfully behaved how you planned, its time to learn.
Analyse. "What went wrong? Who's to blame? Why did it go wrong? How do I ensure this doesn't happen again". Ask these questions and learn from their answers. Let the learning fuel you to work hard to prevent this happening again. New variables will always arise and some old ones may come back. Scenario-ize these too and view them only as more lessons.
(Variable eliminated).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The little victories:
With every failure will come a few small or even tiny victories. Focus on them. When you are the underdog or out numbered with a high likelihood of failure, play for the little victories."We held that amazing jammer for 30sec"
"I got 1 lead jammer over someone far better than me"
"I finally used that thing i learnt at training and it worked"
"We were expected to lose by 100 and only lost by 50"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter what happens, good or bad nothing will detriment me. Be prepared to lose but also get ready to win.
(Variable eliminated).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mini victories are bricks too. The mind is built with stones of all sizes. For every achievement my wall gets bigger. For every success my building only grows.
Every brick makes my mind stronger. They are skills, they are happiness and they are esteem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 bricks forward, 1 brick back:
"Don't get too high".
Consider the idea of numeracy. We as humans love numbers. "I have £200. I lost 3kg. We won the last 2 games. I scored a 30point jam". Using this theme and if we  allocated points to our success bricks, we will start to accumulate points. If each brick represents 3 points we will eventually over the course of time build up a lot. Success breeds success. The more we achieve.....the more we achieve and the more we want to achieve. However, with success come a few poisonous characteristics that CAN cause our building to crumble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selfishness, arrogance, vanity &amp;amp; looking down on those considered weaker etc.
The points acquired are your points and for you to do as you want with them. So consider that if I use all 3 point to always climb high and feel better about myself,I may topple. "My ego was my down fall. My head got too big. He/she/they are amazing, but they are arrogant dicks". 2 to move up and one to step back..... and reflect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best heroes are the humble ones. "They were incredible &amp;amp; it was amazing how DOWN to earth they are". Be that hero and view the points as things to be rationed.
If I start at ZERO 0, my first success will give me 3 points with a potential score of 3. But! If i only use 2 and put 1 away for something else, i am still at 2 and still higher than I was at the beginning. Then over time, I will grow as my bricks add up. i will grow slower but, more stable. I will not get too high, I will NOT poison my wall with ego, arrogance and vanity &amp;amp; I will aim to be of use to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Variable eliminated).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1460021080516.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="wp-1460021080516" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1460021080516.jpg" alt="image" width="1120" height="720"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/john.hesse.902"&gt;John Hesse&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharing is caring : I grow, we grow:
"If you want to succeed quickly go alone. If you want to succeed forever, go together"
The effect you have on others is the most valuable currency there is. Life is built in teams. My family team. My relationship team. My work team. My friend team. My health team....my derby team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"2 points for me &amp;amp; 1 for you".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a metaphor, use 1 of those points that was for your growth that was stored away and give it to someone else. Use it to fuel their need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compliments, praise, gifts, smiles, congratulations, feedback, encouragement. Be that humble hero and lift those up around you. Reflect on your needs, but also your teams needs. Recognise who could do with a boost emotionally. What do they need that your talent can provide? Succeed, Grow &amp;amp; Give back, as there may be someone in your Team that will need it more than you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final variable:
Mental strength is about control. Control of your own mind, thoughts, ideas and emotions. Mental strength is about controlling and eliminating variables that may be of detriment to your minds. 'The final &amp;amp; uncontrollable variable is other people'. Not everyone will have the same goals as you, or be as strong or as driven as you. Drive and strength are variable. There is nothing anyone can do to change that. We can only gently influence those who are involved in our journey to be as positive as we are. Set an example. "Monkey see. Monkey do"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Scenario-ize the reactions of other people. Pretend in your head the eventuality they will react negatively. Then plan what you can do to help them &amp;amp; prevent them being of detriment to themselves, to others and to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus on:
○Avoiding the little feelings
○Their little victories
○Scenario-ize with them (prior)
○Share your defeats &amp;amp; successes together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Variable eliminated).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Body &amp;amp; the Mind:
One will always effect the other. Neither is more or less important than the other but they both need the same due care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If my body becomes stronger, I will perform better and grow the success bricks for my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If my mind becomes stronger I will eliminate variables that would deter me to try new things in my skates or exercise my body more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Become balanced. Become more. Become awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1460021085772.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="wp-1460021085772" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1460021085772.jpg" alt="image" width="800" height="800"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Photo: &lt;a href="http://lauramacd.co.uk/roller-derby-photography/"&gt;Laura MacDonald&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>guest articles</category><category>mental strength</category><category>optimus grime</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>training</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/07/guest-post-mental-strength-with-power-of-scotlands-optimus-grime/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 13:27:24 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>