<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about tyne and fear)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/tyne-and-fear.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 08:59:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Roller Derby Is Back in Grangemouth in 2018</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/02/14/roller-derby-is-back-in-grangemouth-in-2018/</link><dc:creator>despicablev</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9205" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/bcr-banner.jpg" alt="bcr-banner" width="851" height="315"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby in 2018 has well and truly started after the Christmas break as we have just witnessed the Womens World cup in Manchester recently and still have the Men's world cup to look forward to in April. But this month sees the return of derby in Scotland, with the first games of 2018 taking place thanks to Bairn City Rollers. As they will be kicking of their 2018 by hosting a double header in Grangemouth Sports Complex on Saturday the 24th of February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a double header with a Geordie feel to is as BCR's Skelpies take on Tyne and Fears &lt;span class="_4n-j _fbReactionComponent__eventDetailsContentTags fsl"&gt;Inglorious B&lt;em&gt;Stars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for the first game of the day followed after there is an &lt;span class="_4n-j _fbReactionComponent__eventDetailsContentTags fsl"&gt;All Gender game made up of skaters from Newcastle.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="_4n-j _fbReactionComponent__eventDetailsContentTags fsl"&gt;The Skelpies and the BStars have faced off against each other three times to date, with the B*Stars taking the win each time, can the Skelpies take the win this time? Be sure to come along to find out.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="_4n-j _fbReactionComponent__eventDetailsContentTags fsl"&gt;Doors open 1.30pm and tickets are priced at £5 on the door. If you would like to know more &lt;a href="https://en-gb.facebook.com/events/587963344880848/"&gt;visit the facebook event page here&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bcr</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mens roller derby scotland</category><category>skelpies</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>tyne &amp; fear</category><category>tyne and fear</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/02/14/roller-derby-is-back-in-grangemouth-in-2018/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 11:15:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Doonhame Roller Derby show collaboration is the way to victory.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/10/03/doonhame-roller-derby-show-collaboration-is-the-way-to-victory/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst one of the prevailing narratives in Roller Derby is that the sport is the "fastest growing female sport in the world", it's worth noting that even when this was unarguably true, growth is always unevenly distributed. In order to keep growing, a league needs enough skaters to form good bouting team, in order to get those games which build visibility and retain ambitious players. If you're a smaller team, this can be challenging!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-24847" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/10/doonhameunicorn.jpg?w=596" alt="Doonhameunicorn" width="298" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dumfriesshire's Doonhame Roller Derby have found that collaborating with other leagues is a profitable way to enable more derby, more of the time, and help grow both themselves and their collaborators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more long-term collaboration is with fellow-West-of-Scotland league, Ayrshire Roller Derby - the resulting "Doonshire" train together and have even played a closed bout, with perhaps more fixtures in the future. Doonhame's Suze MacBruise told us, "Ayrshire Roller Derby are in a very similar situation to us: they had a big shake up when they lost their regular training hall, moving them to actually training in Kilmarnock rather than Ayr. We find that, with smaller towns like ourselves and Ayrshire, that we almost get up to full team numbers, and then when the slightest thing happens we're pushed back to training again."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it's another collaboration which is providing a bigger event, as Doonhame are joining forces with Durham City Rolling Angels to take over Newcastle's &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Walker+Activity+Dome/@54.9687347,-1.5582393,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487e7068944e76d1:0xe1a6394d9f25325!8m2!3d54.9687316!4d-1.5560506"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for a special Triple Header event for Halloween.
Whilst Durham might not be the obvious collaboration, Suze told us "we also have always got on really well with DCRA, and myself and [Durham's] Clairely Psycho hatched this plan to get a game together... we got far too excited and now it has turned out to be this marvellous Halloween event, focusing on players stuck in the 'twilight zone', who've played too many games for a cherry popper, but are not quite confident enough to play advanced."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as an opening Cherry Popper bout, the remaining bouts will both be previously-unseen collaborations:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Doonhame and Durham forming the "Doom Angels" to take on an exhibition team of low/intermediate skaters&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Newcastle's Tyne and Fear joining with Teeside Skate Invaders (as the "Tyne Invaders") to take on an advanced, open/coed exhibition team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Durham and Doonhame's Halloween Triple Scrim is on Saturday&lt;strong&gt; October 28th&lt;/strong&gt; , with tickets for skaters who wish to play in any of the games available from EventBrite (&lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/halloween-triple-header-scrim-tickets-37317907867?aff=efbeventtix"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;link&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The same link also allows spectators to get a ticket to see all the lovely games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event is also in need of lovely NSOs and Referees in order to support all three bouts: if anyone is interested in joining the Officiating team, they should &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/805242299645606/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;look here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event Facebook page is: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/111674759544178/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/111674759544178/&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;for updates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ayrshire roller derby</category><category>doonhame roller derby</category><category>durham rolling angels</category><category>teeside skate invaders</category><category>tyne and fear</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/10/03/doonhame-roller-derby-show-collaboration-is-the-way-to-victory/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 18:56:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Let's get ready to Rhumble - Mean City can't wait to welcome the Fear</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/02/02/lets-get-ready-to-rhumble-mean-city-cant-wait-to-welcome-the-fear/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;THIS Saturday will see the Jocks and the Geordies have a 'Dandy' time on skates as Glasgow's Mean City Roller Derby welcome the Inglorious B*Stars from Newcastle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mighty Mean machine is preparing a traditional Scottish welcome for the rising stars from Tyne &amp;amp; Fear Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Geordie warriors will be swapping the foggy Tyne for the cool waters of Clyde in what is certain to be a close encounter of the thrilled kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old-school fans of ‘The Dandy’ will remember the Jocks and the Geordies - but this is no Beano for the boys north and south of the border.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Expect action from the first whistle to the last - featuring fast-paced thrills, spills, sporting heroics, skating &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/1371335-jocks_and_geordies.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4568 alignright" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/1371335-jocks_and_geordies.jpg?w=300" alt="1371335-jocks_and_geordies" width="409" height="236"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;and scoring.&lt;/p&gt;
This ain’t for the faint-hearted - Mean City will sell you the whole seat, but you aren’t going to need it.
&lt;p&gt;Newcastle was once home to the Likely Lads - but the guys from both teams are only likely to do one thing this Saturday - deliver a sporting contest like no other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The match takes place on Saturday, February 7 – doors open at 3.45pm. Tickets cost £5 with free admission for under-14s with a paying adult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller derby is one of the fastest growing sports in the world – combining athleticism, agility, endurance and stamina … all on skates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each team fields five players at a time, one scorer (called a jammer) and four blockers. Points are notched up when the jammer laps the opposing players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a thrilling collision of skill, physical contact, tactics and guts – played on an oval, flat track over two halves of full-on, heads-up action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alan Muir, Chairman of Mean City Roller Derby (MCRD), said: “We ‘canny’ wait to welcome our friends in the north to Glasgow. It's going to be a sensational game between the two sides, with the Inglorious B*Stars in terrific form recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Mean City is the West of Scotland’s first and only roller derby league for men and women, and has been going from strength to strength since it was formed in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We’re genuinely thrilled to be welcoming Tyne and Fear to Glasgow and hope sports fans will turn out in force to cheer on both teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s going to be a great showcase of all that roller derby has to offer – an action-packed afternoon of skating, scoring, skills, thrills and spills for all the family.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby has been developing as a league since its formation in 2012. It was initially aimed at men, but the decision was taken in 2014 to open the league to all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City train regularly in the Glasgow area and new members are always welcome to give the sport a go in a supportive environment. Equipment can be provided – just get in touch in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby"&gt;www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby&lt;/a&gt; to buy tickets for the event and to find out more about joining the revolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>in the news</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>tyne &amp; fear</category><category>tyne and fear</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/02/02/lets-get-ready-to-rhumble-mean-city-cant-wait-to-welcome-the-fear/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 18:49:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bairn City Rollers presents "Scrape Fear"</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/06/04/bairn-city-rollers-presents-scrape-fear/</link><dc:creator>graememcphail</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;June 30th will be a date to remember for &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;, with the male Skelpies and the female Central Belters bouting togther in the same venue on the same day in a landmark double header!&lt;br id=".reactRoot[136].:1:1:1:comment527421823980926_528201383902970.:0.:1.:0.:1.:0.:0.:0:2.:0.:0.:4"&gt;&lt;br id=".reactRoot[136].:1:1:1:comment527421823980926_528201383902970.:0.:1.:0.:1.:0.:0.:0:2.:0.:0.:5"&gt;Come along to The Peak in Stirling to catch the Skelpies take on Tyne &amp;amp; Fear B-team in what promises to be a thrilling - and bruising - encounter. If you're the sort of person that can handle two shots of action in your derby coffee then following that the Central Belters will make their home debut against the ladies from North Wales Roller Derby.&lt;br id=".reactRoot[136].:1:1:1:comment527421823980926_528201383902970.:0.:1.:0.:1.:0.:0.:0:2.:0.:3.:0.:1"&gt;&lt;br id=".reactRoot[136].:1:1:1:comment527421823980926_528201383902970.:0.:1.:0.:1.:0.:0.:0:2.:0.:3.:0.:2"&gt;The previous two B.C.R. bout days have already provided some &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=khwS2S7oNXA"&gt;unforgettable moments&lt;/a&gt;, this will be one not to miss!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/06/scrapefear-poster.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image aligncenter" id="i-2655" alt="Image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/06/scrapefear-poster.jpg?w=533"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The action begins at 15:30, tickets are already moving so make sure you grab some while you can. We'll see you at The Peak!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/345747832218293/"&gt;Facebook event&lt;/a&gt; to keep up to date with the latest information.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; Purchase tickets for Scrape Fear &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/391647"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>double header</category><category>north wales roller derby</category><category>tyne and fear</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/06/04/bairn-city-rollers-presents-scrape-fear/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 19:04:47 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>