<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about ukrda)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/ukrda.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>UKRDA Elections Update: your new Directors!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/26/ukrda-elections-update-your-new-directors/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a democratic organisation, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://ukrda.org.uk/"&gt;UK Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; undergoes a yearly AGM, in which vacancies for its Directorships can be filled by vote within the member leagues. The most recent AGM was held this month, 5th of June, and resulted in a particularly large number of changes to the Directorships, due to retirements and the filling of previously empty posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're giving you a quick overview of the current Directorships and their holders, to help you get to know your organisation.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26918" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/ukrdadirectors2018.jpg" alt="UKRDADirectors2018" width="960" height="720"&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Halo Jones - Secretary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halo Jones remains in the position of Secretary for UKRDA from before the AGM. Outside of UKRDA, she is well known in the world of NSOing around the Oxford area (especially for &lt;a href="https://www.oxfordwheelsofgory.co.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oxford Wheels of Gory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), and beyond. A nominee for the Talk Derby To Me NSO Listener Awards in 2017 and 2016, she has officiated at multiple high level events, including the 2017 MRDA Championships, and both the Roller Derby World Cup and the Men's Roller Derby World Cup 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maw Deuce - Director for Internal Communication&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maw Deuce continues in her role as Director for Internal Communication from the last elections. The longest term member of the UKRDA family, Maw previously served as the UKRDA National Squads chair, responsible for interactions with and support of the affiliated national teams, and has held additional roles before then.
Outside of UKRDA, Maw is a member of &lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and a referee and official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rollin Rat - Director for Officials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rollin Rat continues as a Director from before the AGM, moving from the position of Director of Policy &amp;amp; Strategy to Director of Officials. Outside of UKRDA, he is a Referee for &lt;a href="https://centralcityrollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Birmingham, and has refereed at many high level events, including the Roller Derby World Cup 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stat Man - Director for Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stat Man has a long history in Roller Derby, as both an Announcer and an Official. As well as starting one of the first attempts to rate and rank European teams, he was one of the individuals responsible for establishing the ongoing &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;s, of which he remains the Chair of the Organising Committee. He may also have been involved in the short-lived attempt to have a roller derby team based in Sealand. He has also continued to announce at high level events, including both World Cups this year.
Stat Man has also previously served as Executive Director of Sanctioning and Games for the MRDA (2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smacktivist - Director for Communications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smacktivist is new to the Director of Communications role. She hails from &lt;a href="http://rollerbillies.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cambridge Rollerbillies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where she's currently Line Up Manager for their B-Team, the Punt Rockers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dorkmistress - Director for External Engagement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dorkmistress has a very strong history in Roller Derby, as both an Announcer and an Official. She has previously Managed several iterations of Team Wales Roller Derby, as well as announcing for &lt;a href="http://www.swanseacityrollerderby.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swansea City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and announcing and officiating for &lt;a href="http://www.sws.pizza/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;South Wales Silures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; she's also been seen announcing across a gamut of high level events, including the most recent Men's Roller Derby World Cup, and Newcastle Roller Girls' EuroClash tournament.
As well as UKRDA External Engagement, she currently holds the position of &lt;a href="http://www.rollerderbynationscommittee.org/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roller Derby Nations Committee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Regional Representative for Northern Europe, representing all the World Cup Nations from that region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buckfast - Head of Tech&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buckfast is new to the role of Head of Tech (which is not a Directoral role, and has been semi-empty since the last AGM). He's relatively new to Roller Derby - having recently begun Bench Coaching at &lt;a href="https://www.yorkminxters.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>agm</category><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>in the news</category><category>news</category><category>ukrda</category><category>ukrda directors</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/26/ukrda-elections-update-your-new-directors/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 11:22:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team England Training Roster announced!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/04/team-england-training-roster-announced/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Down south, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamenglandrollerderby/"&gt;Team England&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; have been hard at work with a massive set of tryouts over the last 2 months. After two initial tryouts in August, one in the North of England (hosted by Rainy City Roller Derby, the highest WFTDA ranked league north of London), and one in the South (hosted by London Rollergirls themselves), the initial talented few still had to face the final second-round tryout session in Birmingham, hosted by Central City Rollergirls. UKRDA Observers were, of course, present at each tryout to ensure fairness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Team England Manager illbilly, along with multiple selection teams chosen for their expertise in the Regions have deliberated and come to their final conclusions for the Training Roster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected, the roster draws strongly from the highest ranked UKRDA member teams: London Rollergirls provide 14 members, and Rainy City Roller Derby an impressive 7, with Middlesbrough Milk Rollers, Newcastle Roller Girls, Bristol Roller Derby, Liverpool Roller Birds, London Rockin' Rollers, Central City Rollergirls, and (across from the 'States) Charm City Roller Girls all helping to fill out the roster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official England Photographer Jason Ruffell captured images of the tryouts &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamenglandrollerderby/photos/?tab=album&amp;amp;album_id=1117984021615161"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamenglandrollerderby/photos/?tab=album&amp;amp;album_id=1161561447257418"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In full, the  Team England Training Roster is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-9153 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/england.jpg" alt="england" width="480" height="339"&gt; Image by:Sam Bishop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex Valentine &lt;strong&gt;666&lt;/strong&gt; Rainy City Roller Derby
Alex Wilde &lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; Rainy City Roller Derby
Becky Ruckus &lt;strong&gt;105&lt;/strong&gt; Liverpool Roller Birds&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;
Carley McAdam &lt;strong&gt;369&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Delta Strike &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Bristol Roller Derby
Ella Storey &lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; Middlesbrough Milk Rollers
Fay Roberts &lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt; Rainy City Roller Derby
Fayetal Blonde &lt;strong&gt;38&lt;/strong&gt; Rainy City Roller Derby
Fisher &lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; Rainy City Roller Derby
Florence the Machine &lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Gaz &lt;strong&gt;8008&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
GG Hardy &lt;strong&gt;308&lt;/strong&gt; Charm City Roller Girls
Ho Chee &lt;strong&gt;1971&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Jack Attack &lt;strong&gt;101&lt;/strong&gt; London Rockin' Rollers
Just Jess &lt;strong&gt;129&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Katie Hellvetica Black &lt;strong&gt;84&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Kid Block &lt;strong&gt;40&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Kristen Lee &lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Lexi Lightspeed &lt;strong&gt;55&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Lucy &lt;strong&gt;314&lt;/strong&gt; Newcastle Roller Girls
Menace &lt;strong&gt;6955&lt;/strong&gt; Rainy City Roller Derby
Missy Rascal &lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; Rainy City Roller Derby
Onyeka Igwe &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Philly &lt;strong&gt;419&lt;/strong&gt; Rainy City Roller Derby
Rammit &lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; London Rockin' Rollers
Rogue Runner &lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Shaolynn Scarlett &lt;strong&gt;888&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Stefanie Mainey &lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Terri Sudron &lt;strong&gt;86&lt;/strong&gt; Middlesbrough Milk Rollers
Trisha Smackanawa &lt;strong&gt;42&lt;/strong&gt; London Rollergirls
Woo &lt;strong&gt;19&lt;/strong&gt; Central City Rollergirls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>team england roller derby</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/04/team-england-training-roster-announced/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 18:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UK's first Coaching Summit: Derby Stance</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/03/uks-first-coaching-summit-derby-stance/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back when we&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/27/an-interview-with-ukrda-chair-tess-robinson/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; interviewed&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;UKRDA Internal Chair, Tess Robinson, one of the ongoing projects she mentioned was to support Coaching, via certifications and other events.
Well, in combination with Coaching outfit &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com/derbystance-1/"&gt;Rule 56&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Female-Coaching-Network-900335303354547/"&gt;Female Coaching Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, part of this is coming to pass: in &lt;strong&gt;November 19th&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;20th&lt;/strong&gt;, the UK's first "Coaching Summit" will be held, in &lt;strong&gt;Leeds&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/536421803211316/"&gt;"Derby Stance"&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;will be a two day event, with sessions available to see on the website, and including aspects across the community, including Junior Derby Coaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A host of guest speakers and presenters will be there, of who more in a bit, but this is also seen as being an opportunity for Roller Derby Coaches across the UK to get together to influence the future of coaching, the certification process and any other developments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To support this, Rule 56 have managed to get coaches from some of the top teams in the UK: Auld Reekie's own Stef Skinner, London Rollergirls/Team England and Double Threat Skates' Kirsten "Kitty Decapitate" Lee, ex Team England/current Wizards of Aus/Southern Discomfort Ballistic Whistle (who we &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/10/an-interview-with-outgoing-team-england-coach-ballistic-whistle/"&gt;interviewed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; not long ago) and many more. But, more than this, they've also managed to get Texas Rollergirls' own Smarty Pants (Nadia Kean) to come across to provide her own sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smarty is a very experienced coach, both in Roller Derby and other sports; she runs Get Smarty Coaching to provide coaching services across the USA and worldwide, as well as skating for Texas. She's also working on a book on coaching!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were lucky enough to get the chance to talk to her about her experience in coaching, roller derby and a lot of other topics. You can hear the interview, in a first for us at the blog, here (forgive the initial uming from yours truly, this is a new thing for us):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[soundcloud url="https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/285835975" params="auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true" width="100%" height="450" iframe="true" /]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you're inspired by that, get booking your tickets for Derby Stance, if you haven't already!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>annoucements</category><category>coaches</category><category>interviews</category><category>rule56</category><category>smarty pants</category><category>texas rollergirls</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/03/uks-first-coaching-summit-derby-stance/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 19:07:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An Interview With... outgoing Team England Coach, Ballistic Whistle!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/10/an-interview-with-outgoing-team-england-coach-ballistic-whistle/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of people were surprised to hear that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamenglandrollerderby/"&gt;Team England Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s Ballistic Whistle announce that he did not intend to reapply for the role in the current round of recruitment. (The applications for the Team England (Women's) coaching and management roles are currently being voted on.) Considering his contributions to Roller Derby, both in the National teams, and also ongoing with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://londonrollergirls.com/"&gt;London Rollergirls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.southerndiscomfort.co.uk/"&gt;Southern Discomfort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, we thought it was a good idea to catch up with him and talk about, well, him.
(This interview is also undertaken in collaboration with the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UK Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, as part of our National Teams series.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/10/an-interview-with-outgoing-team-england-coach-ballistic-whistle/9012365607_0dd177bdf1_k/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-7241"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-7241" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/05/9012365607_0dd177bdf1_k.jpg?w=700" alt="Ballistic Whistle (London Rollergirls v Rat City) (Photo: Eric Von Flickr)" width="700" height="467"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Ballistic Whistle (London Rollergirls v Rat City) (Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/31756530@N08/9012365607"&gt;Steve Messerer&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Despite the wide range of your involvement in Roller Derby, you're probably best known as the Coach and Bench Manager of London Roller Girls, who pretty much were the vanguard of Europe's entry into the top levels of Roller Derby. Did you feel responsible, in a way, for representing the UK or Europe in the early days of LRG going across to the States (and is it more of a relief that other teams are now increasingly high level)?&lt;/strong&gt;
I don't feel that was ever a specific goal or aim of ours. From a really early stage we had aspirations of travelling to the States to play high level derby. That benchmark over the years has continued to be pushed on and on to test how far we can go. Through our first tour of the States, and the first visit of American teams to our shores it was quite evident just how much support we were receiving from the UK and Europe. Feeling that during our Stateside trips has always been amazing for us and serves as quite an emotional motivator when away from home. If we have had an impact on how enthusiastic other players and teams are for playing the sport then we've definitely achieved one of our aims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Literally everyone we've spoken to before this interview has mentioned specifically that you're a nice guy (and you parodied this in your appearance in the LRG Fort Wayne's World promo videos [which sadly seem to have mostly disappeared from the internet]). Do you think this surprises people?&lt;/strong&gt;
Haha, that's nice of you to say. I guess I try my best not to irk people on purpose, but I definitely have my foibles and personality clashes just like anyone else. I guess what I find most interesting is how people will formulate an idea of you without ever having met you, purely by how they would expect a person in my position to be. I'll often meet someone for the first time and there will be a period of trying to balance out the shockwaves in our interactions as a result of how they expect me to behave. I'd really love to not have to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As well as coaching and bench managing, you also find the time to play on track, with Southern Discomfort (as well as another signing we'll get to next…). How does your time on track contribute to your coaching decisions (and which would you rather be known as: a great coach, or a great skater)?&lt;/strong&gt;
I took some time off during the 2015 season to try and rehabilitate a back injury. It was during this season that there was a major swing towards formation defense. I realised after a number of months that I was lacking empathy for the difficulty our players had working against this formation. Some of the minor adjustments I was asking our players to make, were actually majorly difficult. Getting back into playing has helped me incredibly to understand what is possible and where the difficulties lie in the modern game. I also get the opportunity to jump in with Brawling from time to time, which I find incredibly helpful to understand what it feels like being inside of the on track action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I roll all of these experiences into my coaching; I guess that answers your parenthesised question. I have no doubt that I love coaching more than playing. I feel like seeing my friends achieve amazing things is much more rewarding for me than achieving them myself. The great thing about fighting to see your team-mates reach their goals, is that you generally achieve yours as a result!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And you recently made the roster for the Team Australia (&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/WizardsofAusDerby/"&gt;Wizards of Aus&lt;/a&gt;) who will be competing at the &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; in Calgary. How did you make the decision to represent your birth nation in the World Cup, and how does it feel to be on the team?&lt;/strong&gt;
Um, actually, it's not my birth nation. I was born in Denmark to a Danish father and Belgian mother. I arrived in Australia on my 2nd birthday and remained there until age 25. But, if you were to ask me what I considered my nationality it would be Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the first World Cup, I had the amazing opportunity to participate with so many of my great derby friends for Team England. Being a part of that team was a fantastic experience, but it wasn't until I was selected for the Australia team that I truly understood what the other players on that English team felt during that first World Cup. In hindsight, I felt incredibly guilty for taking that feeling from someone during the first World Cup, and I feel that is the special thing about that event. Playing for your nation is something that can call on something deeper. At all World Cups I have attended, both male and female, hearing the Australian national anthem has been a...tricky...moment for me emotionally. At this next World Cup, I am going to be so happy to be able to belt out the anthem without any mixed feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You've been Team England Coach for two World Cups, and London Roller Girls coach for 5 years. While both positions are top-level coaching positions, are there more differences than might be apparent?&lt;/strong&gt;
Absolutely. There's no substitute for working with the same team week in week out. You can definitely deliver the most effective change in strategy and refine what you do on track on multiple occasions over a shorter period of time. With both teams you are dealing with a group of incredibly talented skaters, but with Team England it was much more of a situation of building cohesion. Nailing down defaults and making sure, as much as possible, everyone is on the same page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the England team, there was the tricky balance of trying not to be just Brawling + friends, but really appreciate that there are different ways to play. World Cups comprise a number of nations from the extreme fledgling derby countries to the most seasoned. We had always set our sights on taking on the most seasoned. Hopefully in coming World Cup cycles, there will be more English players in other teams who have more of that high-level derby play and will be ready to take on the best countries in the world. With limited training sessions, it becomes a lot more sink or swim when put into that intensely hot cauldron of competition, and so it is all about looking for the players who can take that pressure and really excel. Without the experience of that level, it comes so much more down to personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recently, you announced that you would not be applying for the role of Team England Head Coach this time around. Can we talk a bit about your reasons for this, and your feelings about the decision?&lt;/strong&gt;
The 2015 season was one that definitely took a toll on me. Brawling, at the beginning of the season, had set ourselves what we thought was the ultimate goal (incidentally, we have since understood that the Hydra is not the ultimate goal). Having an amazing season and falling short at the critical time definitely hit me with my first proper feeling of derby burnout in the 9 1/2 years I've been in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we've set our sights even higher than the goals we set last year and I understand what that is going to take from me on a personal level. I also feel that this time around, we are blessed with a number of candidates that could really use this as a springboard to get that experience of that new level. I obviously have mixed feelings about it. Watching England at the World Cup is going to be tough as I'll be wanting the best for all my friends on that team, but will have zero input on helping them achieve that. I'll be waving the 3 Lions flag regardless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And, what have been the high and low points in your 6 years as TE Head Coach?&lt;/strong&gt;
Again, it's only 5 years really as the lead up to that first World Cup happened in the same year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lows have always been any time we needed to make some kind of cut to the squad, whether that be to the charter that would go to an event or the roster of 14 that would play. I've been tasked with making these decisions countless times during my life as a coach, but it never gets easy telling talented players that they aren't going to have the opportunity, this time, to do what they love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As bad as those moments are, they are eclipsed by the highs, and I feel like one of the biggest highs was our final against the USA at the 2014 World Cup. Prior to the game I had pored over and re-written my pre-game speech so many times I thought I had written the perfect speech. I got in there and saw all of those players looking at me to hear the message I had for them at that point. Prior to a game where getting all of the 1 percenters right mattered. I threw everything I had written out the window and just spoke from the heart. Anyone in that room will be able to tell you that the message was pretty simple. Regardless of its simplicity, I feel like it resonated with the players, and really struck a chord. In spite of the result, it was one of those games where we just felt like we were playing on point, executing our strategies so well. It all felt so streamlined and precise, against potentially the toughest group of individual skaters you could ever face on track. For it to culminate in one of my derby idols - Kamikaze Kitten - taking us over the 100 point mark in the final jam, I couldn't have asked for a better written story. For me, that game illustrated what Roller Derby (and playing team sport for that matter) is truly all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Given your experience in the role, do you have any advice to pass on to your successor as Head Coach?&lt;/strong&gt;
I feel like there are a lot of coaches out there who work with a top down decision making structure. The coach will dictate the direction and decisions the team makes, sometimes opening the floor to the players for input. When working with some of the best players to ever play the sport, it would be remiss of any coach not to leverage that knowledge and experience. Every single player that played for Team England has a wealth of experience, has an incredibly active derby brain. It's so important to keep those brains ticking over and thinking at a high level, rather than trying to stifle them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with both Brawling and England has shown me that when you are dealing with these incredibly talented groups of players, you are just one equally important part of the team, rather than the single decision making point. Having said that, there definitely comes a point whereby the players need to focus on playing and the decisions need to be directed. The closer to game time this is, the more important it becomes for the coach to take responsibility for decision making. So, rather than a top down, triangle type shape, I think of it more of an hourglass decision making shape. The active brains in the team will feed their ideas into the team's leadership or management, and the leadership with all of this great information will compile it and disseminate a directed decision to the team to execute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, coaching a high level national team at a World Cup is something that not many people the world over will ever be able to say they did with their life. It's exhilarating, and the more you put into it, the greater the reward will be. Don't fuck it up!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2011</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team england roller derby</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/05/10/an-interview-with-outgoing-team-england-coach-ballistic-whistle/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 09:16:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>An interview with UKRDA Chair Tess Robinson</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/27/an-interview-with-ukrda-chair-tess-robinson/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the National Squads selection processes well underway, under the Observation of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UK Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, we thought it was a good time to catch up with the organisation's Chair, Tess Robinson, to find out more about what they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-7182" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/fb_img_1461766969488.jpg?w=2046" alt="FB_IMG_1461766969488" width="1023" height="1024"&gt; Tess herself. (Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/graemewillettsphotography/"&gt;Graeme Willetts&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I guess we should start by talking a bit about who you are, and what you do with UKRDA.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I'm Tess Robinson, and I skate with the London Roller Girls B, the Brawl Saints, and I am currently the Chair of the UKRDA Board of Directors, and also the Director of Internal Affairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the Directors has a remit in terms of overseeing different committees, so I directly oversee Membership and Grievances, but really all of the directors are such a big team that we're always communicating and collaborating with each other about everything that comes to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it's not so strict in terms of what people oversee, we just work together to make sure everything runs smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After that easy intro question, I'd like to lead with something a bit more philosophically difficult: what is the purpose of UKRDA?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, our mission statement is: "Promoting and Developing the Growth of the Sport in the UK". So, it would be very specific to the UK: we could just say "Growing and Developing the Sport", but it's specific to what we want to achieve in the country. And I think that's very special - because we have such great teams, and because the UK has something different to everyone else (I think that's true of every nation [that they have unique aspects], but I like what we have here).
We've got specific kind of projects that we're working on now, but really, I just want to, this is a really difficult question…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main thing that I would want people to see the UKRDA as is Themselves! After the AGM this year, I started trying to tout this hashtag, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23YouKRDA"&gt;#YouKRDA&lt;/a&gt; , because I feel that a lot of people think that the UKRDA is a certain person, or a certain group of people. Maybe they think that the UKRDA is the Board of Directors, that we should be Doing Something (and we do, we do do lots of stuff), but people need to understand, and if I'm honest, take responsibility for, the fact that every single person whose team is a UKRDA member is a member of the UKRDA, and they have the power to do whatever they want with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people ask us, "What is the UKRDA, what does the UKRDA do; what is the UKRDA doing, why isn't it doing This?", and the simple answer is: because the community isn't doing it.
We [the Directors] wholeheartedly listen to the members, and we just need our members to know that they have the power as individuals, to instigate any changes that they want to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, for you, the democratic and communal nature of Roller Derby is key to how UKRDA works?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely! UKRDA is a league of leagues. (Or, I think a lot of people are trying to move away from "league" as a word: UKRDA is a Team of Teams.) So, we're just one big Community. We oversee and ensure that everything is running as it should, and as we want it, as a community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the things that I think is key to this Role for UKRDA is your relationships with the other bodies that affect Roller Derby in the UK - the WFTDA (on the side of Roller Derby), and the British Roller Sports Federation (on the side of UK Sports). How you do get on with and interact with them?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a really great relationship with both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a great relationship with the WFTDA. Gareth Lowson, who was the previous Chair, and is our Director of External Engagements, did some amazing work building a strong working relationship with the WFTDA. He met personally with [WFTDA Executive Director 2009-2016, Juliana Gonzales] Bloody Mary a number of times, and they had a really good working relationship.
And the WFTDA have always supported us, especially in things that we've done that they haven't. Like: we've just started sanctioning and chartering B-teams; they were supportive of that idea. There was a big B-Team tournament in the USA last year, I think Gareth went to that, or he spoke to Bloody Mary after that, and told her about this multi-team sanctioning that we were at the time trying to vote through, and she thought it was a really great idea.
It makes me really happy to know that someone representing the Directors of the WFTDA is supportive of what we're trying to achieve. She's always helped with UKROC and been supportive of our events.
Obviously, she's just stepped down, and there's soon going to be a new person in her place [new WFTDA Director Cassie Haynes], and we're hoping that we'll be able to forge the same strong bonds that we've had, with her. But, generally, our relationship with WFTDA has always been good because we're always trying to follow in their footsteps, and they always try to support what we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Well, sometimes you're ahead of them - the UKRDA Gender Policy, for example.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah!, we work together and it's you know, very much a relationship!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other side, with BRSF… BRSF is a really interesting kind of link that we have, because that is how we receive recognition from Sport England, which is kind of the key to sporting achievement and recognition in England. As the biggest organisation for sports in the UK (not to downplay what Scotland and Wales have, we've not had as much of a tie with them) in England at least, they recognise Roller Derby as a sport because we have our tie with the BSRF, which is really great for us. And, it's pretty clear, I haven't got definite numbers but I'm 99% sure that, Roller Derby is officially the biggest roller sport in the UK. Out of all of the other disciplines that the BRSF cover - roller hockey, inline hockey, inline speed skating and artistic skating - I'm pretty sure that we have more members than all of the rest of them combined. So it seems ridiculous that the only way we can garner recognition from these big kind-of multi-sport governing bodies, like Sport England, is through BRSF, given our relative sizes.
But! That's our gateway, and BRSF is a really important organisation, not just for us but for all roller sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;In a way, isn't an entity UKRDA what Sport England needs in order to conceptualise how to interact with a sport, though?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completely!
So, we have strong ties again with BRSF; Gareth sits on their board of Directors as our representative, but I feel like Roller Derby is really a pioneer in Roller Sports in that respect. We are far more proactive and we have a bigger membership, and we're more of a go-getter than the other sports. Probably because we have more that we need to achieve, in terms of getting that recognition, but the other sports aren't really fighting for anything. (But we are.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7176" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/fb_img_1461765537634.jpg" alt="FB_IMG_1461765537634" width="800" height="533"&gt; Tess Robinson with London Brawl Saints versus Glasgow Roller Derby (British Champs Tier 1). (Photo: &lt;a href="http://boutday.com"&gt;Dave McAleavy&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, moving to the internal aspects of UKRDA; obviously, UKRDA has some obvious things that it has organised - there've been two UKROC conferences now, and the Tattoo Freeze tournament is something of a long-standing tradition. What else does UKRDA do for the community?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, Tattoo Freeze is something that we put on, or we try to put on, every year. They've now asked us to start paying, to do it; I'm not sure if that means we'll continue it. But…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man, what is other stuff we've done(?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the big kind-of things which I think is a really great achievement is our insurance that our members get. They get just a super insurance deal through our brokers, and it's something that we get a lot - I'm on the info@ukrda.org.uk email account, and by far the most frequent inquiry we get is about insurance and how, especially new teams; a lot of new teams can't get practice space if they're not insured, and they struggle to find people who will insure them in the sport, so one of the biggest achievements we've had is a reasonable and [searches for word] comprehensive enough to cover what we do, so that we can continue to play. So that's something that's really great.
and I'm pretty sure it's the most competitive rate that anyone will get for this sport in the UK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing is just, well, I dunno, we provide a community and we try and make things fair; the National Squads is something that's huge, and a lot of that is going on right now. I think it's very important to have those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;We should say that this is the &lt;em&gt;Women's&lt;/em&gt; National Teams; and that this is a fairness-motivated oversight role, not a controlling role.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, the way it works is that we facilitate the recruitment of the Women's National Teams, the ones who are affiliated and soon to be affiliated, (and there will be more news on that coming up in terms of Men's teams, following the World Cup and things like that).
We facilitate the recruitment, to make it fair - one thing that I've always wondered was, in countries where there's not a national governing body, like the UKRDA, how do they even start? Where do they begin? Who just Decides that they are going to start the national team? I feel that the UK is lucky to have something to kind of do that [in an impartial way] because it's something that's so big and so important for our sport to have National and International recognition.
And then, basically, after Management is recruited, the National Teams go off and do their own thing, and the only position that the UKRDA takes is that things are done fairly, and there's no kind-of-like favouritism, bias; to make sure that if people have problems, they have someone that they can come to; and because the National Squads are affiliated [with UKRDA] they get votes on our policies, because those affect the National Squads as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the National Squads are huge and it's a massive part of what we do, so it's important that we feel that they are run correctly and fairly, so that people can have the best time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;It's important to note that this does not mean that you have to be from a UKRDA member league to apply for National Team Management. The involvement of UKRDA is not intended to restrict skaters from applying!&lt;/strong&gt;
Yeah. Yeah, with Team England Women's parting from their affiliation last time around, I feel like people got certain ideas about why and what happened, and I mean, there were disagreements, there always will be, especially when two partners are working together like that, and Big Names like England and UKRDA, there's always going to be disagreements in things that are done. But I will say that since then, we have made massive changes, we've listened to all of the National Squads and our Members on what they want us to do, what the National Squads want us to do, we've had so many meetings, both in person and over the phone, and we've made a huge effort to conform to how our members want the National Squads setup to be, so that it can be what everyone wants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what they want is: for National Squads to operate as their own entities, but with, a Body in place, so that if something goes wrong, they have that support, which is what we will do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, and that's it really. Absolutely no restriction going on.
[laughs]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This kind of centralised oversight is a model being adopted in other countries, to various extents for the French and German national teams, for example...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm, yeah, and it's always really nice to get questions and requests for support from other countries. Like with Spain: last year, they came under fire from FIRS when they couldn't get training venues for their teams, and they came to us and said, "You guys have obviously created a National association that would deal with this kind of stuff, and we don't have that, and we don't want FIRS to, you know, kill our sport over here, or take it, at least. Will you help us?" And so that was really nice, to have that recognition that we've done something good, and that other people want our support, was a nice realisation to have as a National Governing Body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UKRDA was (possibly) the first Roller Derby national association...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was, yeah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, you guys have more experience at this than everyone else.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, it makes me really proud to think that we were the first ever National Governing Body, for Roller Derby. And so, I think the whole community needs to give itself a pat on the back for making it something that has worked for so long…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's been about 6 years since first AGM...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[surprised]Erm, possibly, I don't…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first AGM was in 2010, so…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, okay, then yeah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/27/an-interview-with-ukrda-chair-tess-robinson/26193888381_1d277a9ef5_k/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-7187"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-7187" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/26193888381_1d277a9ef5_k.jpg?w=700" alt="Tess v Newcastle Roller Girls (Photo: Dave Moore)" width="700" height="926"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Tess v Newcastle Roller Girls' Gin + Sonic (Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/gridiron/albums"&gt;Dave Moore&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, although UKRDA was the first NGB (and some people tend to think of it as an inflexible Institution), 6 years isn't so long that there's not the possibility for change and growth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely! I mean, one thing that I certainly learned, coming into the UKRDA, is that there is an infinite amount of room for change. I have no problem admitting that, before I joined as a member of the board of Directors (I joined in 2015 as Secretary) I was exactly one of those people who was like: "Urg, the UKRDA does nothing, I don't understand what their purpose is, what are they doing for us?". I was 100% one of those people.
And it wasn't until I actually sat down and spoke with Gareth about it at EROC that year that I realised all of the things that I'm now telling you! And so, then and there, I said "I'm in! I'm up for it: how can I help, how can I start changing things?". I came in, and I just said "I want to do: this, this, this", and everyone was like "Great: you go and do that".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is exactly the way that I would be if anyone else came to us with ideas. I think people were surprised at our AGM; at how open we were. I said to people, "You know, what do you want to see? What do you want the UKRDA to do? What do you want us to achieve in 2016?" And people had so many ideas, which is excellent! It's so great to have that! People just need to realise that they can't just give ideas and expect someone else to do them; as much as we need ideas, we need people to follow them through! And we've been incredibly lucky that a lot of those people have stayed on since the AGM to follow a lot of these things through. This first kind of part of the year has been really positive in terms of getting things done and ideas moving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, these ideas, are they secret? Tell us about them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, all of them [are public]. So, a lot of the projects that we're working on are… you don't have to be a Rep or someone with a Post in the UKRDA to work on something, anyone that's part of a UKRDA team [league] can help. I would say anyone outside of the UKRDA can help! We would never put barriers up against people who want to give us their time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things that we're doing is looking into sublimation of our patch onto uniforms. So, we're scoping out suppliers, finding out Pantone numbers, and getting samples in. So, we're going to be contacting a lot of suppliers soon about that.
We are looking into how to incorporate and support invisible illnesses more. So that's anything, any disabilities that are not like, breaking your leg, the stuff that you can't see - anything from mental illness, chronic illness, epilepsy, anything like that. So we've started recruiting people who seem interested, to start putting together policies, guidance and support resources on that kind of thing. which is excellent - a lot of people from the Community on Facebook for Roller Derby mental health have been really supportive and helpful with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A massive one for this year, and I think probably infinitely, for ever, is Coaching Qualifications. Everyone wants to see Coaching Qualifications, so that's something that we're trying to work hard with now. There's so much politics and [so many] complex relationships that we have to work on with Sport England and Sports Coach UK, coaching structures in the BRSF, in order to get that done. So it's expensive, but given that I think it's so important - I'm a real driver of that ambition, because it unlocks funding, and that's so important.
We have a lot of councils who will deny spaces for Roller Derby, or deny funding for Roller Derby, because they don't have qualified coaches. So, I think as soon as we get that, both teams will be able to get funded easier, and also it brings in an income, both to the UKRDA and to people who are Coaches in our community, something which I think is really important.
Obviously, it's the kind of thing which we would charge for: we can't offer things for free when people are going to work so hard. We're going to have coaches writing specifications and curricula, and delivering the courses, and travelling; so it's the kind of thing we'll charge money for, and the kind of thing that the UKDA would make a "profit" from, but only because we would want to give that money back to coaches, for their time, and also fund ourselves so that we can do more.
Obviously, we are a non-profit organisation, but we don't have any way of making money right now. So, I feel like it's important for us to have money, so we can give it to other people! One of my dreams is that one day, the UKRDA will have a steady income, and will be able to offer grants to teams that they can then apply for it - for travel, or uniforms, or hire-kit for fresh meat, venues. That's kind of like one of my ultimate dreams for what I want us to offer as a governing body. We just need to build up first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And you have only been going for 6 years!&lt;/strong&gt;
I know! So ambitious (!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's lots of stuff going on with Officials as well. We're trying to champion this new kind of position, where we will offer, I think - this comes from Rocky, our Director of Officials, so I might get this wrong - we want to develop something along the lines of offering an Officials Observer to watch games, to more usefully fill out Officials Evaluations.
You know, I still compete in the sport, and we always get chucked a handful of eval forms at the end of a game, and you think: I wasn't even watching the officials, I have no idea how to fill this out, so it results in stress for the teams filling it in, and the officials end up with poorly done evaluations; and most of the time people will only say stuff if something went badly, so we really want to offer something more for the officials on that sense
And personally, I'd just like to see more development and support for officials in the UK anyway; I know it exists out there, but I'd love to see more training, and stuff for newer refs, to make their transition into officiating as great as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, that's quite a lot of things(!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, it's a lot of things!. And there's a lot more, as well: we've just gotten Valkyrie on board, as our Director of Gameplay, and she's really doing a lot of work to forge this connection between British Champs and the UKRDA. She really wants that to become more cohesive, so that we can offer better gameplay across everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's the Big Stuff that we're working on; there's a lot of little things from day to day that we join up with, so …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People might think that's a lot of stuff, but I would still welcome 10 times more, if it meant that it made our community happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, I'd like to talk a little about a sore point, perhaps: UKRDA's visibility. You've said earlier that you didn't know what UKRDA did before you joined it. Do you think this is still a problem - that no-body seems to know what UKRDA does?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's definitely a problem: what's the point in having an organisation like ourselves when people don't know about it?
A lot of people from outside the sport that I've talked to about it say "Well, how many members do you have?" I say "we have 63 or 64 members" (maybe, it is 65 now?), and they say "Oh, cool!", but I say, "Well, yeah, but there's also so many more teams in the UK who aren't members…", and they say "WHY? Why would they not be members?" and I think, Well, I dunno(!)
People say "What's your strategy for recruiting those teams?" and I think "I dunno… there's so much more work that we could be doing…"
Especially in regards to communications - all of last year we had a really great Director of PR &amp;amp; Communications, Katy [Gordon] from Auld Reekie Roller Girls, and she did a great, I think two or three years, with UKRDA. She stepped down at the most recent AGM, and we had no-one run for Director of PR, and no-one run for Head of Communications in the first round. We've only just had a couple of people step up and apply to be our Head of Communications. So certainly for the first part of this year, we've had no-one to do our PR - it's just me and the people who are still on the PR Committee, kind of doing bits and bobs now and then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's a massive gap in our organisation. Obviously, I don't really know anything much about it, and hopefully we've now got a new Head of Communications, but it's come at such a crucial time, when we've had all of the National Squads stuff, that it's really left us in not a great situation, with poor turn out for [Squads] Management Applications.
So it's definitely something that we could improve on… I have nothing against admitting that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's just a matter of getting people who want to work with us, and all that kind of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And hopefully your new Head of Communications will be spearheading this.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, definitely!
* &lt;strong&gt;On the topic of National Teams, you yourself are trying out for Team Wales, I hear.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;[This interview occurred just before the Team Wales first round tryouts on 24 April.]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah! I tried out last time, and I got through round 1, and I was really gutted that I couldn't attend Round 2. I was at University and it was the same date as one of my assessments which I definitely couldn't miss, because it was the equivalent amount of credits as my dissertation. It was the kind of thing that was assessed on one day - it was a theatre performance; I did Drama at Uni.
So I was super gutted that that kind of ruled me out completely, so I did feel a bit lost, knowing that… I was a real champion for the Welsh teams that we have; I came from Swansea Roller Derby, and I know a lot of people in the Welsh Roller Derby Community. It was really sad, also exciting, to see so many of my friends, you know, go to the World Cup, I was so supportive of Team Wales - so that was really, like a Challenging Time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But! I've waited, and worked really hard for the past 2 to 3 years, to be able to try out again, and I've graduated from Uni now, so there's nothing, absolutely nothing in my way. I'm really excited, and I absolutely cannot wait for tryouts on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's going to be great to see my friends, it's going to be great to give my all, and see the other people that are trying out. You know it's been 4 years since I played Roller Derby for a Welsh team, and the community and the people there have changed a lot, so I'll be really excited to meet new Welsh skaters, and people from new teams. so, it's just a very exciting time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just can't wait for the whole process to get going, it's going to be great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hopefully you make it, at which point you'll be on 3 important UK Derby entities [London Roller Girls, Team Wales, UKRDA]!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[laughs] Yeah, I'm feeling confident, you know! I play at a high level, and I work really hard: as long as I do my best, that's all that matters and counts .
Obviously, because I am also Chair of UKRDA, and trying out for a National Squad, my permissions have been quashed, so I can't actually see inside any of those files and folders; so, yeah, I'm not allow access to any of that!
Before I try out, I was, as Chair, with the National Squads, if there's ever a tied vote, the Chair is the deciding vote, so I'm now no longer allowed to do that(!). Which is fine: there's a lot of privilege that I've lost, through trying out, but I don't think there's any greater privilege than representing your country, so it's really important to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good luck!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/27/an-interview-with-ukrda-chair-tess-robinson/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 14:29:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Wales Assistant Coach: Chant-Hell</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/21/team-wales-assistant-coach-chant-hell/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Completing our set of interviews, in collaboration with &lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UKRDA&lt;/a&gt;, with &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamwalesrollerderby/"&gt;Team Wales Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s coaching and management team, we present Wales' Assistant Coach: Chant-Hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;(Tryouts for skaters in the current Team Wales Roller Derby are this Sunday!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/wp-1461262604145-jpg/"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-7084 size-large" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/wp-1461262604145.jpg?w=678" alt="Chant-Hell, playing with Tiger Bay Brawlers against London Rollergirls (Photo: Adam Chard)" width="678" height="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Chant-Hell, playing with Tiger Bay Brawlers against London Rollergirls (Photo: &lt;a href="http://www.croatoandesign.co.uk"&gt;Adam Chard&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Chant-Hell started out in the Cardiff Roller Collective in 2011, before moving to coach and skate for Tiger Bay Brawlers in 2012, where she remains. She is also owner of the Skate Alley skate store. Pregnancy ruled out Chant Hell from trying out for positions in the 2014 Team Wales, but this time around she is both Assistant Coach, and also planning to try out for the team itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;What led you to apply to coach Team Wales?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted a new challenge, I think getting to know and then coach a group of skaters that I don't really know in a high pressure and competitive environment will be both fun and challenging. Obviously representing my country in a sport I love is a pretty huge bonus too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last time around you had to sit out tryouts. What was it like to experience Team Wales from the sort-of-outside, as a Welsh skater? (And, as Assistant Coaches are eligible to try out, are you planning to tryout yourself this time around?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time around I was heavily pregnant over the Team Wales try out period so if I'm honest as I didn't skate during my pregnancy I spent a lot of time pretending Roller Derby didn't exist. I did volunteer at the first stage of try outs in Cardiff but other than that I experienced Team Wales from a complete outsider perspective and was really impressed by their performance and the progression of each individuals skater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes I'm planning on trying out this time around, its super exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the duties of the Assistant Coaching position is to sit on the selection panel for try outs. What will you be looking for in skaters trying out for Team Wales (and what advice would you give prospective applicants)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I'm trying out myself I have no involvement in the try outs or selection process at all, I think this makes it more exciting as I have no idea who or how many people have put themselves forward. The advice I'm giving myself is to let go of any nerves, have fun and be badass 😊&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The other main duty of an Assistant Coach is to, well, assist with coaching! From your experience coaching Tiger Bay Brawlers, what aspects of training are you planning to focus on for the National Team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coaching and being part of Tiger Bay has taught me so much, I think focussing on team work is going to be really important as we are essentially a mixed Roller Derby team made up of skaters who have potentially never even met each other! I would think that skaters on a National squad would already have a high level of skating skills so I think strategy &amp;amp; team work are going to be a main focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last time around, Team Wales hosted the Road To Dallas event as an intermediate tournament before the World Cup. There's a training and coaching advantage to playing a number of bouts before the Cup itself - are you planning any similar things this time around?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I'm aware we do intend to host another Road to Dallas style tournament, like you said there are huge advantages of playing bouts/tournaments before the Cup and it's a great way for all of our skaters to gain tournament experience even if  they don't play in the World Cup itself. Tournaments are tough so I think we should take as many opportunities as we can to prepare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We don't know much about Blood &amp;amp; Thunders plans for the 2017 World Cup yet: if you could have the tournament anywhere, where would you pick? Last time around, Wales played an eclectic mix of teams from across the world. What teams would you most like to see Team Wales play in 2017?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe!!! I would love for us to play Norway and Team West Indies (again!).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>team wales</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/21/team-wales-assistant-coach-chant-hell/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 18:54:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Wales Head Coach: Smirkcules</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/05/team-wales-head-coach-smirkcules/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The chance to learn more about &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamwalesrollerderby"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;' Management team continues, in collaboration with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UKRDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, as we cover the first of the two Coaching positions with Team Wales Head Coach Smirkcules.&lt;/p&gt;
If you would like to try out for Team Wales as a skater, then you can apply via the form here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The FAQ concerning applications is here:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1"&gt;https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; . The application deadline is April 17, so there's only 2 weeks to get yours in!
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/05/team-wales-head-coach-smirkcules/11816794_870899459662448_9095224078660854342_n/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-6933"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-6933" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/11816794_870899459662448_9095224078660854342_n.jpg" alt="Smirkcules, " width="700" height="467"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Smirkcules, benching Birmingham Blitz Dames (Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Cinderwreckerphotography/"&gt;Cinderwrecker&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Smirkcules has had an extensive Coaching career in Roller Derby, starting out with London Rockin' Rollers in 2010, before moving to Croydon Roller Derby, and &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; moving the considerable geographical distance to Newfoundland, coaching 709 Roller Derby there. After a few years coaching in Canada and Australia, he arrived back on British shores in time to coach Birmingham Blitz Dames to top of the Tier 3 table in British Champs 2015. He's also an ex-skater for Southern Discomfort!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;As well as all of that, he's a fairly prolific announcer, and announced at the Road to Dallas event in 2014 where Team Wales last battled it out against the UK's other teams (and Team West Indies). He's co-announced with Team Wales Manager &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/24/team-wales-manager-dorkmistress/"&gt;Dorkmistress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, at other events, as well as being involved along with her in the short-lived Team Sealand, placing him in good stead to collaborate in his current role as Team Wales Head Coach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;You've got a whole host of coaching experience, in the UK and Canada and Australia, but not especially in Wales. Why did you apply to coach Team Wales specifically?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wales is where I took my first guest coaching session and where I've returned multiple times to coach, announce and watch matches. It's also where I played the majority of my games in mixed scrims and co-ed matches, before injury knocked me out as a player for a long time. I have a lot of friends and derby colleagues I like working with in Wales. I have a lot of love for Wales and as a roller derby coach I like working with the Welsh derby community in different ways.
In my personal statement during the application process I summed it up with the following:
"I am really excited to be applying for the position with Team Wales as I enjoy working with passionate, hard fighting athletes who give their all."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's still true today. I'm really looking forward to our tryouts on April 24&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; to see these passionate fighters turn up and give their all to earn a spot to represent Wales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part of the Head Coach role is sitting on the selection panel for skater tryouts. What will you be looking for in Skaters trying out for Team Wales? (And what advice would you give those thinking about trying out?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of things we'll be looking for. We're looking to build a squad of skaters who can work and develop together. Boiling it down as simply as possible I'd say the two main things are: ability and attitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're looking for skaters who can perform at the highest level comfortably and confidently. Who have the capacity for moments of greatness. But we're also looking for skaters who are determined and have a strong work ethic, who don't mind doing what is asked of them at any time. Skaters who know and play roller derby as a team sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two aren't mutually exclusive. Skaters should be able to demonstrate both of these during tryouts. So if you are coming to tryout or want to sign up, I'd say put your best skills on show and work hard during your session. The expectations are high because they will one day be up against some of the best skaters in the world and we are building a squad to work together and compete at that high level. So as long as skaters understand this and give their best, they'll do fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In common with Team Wales Manager Dorkmistress, you've also done a lot of announcing, including at the Road to Dallas pre-World Cup event in 2014. How did you feel announcing Road to Dallas?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've done a lot of things in roller derby; coach, player, bench staff, NSO. The only thing I've not done in a bout is ref. Announcing is fantastic because you act as the middle person between the game and the crowd. You have to know both of these aspects well to get a good vibe going and ensure the game isn't compromised by your announcing whilst also keeping the crowd informed. It's a challenge but a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Announcing at Road to Dallas was great! It had four great national teams playing, one of which was making their international tournament debut. I love watching Team Scotland's packwork. Team Ireland showed some great high speed derby. West Indies was a new team to watch. Team Wales included skaters I like to watch play at anytime. So was really exciting and fun day. For anyone wanting international experience in the crowd, NSO or reffing, these smaller scale events are great opportunities if they come around. The audience was fantastic for Road to Dallas for all the teams playing. Was great derby to watch and commentate on and a great crowd to work with and for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The other component of being Head Coach is, well, coaching Team Wales. What principles are you going to be adopting to take the Team as far as they can go in the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well I don't want to give too many secrets away just yet but I have a personal coaching style and play mentality I refer to as the Complete Game. This involves not letting any moment go wasted. Every second counts and I want the team to make every second matter. Essentially I want to create a squad of ruthless, fierce warriors who are a challenge to any team they come up against, giving no quarter and expecting none in return. The image and motif I often use to describe it is a bunch of elite guerrilla warriors getting in, getting the job done and sticking the knife in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We don't know much about the potential location of the 2017 World Cup. Where would you like it to be, and what teams would you most like to see Wales play at it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My top three locations would be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wales – home crowd and Wales is a very welcoming, friendly place that people should visit. Derby just makes it better.
Finland – I love Helsinki and if at the end of the year, lots of snow and winter fun.
Australia – Outdoor tournament anyone? BBQs, beaches and huge love of sport! Lots of Summer fun if at end of year again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three teams I'd love for Wales to come up against at the next World Cup are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Norway – I'd like to have another game against them as I think the game against them in 2014 was a good match up. Be good to see how both teams have progressed since then.
England – Classic England vs Wales matches in every sport are always exciting so let's make it happen in roller derby.
Finland – I like Team Finland. I think it'd be a tough game but exciting.
Dream Final:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wales vs Australia – The team I coach vs the nation I was born in competing for the world cup. Couldn't ask for more than that!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>team wales</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/05/team-wales-head-coach-smirkcules/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 20:07:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Wales Line-Up Manager: Professor Moriarty</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/03/team-wales-line-up-manager-professor-moriarty/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier, we covered &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamwalesrollerderby/"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;' &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/24/team-wales-manager-dorkmistress/"&gt;Manager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and one of their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/28/team-wales-skater-buccaneer-betty-fear/"&gt;skaters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from the 2014 team, but we shouldn't forget the Coaching team, who will be training and organising Team Wales on track into the 2017 World Cup. In collaboration with &lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UKRDA&lt;/a&gt;, we're happy to start off our run of Coaching team interviews with Team Wales' returning Line-Up Manager, Professor Moriarty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to try out for Team Wales as a skater, then you can apply via the form here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The FAQ concerning applications is here:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1"&gt;https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; . The application deadline is April 17, so there's only 2 weeks to get yours in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/03/team-wales-line-up-manager-professor-moriarty/10858600_885961641434940_5869953106835376334_n/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-6918"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-6918" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/10858600_885961641434940_5869953106835376334_n.jpg" alt="Professor Moriarty, at the left, walking out with Team Wales in Dallas. (Photo: Jason Ruffell, Roller-derby-on-film.)" width="700" height="382"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Professor Moriarty, at the left, walking out with Team Wales in Dallas. (Photo: Jason Ruffell, &lt;a href="http://www.roller-derby-on-film.co.uk/"&gt;Roller-derby-on-film&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Moriarty has been a member of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/NPTRD"&gt;Neath Port Talbot Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; since she started in the game, 3 years ago. She bench coached the team through last year's British Champs, and into this year's. Selected as Line-Up Manager for the first Team Wales which competed in the 2014 Roller Derby World Cup in Dallas, she reapplied for the role, and was successful in this earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In common with other members of Team Wales, you're returning in your role as LUM from last time around. What lead to you reapply to the role for a second run?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yep, I’m a glutton for punishment! I had an amazing time during my first term with Team Wales but it was quite an emotional rollercoaster due to us being a brand new team.  We had to start everything from scratch; some said that we would never make it to Dallas, but we proved the doubters wrong and were placed 17th in our very first World Cup. I feel like Team Wales is our baby and I want to be able to nurture it and watch it grow from the fledgling team we were last time. I want to be able to say; "I was part of that. I helped that grow to new heights within the Derby community."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The LUM is also involved in selection and training for the National Teams. What things were you looking out for in Team Wales selection last time (and what are you looking out for in the new applicants this time)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During our first try outs we were trying to find as many skaters that were able and prepared to give the commitment to a new team that was needed. I remember seeing Jen (R27) for the first time and she blew my mind with her passion and love of the sport.
With our ability to now prove we are a country that wants to be present on the World Stage of Derby, I think our thoughts are different. We want to build on what we did last time and need to be more specific in the direction we take. We’ve done the “Got there, did that”, we now want to inspire local skaters to want to be part of their countries team. This can only be done by ensuring that we look for not only existing talent, but also rough diamonds.
I may offend a few skaters but my ideology is: we are Welsh, we are not pretty players but what we do, we do well, with the grit and determination of a country that is hardworking and focused on being the best they can possibly be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And how are you planning on contributing to the training process for the selection?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a coach and will never claim to be one; what I bring to the table is the ability to read people and be able to know what they are capable of. During the last term we had a skater that was not the best, but her communication was second to none. I fought against a lot of opposition to ensure that she was given the chances she deserved and it paid off. Just because you don’t have the right footwork or the right build shouldn’t mean that you’re not suitable to play for your country. This sport was built on inclusivity and I am a huge believer in the underdog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LUM can get fairly pressured, especially when playing against a tough team (like New Zealand), on a national stage. How you do manage the job in that kind of situation (and what's it like)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a very level headed person (my Husband may disagree with that). When others are losing their heads around me, I am looking ahead to see where we can make changes to improve what we are doing, so as to alleviate the problem. I like to know each and every one of my skaters, their abilities and what I think they are capable of. With this in mind, I am able to read situations and correct them without causing any pressure on my skaters. I believe in forward thinking, analysing what could and may go wrong and having strategies in place to combat them even before they arise, so as to make sure my skaters are in their Zen place when playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Returning to the role means that you bring a lot of experience with you. What you do think the last World Cup taught you about LUMing the National Team (and is there anything you'll be doing differently this time?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last World Cup taught me to be prepared for all eventualities: Know who does what and where, so when something does crop up it can be dealt with immediately. It taught me to appreciate help and to work as a team. To quote Fear's mantra, “Team work, makes the dream work”. The only thing I’d do differently this time is to try and soak more of the atmosphere in, as while it's happening it’s like a whirlwind all around you and then, poof it’s over!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(And what has been the best part of LUMing Team Wales so far…)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part for me was during the World Cup each country had its own room, which was situated on the floor below the auditorium. Before each game we would congregate here and walk up as a team singing. We sang everything from the National Anthem to Tom Jones, it was amazing!!!!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last time around, you were reluctant to say who you'd like to see Team Wales take on in the World Cup. But, we're going to try again! If you could have any team (existing or not) play Team Wales, who would it be? (And if the World Cup could be anywhere, where would you want it to be?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to see the World Cup in Europe this time. It’s a very expensive time and I think the European countries need a chance to be able to show what we can do. I'm still reluctant [to pick opponents] but would love to see a proper  6 Nations competition, just like the rugby!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>team wales</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/03/team-wales-line-up-manager-professor-moriarty/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 18:00:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Wales Skater: Buccaneer Betty Fear</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/28/team-wales-skater-buccaneer-betty-fear/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing our series of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamwalesrollerderby/"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Interviews, in collaboration with the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UK Roller Derby Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, we present Buccaneer Betty Fear, who skated on the first Team Wales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tryouts are currently open for the next Team Wales, who will compete in the 2017 Roller Derby World Cup. To learn more about the Tryouts, read the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1"&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform"&gt;Application Form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The Application Form also has details of the dates and locations that Tryouts will occur, in &lt;strong&gt;April&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;May&lt;/strong&gt;. If you would like to represent Wales internationally, then sign up to try-out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-6874" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/230c42621.jpg?w=2048" alt="230C4262" width="1024" height="647"&gt; Fear skating in the 2014 World Cup (against New Zealand), on the right. (Courtesy &lt;a href="http://www.girlsofderby.com/"&gt;Sean Murphy&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buccaneer Betty Fear started out in Roller Derby with Severn Roller Torrent in 2011. She remained with Severn, skating and coaching until 2015, when she joined Tiger Bay Brawlers. She was an active member of Tiger Bay during their first and only season in British Champs. She attended the 2014 Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup as a member of Team Wales, playing against Norway, South Africa, New Zealand and Puerto Rico.
Before her retirement from Roller Derby at the end of the last season, she blogged on roller derby and other topics at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://itsahardblocklife.com/author/buccaneerbettyfear/"&gt;It's a Hard Block Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, the obvious first question is at the beginning: why try out for Team Wales?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is so hard to write about why I tried out without relying on cliche. I think it is because it is such a big set of feelings that you run out of words...
Trying out to make a National Squad was not a life experience that I thought I would have. Roller Derby is still at this special, magical time where people who have come to the sport as an adult can have dreams like making a National Squad and have the chance to turn them into reality. If you bring the work and the commitment and the courage to put yourself on the line, you can make it happen. Our sport might not be like that forever (have you seen those juniors??), so grabbing that opportunity now, while we are in this meeting place where hard work can turn you into an elite athlete... was an obvious. At the point of trying out, even the trial felt like a win and an experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell us a bit about the mental game of the tryout process. What did it feel like to go through the tryouts; and wait and then discover you had made it onto the roster?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tryout experience was utterly unlike I expected. I thought it would be this pressurised, lonely experience where everyone was out for themselves. Nope. Within minutes of arrival the skaters trying out were forming bonds with each other. There was a palpable sense of community and support. It was like the larger Roller Derby community, but squeezed into this incredibly intense experience. During drills people were supporting each other and rooting for each other. During scrimmage we were urging each other to jam and to pivot.
Physically and mentally it was one of the toughest experiences I have gone through. The trials were long, demanding and I think they were designed to ensure you were pretty exhausted by the time you scrimmaged. Waiting for the results of the first round of trials was agony, the elation of finding you had made the next round was swiftly followed by the awful realisation you had to do it all again, with more at stake...
Finding out I had made the Squad was an incredibly proud moment. I had spent so long prepping for those trials... I had spent all my money hiring lonely sports halls  at early hours on weekend mornings, I had trained relentlessly in the gym, I'd read pretty much every sports psychology book I could get my hands on. I'd gone all out to make the Squad. Knowing I would wear a Welsh jersey was incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Training for a National Team is a significant additional investment for a skater, on top of their existing league commitments. How did you manage the time needed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the time I was in the Squad, there was no balance in my life. It was Roller Derby, all in. I worked, I played derby and I cross trained. I mumbled 'sorry' to my brilliantly supportive partner as I disappeared every weekend, usually on both days, for League and Squad training. I spent my money on Roller Derby travel, the gym and physio. I missed the wedding of a close friend and countless nights out and weekend adventures.
At some point it stops being about you, and becomes about what you owe the Squad. You know that there were other skaters who would have done anything to have the spot on Squad you have, you owe it to them to go all out. You know that your team mates are missing birthdays and weddings and not seeing their kids in order to train, you owe it to them. And there is always the thought of not letting your Country down. You are going to skate out with a Welsh dragon on your chest, you want to show the World (and the Welsh) that we were serious about this sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the lead up to the World Cup, Wales played several other games, including a kind of home-series (Road To Dallas) against Ireland, Wales and the West Indies. What do you think you and the team gained from these games?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The games we played in the lead-up to the World Cup were an incredibly experience. I think the proliferation of European (and UK-based teams) really lifted the quality of derby that was played at the World Cup. By the time we got there we had played half a dozen games as a National Squad - that makes a huge difference.
Instead of working out kinks in our game at the World Cup, we had a squad who had skated together, understood each other and had developed our game. We also got to learn from the experiences of teams that had skated in the first World Cup. Scotland and Ireland had such strong, experienced Squads. Playing them beforehand gave us a chance to learn and adjust. The West Indies were great to play against as well... they were such a tough, hard-hitting Squad... it totally warmed us up (tenderised us??) for the hard-hitting play we experienced in Dallas.
It also gave us a chance to experience skating as Team Wales and the whole different set of nerves that comes with that. Finally, it meant that more players had the experience of playing for their country. Not everyone made the Squad in Dallas, so some great skaters who didn't get the chance in Dallas still had the incredible experience of skating for their country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representing Wales in Dallas, you played against New Zealand, South Africa, Norway and Puerto Rico. What was your favourite game, and why? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each game was a special and intense experience and created memories that will stay with my forever. South Africa were a great, physical side, having the time of their lives and their spirit was infectious. New Zealand were, well, HUGE! They were formidable and it was brilliant to have the chance to go up against them. Puerto Rico was a joy of a game - the final of the one we played at the World Cup and just a riot.
But my favourite... was Norway. They were skilled, strong and relentless, but we had a moment where Wales came together and realised that everything we had worked for was now and that this was our chance. We went back out on track with a vengeance, lifting our performance. We lost, but that switch in how we were operating on track was special. It was a moment of mental resilience and this incredible sense of skaters going out there for each other. We did each other proud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you planning on trying out for Team Wales again?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've retired now - full of dreams made reality! But to anyone considering it - go.
Try out.
Yes: you.
Imagine being able to say you were at trials for a National Squad... imagine being able to say you made it. Get your butt to training, get to the gym, get watching footage and grab yourself a derby dream. You will get something from any part of the process you go through. Go get it, skater!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We currently don't know much about the 2017 World Cup. If you had a choice, where would you like it to be (and who would you like to face on track?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd love to see it in Europe: the cost for so many teams to travel to North America was prohibitive. I'd love to have it closer to home, and see more European teams able to have all their skaters there and more skaters get the chance to have their moment on track.
Who would I like to see Wales face on track? It's got to be Norway. But this time with a different ending...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team wales</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/28/team-wales-skater-buccaneer-betty-fear/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 13:09:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Team Wales Manager Dorkmistress</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/24/team-wales-manager-dorkmistress/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, we interviewed the outgoing members of the Team Scotland Management and Coaching Team, in collaboration with the &lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UKRDA&lt;/a&gt;. In an ongoing collaboration with UKRDA, we're happy to present interviews with &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamwalesrollerderby/"&gt;Team Wales&lt;/a&gt;' Management and Coaching team, starting with Team Manager: &lt;strong&gt;Dorkmistress&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(You can apply to try out to skate for Team Wales here: &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1QhY0y8WdT_D7O5LPclsMFEdi1ZMoSdJ-V7CaERtOLkQ/viewform&lt;/a&gt; , with a FAQ concerning tryouts here: &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1"&gt;https://docs.google.com/document/d/19Tw2QvnOzoU3PcD9U4SYPAOLr6tRESI085zvigrlPH4/edit?pref=2&amp;amp;pli=1 &lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dorkmistress has had a long and varied time in Roller Derby. Starting in 2011 with the Cardiff Roller Collective, as a skater and announcer, she has since moved to Swansea City Roller Derby (in 2013), and moved into refereeing for both Swansea and the South West Silures in 2014. She was Team Manager for Team Wales Roller Derby for the 2014 Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup, and continues in this role, having been re-elected in the post earlier this year. Her derby CV is extensive, including over 60 games refereed, and 100 announced, over her 5 year period in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full aligncenter" title="wp-1458819373825" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/wp-1458819373825.jpg" alt="image"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In common with other Team Wales roles, you're returning to the role of Manager from the last iteration of the National Team. What led you to decide to continue in the role? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a big decision - I loved the last two years but it's a fairly big commitment. We learnt so much in the last two years, starting the team from scratch and I wanted to make sure that I could see these lessons implemented. I know how I want to do things differently and think that I can do a much better job this time around. Plus, I'm not ready to watch Team Wales on track without being part of it! When I was thinking about how to answer these questions I looked back on the Team Wales Facebook page and seeing the support, encouragement and emotion on there made me remember what an incredible experience and honour it is to be part of Team Wales, and to be part of a team of such amazing people. And I still regularly look at the pictures of the Team Wales supporters gang - those crazy laydees from Neath Port Talbot, the supporters who travelled to Belgium and Dallas with their inflatables and daffodil hats, our own official leader of chants, Rhys Jones. Who wouldn't want to be part of that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managing a National team is quite a complex task, with many things to keep track of (and you've technically managed 2 Nations, what with Team Sealand). What do you think are the most important aspects of the job? (And coping with the workload?) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able and willing to keep all the plates you are spinning in the air is probably the key to success! And you can only achieve that with delegation and lots of communication. I worked with the skaters and other members of the management team to set up committees to cover key areas, like fundraising and events, and each group had an action plan and regular meetings. I did live on Facebook and Google Docs for the year, and ended up missing training a fair bit, but I wanted to make that commitment to make sure Team Wales was in the best place possible in Dallas. I have a busy real life job, but that's given me lots of time management and project planning skills, which were essential. Team Sealand was much easier, I just had to sort out travel and bout contracts ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last time around, a big part of the Management for most National teams was simply raising the funds to make it to Dallas. How did you guys go about managing the process, and finding new ways to get funds?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were really clear that fundraising was the responsibility of everyone in Team Wales, and everyone got involved. We had huge support from leagues from Newcastle to LRG to Severn Roller Torrent to Swansea City Roller Derby, giving us raffle proceeds, holding fundraising events and giving us stall space at their events. We had people donate money, we sold a LOT of t-shirts, we held kare-oke nights, we made loom bands, we had a baby picture competition, we had face painting at our games - literally any way we could get money out of people, we tried. We also decided to hold the fabulous Road to Dallas tournament in Newport in October 2014, hosting Teams Scotland, Ireland and West indies. Fundraising was constant - the challenge was to make it fun and to try and not just ask the same people all the time....same as most leagues face. It will be easier in some ways this time - we have our merch in place and an existing fan base - but harder in a sport where we have more leagues trying to fundraise from the same audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What've you learned from the last time around that you'll be applying this time, to improve Team Wales' management?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you got enough space in this blog? We're starting in a better position - we have a clear identity and design, so we will have t-shirts and merch available sooner and more options for our supporters. Do more on social media - keep everyone updated on our journey towards the World Cup. Delegate more and more completely - easier when you know what you are trying to achieve and know all the details and issues that need to be considered. Get the right partners and sponsors so things are as easy and cheap as possible for us. Play more games - we had 9 months from team selection to the World Cup last time and that wasn't enough - one reason we were keen to kick off the National Squad selection process in the UK. Everyone's going to freak out a bit on this journey - we are all allowed a freakout, just hopefully not at the same time. Sleep more and stop looking at Facebook messages at midnight and then again at 7am. Don't share a room with morning people if you are a night owl - probably the hardest and most important lesson I learnt.....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You've also announced in many places, including at the first Men's World Cup. How would you compare your two World Cup experiences?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very different experiences because they were very different sized events on very different continents. The Men's World Cup memories I have will last me a lifetime. It was my first taste of international roller derby and it was small and perfectly formed - the announcing team was incredible and the size of the schedule and event meant you could keep up with all of the action and see all of the teams and skaters sat next to you. I got to hang out with Team Japan and watch Team Argentina and nearly lost my voice shouting at Team Wales scoring points against Team USA - and those moments were all in the same room, right next to each other. It was the first time I got to introduce the Welsh National Anthem and I can still feel the hairs rising on the back of my neck. I also got to do the in-house announcement for &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; Wales V Australia game and the emotion in the venue at that last jam overwhelmed me so much I cried for 30 minutes at the end of the game - us announcers feed off that crowd emotion and I have never felt anything like it. It was such a personal experience I am not sure anything will ever really be the same as that. I'm desperately proud to have been part of the delivery of that event and I am more than a bit heartbroken that I can't go to Calgary this July - but I know Team Wales will make me and everyone else even prouder than they did that day in Birmingham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blood and Thunder World Cup was just so much bigger. When we arrived at the airport the customs guys said 'you here for the roller derby?'. Thats because they had already seen so many skaters and fans. 30 teams is a lot of people, three tracks in this massive room in a ginormous exhibition centre in America? Much bigger than the Futsal! If I went to the team room (each team had its own room! what?!) it was a good 5 minute walk, which, by the end of the day, felt like 5 miles. We'd gone to the European Roller Derby Tournament in Belgium and shared the underside of the bleachers seating with 7 other National teams and the next thing you knew we had a Team Support person, and a room and all sorts of things to make our time easier. I missed announcing though, you watch games in a different way and I didn't see a lot of other games as I was busy on the merch stall or sorting transport or one of the many other things that went on. And I missed being part of the team that showed you the event and explained what was going on. However, nothing in my life will ever compare to being able to walk out on the biggest Roller Derby stage in the world as part of Team Wales in the Parade of Nations. I can't even now, all this time later, put that experience and feeling into words. It's something I will forever be proud of and proud to have been part of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you were interviewed last time around, you noted that you were most looking forward to Team Wales playing "teams from far off places". In the event, Wales played South Africa, New Zealand, Norway and Puerto Rico, at least three of which probably count! If you could play any teams (announced or not) in the upcoming World Cup, what would they be?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Norway are going down this time ;-) It was almost impossible to watch the game  - seeing the team play out of their skins to claw back to within reaching distance for Norway to pull away just at the end. I'd love to see us play Argentina, they were incredible in Dallas and I think the South American teams are going to go to the next World Cup with a huge step up in skills and strategy. And there will be teams from new places - Iceland, definitely, maybe even Egypt, or Russia [where there are teams, but no established National infrastructure, yet]! We think and talk a lot about European Derby and Derby in North America, but the World Cup is the only place we get to see derby developing as a Global sport, and thats going to be really evident in the next World Cup for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(And if you have a place you'd like the World Cup to be, for any reason…)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would love it to be in Japan as I have always wanted to go there but even pretending I'd have to fundraise for that makes me want to cry! Very boringly I'd like it to be in Europe next - I think that showing as many people as possible international level derby inspires skaters and so would like to see it move around continents to give everyone that experience - watching it on the internet isnt quite the same. So next time Australia or New Zealand. Then South America or Asia or Africa. A true world tour!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>team wales</category><category>ukrda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/24/team-wales-manager-dorkmistress/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 11:38:06 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>