<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about voodoo roller dollies)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/voodoo-roller-dollies.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Voodoo and Hades in 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/12/voodoo-and-hades-in-2015/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2015 was a particularly packed year for the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Voodoo-Roller-Dollies-571771319549241/"&gt;Voodoo Roller Dollies&lt;/a&gt;. As well as participating in &lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/category/women-local/local-north/"&gt;British Championships Tier 4 North&lt;/a&gt;, they also managed to both host and attend several tournaments, and fly across Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, before the Tier 4 fixtures even started, Voodoo had already hosted their own mini-tournament, taking on fellow Tier 4 competitors, New Town Roller Girls, and Glasgow Roller Derby's Cannie Gingers in the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/144431299060564/"&gt;Highland Rampage&lt;/a&gt; in Edinburgh's Jack Kane Centre.  While the Cannies emerged victorious, VRD took the win against New Town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VRD also managed to sneak in a battle of the Zombie themed teams, playing Tournai, Belgium's Rolling Zombie Dolls away, and North Wales Roller Derby's Zom Bs at home, before British Champs started in April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5609" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/01/11024650_10100359068288294_1208772091011200554_n.jpg" alt="11024650_10100359068288294_1208772091011200554_n" width="960" height="640"&gt; Voodoo Roller Dollies take on New Town for the first time in 2015 (Credit: &lt;a href="http://lauramacd.co.uk"&gt;Laura MacDonald&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In between Champs fixtures, Voodoo even took a side trip to Ireland, successfully taking on Belfast City Rockets on the way to a rematch against the East Coast Cyclones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Voodoo failed to earn promotion in British Champs, they also avoided relegation, defeating New Town a second time to stay off the bottom of the table. (VRD are also one of quite a few teams not returning to British Champs in 2016, so that they can concentrate on the rest of their bouting fixtures.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voodoo indulged their love of sur5al in November, sending a team to the Blackpool Roller-Coasters' Sur5al 2015 Mini Tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the Dollies capped off the year by hosting their &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/908423505918913/"&gt;second mini tournament&lt;/a&gt; of 2015, with returning Cannie Gingers also taking on Lucerne's Hellveticats in the triple header in Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HadesRollerBoys/"&gt;Hades Roller Boys&lt;/a&gt; were not letting their sisters in Voodoo have all the fun. At the same time as changing their Facebook page, the Boys started their year in March taking on Bristol's Vice Quads away for a loss, and Cornwall's Scrumpy Old Men for a win the very next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hades followed this up by taking on the impressive Tyne and Fear B in May (as part of a double-header, featuring Newcastle v Brussels), and facing off against Portsmouth's Scurvy Dogs (also as part of a double header, featuring Portsmouth Roller Wenches v Norfolk Brawds) in July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hades also love sur5al, and they competed well in both Glasgow Roller Derby's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1128420117173784/"&gt;tournament&lt;/a&gt; in June, and Leeds Roller Dolls' &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1658884867657678/"&gt;Rolling Dead&lt;/a&gt; in October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5612" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/01/12362692_1012007705529392_4768291942966720645_o.jpg" alt="12362692_1012007705529392_4768291942966720645_o" width="2048" height="1365"&gt; Hades take on De Ronnys in the BEARDI final! (Credit: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/orelkichigaiphotography/"&gt;Orel Kichigai&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important event in Hades' 2015 must be their attendance at the alternative men's European tournament, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BEARDi-1456637027957678/"&gt;B.E.A.R.D.I.&lt;/a&gt; As the only Scottish team attending, Hades had a lot of weight on their shoulders, and they excelled, defeating all comers to make it to the final against Germany's De Ronnys. After a very physical bout, Hades emerged triumphant as 2016 B.E.A.R.D.I. champions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Hades and Voodoo also found the time to fully combine their powers, with &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HoodooCoedRollerDerby/"&gt;HooDoo Co-ed Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; making their track debut against the "Beach Brawl All Stars" exhibition team. We expect more fixtures for HooDoo this year, as Co-ed roller derby continues to grow in Scotland!&lt;/p&gt;
Finally, 2015 saw the end of an era as two of Voodoo and Hades' founders, Raven and Pete, moved on to other geographical locations. (Raven's last ever bout was also the last bout of the year.)
&lt;p&gt;We'll finish on this message from the current Voodoo Roller Dollies team:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;We would like to say Thank you to Raven and Pete for their contribution to the team and wish them well for the future.
2015 was a very busy year for us and we managed to do more than we even thought we could manage. We are looking forward to 2016 and the opportunities and potential it holds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>hades roller boys</category><category>hoodoo roller derby</category><category>review of the year</category><category>voodoo roller dollies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/12/voodoo-and-hades-in-2015/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 16:11:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>From Lucerne with Shoves: Voodoo's international tournament plans!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/12/from-lucerne-with-shoves-voodoos-international-tournament-plans/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While this weekend continues the tradition of being rather busy in roller derby, in Glasgow, something a little epic is being planned. Fresh from the end of the British Championships Tier 4 competition, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Voodoo-Roller-Dollies-571771319549241/"&gt;Voodoo Roller Dollies&lt;/a&gt; are hosting a mini-tournament, with an international bent. Returning from Voodoo's last tournament (only this February!) are Glasgow C, the &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/content/cannie-gingers"&gt;Cannie Gingers&lt;/a&gt;; however, flying in all the way from Lucerne (Luzern), Switzerland, the third team are &lt;a href="http://www.thehellveticats.ch/"&gt;The Hellveticats&lt;/a&gt;, part of the new wave of Swiss and Central European roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/12/from-lucerne-with-shoves-voodoos-international-tournament-plans/12006363_963059253753777_8455008463369869288_n/" rel="attachment wp-att-4938"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4938" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/12006363_963059253753777_8455008463369869288_n.jpg" alt="12006363_963059253753777_8455008463369869288_n" width="614" height="231"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2012, the Hellveticats started with the usual enthusiasm of new leagues, despite, as Referee Lucy Cat Rolls told us "that most of the girls on the team haven't even watched a roller derby game, we did our best to train and build up our league". They've been bouting since late 2013, according to Flat Track Stats, mostly playing the rest of the Swiss and Central European derby community. In fact, the tournament will not just be a new experience for the Scottish teams, as it's the furthest trip that the Hellveticats have made in their history."As we have many members with family or other responsibilities we try to get bouts which are possible to travel within a day trip. But, every now and then, we make a journey with the team - we went to [Prague] in the Czech Republic and to Nice in France. Scotland is within a very good distance by plane so we decided to travel there together, we are thrilled to be invited to this awesome event."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it happens, the fact that the tournament exists at all is actually down to the Hellveticats' enthusiasm for a long distance trip. As Voodoo's Roll-N-Pin told us: "[The Hellveticats] actually contacted us, believe it or not. They got in contact with our very own Titan and from there it progressed. We wanted to make sure that they got as much of a Scottish derby experience as possible, [so we organised the tournament around them]." Not that Voodoo have ever been shy of a tournament, as Pin admitted, "tournaments are always a great way to involve so many people at the same time. To come up against new teams and get to spend even more time in a weekend or day playing against them. I mean, who doesn't love more derby time? It's double, and even triple, the fun at times with tournaments."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Hellveticats are travelling the furthest, it's Glasgow's &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/45330"&gt;Cannie Gingers&lt;/a&gt; who are the most dangerous competitors in the tournament, sitting almost 200 places above &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/38908"&gt;Voodoo&lt;/a&gt;, and 130 above the &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/20691"&gt;Lucerne&lt;/a&gt; team, in Flat Track Stats' European ranking scheme (although our own prediction scheme places the latter somewhat closer in ability to the Glasgow team). Despite the huge challenge they represent, Voodoo are relishing the rematch. "The Canny Gingers are always a fierce opponent and are really the definition of a true challenge, " said Roll N Pin, "but with each bout we play against superior teams, we gain more knowledge , discover more tactics  and get to try out more strategies. It would take a phenomenal achievement on our part to win against them, but for us it's not all about the win. At the end of the day if the other team are walking away with bump and bruises, sore spots and dead arms or legs then we know we have put up a great fight and have made them work for it. It gives us a goal to work towards as well, a comparison to ourselves to see how much we have improved and how we can improve more." And the Cannie Gingers aren't willing to rule out the possibility of a Voodoo win, saying "there are no guarantees in Derby; just look at the Rose/Victorian/Gotham games in the WFTDA Championships. We just want to play our games and take each jam as they come!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow C are also keen to see what Swiss derby has to offer, noting that "one of the great things about roller derby is the opportunities it brings, and it's an honour to play every team we face, for the things we are taught in each game. It will be interesting to see how our styles play against each other; we hope it will also be a fun experience and that [the Hellveticats] have a good Scottish welcome".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of who actually wins, all the teams have the same goals at heart. Roll N Pin "First and foremost, and it may seem cheesy, [our goal] is to have FUN! We want to present an environment to welcome all and make sure that the players and the crowd are having fun. But hey that's not too hard to do when you've got derby, tunes and CAKE!", and Lucy Cat Roll agrees, "I guess the biggest challenge will be understanding the Scottisch dialect and resisting to the urge of drinking whisky before the first whistle ;-) We hope to have fun and to meet many nice derby people and we hope to have you over in Switzerland one day and invite you for a nice tournament, some cheese and a ton of chocolate." The Gingers also, "above all, [] just want to have a nice time! We have some established skaters, and some who will be playing their first game, so it's a nice mix. We work hard at training, and in running our league, so we just want to represent GRD in the best way we can."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voodoo Roller Dollies have a new intake planned for the end of November, and extensive plans for the future. As Pin puts it: "Voodoo's future is looking bright. We have a new intake at the end of this month (as always we are looking to expand) and we have many a teams to play again for return games. We are hoping to get more involved in the derby community and attend more scrims. Maybe even host a few ourselves. One thing is for sure we will always come back hitting harder and pushing ourselves further."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tournament starts from &lt;strong&gt;Midday&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8666126,-4.2505074,17z/data=!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7"&gt;ARC Sports Centre&lt;/a&gt; in Glasgow Caledonian University on Saturday &lt;strong&gt;14th November&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event page can be found on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/908423505918913/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, and tickets will be £5 on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as we are aware, the planned schedule of play is:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Doors 12:00&lt;br&gt;
Skate outs 12:20&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
1st game - VRD v GRD - 12:30&lt;br&gt;
2nd game - GRD v Hell - 13:55&lt;br&gt;
3rd game - Hell v VRD - 15:20&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>cannie gingers</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>hellveticats</category><category>international</category><category>interviews</category><category>tournament</category><category>voodoo roller dollies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/11/12/from-lucerne-with-shoves-voodoos-international-tournament-plans/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 20:42:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spookapolooza: A Very Derby Halloween</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/23/spookapolooza-a-very-derby-halloween/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/spookapalooza.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-4111" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/spookapalooza.jpg?w=614" alt="Spookapalooza" width="614" height="228"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hallowe’en weekend sees the Hades Roller Boys have their last bout of the season at the ARC in Glasgow. They’ll be playing host to the boys of Mild Discomfort (Southern Discomfort B) who play for the first time in Scotland. As usual this will be a nail biting, hard-hitting Mens bout. With whistles at 12:15, be sure to buy tickets in advance!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then to top it off the girls of Dundee Roller Girls Rising Stars face off against the Voodoo Roller Dollies in the Dollies last home game of the year. Well worth a watch and tickets are available on the door, but cheaper when bought in advance!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event via facebook: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/648479905259577/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/648479905259577/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets: &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/spookapalooza-derby-double-header-tickets-13790767557"&gt;https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/spookapalooza-derby-double-header-tickets-13790767557&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>hades roller boys</category><category>southern discomfort</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>voodoo roller dollies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/23/spookapolooza-a-very-derby-halloween/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 13:00:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sur5ors: Charity Tournament</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/15/sur5ors-charity-tournament/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Team Scotland are off to Wales this weekend to skate in the Road to Dallas, the rest of us would be bereft of derby action if it weren't for the foresightedness of Alison Renton - following up last year's charity bout with a whole Sur5al tournament this time around!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/sur5ors.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-4067" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/sur5ors.jpg?w=614" alt="sur5ors" width="614" height="869"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/302622106565291/?fref=ts"&gt;Sur5ors&lt;/a&gt; will see teams from&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/auldreekierollergirls"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BairnCityRollers"&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BlackpoolRollerDerby"&gt;Blackpool Roller Derby Team&lt;/a&gt;
Dundee Roller Girls
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/FierceValleyRG"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; (twice)
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/furnessfirecrackers"&gt;Furness Firecrackers - Roller Derby League&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GlasgowRollerDerby"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; (twice)
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/NewTownRollerGirls"&gt;New Town Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/mhrollerderbyuk"&gt;Team Crazy Legs: Roller Derby, Mental Health &amp;amp; Chronic Illness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;and
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Voodoo-Roller-Dollies/571771319549241"&gt;Voodoo Roller Dollies&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to compete in the usual 5-person team endurance derby that is Sur5al.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All profits will go to &lt;a id="js_3" class="" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Glendrick-Roost-Animal-Welfare-Centre/295429747140376"&gt;Glendrick Roost Animal Welfare Centre&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/standrewsfirstaid"&gt;St Andrew's First Aid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are still available at: &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/838260"&gt;http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/838260&lt;/a&gt; , and the event kicks off at 11:30 am at The Peak, Stirling on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>blackpool roller derby</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>furness firecrackers</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>sur5al</category><category>team crazy legs</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>voodoo roller dollies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/15/sur5ors-charity-tournament/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 12:31:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Voodoo Roller Dollies vs Preston Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/16/voodoo-roller-dollies-vs-preston-roller-girls/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a title="Voodoo Roller Dollies Facebook Page" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Voodoo-Roller-Dollies/571771319549241" target="_blank"&gt;Voodoo Roller Dollies&lt;/a&gt; will make their home-game debut on Saturday July 26th in the Jake Kane Centre in Edinburgh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voodoo played their first game in March against The Flaming Noras in Furness - and won with 205 pints to 155! The team are hoping to continue with their success and have been working hard in preparation for their first game at home where they will take on Preston Roller Girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day itself is guaranteed to be fun-filled, with a Rocky Horror Picture Show theme. Fancy dress is actively encouraged and prizes will be awarded for best costume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 12:30. Join the &lt;a title="Voodoo vs Preston Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/290841551085852/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/blocky-horror.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3543" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/07/blocky-horror.jpg" alt="Image courtesy of Voodoo Roller Dollies" width="614" height="868"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Voodoo Roller Dollies
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Celebration Skate - Sunday, 27th July&lt;/h4&gt;
And as if that wasn’t enough, the Dollies will be opening up their regular training session on Sunday 27th July in Hallglen Sports Centre for a Celebration Skate. They would like you to join them to celebrate their debut game, with music and cake. Skaters from all skate backgrounds are welcome at a cost of £5. Please see the &lt;a title="Celebration Skate Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/707176349319443/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event &lt;/a&gt;if you would like to join in the celebrations.&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>hallglen sports centre</category><category>jack kane centre</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>voodoo roller dollies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/07/16/voodoo-roller-dollies-vs-preston-roller-girls/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 19:44:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Stick a pin in your calendar: Voodoo Unplugged.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/05/08/stick-a-pin-in-your-calendar-voodoo-unplugged/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/vrd.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-3413" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/vrd.jpg?w=614" alt="VRD" width="614" height="614"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there's a huge amount of exciting roller derby happening this month (Internationally, and otherwise), sometimes you may need a break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily for you, Voodoo Roller Dollies are holding the Voodoo Unplugged event on May 29th, providing an evening of acoustic music from local bands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are £5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information can be found on the event page on Facebook:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1380425432218066/?ref=5&amp;amp;source=1"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1380425432218066/?ref=5&amp;amp;source=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funds raised from this event will go towards future VRD bouts. The Dollies are also running a GoFundMe page to specifically raise money for their planned away bout against Belfast. You can donate to that here: &lt;a href="http://www.gofundme.com/8s3j64"&gt;http://www.gofundme.com/8s3j64&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fundraiser event</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>voodoo roller dollies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/05/08/stick-a-pin-in-your-calendar-voodoo-unplugged/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 20:08:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Review 2014: Nitemare, Voodoo and Hades... and Bob.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/12/derby-review-2014-nitemare-voodoo-and-hades-and-bob/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A slightly unusual Review entry this time: not a league, but a collection of Derby Happenings all tied together by one common feature: Falkirk's own skate and roller derby store, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/intothe.nitemareclothing"&gt;Into The Nitemare&lt;/a&gt;. We thought that, what with having their own exhibition team, founding two others during the year &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; putting on a national tournament, they probably deserved an article to themselves...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/img_0002.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-3280" alt="img_0002" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/img_0002.png?w=614" width="368" height="553"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Titan and Raven, Into The Nitemare, at the end of Battle of Britain (Copyright: Sam Skipsey)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/img_0001.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3281" alt="Newcastle Roller Girls, winners of BoB." src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/02/img_0001.png?w=614" width="614" height="408"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Newcastle Roller Girls, winners of BoB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This has been an eventful year for Into The Nitemare's derby involvement, with Team Nitemare holding their first exhibition bouts, the formation of Hades Roller Boys and Voodoo Roller Dollies, and the successful hosting of Scotland's second ever national tournament, Battle of Britain. What has been the standout experience for the two of you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve had an amazing year derby wise, and there are far too many highlights to name just one. Team Nitemare was just amazing, I remember welling up at the skateout. Just so proud to see two amazing groups of such talent under one roof. The Jakey Tayzers proved to be a force to be reckoned with and as it turns out, many of them have found themselves on their gender's National Team Scotland. That was also the day of the Hades debut, which was one of the most exciting bouts I’ve had the pleasure of experiencing…I got so wrapped up in the game I have since been sacked as Line Up…by my own husband no less, hehe. I am so not cut out for that position.
The Hades boys put together a charity bout in November, just the week before BoB, which got people coming from all over the UK, and we were chuffed to bits that all these people made such an effort to come, from Manchester Roller Derby, Blackpool Roller Derby League and Belfast Men's Roller Derby, not to mention representation from leagues all over Scotland. It was an amazing day.
Then we get to BoB…well that was a year in the making and we’d again like to pass along our thanks to all that made it possible. We had representation from wider Europe and even the good ole USofA. The only drawback of the day was not skating in it!
As for the Voodoo Roller Dollies, well you’ll have to keep your eyes peeled for our upcoming news but needless to say we’re training hard in preparation for an incredible first year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coming back to the events in sequence, last time we spoke, we talked about your plans for coed exhibition team, Team Nitemare. This year, they managed to bout for the first time, taking on the Jakey Tayzers for a narrow 174:215 loss and then travelling to play Middlesborough Milk Rollers' Milk Invaders away to a resounding 278:168 win! How was the experience of building to those two bouts?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beauty of Team Nitemare is that we have built on it throughout the year and we have expanded our ranks. There were a few hiccups in the the run up to the Jakey Tayzer bout, but in true roller derby fashion, it pulled together and ran smoothly on the day. The Tayzers were a formidable force and showed how well a co-ed team can work together. All of the lead up to the Milk Invaders (Middlesborough Milk Rollers and Teeside Skate Invaders Mash up) was all down to the lovely Terri Sudron and we the team. It was intense in the run up though, especially the first one, it was almost like Christmas, so much tension for an hour or so of watching it all come together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Nitemare's debut was also Hades Roller Boys', the second bout pitting them against Ireland's Men Behaving Derby, for a narrow win. Hades later played Wirral's men's team away in December. This is a bit of a reversal for the two of you, with Raven getting to cheer on Titan[Cronos?] for the first time! Tell us a bit about the experience…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit here, I was a very bad wife and abandoned Titan to go and have fun at Team Scotland Try-outs… The debut is the only bout I’ve seen of Hades, as their next one was over in Montpellier against the Kamiquads.
Although I will be at their next game, most definitely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A little after Hades was founded, the Falkirk area also gained its third women's team in Voodoo Roller Dollies. With Fierce Valley and Bairn City already in the region, how are Voodoo planning on distinguishing themselves?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We set ourselves apart from the two other big teams in the area by being small. We are not looking at expanding to league proportions but our initial aim is to gain a roster of 20. I’ve been a part of a big and fast growing league and found that it wasn’t for me. I like feeling that I know all of my team mates and we speak every day. We aim to conduct the team with as little of the traditional structure as is expected. So if you’re looking to become a new blood at Voodoo, you can expect to have fun , just skate and be a valued member of VRD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capping off the year for Into The Nitemare was the 6-way Battle of Britain tournament, pitting teams from across the UK (with a few last minute substitutions from the original lineup) against each other. With three teams in the event, Scotland did creditably, with Dundee finishing a strong second after Newcastle's Whippin Hinnies' first place.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; How was the experience of running your first big event? Anything you'd do differently next time [will there be a next time]?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoB as it was fondly known was a great day. We were so proud to see Scotland do so well, with Dundee rampaging home in silver position, Lothian Representing extremely well on the day despite injury and some brand new skaters and the Belters getting their first win.
Newcastle, having stepped in at the last minute, were valiant in their win, Belfast showing some massive hits and the Reapers playing their first open bouts and getting that first public win under their belts too. The day was fantastic and without the help of Teams, Refs, NSOs, Photographers, Announcers and event staff it would not have been possible. As I said before the nature of derby is to throw a spanner in the works and there were more than a few in the final weeks of preparation with two teams pulling out, venue issues and then on the day a minor mishap with a team bus..but it all came together in the end.
Special mention has to go to Head Ref: Ella Bella Bang Bang (ARRG) and our Head NSO [Crashing] Wookiee [Broken Zebra] (GCRG) without whom, I would have been pretty much a wreck.
Will we do another tournament? Maybe, you’ll just have to wait and see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With all that happening in 2013, Into The Nitemare must have plans for 2014. Is there anything you can reveal now, or is it all secret?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not secret, but it hasn’t been announced yet. We have a busy year ahead in all aspects, Hades, Voodoo and Team Nitemare , so you’ll just have to watch on the facebooks and twitters to keep abreast of all our happenings!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>battle of britain roller derby tournament</category><category>derby review 2014</category><category>hades roller boys</category><category>into the nitemare</category><category>team nitemare</category><category>voodoo roller dollies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/02/12/derby-review-2014-nitemare-voodoo-and-hades-and-bob/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 19:34:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>