<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about #wearefierce)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/wearefierce.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Girls - Wanna Join?</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/22/fierce-valley-roller-girls-wanna-join/</link><dc:creator>alibonanza</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="" title="11908592_1042693805742471_2412030954146539060_o" src="http://i1.wp.com/www.fvrg.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/11908592_1042693805742471_2412030954146539060_o.jpg?resize=530%2C355" alt="11908592_1042693805742471_2412030954146539060_o" width="222" height="149"&gt;&lt;img class="" title="11888546_1042693869075798_8615470236872184543_o" src="http://i1.wp.com/www.fvrg.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/11888546_1042693869075798_8615470236872184543_o.jpg?resize=262%2C176" alt="11888546_1042693869075798_8615470236872184543_o" width="221" height="149"&gt;&lt;img class="" title="FVRG Taster Sessions" src="http://i1.wp.com/www.fvrg.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/11875044_1042689072409611_6975712594037629319_o.jpg?resize=262%2C175" alt="FVRG Taster Sessions" width="222" height="148"&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;7th August&lt;/strong&gt;, FVRG will be hosting a roller derby taster in &lt;strong&gt;Grangemouth Sports Complex&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;from 11.30 - 13.30.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Fierce Valley Roller Girls is a not-for-profit women's roller derby league within the Forth Valley area. Whilst our competitive team is women-only, we welcome all genders to be referee or non-skating members. Our training sessions and our home games are held in Grangemouth Sports Complex.
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in joining Fierce Valley Roller Girls and are aged 18 or over, please complete our Registration Form &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/join-fvrg/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Signing up as a competitive skater or as a referee?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
If you would like to register as either a skater or a referee, the taster session will give you the opportunity to learn the basics of skating (and stopping!) safely. You will be buddied up with an experienced skater who will share their wisdom - and their equipment - with you. Please bring your own mouth guard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the taster session, we will welcome you into a dedicated roller derby training programme for beginners, tailor-made and led by FVRG coaches. On completion of the beginners training, you will also attend the intermediate training, where your roller derby 'minimum skills' will be assessed. Beginner-training is held on Sunday mornings; intermediate-training is held on Wednesday nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competitive skaters will then move into the advanced training programme and have the opportunity to try out for our travel team. Advanced-training is held on Friday nights; team-training is held on Tuesday nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon completion of their intermediate training, referees will branch off into the referee training programme. It's common for referees to gain their basic training in our intermediate sessions, and then move onto officiating drills in the advanced and team sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Signing up as a non-skating member?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Not everyone in at FVRG skates, believe it or not. If you want to be part of the roller derby community but don't wish to compete of officiate, then you can join us a Non Skating Member. We're always looking for 'Non Skating Officials' (NSOs); artwork designers; photographers; bloggers - the list goes on. All we ask is that you attend at least one of our 'scrims' (internal games) per month to keep you integrated with the league and to learn the rules of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We hope to see you there !&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>#wearefierce</category><category>annoucements</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>fvrg</category><category>join roller derby</category><category>taster session</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/22/fierce-valley-roller-girls-wanna-join/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 08:57:35 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>