<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about wftda)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/wftda.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Guest Article: Strength Factor Challenges for Europeans</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/09/guest-article-strength-factor-challenges-for-europeans/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;As part of our irregular series of Guest Articles, we're bringing you a feature from Blind Io (NSO, Paris Rollergirls + Flat Track Stats (European region)), presenting a position on why European WFTDA leagues should play more SFCs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;I want to talk about the Strength Factor Challenge (SFC), and its under-use as a tool for improving the rankings of competitive European WFTDA leagues.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Problem:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;As the 2018 WFTDA European Continental Cup has just wrapped up (and oh my what an exciting one it was!) it’s reasonable to imagine that quite a few European leagues are making goals to qualify for the 2019 version, by becoming one of the top-most European leagues in the WFTDA rankings.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;However, climbing the WFTDA rankings table isn’t as straightforward as “being the best”. The most highly-ranked teams put a lot of work into determining which teams they should play, as well as precisely by how much they must beat them (or how little to lose by), in order to get into the highest ranks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;A team’s rise and fall in the WFTDA rankings is decided by the WFTDA Rankings Algorithm (&lt;a href="https://wftda.org/rankings-policy/algorithm"&gt;https://wftda.org/rankings-policy/algorithm&lt;/a&gt;), which is an equation that uses the score from a sanctioned game as well as the “strength factor” of each team to calculate by how much each team’s ranking will change. We’re not going into the fine details of the algorithm, but for the purposes of this article it’s important to know that in a sanctioned game, as the rankings difference increases between the two teams, the higher-ranked team has to win by a greater and greater margin in order for their ranking to improve (or break even). There is a point at which the score margin becomes physically impossible to achieve (for example a Rank 20 team would have to prevent a Rank 80 team from scoring &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; points just to break even, and the Rank 80 team would have the same problem against a Rank 200 team).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;For an extreme example of the difficulties involved with finding suitable sanctioned games for high-ranked teams, consider a little piece of London Rollergirls' history. For many years London was the only European team in the top tier of the WFTDA Rankings: at the end of 2014 when London was ranked 6th in the world, everyone else in Europe was ranked 50 or worse! Such a great rankings gap meant that London was unable to play a Sanctioned game against any other European team, as it would have guaranteed a drop in their rankings and reduced their chances of going to WFTDA Playoffs &amp;amp; Champs. Because of this, London couldn’t play a single sanctioned game against another European team for 3 years from the end of 2012 until late 2015!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Here’s a TLDR:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; teams become less and less likely to sanction games against each other as their ranking differences increase; and when high-ranked teams won’t play low-ranked teams, it gets very difficult for the low-ranked teams to climb the rankings ladder!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Clearly, making it into the top-X European teams that qualify for the European Cup is not easy! At the time when the qualifying teams were selected for this year’s European Cup (July 2018), the average ranking of the 8 chosen teams was 55 -- and there were only 6 other European teams within 40 ranks of that (15-95). With so few teams at the top levels of European rankings, it can be very hard to find enough suitable sanctioned games needed in order to join them, at least not without travelling to North America as many teams have had to do in the past.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Strength Factor Challenge:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Four years ago, WFTDA came up with a solution to this problem of ‘not enough similarly-ranked local teams’: the Strength Factor Challenge (SFC). This was a tool that would allow unranked/new teams and under-ranked teams to play a special SFC game against a higher-ranked opponent, that if successful would make them much more attractive to higher-ranked opponents for subsequent sanctioned game play. It means that under-ranked teams can jump up the ranks very quickly if they know what they’re doing!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Details &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.org/rankings-policy/strength-factor-challenge-program"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;https://wftda.org/rankings-policy/strength-factor-challenge-program&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;A Strength Factor Challenge game (SFC) is an unsanctioned game that a lower-ranked charter team (Challenging Team) schedules versus a higher-ranked charter team (Opponent Team) in order to attempt to temporarily increase their strength factor. If they are successful with their challenge, the Challenging Team will be assigned a higher strength factor for a limited time (4 months), while there is no effect on the Opponent Team. A team can lose an SFC game and still be successful in their challenge. To prevent over-use, each team is only allowed to challenge another once every 12 months&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The benefit to the Challenging Team is indirect. Having a higher and more reflective strength factor of their skill level will make a Challenging Team a more attractive opponent for subsequent sanctioned game play. Potential future opponents who would not have sanctioned games solely because the Challenging Team’s strength factor was too low, are more likely to schedule a game with the boosted strength factor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Challenging Teams must choose their SFC strategy wisely. An SFC game alone will not impact the Challenging Team’s rank: a team’s rank is purely based on successful sanctioned game results against more attractively ranked teams in the months in which the boosted strength factor is active.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Note: the Opponent team gets zero rankings effect from the SFC Game, they do this purely from the goodness of their own heart, but will benefit in the long run from having another team to play sanctioned games against in the future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Example:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Are you an under-ranked team? You’re rank 200, but can give a rank team 100 a real run for their money but they never want to play against you? Then SFCs are for you!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;If you perform well in a SFC game against the rank 100 Opponent, then you will be granted a several-months-long boost to your strength factor, which will mean that anyone who plays against you in that time will get all the rankings benefits of playing against a team much-higher-ranked than your current rank. Suddenly everyone will want to play against you and you can finally get your sanctioned games against the rank 100s, or maybe even better!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;And if you fail your SFC game, well, you don’t get the boost and you can try again next year.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Should My Team Try It?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Probably, yes! There are roughly 60 WFTDA leagues in Europe spanning the full range of rankings all the way up to rank 350, and there have been only 3 SFC game in Europe in the last 2 years. That’s far too little (remember that every team is allowed to SFC once every 12 months)! Many people know at least one example where a team has been unable to find a suitable sanctioned game against a good opponent because they’re “too lowly ranked”, especially when the teams involved are aiming for Continental Cups or WFTDA Playoffs, and this issue is exactly what the SFC game is designed to solve.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;For more evidence, let’s have a look at the top 25 teams in the FTS-Euro* (Flat Track Stats European rankings system&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/europe"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;http://flattrackstats.com/europe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;). Pictured below is a snapshot of the FTS-Euro rankings compared with the WFTDA rankings from October 18th, just before the Continental Cup.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27688" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/screen-shot-2018-10-31-at-19-48-17.png?w=1024" alt="FTS-Euro versus WFTDA Rank (Oct 2018)" width="1024" height="879"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;From this picture we can see that there are a number of teams that appear to be significantly under-ranked in the WFTDA rankings. For example, FTS believes that a game between Antwerp and Tiger Bay could be very close, but the current WFTDA rankings difference is so great (112th to 49th) that this game will almost never get sanctioned without costing Tiger Bay greatly in the WFTDA rankings. However, if Antwerp were to have a SFC game against Tiger Bay (or, for example, Dock City), they could have a good enough game to grant them a much higher strength factor, that then makes them very enticing for all of this year’s Continental Cup teams to play sanctioned games against. Why, with a few well-planned SFC games I can easily imagine the number of European teams in the top 100 growing from 18 to 25+ during 2019!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;For those who really like their charts, here’s another one showing the comparison between FTS-Euro rankings and WFTDA rankings, which should demonstrate that there are a number of European teams that are clearly under-ranked (and perhaps even some that are over-ranked):&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27689" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/screen-shot-2018-10-31-at-19-50-54.png?w=1024" alt="Graph of WFTDA Rank v FTS-Euro Rank" width="1024" height="609"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Summary:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;There are a number of under-ranked teams in Europe, and the WFTDA Rankings Algorithm makes it very hard for these teams to find their appropriate ranking without using SFC games. There’s also very few SFC games taking place in Europe at all, (probably because it’s not a heavily-advertised programme). Having more SFC games in Europe will improve the rankings of a lot of teams, and is recommended particularly for anyone who is aiming to get into the Continental Cups and WFTDA Playoffs. One can also use alternate rankings systems like FTS (or SRDRank &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html&lt;/a&gt;) to help find suitable opponents for SFC games.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;*Note: The FTS rankings algorithm is different from the WFTDA rankings algorithm, and the FTS-Euro uses a different set of data (all recorded Sanctioned &amp;amp; Regulation games between European teams). Because of this, one much always be careful when making comparisons between FTS and WFTDA rankings. I’m gonna do it anyway, but take my analysis with a pinch of salt ;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>guest articles</category><category>rankings</category><category>statistics</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/09/guest-article-strength-factor-challenges-for-europeans/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 09:58:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Europe's First Continental Cup: the UK's next International Derby fixture in 2018</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/04/europes-first-continental-cup-the-uks-next-international-derby-fixture-in-2018/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By any account, 2018 has been a very good year for Roller Derby's international profile, in both Europe and the UK. From the third Roller Derby World Cup in Manchester this February, and the third Men's Roller Derby World Cup in Barcelona a few months later, we've gone on to host an MRDA Playoffs, in Halifax/hosted by Manchester Roller Derby, and a WFTDA Playoffs, in A Coruña.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pendulum is, inevitably, swinging back again from Spain to the UK, with the last event in this sequence: the first ever &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wftdaecc2018.com/"&gt;European WFTDA Continental Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, bringing up the rear in this inaugural year for the new format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the MRDA Playoffs (hosted by Manchester, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; Halifax), this is hosted by Birmingham Blitz Dames, but physically &lt;i&gt;located&lt;/i&gt; in Telford... but the hosts have done a lot to make the brand of the tournament their own. The distinctive diamond logo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-27531 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/blitzdamesdiamon.png" alt="BlitzDamesDiamon" width="245" height="240"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;has both a general connection to Birmingham's jewellery industry, and to the Blitz Dames themselves - and even references their ex-skater, goldsmith Isabella Day, who made the trophy for the tournament!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27532" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/10/continental_map_logos.png" alt="Continental_map_logos" width="1562" height="1070"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Continental Cups framework is a response to the increasing spread of Roller Derby, and particularly the increasingly global membership of WFTDA. With more than 400 member leagues, an ever decreasing fraction of travel teams can hope to compete in a WFTDA Playoffs (and travel costs become increasingly prohibitive if you just extend the cut-off for Playoffs, or extend the old Division 2). &lt;i&gt;Regional&lt;/i&gt; "Continental Cups" provide a WFTDA-certified tournament, for every region with enough teams, at a level just below that of Playoffs - but with much less travel costs. (Next year, there will also be a set of regional "Development Cups", providing a WFTDA-certified tournament option for regions who aren't competitive at the old "D2" level, with guest "seed" teams from more "connected" regions to help improve ranking accuracy.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe's Continental Cup, then, has a familiar set of teams (and countries) represented (order from WFTDA announcement):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Kallio Rolling Rainbow (Finland)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dublin Roller Derby (Ireland)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dock City Rollers (Sweden)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers (Wales)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Central City Roller Derby (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls (England)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby (England)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
The current FTS Europe rankings (which include a different subset of games to WFTDA rankings; excluding games against teams outside Europe, but including unsanctioned games) disagree somewhat with this ordering - FTS thinks that some of these teams were strong enough to make Playoffs ahead of some of the European representation there! - but predict a rather close set of games, regardless. In fact, FTS currently rates the two "local" teams - hosts Birmingham Blitz Dames, and Central City Roller Derby - as being exceptionally close in strength - sadly, the bracket prevents them from meeting unless they both lose their first games, or meet in the final.
Similarly, FTS expects some surprisingly close matches in the first round of the elimination bracket, despite WFTDA's usual slaughter pairing setup: Kallio versus Middlesbrough should be a near-draw by European data; although WFTDA sanctioned ratings place Kallio much higher than the UK team. If you're playing the Bracket Challenge for this contest, that's your best chance for an early upset...
&lt;p&gt;Despite, or perhaps causing, of the possibility of so many upsets and ranking disparities, the European Continental Cup should continue the example of the two North American CCs, in having a higher than "usual" number of close bouts, despite the tendency of elimination tournaments to start with a round of blowouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bracket is available here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.wixstatic.com/ugd/590519_be81975ec1304fcf96b32590ddbe2d8a.pdf"&gt;BRACKET PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (note for those not in the UK - this event is on the weekend that the UK changes over from Daylight Savings Time, so be careful checking timings for the Sunday, in particular).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-27324" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/officials_eur_map.png?w=2048" alt="Officials_EUR_map" width="1024" height="768"&gt; Geographical distribution of European Officials at the ECC! Stars may represent more than one official from a given location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as for the competition, the Continental Cup is also a great chance for more representation for our highly skilled European Officiating community. Just at the Tournament and Crew Head levels, we have officials from Karlsruhe, Newcastle, Dublin, Nottingham, Paris/Lutece, London/Southern Discomfort, (and Michigan...) - including all of the other crew positions adds (deep breath) Amsterdam, Antwerp, Bath, Belfast, Birmingham, Brussels, Cambridge, Cardiff, Chelmsford, Copenhagen, Darmstadt, Devon, Dresden, Dundee, Essex, Falkirk, Frankfurt, Gothenburg, Kallio/Helsinki, Manchester, Metz, Mons, Nantes, Northampton, Oxford, Riems, Ruhrpott, Southend, Southampton, Vicenza, Vienna, Wiltshire, Wuppertal,  (and Rochester, NY; Monterrey County, CA; St Louis, MO; Boston, MA; USA... and Adelaide, SA, Australia)! Just as with the other international events in Europe this year, this kind of exposure, and opportunity to both officiate at a high level, and meet up with a wider-flung segment of the Derby Community is fantastic for Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not all, as there's also fantastic line-up of (mostly...) European announcers, from Head Announcer Biertrix (Rainy City Roller Derby), through a host of UK announcers from London through Manchester to Durham and Newcastle; and from Germany, Denmark, as well as the USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, as with all WFTDA post-season events this year, there will be a genuine chance for all members of the community (WFTDA-members or no) to connect with WFTDA Membership via the co-hosted "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/772801099579539/"&gt;WFTDA World Summit Satellite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" event. We're very impressed by WFTDA's increased commitment to listening to the voices of the whole community, and would encourage the community to also make use of these opportunities in return: listening should be rewarded with dialogue. (On that note, WFTDA are also surveying every league which does derby and are not WFTDA-members - regardless of their gender policy etc - and we'd encourage everyone eligible to respond to this too, here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.org/surveys"&gt;WFTDA.org/surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The European Continental Cup will run from &lt;strong&gt;October 27th to October 28th&lt;/strong&gt; at The International Centre, Telford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WFTDA Continental Cup page: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/events/wftda-continental-cups/"&gt;https://wftda.com/events/wftda-continental-cups/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Facebook Event for European Continental Cup: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/130422437830313/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>birmingham blitz dames</category><category>central city roller derby</category><category>continental cup</category><category>dock city rollers</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>kallio rolling rainbow</category><category>middlesbrough roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>tournament</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/04/europes-first-continental-cup-the-uks-next-international-derby-fixture-in-2018/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 15:54:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EuroClash 2018: Newcastle Roller Girls' tournament expands beyond the "Euro".</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/26/euroclash-2018-newcastle-roller-girls-tournament-expands-beyond-the-euro/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Readers of the blog will remember our coverage of Newcastle Roller Girls' first European Tournament, &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/365884340424845/"&gt;EuroClash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, back in 2017. Newcastle's first WFTDA Recognised Tournament brought together teams across Europe for some high level action, and prefigured performances as far ahead as WFTDA Playoffs; as well as presenting a sneak peak at two of the National teams (Scotland and Ireland) as they worked towards the 3rd Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the ridiculously tournament-filled start of this year has delayed us, we're also going to be bringing you as much coverage as we can of the return of EuroClash this year... although, given one of the attendees this time, the tournament has already outgrown its name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this initial article, we're just going to introduce you to the competitors, and their current placements in the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst 2018's edition is slightly smaller than 2017's - 9 attendees (6 returning from last time), rather than 11 - their geographic distribution is &lt;em&gt;substantially&lt;/em&gt; wider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning from 2017's inaugural event are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls (hosts)
Auld Reekie Roller Girls (soon to &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/25/auld-reekies-10-anniversary-rebrand-with-your-help/"&gt;rebrand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; to Auld Reekie Roller Derby) [Edinburgh]
Central City Roller Derby (competed last year as Central City Rollergirls) [Birmingham]
Dublin Roller Derby
Middlesbrough Roller Derby (EuroClash2017 was their first fixture after rebranding)
Tiger Bay Brawlers [Cardiff]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joining them to make up the full nine are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames
Dock City Roller Derby [Gothenburg]
Steel City Roller Derby [Pittsburgh]!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-26639" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/euroclash2018.png?w=2048" alt="EuroClash2018" width="1024" height="768"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, EuroClash served as the first step for several of the attending teams' campaigns to get into WFTDA Playoffs - Auld Reekie, Bear City, Paris and Dublin all gaining valuable ranking points from their attendance, as all bouts are WFTDA Sanctioned games.
Whilst EuroClash itself is not arranged to provide a final ranking, or a tournament cup, we did analyse the tournament itself &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/30/euroclash-tomodachi-and-quad-wars-three-tournaments-one-weekend-stats/"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Our analysis was good enough to predict the results of Paris Rollergirls' subsequent two games against other attendees, so it's probably as good as any other attempt at rating the teams...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since last year, the returning teams have played a lot of Roller Derby, with varying stories; so we can expect some changes in the matchups this time around. [We're using the FTS "WFTDA" ratings here, as not all the teams can be rated with the usually-more-accurate Europe ratings.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the time of writing, the attending EuroClash 2018 teams span a 41 position zone within FTS's rankings - but a fairly closely rated one. (FTS's built in predictor tool expects only a 2:1 score ratio between the highest rated - Dublin - and lowest rated - Auld Reekie - teams if they played today.) We've also included, in parenthesis, the WFTDA Official ratings and rankings for the teams - despite the different ordering, the "range" in strengths is about the same for WFTDA's own ratings, perhaps slightly larger.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="3" rowspan="1"&gt;FTS "WFTDA" Ratings 23 April 2018 (WFTDA Rating 31 March)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rank&lt;/strong&gt; (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Name&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;Rating (Official WFTDA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;53&lt;/strong&gt; (46)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7775/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dublin Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;745.2 (391.51)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;62&lt;/strong&gt; (65)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/29732/rankings/wftda"&gt;Dock City Rollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;732.4 (318.9)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;63&lt;/strong&gt; (68)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7948/rankings/wftda"&gt;Middlesbrough Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;729.4 (307.57)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;70&lt;/strong&gt; (94)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7763/rankings/wftda"&gt;Central City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;713.3 (242.58)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;83&lt;/strong&gt; (62)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7949/rankings/wftda"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;691.7 (323.67)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;86&lt;/strong&gt; (95)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/3417/rankings/wftda"&gt;Steel City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;683.0 (241.15)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;88&lt;/strong&gt; (88)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7736/rankings/wftda"&gt;Birmingham Blitz Dames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;682.2 (259.63)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;93&lt;/strong&gt; (85)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/7953/rankings/wftda"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;676.0 (262.62)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;94&lt;/strong&gt; (87)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/teams/5912/rankings/wftda"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;" colspan="1" rowspan="1"&gt;674.9 (259.86)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
Auld Reekie and Middlesbrough both suffered ratings reductions against 2x4 Roller Derby during the latter's Jan-Feb tour of Europe, where the Argentine team outperformed expectations against almost &lt;i&gt;everyone&lt;/i&gt;. The jury is out as to how much of this is due to 2x4's general under-ranking, and how much is due to over-ranking of the teams they played - in general, we'd expect better-than-ranking performances from both teams at EuroClash.
Middlesbrough could potentially surprise the current #1 seeds, Dublin; the gap between their WFTDA ratings is entirely due to that loss to the under-ranked 2x4, and their European rating, by comparison, places them above the Irish team (and only just below Paris)!
Similarly, Auld Reekie's European rating places them in the middle of the field, rather than at the bottom, although their trajectory is in the same direction - however, some of this is due to their bout against Leeds Roller Derby, who are almost certainly under-ranked at this point in the year.
&lt;p&gt;Hosts Newcastle have also had difficult bouts, against EuroClash 2017 returnees Central City Roller Derby - given CCR's stronger-than-previous performance against other recent opponents, we consider this to be more of a reflection on CCR than Newcastle - and Leeds Roller Derby (who, again, are simply improving themselves, as they knit together as a team after their first year). We suspect Newcastle are somewhat underranked due to their choice of opponents, and as the hosts they'll be wanting to show that at EuroClash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remaining steady, Tiger Bay Brawlers have still had a pretty good year - and even their recent loss to Central City is not a bad sign, as their performance was near identical to that at EuroClash 2017; if CCR show signs of being back on the up, then this is actually good for the Cardiff team too. The recent transfer of Kid Block back to TBB from London can only improve their strength further - we expect strong performances from the team, beyond what their current rating implies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dublin Roller Derby have also had a pretty good 2017, continuing their upward trend in the FTS European ratings, and remaining steady in the WFTDA rating. Their current placement at the top of EuroClash 2018's rankings seems solid, barring improvements from Dock City, or Middlesbrough. This could all change this weekend, however, as Dublin play some competitive sanctioned games over in the USA at Southern Discomfort 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also remaining steady for the past year, Steel City Roller Derby - after losing around 100 rating points in 2016, the team had a very stable 2017, sticking around the 680-690 rating they still reside at entering EuroClash. A return to their 2016 high would make them easily the strongest team in the tournament, but we suspect their middle-table ranking is more likely, especially given the effects of trans-Atlantic travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gothenburg's second league, Dock City Rollers, continued their generally upwards climb over 2017 (and 2016), and show no particular signs of stopping this progress in WFTDA bouts. They're one of two teams which could challenge expected #1, Dublin if they play against them. Looking at the more plentiful data in the European FTS rankings, they've suffered a "correction" to their ranking as a result of their performance in last year's Swedish national tournament, but their trend is still upward - if we believe the European values, however, they'll be better matched against Auld Reekie than Dublin's finest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representing Birmingham, we have both Birmingham Blitz Dames and Central City Roller Derby, and both seeing upwards movement in the rankings over the past year - Central City in the past month or two, and BBD earlier in 2017 - although the more detailed European ratings show signs of a correction in the Blitz Dames rating at the start of this year, albeit again against the probably-underranked Leeds Roller Derby.  We'll see if the Blitz Dames still have more rating gains to come in the WFTDA rating, as they play in the 2018 K Town Shakedown this weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be back with some more articles, and a guide to the schedule when its published, closer to the event...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.euro-clash.com/"&gt;EuroClash 2018&lt;/a&gt; will be hosted at the &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/6NHQpKxP5Em"&gt;Walker Activity Dome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; on the &lt;b&gt;19th&lt;/b&gt; and&lt;b&gt; 20th May&lt;/b&gt; 2018 - less than a month away! Tickets are on sale, for &lt;b&gt;£30&lt;/b&gt; in advance (£35 on the door), or at a limited special group discount price of&lt;b&gt; £100 for 4&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>birmingham blitz dames</category><category>central city roller derby</category><category>central city rollergirls</category><category>dock city rollers</category><category>dublin roller derby</category><category>euroclash</category><category>middlesbrough roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>steel city roller derby</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/26/euroclash-2018-newcastle-roller-girls-tournament-expands-beyond-the-euro/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 13:04:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Vanishing History of Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Whilst we've been concerned by archiving the history of roller derby for several years, this particular article was inspired by the following threads on twitter: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thederbyapex/status/971562257518821376"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://twitter.com/thederbyapex/status/971562257518821376&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Nicktroptopolis/status/971840386011410432"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://twitter.com/Nicktroptopolis/status/971840386011410432&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern Roller Derby is a product of, and inescapably shaped by, the Internet, as is much of culture produced since the mid-1990s. Whilst this has positive effects, it also can have profoundly negative ones, especially regarding the transient and ephemeral nature of our cultural records and history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of time, records have been made with physical marks (scratches in clay, ink on paper, papyrus or animal skin, and so on; or even the physical structure of vinyl records or CDs), and mostly permanently. Secret physical records are kept secret by locking them in a safe, rarely by encrypting or enciphering them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As information technology became more prevalent, over the 20th century, and predominant over the early 21st, more and more of our records - which are our history for future generations (or even ourselves a few years later) - have no physical, human-readable representation. Documents, and photos, and forum posts, are patterns of bytes on a server which we often don't even own, or have direct access to. &lt;em&gt;Secret&lt;/em&gt; documents are encrypted patterns of bytes on a server we don't own, and are completely unreadable if the key to decrypt them is lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, it is now much harder to maintain a historical record of the recent past - the recent culture - than it was even two decades ago. This worrying phenomenon is sometimes referred to as a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_dark_age"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Dark Age&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; , and we should be more concerned about it than we are. In previous periods, some level of archiving and historical preservation happened "for free" - if you don't deliberately destroy a piece of paper, it will last a fairly long time. In the modern period, records from that old forum your league had before you updated are &lt;em&gt;gone forever&lt;/em&gt; unless you deliberately copied them and saved them elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller Derby's entire modern culture is stored mostly on electronic documents - there are very few physical artefacts, outside of bout programmes, to cover the history of the sport. (It's also important to preserve those physical artefacts - and projects like the UK-based &lt;a href="http://nmrd.org.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Museum of Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are working on that.)
We currently have volunteer-run operations preserving some statistical records, for example, &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an open repository of all the bout scores, and bout stats, uploaded to it, and this is a &lt;em&gt;more important&lt;/em&gt; social and cultural role than the ratings and rankings it produces for subsets of those stats. However, these are both volunteer-run, and patchy in their coverage: for various reasons&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/#footnotes"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, much of Latin America ignores FTS and does not upload their records there, so we don't even have a good historical record for &lt;em&gt;games&lt;/em&gt; in Latin America (Mexico maintains its own website for game results, which does not sync with FTS, for some reason).
Similarly, &lt;a href="http://derbylisting.com/word/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derbylisting.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; attempts to record the status of leagues across the world, but is also very much dependant on engagement by leagues and the community itself. (And it's not clear to us how well it records historical changes.) There are also several other sites which have tried/are trying to do a similar thing - &lt;a href="https://derbyposition.com/en/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;derbyposition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, for example, and fragmentation of effort here makes things much harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/2/"&gt;In the next page, we'll talk about the harder problem of recording our shared cultural heritage - the stories of Roller Derby.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="footnotes"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;*The most important reasons being lack of volunteer effort in some regions, because:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;FTS still talks about, and displays, mostly WFTDA branding on itself, even though it takes records from all flat-track derby, not just WFTDA-member, or even WFTDA-rules, leagues (the MRDA branding, which it also has, is not visible on the front page - and &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; WFTDA is actually mentioned in the site's description of itself). Several leagues we've talked to in the past were under the impression that they simply couldn't use FTS if they weren't WFTDA members, or if they were, they couldn't use it for anything but their A teams.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;FTS doesn't have a rating or ranking scheme for Latin America. FTS's popularity in Europe is driven by (ironically, in contrast to the above) the fact that it provides a ranking and rating for all European teams, regardless of their WFTDA membership or if they're an A or B (or even C) team. This is the carrot part of the FTS system, and it simply doesn't exist (officially) for Latin America.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
 Strictly, it does, as &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRank.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SRDRank&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a rating and ranking system for the entire world, using FTS's records; but we're not anywhere near as visible as FTS, and we are acutely aware that the SRDRank site needs updates after resources devoted to it were diverted to the Roller Derby World Cup for several months. Lack of resources is a problem everywhere, sadly.
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Recording Culture and Stories&lt;/h3&gt;
Statistics are easy to record.The situation for more complex cultural records - forum posts, discussion threads, the entire contents of online magazines or journals - is both more subtle, and also more difficult to resolve. Members of the Roller Derby community who joined post-2014 may not even recognise the name "DNN" -&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.derbynews.net/"&gt;Derby News Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, but that titan of Roller Derby reporting and bout streaming was a central part of the Roller Derby community for the seven whole years - almost two fifths of the entire time Roller Derby has existed - before it died. We're extremely &lt;em&gt;lucky&lt;/em&gt; that the owners, and community, came together to keep the servers holding the site running - albeit with reduced resources - and to archive its valuable historical records. Because of this effort, we can still, for example, look back at &lt;a href="http://www.derbynews.net/2008/09/09/5_texas_stops_9_detroit_83_46/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;how Texas fared against Detroit back in 2008&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (and their rosters at the time!).
&lt;p&gt;For public sites, there is at least the hope that you can pretend it's someone else's problem - the &lt;a href="https://archive.org/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; exists explicitly to combat the loss of history due to the ephemeral nature of websites by trawling the web and taking archival, historical snapshots of sites it can access. This isn't perfect: the Archive can't check every site every day - or even every site every year; and it tries to focus on the websites with the most interest and links, as they're likely to be the most important. But it does give a certain minimum insurance against total loss - something, albeit possibly a tiny fragment, will possibly survive, even if you don't care to take precautions yourself.
When the next site with a huge chunk of Roller Derby culture dies - and &lt;a href="https://indieweb.org/site-deaths"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sites die all the time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - we may not be so lucky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're taking some steps to combat this, starting with a small thing today: we're working on an archive, to be public, of Roller Derby collective culture - the stories that make up the history of the sport from 2001 onwards - collected from the community itself. You can submit your stories to our Google forms - we have &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeFg0uCe1GrSUdv-2VrRU4Sczv_NhIygRZg3UwjjM-AxvIJKQ/viewform?usp=sf_link"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;one version in English&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeRppNu4hkwlRzofmcD_stFmuYzgM9-ZNW1jK_GWulDzPgagA/viewform?usp=sf_link"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;one in Spanish&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for more accessibility - in any language you want, and about any event in roller derby you can relate. (We're especially interested in making sure we get stories from the early days of the sport before they are lost, and from regions and leagues who aren't often covered... but all stories are welcome.)
In the near future, we'll be talking about how we'll make this archive available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/3/"&gt;In the next page, we'll talk about the issues recording the history of Roller Derby's governance.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Recording Our Sport's Governance &amp;amp; Transparency&lt;/h3&gt;
Much of the existing Roller Derby cultural history isn't even public - it's in private silos across the internet. The majority of governing bodies in Roller Derby maintain almost entirely private spaces, as do the majority of leagues. (Even when those spaces are not private, the use of restrictive copyright may also inhibit preservation - as several digital archiving projects have discovered; this is another reason why using better, more open licenses - &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or otherwise - enriches the community.)
We can trust that WFTDA, or MRDA, say, keeps a full and complete backup of all of their forum discussions. But we &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to trust, because we have no way to have an independent record of any of that contents - both because of technological walls (the forums are private, password-protected spaces), and legal ones (the WFTDA, etc, NDAs prevent public disclosure of those contents by anyone who does have access to them).
This is not to pick on WFTDA alone, as we're hopeful is clear - all Roller Derby governing bodies have this problem to various extents, even when they've committed to more open and transparent communication. For example, UKRDA has made some positive steps towards this - making minutes of Board Meetings &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1387CqPTaHx_dp1JAgoxSrHlnrbC45aBj"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;public&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - and have shown interest in working towards further transparency, but they're still working &lt;em&gt;towards&lt;/em&gt; them.
&lt;p&gt;We should note that problems of transparency have dogged many Sports Governing Bodies in the last few years - and &lt;a href="http://www.playthegame.org/news/comments/2016/034_the-rules-of-the-game-the-need-for-transparency-in-sports-governance/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;there are calls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a href="http://www.playthegame.org/knowledge-bank/downloads/sports-governance-observer-2015/c14e0343-6716-42b5-9aa0-a6c700daeb48"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reports&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) from those in the wider sports governance community for all SGBs to become as transparent as other democracies already are. WFTDA&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/#footnotes2"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; does do better than a great many SGBs; but some SGBs are particularly opaque (FIFA comes to mind).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transparency is sometimes hard, but it doesn't have to be this way. The British Government, which has not been an exemplar for good transparency over most of its existence, still manages to publish and archive a &lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;completely public record&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of all debates in Parliament&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/#footnotes3"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, since around 1800. This &lt;em&gt;Hansard&lt;/em&gt; system is also used by many other democracies across the World - New Zealand, Canada, Australia, South Africa, Singapore - and other similar systems are used by, for example, the &lt;a href="https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;United States of America &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;(in fact, the Constitution of the USA &lt;em&gt;requires&lt;/em&gt; that Congress keep such public records), and the &lt;a href="http://www.europarl.europa.eu/plenary/en/home.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;European Parliament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
In all of these cases, these records required a lot of effort to generate - they're hand-stenotyped transcriptions of verbal debates, with post-editing for readability and references - but because they exist, we know much more about the history of those institutions, their culture, and how this changed over time. (And because they're almost all public, copyright-free records, other copies can be made of them, so the risk of them being lost to the world is negligible.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, almost all of the debate in Roller Derby happens online, in text conversations on forums and chat rooms. Making available an "MRDA Hansard", or a "WFTDA Congressional Record" is almost trivial - the data already exists in written form, it just needs to be published somewhere, and with the correct level of access for the community. (We'd argue that if national governments can manage to make their debates Public to the World, it shouldn't be a big deal for any Governing Body of a sport whose founding ethic is "For The Skater, By The Skater").&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is obviously a trade-off here between transparency and the right to privacy. All organisations need private spaces - for grievance committees, embargoed information from other sources, and so on - but they need much fewer private spaces than they often create for themselves. Organisations also need to protect the rights of individuals to privacy of personal information - for example, any organisation in Europe needs to comply with the &lt;a href="https://www.eugdpr.org/gdpr-faqs.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GDPR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on this topic - and this will require some secrecy in some areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also important to note that just because a space is publicly accessible does not mean that it has to be open to public's input - only Members of Parliament may speak in the British House of Commons, but the entire world can see (and hear, nowadays) what they say. In the case of roller derby, Derbylisting.com records around &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1800&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; leagues playing under WFTDA/MRDA rules - even though the majority are not members of either organisation, they do have some moral rights to know what the community has coming for it, in return for the legitimacy they lend the organisations merely by adopting those rules. (Transparency can also be a good way to engage your community in the present, as well as allowing your record to be preserved in the past!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With more of our history and community in the public domain (both visible, and licensed to distribute more rights), maintaining our history becomes a shared possibility for the entire roller derby community.
We at the Scottish Roller Derby blog are also looking a hosting some smaller-scale public resources to help encourage transparency and community - we'll be writing more about the technology side of this in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="footnotes3"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;*The British Government also, since 2000/2002 commits to making a lot more of its internal documents and records available to the public of the world, via the Freedom of Information Acts (&lt;a href="https://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/2000/36/contents"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2000&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - England &amp;amp; Wales, &lt;a href="http://www.legislation.gov.uk/asp/2002/13/contents"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2002&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - Scotland), after consultation started in 1997 ("&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/your-right-to-know-the-governments-proposals-for-a-freedom-of-information-act"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Right To Know&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;"). Many other governments have committed to similar levels of free access to the public - not just their own citizens, but the world; Sweden may hold the record for first raising this issue in 1766!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="footnotes2"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;**WFTDA deserves credit, for example, for the amount of material it does publish, when out of NDA, on officiating the rules; for making its rating calculations completely public (something MRDA does not do, by contrast); for (albeit without a good interface other than sending an email) making bout stats for all Sanctioned Games available to anyone who asks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dnn</category><category>in the news</category><category>international</category><category>international derby</category><category>open</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/09/the-vanishing-history-of-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 11:59:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Ranking Systems - an extension to Papa Whisky</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/14/derby-ranking-systems-an-extension-to-papa-whisky/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, Papa Whisky published an &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@papawhiskey/how-do-rankings-work-1d0a1c5bc5d3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;article on how the WFTDA Ranking system works&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a good introduction to the system, but perhaps missed a few technical points, which we feel are important. In addition, we think it might be useful to introduce other rating systems used in Roller Derby for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article aims to address these two issues, and should be read in concert with the above linked article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, there is some maths. In this maths, we use: &lt;strong&gt;Pu&lt;/strong&gt; to mean "the points scored by your team", &lt;strong&gt;Po&lt;/strong&gt; to mean "the points scored by the opponent", as well as some other values later on.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Other Ranking systems - &lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
While Papa Whisky implies that Flat Track Stats does ranking and rating in a similar way to WFTDA's own official ratings and rankings, in fact the FTS algorithm is somewhat different.
&lt;p&gt;FTS ratings are a variant of &lt;em&gt;Elo ratings&lt;/em&gt; - named for Arpad Elo, who developed them for Chess in the late 1950s. Rather like WFTDA Ratings, FTS Ratings are an indication of how well you should do, but with a different basis - Elo Ratings are logarithmic, like Richter factors for earthquakes, or decibels for sound, so every 400 (or so) difference in Elo Rating is a ten-&lt;em&gt;fold&lt;/em&gt; (or so) factor in expected score &lt;em&gt;ratio&lt;/em&gt;. [FTS probably doesn't use the number 400 exactly.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FTS ratings also update based upon how well you do, versus your expected performance. FTS measures performance in terms of what they call "difference over sum" (DoS) - this is the ratio of the point spread (your points minus their points) to the total points (your points plus their points) in the game:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;(Pu-Po) / (Pu+Po)&lt;/p&gt;
 Essentially, every game you play adds points to your rating, based upon how well you beat the expectation from your relative ratings. (The actual calculation used by FTS is not published, but classical Elo ratings give you a bonus based on the sum of your opponent's rating and a factor proportional to the fraction of the score you got.)
&lt;p&gt;At any given time, a team's FTS Rating is the sum of all of the bonus points they have gotten over the team's entire history. [In fact, most teams will have more than one FTS Rating - FTS maintains multiple ratings; for WFTDA, MRDA, Europe, North America etc - which differ mostly in which games count towards a teams' total points.]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Other Ranking systems - MRDA&lt;/h3&gt;
The MRDA also does not use WFTDA ratings or rankings for their quarterly ratings. In fact, non-members have no knowledge of how the MRDA Rankings are calculated.
&lt;p&gt;This also means we can't say much more about it here, which is extremely problematic.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Other Ranking systems - &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRankv2.html"&gt;SRDRank (v1,2)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
Our own rating system, SRDRank, is the most different in principles to the rating systems here.
&lt;p&gt;Every other rating system works on pairwise comparison - a given game affects only the ratings of the two teams which play, and the rating of Team A will be the sum of all the effects from the games in its history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRDRank is based on global optimisation: every game doesn't just tell us something about the two teams which played, but also something about every other team which has played them recently, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRDRank v1 and v2 perform this calculation in slightly different ways, but in both cases they care about the points ratio:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;Pu/Po&lt;/p&gt;
in any given game. (Technically, we use log(Pu/Po), but that doesn't affect understanding.)
&lt;p&gt;SRDRank v1 models each game as a "spring" between the two teams (which has a natural length proportional to the result of the game) - we run a simulation of the system with all the springs in place, and see where it ends up putting all the teams. The relative positions of the teams as the result of the springs tensioning against each other give their "ratings", and "Rankings".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRDRank v2 uses least-squares linear regression to do the same thing. This is a technique to find the values for a set of unknowns (in this case, the team strengths) which "best fit" the observations (in this case, the ratio of scores in the games played) by minimising the distance between the results in reality, and the results predicted by the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both SRDRank v1 and v2 adjust the importance of games so that older games are less significant than newer ones (by making the springs "weaker", or by allowing more distance with less penalty) - the amount we do so has been optimised itself by analysis of the history of the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRDRank v2 also attempts to detect teams which have changed suddenly in strength (because, say, their roster completely changed at the start of the season), by performing statistical tests on the predictions it makes. Teams which do change suddenly are "split" into a new and an old team, at the point of the change - which means both that the new roster can be given a different rating to the old one; and also that the history of the team doesn't contaminate our predictions for teams which play them in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRDRank v1 and v2 are included in our github repo for prediction code, &lt;a href="https://github.com/aoanla/ranking-chain-inference"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Pros and Cons of Rating Systems - WFTDA&lt;/h3&gt;
In his article, Papa Whisky notes that one of the weaknesses of the WFTDA rating system is that it is currently slightly opaque - the magic "median" value isn't what you'd expect it to be from the published results, because the WFTDA median is calculated from a longer list which is not published.
&lt;p&gt;However, that isn't the real problem with WFTDA ratings - although it is related. To explain their issues, we'll need to do a little bit of simple mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you know from the article, WFTDA ratings award you points for any sanctioned games based on the result of the calculation:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;300 * Pu * So / (Pu+Po)&lt;/p&gt;
where So is the Strength Factor of the opponent. Given that a Strength Factor is just the WFTDA Ranking Points divided by the median Ranking Points, we can write this as
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;300 * Pu * Ro / ( Pu+Po) * Rm&lt;/p&gt;
where Ro is the opponent's ranking points, and Rm is the median of them.
&lt;p&gt;In order to "keep the same rating", a team needs to score equal to its current WFTDA Ranking Points. So, we can write the condition for retaining Rating as:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;300 * Pu * Ro / ( Pu+Po) * Rm = Ru&lt;/p&gt;
This relationship is the source of all of the issues with the WFTDA Rating system.
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, let's rearrange this to give the fraction of points the team needs to score to maintain rating, in terms of everything else:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;Pu/(Pu+Po) = (Ru/Ro) * (Rm/300)&lt;/p&gt;
So, the first thing we notice is that the "fraction of points" you need is proportional to the &lt;em&gt;ratio&lt;/em&gt; of the two teams' WFTDA Ranking Points. This is the source of those "weird results" which Papa Whisky notes for bouts between teams of very different strengths.  In particular, it can mean that there's simply not enough available points for a team to retain its ranking, even if it got 100% of the points.
&lt;p&gt;To see that that's true, let's imagine that our team gets 100% of the points, so Pu/(Pu+Po) is 1. That implies that
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;(Ru/Ro) = (300/Rm)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;Ru = (300/Rm)*Ro&lt;/p&gt;
300/Rm is a bit more than 2 (we'll come back to this later), so our team needs a 100% blowout to break-even against a team with about&lt;em&gt; twice&lt;/em&gt; its Rating. In the example Papa Whisky uses, Gotham had a SF (and thus rating) more than twice that of Windy: there was no possible way for Gotham to benefit from that game, as they would need to score &lt;em&gt;more than 100%&lt;/em&gt; of the points!
&lt;p&gt;The other problem is that teams need to continually beat expectations in order to retain ranking. To see that this is the case, let's assume that the two teams have identical WFTDA Ranking Points, Rx. In that case, the formula gives:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;Pu/(Pu+Po) = (Rx/Rx) * (Rm/300) = Rm/300&lt;/p&gt;
where the final step is straightforward.
If a team plays a team with exactly the same strength as it, we would expect the points to be divided equally, so Pu/(Pu+Po) should be 0.5 ... which implies
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;0.5 = Rm/300  ⇒ Rm = 150&lt;/p&gt;
Of course, Rm does not equal 150 - it's set to the median WFTDA Ranking Points, which is currently around 141.
&lt;p&gt;The result of this is that teams need to &lt;em&gt;beat&lt;/em&gt; their own expectation by about 7% in every game, &lt;em&gt;just to stay where they are&lt;/em&gt;. In a case where two well matched teams perform as expected... not only does the losing team lose ranking, but so does the &lt;em&gt;winning&lt;/em&gt; team. (This does balance out a little, in that it affects all teams, so there's a general "deflation" in scores one month to the next... but it is still counterintuitive.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pro of the WFTDA rating system is that it's very easy to understand, and you can calculate expected scores and so on with just a piece of paper and some mental arithmetic (as long as you know the median Ranking Points). However, with computers ubiquitous nowadays, it is not clear how much of an advantage this is - &lt;a href="https://derbyontoast.com/head-to-head"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DerbyOnToast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (and our own SRDRank visualiser) can both automate ratings calculations for you, so you don't need to be able to do them yourself.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Pros and Cons of Rating Systems - FTS&lt;/h3&gt;
The FTS Rating system has all the problems that Elo systems have in general.
&lt;p&gt;In particular, Elo ratings consider that all results are relevant, even years after they happened. Rating changes only happen as a result of new games being played - so if you don't play any games for a year or two, you'll just keep the same FTS rating regardless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has the counter-intuitive result that it's sometimes better to just not play games, rather than lose rating. (If Gotham had decided not to play any games at Champs or later, they'd still be top of the leaderboard... more strikingly, the Oly Rollers retained a significant FTS rating for several years, despite not entering any scores at all.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related to this, FTS ratings take time to adjust to sudden changes - if a team suddenly becomes much weaker or strong (due to, say, a complete change of roster), it takes quite a lot of games for FTS to catch up, as there's only so much change FTS can accommodate in a single bout. Additionally, while this adjustment is taking place, all of the opponents have unfair rating changes - FTS changes are symmetric, so for team A to gain rating, team B must lose rating, even if the cause is entirely due to a change in team A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FTS's advantage is that, like WFTDA Ratings, FTS ratings are quick and easy to calculate. So quick, in fact, that FTS recalculates all of its ratings at least once an hour, to guarantee that predictions are as up to date as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FTS also does not suffer from either of the problems of WFTDA Rankings - there is no combination of teams for which either team "can't win".
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Pros and Cons of Rating Systems - SRDRank&lt;/h3&gt;
SRDRank, being a different class of rating system to the other two, has entirely different issues.
&lt;p&gt;SRDRank's main issue is its relative complexity. Whilst least-squares regression, and statistical tests, are no more advanced than first year undergraduate level, this is still a significant increase in complexity over the other two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SRDRank's other issue stems from the global nature of its calculation. As with FTS, an undetected sudden change in team strength can cause unwanted effects in the ratings of other teams. As SRDRank is a globally optimised rating, this effect can make (small) changes in rating even for teams which never play the team in question. We attempt to minimise this effect via the statistical test and splitting step, but there will always been a short period where there's not enough evidence to detect a sudden change, and where ratings will be somewhat affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, SRDRank is limited by the depth and quality of information available to it. Because it uses FTS's own records as a data source, it can only use information that FTS consider relevant. Because of this, there a several uncontrolled sources of error which reduce SRDRank's accuracy - we don't always know if there's a "home" team, as FTS doesn't track the host of a bout, and assumes that one team must be a "home" team regardless - and for tournaments, FTS is poor at assigning hosts for tournament type events which run over many fixtures; we don't know the length of a bout (which affects the reliability of a rating); we don't know rosters for most games (because most bouts don't upload statsbooks), so we can't model expectations based on players who are missing or present - and so on.
We also, of course, as with all rating systems, can't rate teams for whom there is no information at all. If your team doesn't upload stats or scores to FTS, then FTS and SRDRank can't rate you. Historically, this has affected Mexico and Latin America as whole more than most other reasons, which is extremely problematic, as it also decreases visibility of the fantastic amount of derby happening in those areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In comparison, SRDRank can rank and rate the entire world's roller derby teams, not just subsets of them. It also allows detection of cliques within the community - groups of teams which play each other more than others, and thus are better rated relative to other members of the group than the outside world - and selection of ratings based on geographical location.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
Knowing a bit about possibilities for rating systems is important in judging how to use them (and which ones are good at which things).
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in gaming your WFTDA rating, it's best to avoid playing teams with less than 70% of your rating (to avoid matchings where you simply can't score enough to improve your rating, regardless of what you do); and preferably play teams closer in rank to you, but who you think you can beat by more than 10% of the score...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>flat track stats</category><category>mrda</category><category>srd rank</category><category>statistics</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/14/derby-ranking-systems-an-extension-to-papa-whisky/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 12:21:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WFTDA Membership Status for DRG</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/28/wftda-membership-status-for-drg/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you may have heard last week, the Women's Flat Track Derby Association (WFTDA) has extended full membership status to nine graduating leagues after completion of the WFTDA apprenticeship program! The full list of new members can be found in the press release &lt;a href="https://wftda.com/wftda-adds-9-new-members/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leagues announced included members from across the United States, South America and more in line with our reporting: Europe! On the back of four skaters making the Team Scotland squad; Dundee Roller Girls becomes only the third league in Scotland to receive this graduated status!  Interestingly enough, Tenerife Roller Derby, the hosts of the &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/12/15/tenerife-roller-derby-bringing-the-heat-to-winter-tournaments/" target="_blank"&gt;December tournament &lt;/a&gt;that featured the Dundee side, have also graduated to full WFTDA membership!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are currently&lt;i&gt; (as of March 2017) &lt;/i&gt;399 WFTDA member leagues and 54 leagues in the WFTDA Apprentice program globally. Leagues joining these ranks enjoy benefits including the ability to compete in sanctioned games, discussions with other member leagues and access to learning resources for skaters and officials. Dundee Roller Girls begin their WFTDA membership a Class C member and we caught up with the leagues co chairs, &lt;strong&gt;Laura Liston #07&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Crown Jewels #67&lt;/strong&gt;, for a chance to learn a bit the history of DRG and what the future holds for this up and coming league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="16584,16583" type="circle" columns="2"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Q: Hi guys! So WFTDA full membership, a pretty huge step for a league that was skating in a car park at the back of 2009, eh?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;L: It's huge for us. I still can't quite believe we get to consider ourselves in the ranks of the incredible teams in WFTDA. Everyone has worked really hard over the years to keep our wee league together so this is a lovely reward.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CJ: Ha Ha! Yes a massive leap for us. I think it’s just amazing how we’ve managed to progress, I think most leagues probably started off in a similar fashion, a very much DIY existence. It still is (DIY) today but there is so much more awareness around derby that is does become slightly easier to progress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: So with Dundee Roller Girls forming around 2011, you both have been involved for a long time. How have you seen the league grow in these past few years?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L: For me I think the biggest growth we've seen is when we created our B team and home teams. Giving our newer skaters the opportunity to develop and to get game experience has allowed the whole league to grow - from them getting games to our new officials getting game experience at an appropriate level. So proud of them all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CJ: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;We’ve seen a lot of league members come and go, but there are still a core few that remain. Year on year we’ve continued to build a group of league members that wants to do their best for DRG, whether that’s officiating or skating. I think the drive in people is what pushes the league forward. We have so many committed members that look for the best guest coaches to come to the league, arrange challenging games for us, run the financial side of things and look to push us on to the next level. This is what has allowed the league to grow to where it is now and will continue to do so in future. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;i&gt;What was the deciding factors for you guys to pursue the WFTDA Apprenticeship program? Was it a hard decision for the league to make since it is quite a lot of work that goes into the full program?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L: It was a lot of work in terms of admin but it made sense as the next step for us. Being so isolated in Scotland, we were finding it hard to find leagues of a similar level who would travel to play us. Joining WFTDA has given us more game opportunities and more varied game offers. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CJ: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;I don’t think it was a hard decision to make, it’s something we have aspired to for a long time and again allows us to push the league forward. The deciding factor was probably looking to get us more involvement in international events, to face and learn from some of the best leagues in the world.
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;i&gt;An interesting point to maybe make here is your discontinued presence in British Championships this year.. Did your decision to pursue WFTDA membership affect your attendance to Brit Champs 2017? A close miss to promotion in 2016, and a great game against Swansea held high promise for your league in the following year?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L: The main factor involved in us leaving British Champs was the organisation as a whole. Having to travel so far to each game meant we needed the organisation to be really clear and far in advance, which it wasn't for us. Our B team was also really disadvantaged by our A team's involvement in Champs as it meant their season was quite limited. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CJ: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;I think partly it did affect our decision to leave champs. We needed to try to make sure we were focusing our energies in one direction and for us, as a league on a whole, that was WFTDA.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: We have already seen your league representing internationally with the aforementioned Tenerife Tournament, are we going to see more of the Dundee crew hitting sights outside of the UK?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;L: Well our officials are now travelling all over Europe for games - Spain, Sweden, Finland and Norway recently. The Colliders are also heading to Ireland this year!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CJ: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;Let’s hope so! My dream is to get to Vienna (my favourite city) after that I may retire! It would be great to get further afield but sometimes finances are a limiting factor in that respect.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Q: Do you have any tips for aspiring leagues, either the new leagues blossoming in Scotland or others wishing to gain WFTDA status?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;!-- I have clearly run out of good Questions.. --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;L: To go for it! WFTDA membership isn't related to wins, or scores etc. It's for leagues who want a say in the future of roller derby. The support we had to develop through Apprenticeship from Auld Reekie, Newcastle Roller Girls and our rep from Hellfire Harlots was amazing.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;CJ: I think mainly consult other leagues for advice. We have always been helped immensely by other leagues in Scotland and across the UK and we are always willing to provide advice to other leagues. Decide on what you want your focus to be and aim for it, find out as much as you can about what you want to achieve and ensure you have committed league members willing to put in the work towards it.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>wftda</category><category>wftda apprenticeship</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/28/wftda-membership-status-for-drg/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 10:00:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The "Dust Devil Cup": An amusement with historical records.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/08/the-dust-devil-cup-an-amusement-with-historical-records/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst the current WFTDA Championships structure provides the opportunity to win the Hydra once a year, commentators have pointed out to us that there's other sports where Championships pass rather more easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, Boxing allows Championship Belts to be won by anyone successfully defeating the holder, at any point in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we thought it might be interesting to see what would have happened to a "Dust Devil Cup" under the same rules; imagine &lt;em&gt;Texas Rollergirls&lt;/em&gt;, winners of the first ever modern Roller Derby tournament, the &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/3475"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dust Devil Cup&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;in &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, passing it on to whoever next defeated them, and on and on up to the present day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, you get a rich and varied look through the history of Roller Derby, like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inaugural Champions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Texas Rollergirls&lt;/strong&gt; 24/2/2006 - 9/12/06
&lt;strong&gt;Tucson Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; 9/12/06 - 18/2/07
&lt;strong&gt;Rat City Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt; 18/2/07 - 28/4/07
&lt;strong&gt;Windy City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt; 28/4/07 - 19/8/07
&lt;strong&gt;Gotham Girls Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; 19/8/07 - 29/9/07
&lt;strong&gt;Kansas City Roller Warriors&lt;/strong&gt; 29/9/07 - 2/12/07
&lt;strong&gt;Carolina Rollergirls&lt;/strong&gt; 2/12/07 - 19/7/08
&lt;strong&gt;Cincinnati Rollergirls&lt;/strong&gt; 19/7/08 - 13/9/08
&lt;strong&gt;Detroit Derby Girls&lt;/strong&gt; 13/9/08 - 11/10/08
&lt;strong&gt;Philly Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; 11/10/08 - 11/10/08
&lt;strong&gt;Gotham Girls Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; 11/10/08 - 14/11/09
&lt;strong&gt;Oly Rollers&lt;/strong&gt; 14/11/09 - 3/10/10
&lt;strong&gt;Rocky Mountain Rollergirls&lt;/strong&gt; 3/10/10 - 4/6/11
&lt;strong&gt;Oly Rollers&lt;/strong&gt; 4/6/11 - 13/11/11
&lt;strong&gt;Gotham Girls Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; 13/11/11 - ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we have a decision to make. If we decide that the "Dust Devil Cup" is only eligible for WFTDA member leagues, then the chain ends with Gotham's first loss at a WFTDA Championships in many years, in 2015:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gotham Girls Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; 13/11/11 - 8/11/15
&lt;strong&gt;Rose City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt; 8/11/15 - 30/4/16
&lt;strong&gt;Victorian Roller Derby League&lt;/strong&gt; 30/4/16 - 5/11/16
&lt;strong&gt;Rose City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt; 5/11/16 -
&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Champions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we embrace all of Roller Derby, however, we remember that Gotham had lost one time before then, in a battle of the Champions held in 2013. In this case, the chain goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gotham Girls Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; 13/11/11 - 6/6/13
&lt;strong&gt;Your Mom Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; 6/6/13 - 18/10/15
&lt;strong&gt;St Louis Gatekeepers&lt;/strong&gt; 18/10/15 - 14/5/16
&lt;strong&gt;Team USA Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; 14/5/16 -
&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Champions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but perhaps having the USA National &lt;em&gt;Men's&lt;/em&gt; team in charge of the Cup is a little too controversial, even for a light amusement like this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both cases, however, there's an other interesting point to be made by this: even allowing any loss at all to count, Gotham's dominance over Roller Derby was genuinely astonishing, compared to the period before (where the Cup would have changed hands at least twice a year), and the new period after (where it has already changed hands twice in the past year). It's also a new period in that teams are actually losing outside of Champs - something which used to be not-unexpected occurrence, but now something which is again no longer quite as surprising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>amusements</category><category>articles</category><category>statistics</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/08/the-dust-devil-cup-an-amusement-with-historical-records/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 15:25:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Creative Commons and For the Skater, By The Skater</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/26/creative-commons-and-for-the-skater-by-the-skater/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the release of WFTDA's new bout stats management / collection project, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/WFTDA/bouttime"&gt;bouttime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (or BoutTime) as "Open Source", we wrote an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/19/bouttime-open-source-what-is-it-and-why-is-it-relevant-to-roller-derby-and-wftda/"&gt;Explainer (linked)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to let the less technical members of the derby community in on why this was exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the points we made was the "Open Source" is essentially the tech world's equivalent of "For the Skater, By the Skater": it's an encapsulation of the community spirit that says we should all collaborate and share to make things better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, far from being a property unique to Roller Derby, this community spirit lives on in many groups. The creative arts community, for example, has a concept and movement called "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/"&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;", formed from the concept that modern restrictive copyright is actively against the spirit of collaboration and improvement of works by the community. Such bodies as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wikipedia.org"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/"&gt;TED Talks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://ocw.mit.edu/"&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brooklynmuseum.org/"&gt;Brooklyn Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (as well as many more: including this very blog) release some or all of their works under Creative Commons. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/"&gt;Flikr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/"&gt;SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and many other content hosts, also recognise Creative Commons, and support their users in adopting these licenses if they wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creative Commons understands that, however, the amount of "sharing" you might want to do can vary, for entirely legitimate reasons. So, if you put something into the Creative Commons, you get to choose from a palette of options concerning what rights you want to give to the world, and which you want to limit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic level of Creative Commons* is &lt;strong&gt;Attribution&lt;/strong&gt; (CC:BY):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Releasing as CC:BY means that you're giving everyone the right to do anything with your work at all (including using bits of it for their own work), &lt;em&gt;as long as they give you credit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
CC:BY is nice, but it lets people make things with your stuff which is not in the Creative Commons itself. You might morally object to this (since the point of Creative Commons is to enrich the community), in which case you want to add the &lt;strong&gt;Share-Alike&lt;/strong&gt; (SA) property:
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Adding SA to your Creative Commons license means that anything that anyone else makes using your work must &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; be released under the same Creative Commons terms.&lt;/p&gt;
You might also have a moral (or legal) objection to people making money off of your work, or things using your work. (For example, American 501c3 non-profits, like WFTDA, can't allow people to use their work for profit.) In this case, you want to add the &lt;strong&gt;Non-Commercial&lt;/strong&gt; (NC) property:
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Adding NC to your Creative Commons license means that anything anyone else does with your work &lt;em&gt;cannot be sold&lt;/em&gt; or used for commercial gain. [Donations etc are of course acceptable]&lt;/p&gt;
Finally, there are some kinds of work which (for practical or moral reasons) that you might want to let people copy and redistribute... but not make anything different out of. (This is generally the most controversial kind of CC limitation, given that Creative Commons wants to enrich the creative community, but it can make sense for, say authoritative rules sets or specifications.) This is what you want the &lt;strong&gt;No-Derivatives&lt;/strong&gt; (ND) property for:
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Adding ND to your Creative Commons license means that all people can do with it is to share it freely (via making copies, printing them out, email, or whatever). [If you don't specify NC as well, they're also allowed to &lt;em&gt;sell&lt;/em&gt; copies, of course.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We at the Scottish Roller Derby Blog believe that the Creative Commons is fundamentally compatible with the core spirit of Roller Derby (as expressed as "For the Skater, By the Skater"), in a way which traditional copyright is not.
Given that WFTDA seems to be realising that the "open sharing" community is a reflection of the same spirit, we'd like to see the organisation take this additional step of applying appropriate Creative Commons licenses to their non-software work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, the "&lt;em&gt;Rules of Flat Track Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt;" are currently explicitly Copyrighted (the license on the website reads: "©2014 Women’s Flat Track Derby Association (WFTDA). The Rules of Flat Track Roller Derby may not be reproduced or translated in whole or in part in any manner without the permission of the WFTDA."). Technically, this means that anyone at all (especially non-WFTDA leagues) who even &lt;em&gt;prints out&lt;/em&gt; a copy of the WFTDA rules (or &lt;em&gt;makes a copy&lt;/em&gt; of the PDF) is potentially breaking the law. (We're also vexed by the explicit translation restriction, as we're aware of unofficial translations to many languages which WFTDA has not officially addressed, and all of these are also potentially forbidden under the current license; although of course we understand WFTDA's concern about the accuracy of translation in complex rules sets.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that, given that a huge community of Roller Derby, outside the set of WFTDA member leagues, use the WFTDA rules, that this kind of heavy-handed Copyright is both unwarranted and unneeded.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Given the options available for Creative Commons licenses, we believe that the true spirit of Roller Derby would be better reflected by releasing the next version of "The Rules of Flat Track Roller Derby" (due in December this year) under a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/"&gt;CC:BY-NC-ND&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; license. This would, unlike conventional Copyright, allow the free sharing of the Rules across the entire community. It would prevent anyone from profiting from doing so, and would prevent anyone from releasing modified copies. (This would also prevent translation of the Rules, but we believe that WFTDA can address that by directly inviting potential translators to engage with them, which we believe is something in progress at the moment.)&lt;/p&gt;
The second aspect where we think that WFTDA might work to improve their use of modern collaborative community spirit is in the reuse and support of common repositories for statistics. Historically, the WFTDA has maintained its own "silo" of statistics for Sanctioned Games, hosted in the WFTDA Stats Repository. Whilst we understand that part of the draw for WFTDA membership is the "official" Sanctioning of games, we don't see how this warrants siloing off their statistics into a separate location.
The FlatTrackStats website has been maintaining Roller Derby statistics for the &lt;em&gt;entire&lt;/em&gt; Flat Track Roller Derby community, for longer (we believe) than WFTDA has had a Stats Repository. (FTS dates from &lt;em&gt;2008&lt;/em&gt;, whereas the Stats Repository copyright is from &lt;em&gt;2012&lt;/em&gt;). In addition, FlatTrackStats is already a member of the Creative Commons community - the entire website, and all of the statistics collected within, are licensed &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/"&gt;CC:BY-NC-SA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Given that the community benefits from the sharing of resources (rather than their splintering apart), and given the existence of a prior community resource suitable for the purpose: we believe that the true spirit of Roller Derby would be better reflected by WFTDA working directly with FlatTrackStats to act as a host for the WFTDA Stats Repository, and that the Stats Repository should therefore be licensed under the same &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/"&gt;CC:BY-NC-SA&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Strictly, there's also CC0 "Creative Commons Zero", which doesn't even have &lt;em&gt;Attribution&lt;/em&gt; attached to it, but this actually has less effect than you might think, as many countries have laws which &lt;em&gt;prevent&lt;/em&gt; you from waiving your right to Attribution! So, effectively, CC0 acts a lot like CC:BY, in most Western countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/" rel="license"&gt;&lt;img style="border-width:0;" src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png" alt="Creative Commons License"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
This work is licensed under a &lt;a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/" rel="license"&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;, because anything else would be hypocritical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>by the skater</category><category>creative commons</category><category>for the skater</category><category>international derby</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/26/creative-commons-and-for-the-skater-by-the-skater/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 08:39:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>European Smackdown - the Statistics</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/08/european-smackdown-the-statistics/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Crime City Rollers' European Smackdown wasn't just a history-making event, bringing WFTDA-sanctioned Division 1 derby to mainland Europe, it was also our first chance to get a look at how those Division 1 teams have changed as the new season starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned in &lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/18/gotham-rose-victorian-a-three-way-tie/"&gt;a previous article&lt;/a&gt;, despite the fact that Euro Smackdown wasn't a true tournament (it was more of an invitational, with teams playing different numbers of bouts, and no attempt at ranking them by performance), the fact that it produced a large number of match-ups means that we can use Bayesian inference techniques to infer what the actual relative power of the participating teams are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start off, lets look at the actual results (versus the predictions from &lt;a href="http://www.flattrackstats.com"&gt;FlatTrackStats&lt;/a&gt;). We don't consider WFTDA Rankings because the ranking scheme that WFTDA uses combines Team Strength with Strength of Schedule (how many "hard" opponents you played), and so does not purely reflect the actual relative strength of teams.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;colgroup&gt; &lt;col width="33%"&gt; &lt;col span="4" width="0*"&gt; &lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#eeeeff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bout&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Score(HT)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Score(FT)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Score Ratio
(HT) FT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FTS Predicted Score Ratio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#ffeeff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;London:Detroit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146:47&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;345:79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; (3.1) 4.3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 6.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#eeffff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Glasgow:Malmö&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;39:257&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;46:536&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; (0.15) 0.09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 0.65&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#ffeeff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;London:Stockholm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;133:31&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;295:49&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(4.2) 6.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 4.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#eeffff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Glasgow:Helsinki&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;43:212&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73:485&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(0.20) 0.31&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 0.85&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#ffeeff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Detroit:Malmö&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;37:130&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;75:233&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; (0.28) 0.32&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 0.875&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#eeeeff"&gt;
&lt;td colspan="5"&gt;DAY 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#eeffff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;London:Glasgow&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;322:3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;526:9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; (100) 58&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 7.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#ffeeff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Malmö:Helsinki&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;79:36&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;176:70&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; (2.2) 2.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 1.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#eeffff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Glasgow:Stockholm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;27:182&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;66:371&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; (0.15) 0.18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 0.59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#ffeeff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Detroit:Helsinki&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;94:73&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;162:216&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; (1.3) 0.75&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 1.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor="#eeffff"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;London:Malmö
&lt;p&gt;(notsanctioned)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;194:33&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;311:98&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(5.9) 3.2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 5.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
What's quite interesting here is that, while FTS was very wrong as to the magnitude of most of the score ratios, it was actually only wrong once as to the result of a bout - calling Detroit/Helsinki for Detroit. This was also the closest bout of the entire tournament - and Detroit was winning, with a score-ratio close to what FTS predicted, at the end of the first period.
&lt;p&gt;Another thing we can see is which games were "games of two halves" - the Detroit/Helsinki, Glasgow/London and London/Malmö games all exhibit very strong shifts between the scores at half-time and full-time - in fact, by almost 50%!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, onto the actual strength calculations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ran 300000 steps of a Bayesian Monte-Carlo simulation on the Euro Smackdown data, with 600 "walkers" per step. This allows us to explore the space of "possible strengths" and determine what the most likely strengths are for each Team competing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As London Roller Girls were overwhelmingly likely to be the strongest team in the tournament, we calculate strengths for the remaining 5 teams relative to London. Strength here is "how many points London would score, in an average game, for every point the team scored". We use FTS ratings as a basis for our comparisons, as WFTDA rankings do not purely reflect the strength of teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6274" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/figure_1-es2.png" alt="figure_1-es2" width="1996" height="1050"&gt; Plot of predicted and inferred Team Strengths (relative to London Roller Girls). Strengths are "approximate number of points London would score, for every point the Team scores")&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This graph shows two sets of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vertical lines indicate how strong FlatTrackStats thought the teams should be, relative to London Roller Girls, before the tournament starts. As FlatTrackStats's ranking algorithm is relatively conservative, this approximates to the performance of the teams at the end of last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The histograms show the distribution of "consistent" team strengths, inferred from the results of European Smackdown. The peaks of the distributions correspond to the most likely strengths for each team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As can be seen, there's two pretty obvious outliers - Crime City Rollers (marked as "Malmo") are significantly stronger than FTS thought they should be; and Glasgow Roller Derby are significantly weaker. The other three teams, Detroit, Helsinki and Stockholm are bunched close enough together that it's hard to separate them in this scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can get a better look at the grouping for lower strength teams if we exclude the London bouts from consideration. One issue with London's strength is that its opponents score lower, meaning that each point is "worth" more in terms of altering their proportional strength. (The difference between a final score of 3 and 4 is a 33% change in your strength!) This makes predictions a bit more fuzzy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6353" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/figure_1-malmo.png" alt="figure_1-malmo" width="1726" height="831"&gt; Inferred strengths for Detroit, Stockholm, Helsinki, Glasgow with respect to Crime City (as Malmo).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above graph is calculated in the same way, but from only the bouts not involving London (and therefore shows strength relative to Crime City, as MALMO). It's a little clearer from this analysis that Detroit is measurably distinct in strength from Stockholm and Helsinki, and Stockholm and Helsinki are almost separable themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another interesting feature of the full analysis, is that, while the outliers are both "far" from their predictions, the set of all strengths is still relatively symmetrically distributed around FTS's predictions. This implies that London themselves haven't significantly altered in strength over the winter - any large shifts in the teams relative to them are due to those teams own strength changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of this analysis suggest that either Crime City Rollers had a significant home-teams advantage, or they're significantly improved (by about 50%) after taking a break over Winter. If the latter is the case, we expect them to be a significant force in Division 1 this year - this performance puts them closer to teams like Montreal or Atlanta!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Glasgow's performance this year seems to have been hit by the departure of several strong pivots from the A-Team Roster, with Mona Rampage, (The Very Hungry) Splat(erkiller), and Jen Sykes all missing from the roster. Conservatively, their performance here is roughly 1/6th as strong as they evidenced in Division 1 tournament in the USA last year. Hopefully, this is simply a consequence of the restructuring early in the season, and the new roster will continue to strengthen and gel over the coming year...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the other teams, Stockholm have slightly fallen back from their high-point last year, possibly following the departure of one of their star jammers, Mad Malooney. (It's tempting to suggest that the slight increase in performance by Helsinki is related, partly, to their gaining the same skater!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recap of the tournament is available from &lt;a href="http://www.derbycentral.net/2016/03/the-european-smackdown-recap/"&gt;Derby Central&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>detroit roller derby</category><category>european smackdown</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>helsinki roller derby</category><category>london rollergirls</category><category>malmo crime city rollers</category><category>statistics</category><category>stockholm roller derby</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/08/european-smackdown-the-statistics/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 17:06:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow at Europe's first WFTDA Division 1 Tournament</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/01/glasgow-at-europes-first-wftda-division-1-tournament/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For several years, one of the rumbling complaints about WFTDA tournaments was that all of the high-level play was confined to the North American continent. If you were a great European, Latin American or Australasian team, you had to incur significant travel costs to really face off against the "big" leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks partly to the signal breakthrough of European teams in WFTDA Division 1 last year, this is all changing. No more obvious sign of this is this weekend's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/551420871678799/"&gt;European Smackdown&lt;/a&gt; - mainland Europe's first ever WFTDA Division 1 Tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6011" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/12661771_1013953921976045_843865028654688318_n.jpg" alt="12661771_1013953921976045_843865028654688318_n" width="960" height="355"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tournament, running all day &lt;strong&gt;March 5th&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;March 6th&lt;/strong&gt; sees many of the European Division 1 leagues: hosts Crime City Rollers (Sweden, WFTDA #25), Glasgow Roller Derby (Scotland, WFTDA #29),  Helsinki Roller Derby (Finland, WFTDA #33), London Rollergirls (England, WFTDA #3) and Stockholm Roller Derby (Sweden, WFTDA #17) face off, joined by Detroit Derby Girls Allstars (USA, WFTDA #20).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tournament structure appears to be an incomplete round-robin&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;, but &lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;'s Irn Bruisers are one of the teams with an almost full set of opponents, scheduled to play every other team except Detroit over the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Irn Bruiser Line-Up Sadie O'Hades talked to us about the team's preparations, "&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;I'm so excited to be doing the line up for the Bruisers this year. Watching the new roster in their training since January has given me the chance to appreciate the individual skill and strength of every member of our team, both returning members and those new this quarter. It's been inspiring for me and I've been upping my game to make sure my dedication matches theirs. We've all been focused on the Malmo tournament as we know its going to be an amazing opportunity to play at the highest level and we can't wait to get over there to compete against the very best that European Roller Derby has to offer. Over the years GRD has developed strong relationships with our fellow European leagues and we will have a great time hanging out with our friends and heroes, but make no mistake - our game faces are on!"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, hosts Crime City Rollers have spent as much time and effort as you might expect to make mainland Europe's first Division 1 Tournament as exciting and professional as possible. Crime City's Katpiss Neverclean told us: "The league are so excited and we've all worked really hard to make this the best tournament possible - and the afterparty will also be amazing  - dancecrew performance, wrestlers, DJs and all you can wish for!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who cannot make it to Malmö for the weekend, Crime City have arranged high-definition streaming of the entire event (excepting the CCR/London bout). This is available at &lt;a href="https://ccr.solidtango.com"&gt;https://ccr.solidtango.com&lt;/a&gt;. This is a paid streaming service, with individual games priced at 79 Swedish Krona (about £6.60 at the present exchange rate) and a discount for the whole weekend at 229 Krona (around £19 - equivalent to about £2 per game).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;Given the structure of the tournament, we are planning to perform a statistical analysis of the results to produce an inferred relative ranking of all the competitors. Stay tuned for the article, hopefully soon after the weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>european smackdown</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>wftda</category><category>wftda division 1</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/01/glasgow-at-europes-first-wftda-division-1-tournament/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 19:41:22 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>