<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about whippin hinnies)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/whippin-hinnies.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 08:59:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Newcastle's Whippin Hinnies update: British Champs T2 and beyond</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/08/01/newcastles-whippin-hinnies-update-british-champs-t2-and-beyond/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Working our way up through the Northern Divisions of British Champs, we've found our way, via Tier 4 and Tier 3, to Tier 2.
Our team for Tier 2 North was &lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.co.uk/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;' B-team, the Whippin Hinnies, who were one of three 3 B-teams added to British Champs this year. (London Rollergirls had led the charge the previous year, with the Brawl Saints competing in Tier 1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13711 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/newcastlerg_1.png" alt="newcastlerg_1" width="122" height="250"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend sees the final fixture in the Division, with Newcastle up against Wirral Roller Derby in &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/104769700121799/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manchester&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. With the Hinnies at the bottom spot currently, with Wirral just one place above them, this should be the closest bout of the tournament for them - SRDRank places them nigh-identically in ranking, whist FTS favours Wirral, but not much. At the top of the table, the other B team in the Division, Rainy City B (the Tender Hooligans) have a tight grip on the top spot, with Liverpool Roller Birds and hosts Manchester Roller Derby fighting it out for the second playoffs spot in the same event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to Hinnies' Co-Captain, Ania Marx about their first Champs experience...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's been a tough Tier for the Hinnies' first Champs experience, so far, with teams like Rainy B in the mix. How has the experience been for the team - and what has it taught you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a challenge ​but we​ always​ knew it would be - being seeded last​ in our Tier against alongside some really strong teams​ and also being a B team​ means that we've also​ needed to absorb a number of charter changes as players move up to our A team​, the Canny Belters​​​,​​ but we're grateful for the opportunity to play at this level - we've learnt a lot and have thoroughly enjoyed the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With just one game left in the season, what are your plans for the post-Champs period...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll have a short break from ​competitive bouts but hope to fit in a few more before the end of the year - we'll update the fixtures page on our website as soon as we've got more games confirmed. Immediately after our last Champs game on the 5th Aug we​'ll definitely be let​ting​ our hair down and enjoy​ing​ the after party and hope all the other leagues will be doing the same​!​&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;...and your thoughts about Champs next year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a great opportunity for the Whippin' ​Hinnies which was only possible due to our A team​'​s ​WFTDA ranking and our own European ranking​ going into Champs​ - if we remain eligible​ as a B team​ we will seriously consider​ taking part​ next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As hinted at in the interview, whilst the Hinnies will be taking a break post-Champs, there's more happening with Newcastle in the coming months.
We'd keep our eyes peeled for an away game in August, as well as the return of the Hinnies (and the Canny Belters) later in the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The British Champs Tier 2 North final fixture: &lt;strong&gt;5 August&lt;/strong&gt;, Manchester &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/104769700121799/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/104769700121799/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>british champs</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>interviews</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>whippin hinnies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/08/01/newcastles-whippin-hinnies-update-british-champs-t2-and-beyond/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 12:44:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs North Update 23 March:York Minxters, Whippin Hinnies and more</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/22/british-champs-north-update-23-marchyork-minxters-whippin-hinnies-and-more/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our second update on the Northern Tiers of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/"&gt;British Champs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. We're aiming to do approximately monthly updates on the Tier 1, Tier 2 North, Tier 3 North and Tier 4 North, partly through the lens of specific teams in each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the last update, the &lt;strong&gt;Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; saw our advertised bout between&lt;strong&gt; Leeds Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; and Tiger Bay Brawlers end in an impressive win for the Cardiff team (294:44). Performance stats show that at least some of this seems to have been "first game" syndrome for LeedsRD, who significantly improved their performance in the second period (scoring 70%  of their points in period 2, as well as taking less penalties). If they perform at their period 2 level, or continue to improve, they'll be a significant force in the Tier in future games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Tier 2 North&lt;/strong&gt; has seen another round of bouts, with our tracked team, Newcastle Roller Girls' &lt;strong&gt;Whippin Hinnies&lt;/strong&gt; facing the formidable Rainy City Tender Hooligans, with the Hooligans taking the win, 348:62. This is a approaching half the score ratio than Rainy B managed against Wirral, which looks promising for the Hinnies' next bout in the tier. Looking at the stats (not published yet), this was a tough game for the Hinnie's jammers, with only Ania Marx achieving lead jammer status against Rainy's exceptional blocking. Hosts Wirral also played, losing to Manchester Roller Derby with the score 101:248.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; saw our tracked team &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; win a pretty closely contended game against Halifax Bruising Banditas - finishing 130:117. The stats show particularly strong jamming performances by GCRD's Lizzie Rascal (75% Lead Jams!), Team Scotland's Udder Mayhem, and Kami-Tazzy; blocking-wise, high VTARs are with Crimson Chaos, Team Scotland's Rock'N Riot, and Pert Hits.
North Wales convincingly defeated hosts Furness Firecrackers in the other bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first &lt;strong&gt;Tier 4 North&lt;/strong&gt; bouts saw tier-champions favourites Mansfield crush Durham City Rolling Angels 398:38, and the second Durham team, Durham Roller Derby, lose to Grimsby Grim Reavers 198:110.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tier 4 North is coming around again for another set of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1002205086551977/"&gt;bouts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; this weekend, and features the &lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt;' first ever bout in British Champs (as well as hosts Mansfield versus Durham). In honour of the occasion, we caught up with their Captain, Gem O'Cide to see how they're feeling:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, let's start by talking about last year, which was a big year for the Minxters. After several years of just playing a few bouts, 2016 saw the team play 7 over the season, with some pretty challenging opponents. What lead to this surge in activity, and has it been a good thing for the team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016 was a year of practice, practice and more practice. We had a lot of changes in the team and a lot of up and coming skaters joining the rostered team- this meant our dynamics changed and we needed to learn how to play together. We very much wanted to take the "Win or Learn" approach and felt some real time game play - working as we would on game day- would be best to learn this. Everyone loves scrimming and it helped us grow confidence and learn how each other work, where our strengths lie and what we needed to improve on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After missing the first two years of British Champs, you're entering this year for the first time. Why now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to get started on the Champs journey! We've had a massive new skater intake and great retention and it would be awesome to get the ball rolling and have something yearly to aim for! Something to show everyone what we are working towards...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You're entering into the tournament in Tier 4 North. Flat Track Stats and us agree that you're pretty much in the middle of the Tier in terms of expected performance - but there's a lot of unknowns, as you've only played one of your competitors before (Grimsby's Grim Reavers). How are you preparing for the tournament&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off shout out to Reavers. We love those guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are playing and training to our strengths. We've had some great input from Rule 56, as well as other guest coaches who have analysed our play. This had helped massively in preparing by knowing what we focus on from A-team players and what direction to take our training in. This has given us concrete goals and really solidified our skills and tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your first bout in Champs looks like being a tough one - Wakey Wheeled Cats are one of the strongest teams in this Tier! What are your aims for this particular game?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Wakey game, we are going into a tough one! But this is a great challenge to practice what we have learnt, and are continuing to learn, in training. For me as Captain, all I ever want to see for my team is that they are working hard as a team and putting our training into practice. We go into and leave this as a team who wins or learns!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As well as British Champs itself, what other plans and events do York Minxters have in store for 2017?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have lots of fun things planned for our newer skaters after Champs - they have helped out with NSO roles and August will be and time of fun and folly for everyone! After Champs we will be having a bit of fun for the team, then looking at some more challenges to prepare for 2018!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upcoming bouts in other tiers are:
&lt;strong&gt;Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; - our tracked team, Leed Roller Derby, host a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/288187818265184/"&gt;massive triple header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;April 8th&lt;/strong&gt;, where they will play Bristol Roller Derby, London Brawl Saints will play Tiger Bay, and newly-rebranded Middlesbrough Roller Derby will take on Birmingham Blitz Dames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next &lt;strong&gt;Tier 2&lt;/strong&gt; bouts are on &lt;strong&gt;22nd April&lt;/strong&gt;, where Newcastle host a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1886091588294805/"&gt;double header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, with the Whippin Hinnies playing Manchester Roller Derby (which should be their closest bout yet), and Liverpool Roller Birds bouting Wirral Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tier 3&lt;/strong&gt; also plays next on &lt;strong&gt;22nd April&lt;/strong&gt;, with Aberdeen the venue, as hosts Granite City Roller Derby play the other Scottish team in the tier, Auld Reekie Roller Girls' Reserves; and Furness Firecrackers playing Halifax Bruising Banditas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>whippin hinnies</category><category>york minxters</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/22/british-champs-north-update-23-marchyork-minxters-whippin-hinnies-and-more/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 10:50:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs North Update 23 Feb</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/24/british-champs-north-update-23-feb/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we've previously mentioned, we're planning on tracking events in the Northern divisions of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/"&gt;British Championships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; this year (that is: the Tier 1, Tier 2 North, Tier 3 North, Tier 4 North, as well as the Men's Tier 3 North), partly via particular teams in each one (Leeds Roller Derby, Newcastle's Whippin Hinnies, Auld Reekie's Reserves and Granite City Roller Derby, York Minxters, and Bairn City's Skelpies and Glasgow Men's Roller Derby respectively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of this, this is one of our regular updates, after some of the teams have played, and as others prepare to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-15248 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/02/britishchamps.jpg?w=263" alt="britishchamps" width="263" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Whippin' Hinnies are the first team we're tracking to have played, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/88843"&gt;last weekend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; facing Cambridge Rollerbillies in Tier 2 (we talked to them &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/14/newcastles-hinnies-off-to-champs/"&gt;about the challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; beforehand). Whilst not managing to defeat their opponents in Manchester, the Hinnies did improve on their expected performance.
Statswise, full statistics are not available yet for the bout, but Co-captain Ania Marx and Miss Wired stand out at the top jammers (by points-per-jam) for the Newcastle team, with other Co-captain Method Mam, Marie Bayonet (also jamming) and Victoria Deck'em the most significant blockers by VTAR (a measure of the relative performance of the team whilst they were on track).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Whippin' Hinnies' next fixture will be against Rainy City Roller Derby's Tender Hooligans on the &lt;strong&gt;11th of March&lt;/strong&gt;, hosted by Wirral Roller Derby. The Tender Hooligans themselves had their first game last weekend, defeating Wirral significantly better than expectations. [Full stats are available for this game, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/88842"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up this &lt;strong&gt;Sunday&lt;/strong&gt;, we have the first Tier 1 bout we're tracking, as Leeds Roller Derby play their &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/241620336288289/"&gt;first game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of the season against the formidable Tiger Bay Brawlers (who are also hosts). Flat Track Stats sees LeedsRD as the underdogs here - and TBB are a strong team - but FTS is basing its rating on the performance of only half of Leeds Roller Derby, inheriting their ranking from the old pre-merger Leeds Roller Dolls. It remains to be seen what the new team, with the infusion of skaters from Hot Wheel Roller Derby, is like on track - having just announced &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/WeAreLeedsRD/photos/a.1199876556747521.1073741828.1192281080840402/1255594731175703/"&gt;their roster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the bout this week.
We talked to LeedsRD about their feelings on the year for EuroClash &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/15/euroclash-interviews-leeds-roller-derby/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also this &lt;strong&gt;Sunday&lt;/strong&gt;, Aberdeen's Granite City Roller Derby are playing their first Tier 3 North bout, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/297370800677088/"&gt;hosted by&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Furness Firecrackers, and facing Halifax Bruising Banditas. Granite City are the clear favourites here, having had a superlative 2016 ending in promotion to the Tier from Tier 4 unbeaten by all contenders.
Speaking about their challenge, GCRD's Kami-Tazzy told us: "We are all feeling really excited about being back in Tier 3 and have been working really hard since Champs finished last year. We are hoping to bring what we did last year plus something a bit extra, as we have some tough opposition and hope to progress further than 2 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have faced Halifax Banditas on two occasions already and have been successful. However with all teams continuing to grow and progress we shall never underestimate any of our opponents. Halifax are going to bring their A game and so are we. We're going to bring all our fight till the last whistle blows."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully both teams will have a successful weekend for us to discuss when we return for our next Champs update!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>whippin hinnies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/02/24/british-champs-north-update-23-feb/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 10:26:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hinnies Head for Scotland - Newcastle Roller Girls on their Month of Scottish Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/05/27/hinnies-head-for-scotland-newcastle-roller-girls-on-their-month-of-scottish-derby/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Up in Scotland, we're no strangers to &lt;a href="http://www.newcastlerollergirls.org.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;; they've played most of our established leagues over the last few years. This year, however, they've made slightly more of an impression, scheduling 4 bouts against Scottish leagues all within the month of May!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we approach the last of those dates, which sees Newcastle's B-team (The Whippin' Hinnies) take on &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie&lt;/a&gt;'s B Cannon Belles in Edinburgh on the 31st, we thought we'd have a chat to Newcastle's A and B teams about their experience so far, and some other exciting things that have happened in the last few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/theasaurus-wrecks.jpg"&gt;&lt;img id="i-3456" class="size-full wp-image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/theasaurus-wrecks.jpg?w=615" alt="Theasaurus Wrecks"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big event was always planned to be the one Newcastle hosted, a double-header at their usual venue, the Walker Activity Dome, featuring the Whippin' Hinnies taking on &lt;a href="http://dundeerollergirls.com/"&gt;Dundee&lt;/a&gt;'s Silvery Tayzers, followed by Newcastle A, the Canny Belters, facing off against &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; B, the Maiden Grrders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hinnies had previously taken on Dundee at the Into The Nitemare organised tournament, Battle of Britain, in November last year. Battling for the title, the Hinnies won with 60 points to Dundee's 51, in an extremely low scoring bout.
Theasaurus Wrecks, Hinnies Captain both for that bout and this year, remembers it fondly: “Battle of Britain was amazing. We were the underdogs, and I always think we perform really well as underdogs. ... we had a fantastic bench who knew the rules very well, and that worked incredibly well to our advantage. We also had a really strong team at the time with a lot of great crossovers [skaters who are on the 20 player pools for both the A and B teams, and thus eligible to roster for either].”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming into the Dundee bout this year, the team composition was a little different, the Hinnies roster having collected newer, less experienced skaters in the interim. In addition, Dundee's Tayzers had already demonstrated a very powerful team for the new year, with an impressive win over &lt;a href="http://granitecityrollergirls.org.uk/"&gt;Granite City&lt;/a&gt; at the end of March. So, it should not, perhaps, have been surprising that the first game of the double header went to Dundee Roller Girls, 163 to 131.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That the score was that close was a testament to the Hinnies' grit and determination, “In the first section of the 2nd half, the Hinnies were quite battered and feeling a bit down about it, but we kinda escalated away and picked up 70 pts in 15 minutes or so. So we sort of really brought it back in,” Thea told us, adding, “[it] shows what a psychological game roller derby is as well. Quite often if you start to think that you're losing it, then you kind of lose your psychological game and sort of give up. If you're willing to battle through to the end, then you can bring it back 'round to your favour.” While the Hinnies didn't quite manage that this time around, Dundee certainly felt the need to work hard, “They said to us afterwards that it was one of the best games they'd played in a long time, because they'd felt really challenged by it as well.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/gin-jamming-close-up.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3458" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/gin-jamming-close-up.jpg?w=614" alt="Gin and Sonic, on track." width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Gin and Sonic, on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the second bout of the day was not to happen, as a leak in the roof of the Walker Activity Dome began to let water on to the track during the inter-game break. With the referees ruling the track unsafe as long as water continued to fall, there was no choice but to call off the game. The Belters' Gin and Sonic was not alone in feeling extremely frustrated by the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So, you think when you play an &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;indoor &lt;/span&gt;sport that it will go ahead rain or shine... Our home venue is in many ways the perfect space for roller derby, and it’s not long since it was refurbished, so to say we were gutted when our GRD bout was rained off after a leaky roof issue is a MASSIVE understatement. We have so much love for GRD, they were really understanding (not to mention incredibly patient on the day while we waited to hear if the bout could go ahead safely...) and we’re hoping to reschedule very soon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently Newcastle are in negotiations with Newcastle City Council to resolve their venue issues – either by fixing the roof or getting a new venue – but they are determined not to let it affect their schedule at all. (Their next home fixture, seeing the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/486333931501291/?ref=5"&gt;Belters take on Birmingham Blitz Dames (in a double header with Tyne and Fear v The Inhuman League)&lt;/a&gt; is still on for the 7th of June, in the Centre for Sport, on the West Road, and has been rescheduled to a later time (but the same date) as a result.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Breaking News, added to this document after publication: The cancelled Glasgow Roller Derby bout has been rescheduled for June 28th, and will be hosted by &lt;em&gt;Glasgow&lt;/em&gt; at their usual venue, the ARC, as a replacement to the previously scheduled Glasgow A v Hot Wheels game (which is now cancelled).]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/theasurus-jamming.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3459" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/theasurus-jamming.jpg?w=614" alt="Theasaurus, pushing past the final blocker." width="614" height="614"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Theasaurus, pushing past Dundee's Milky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the loss of their venue is a setback, it didn't affect the next Scottish bout for the Hinnies, as they travelled up to Stirling to play &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' Parma Violents. This was a return bout, as Fierce Valley had travelled down to Newcastle in April 2013, and while a Newcastle win was expected, the Hinnies weren't going to relax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thea noted “the Hinnies, being a B-Team, being dynamic, is always changing, so we had a completely different lineup to the Dundee game. ... I'm one of the few people who's been with the Hinnies all this time, as the Team Captain, so yeah, we had a great opportunity with FVRG that we could try out lots of new players. So we had 1 brand new player, and 3 or 4 players who'd only played 1 or 2 games before, that was a really good learning curve for a lot of the newer people in the team.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And indeed, taking the opportunity to gain experience for the newer skaters still paid off, with the Hinnies pulling out a close (201 to 169) win – less than predicted, but nothing to sneeze at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we look ahead to the final bout in Newcastle's packed Scottish schedule (and it is exciting for multiple reasons), we should note that Scotland is not the &lt;span style="font-weight:bold;"&gt;only &lt;/span&gt;place that Newcastle Roller Girls have been involved with recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/gin-sonic-high-fives.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-large wp-image-3460" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/05/gin-sonic-high-fives.jpg?w=614" alt="Gin and Sonic, taking high-fives post bout." width="614" height="345"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Gin and Sonic, taking high-fives post bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a start, three of the Canny Belters have made the roster for Team Wales Roller Derby, and will be playing for the Valleys in the Blood and Thunder World Cup in December. Gin and Sonic was one of the three, and was happy to talk to us about her choice of Wales over England:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was eligible to try out for both England and Wales. I tried out for England on a bit of a whim and really steeled my resolve to try out for Wales and gave it everything I have. I’m so glad I did as we have a really great team and they make me really proud of my Welsh side. It’s been brilliant sharing the try out process with [fellow Belters] Hit One Purl One and Marie Bayonet as we’ve been each other’s cheerleaders and it’s great having travel buddies for long trips to training! NRG have been so supportive of us and I know we’re going to learn lots from the experience and bring it all back to Newcastle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Belters have been getting skaters onto National teams, the Hinnies have gone the international route, playing their first European away bout against Eindhoven's Rockcity Rollers in January. Winning by a single point, the experience has whetted the Hinnies' appetite for Euroderby, in Thea's words: “That was one of the most Emotional games [she laughs] that I've ever played. It was really close.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While normally it would be the A team that gets into International derby first, in this case it was an existing connection that brought the Hinnies to the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It came about because we had a skater from &lt;a href="http://www.domcitydolls.com/"&gt;Dom City&lt;/a&gt; which is in Utrect. She came over and skated with NRG for three months, and we kind of just built up a really good friendship. So she said that since they were kind of an up and coming league, they would love to have us come over and do some coaching.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanting to get as much our of the trip as possible, the Hinnies found &lt;a href="http://rockcityrollers.nl/"&gt;Rockcity Rollers&lt;/a&gt;, ranked very closely to them, in Eindhoven, and managed to arrange a bout for the dates they were over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thea is still emotional about the event “we'd been travelling for ages, and it was a covered outdoor venue, and it just... it just was so close.
In final jam, we had our jammer, Torville and Scream, up and I saw her calling it off, and I didn't even know if she'd made the points, but she just was absolutely shattered, so she had to call it off and we were all there holding our breath just hoping that she'd picked up the points, and she had, so it was amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that was the first game that my parents had ever seen me play, so they said they kind of got how exciting roller derby could be from that game.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And more international bouts might be on the cards:
“I think it's all about funding and finances. I think I'd really like to play Amsterdam. One Love is really good as well, I would like to play a lot more teams of similar to us in the rankings, cause the games that we've had recently with Scottish teams have all been so challenging, and so exciting, and really pushing us to our limit. And that's really .. when you learn a lot about your team.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Canny Belters, meanwhile, are focussed on the American side of International derby, as Gin and Sonic revealed: “we’re dead proud of our Hinnies flying the NRG flag in Europe earlier this year and the Canny Belters have big aspirations for the next year! We became WFTDA apprentices earlier this year and we’re hoping to graduate as full members very soon. We’ll be focussing on the Northern Series which is a round robin of UKRDA/WFTDA games between Leeds Roller Dolls, Rainy City Roller Girls and Middlesbrough Milk Rollers. Hopefully our first round of WFTDA sanctioned bouts will put us in a good ranking position to go further afield in 2015. We’re itching to go a big international tournament like ARRG and Glasgow!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it's only an hour and a half from Newcastle to Edinburgh, the Belters will surely be discussing how to dominate America with Auld Reekie's Twisted Thistles, as both watch their B team sistren play this coming weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This looks like being a particularly close fought bout, with the rankings very close between the teams. Theasaurus Wrecks agrees, “
[I'm] Really excited. This is going to be the highlight of the year, I think. I think it's going to be the toughest challenge that the Hinnies have had; obviously ARRG are a really strong team, they've got a fantastic foundation, fantastic coaching from their A Team, they're in a really strong position on the table. So I'm really looking forward to us having that real focused challenge, and trying to achieve the best that we can for that. Having a battle - it's going to be very tough.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is not all, as Fierce Valley's junior derby league, the &lt;a href="http://www.fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs&lt;/a&gt;, are making a debut appearance at half-time, with a demonstration scrim. The Cubs are all big derby fans as Thea has already discovered, “I'm really excited to see that! They sent a really nice email to us, asking if we could do a photo with them at the end. I'm looking forward to that one :D”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe she'd sign an autograph or two as well (as the Cubs have been known to collect in the past)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;laughs&lt;/em&gt; Oh, I'm looking forward to it.
I feel like a minor celebrity(!)”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hinnies won't be the only celebrities present, either. Recently, Auld Reekie revealed that (known derby fan) Phill Jupitus will be co-announcing the bout, alongside long-standing ARRG announcer Stephen Tawking.
“I have noticed, that on QI, he's worn Kent Roller Girls t-shirts quite a bit, so I'm hoping that he'll wear ARRG and Newcastle shirts after this bout,” said Thea. We're pretty sure that Phill will end up getting freebie tshirts from all the leagues present after this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to see the Whippin Hinnies take on Auld Reekie Roller Girls on Saturday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;31 May, doors open at 2pm, for skateout at 2:30. Tickets can be bought at
&lt;a href="http://m.bpt.me/event/643612"&gt;http://m.bpt.me/event/643612
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Newcastle Roller Girls' Theasaurus Wrecks, Gin and Sonic, and PR Pretty Skate Machine.
All photographs from Newcastle Roller Girls - photographers please contact me for attribution!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was edited after publication to include details of the rescheduling of the GRD v NRG bout, and to improve cross-linking to league pages.
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>cannon belles</category><category>canny belters</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>interviews</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>nrg</category><category>parma violents</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>whippin hinnies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/05/27/hinnies-head-for-scotland-newcastle-roller-girls-on-their-month-of-scottish-derby/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 18:55:39 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>