<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about wintourope)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/wintourope.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:34:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Lady Trample’s Ramp Camp @ Chicks in Bowls Scotland</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/31/lady-tramples-ramp-camp-chicks-in-bowls-scotland/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has anything to do with Chicks in Bowls knows of Lady Trample. For any readers who don’t, she is the founding member of CiB. It was created in 2013 and now there are 253 chapters all over the world, including our bonnie Scotland [the pride].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am lucky enough to be one of the managers of CiB Scotland, which I run with my LDD team mate and friend Sam Awry. When GMRD asked us if we would help organise the Ramp Camp part of &lt;em&gt;WinTourope Scotland&lt;/em&gt;, it comes as no surprise that we jumped at the chance!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were given some time to talk to Trample in the car on the way to Unit 23. It was great to be able to hear about the first time Trample went to a skate park with Cutthroat and how she was motivated to learning as many tricks as she could. Within no time, there were a group of skaters going to the park regularly. One thing we agreed on during that car ride, is that sometimes you need to be at the skate park practicing tricks to remind yourself why we all love skating, or when derby becomes intense: Because it's fun; Because it gets the adrenaline going; Because stepping out of the comfort zone can be empowering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beginner boot camp was first with skaters attending from near and far. Everyone was eager to learn from the professional. After a hello and welcome (and how she was so excited to be in Scotland) the session itself covered stance and balance when skating ramps, how to carve up and down bowls, how to turn, transition and drop-in. It was fantastic to see everyone pushing themselves and encouraging each other. The Trample herself was really friendly, warm and reassuring, holding hands and giving words of encouragement in tandem with her instruction and pointers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intermediate session that followed was aimed at skaters who have been rolling about in skate parks for years. All poised and ready for a challenge from Lady Trample, she did not disappoint! Stalls, grinds, seated drop-ins and massive craves were on the intermediate menu. It was great to see so many seasoned and awesome derby skaters playing about and having fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a real excitement about Lady Trample being at Unit 23 that night, and so many quad skaters being together, in custom made skates which involve a unique marrying of trainers and plates and different types of trucks, sharing their passion for ramps and tricks (not to mention the obligatory splinter or two) was great to be a part of. There was a lot of information swapping about Chapters, skate parks, wheels and experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a personal note, for me, skate park skating improves my skills in order to be a better derby skater. Lady Trample coming to Scotland really embedded this for me as she is one of the best Jammers in the world as well as an awesome chick in a bowl! Trample and Ramp Camp has put skate park skating and CiB Scotland on the map. It proves quad skating is growing in all its beautiful forms and Scotland is right there embracing all it has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For information on Chicks in Bowls Scotland, visit our Facebook area &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/chicksinbowlsscotland/?fref=ts&amp;amp;ref=br_tf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For general information about the CIB movement, products and merchandise visit &lt;a href="http://www.chicksinbowls.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;http://www.chicksinbowls.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>chicks in bowls</category><category>wintourope</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/31/lady-tramples-ramp-camp-chicks-in-bowls-scotland/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 19:25:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lannthrax Talks to: Wintourope Glasgow edition</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/16/lannthrax-talks-to-wintourope-glasgow-edition/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So if you were at the Glasgow edition of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1717432861812471/"&gt;Wintourope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, you should probably by now, know your Toe Stop Pop from your Zip Zap Zop. If not, then I'm sorry, all I have for you is an interview with the lovely coaches. Scald Eagle and Lady Trample took the time to chat with me and I must admit, I felt like a fan-girl. These guys are two of my favourite skaters to watch and I'm so glad I got this opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-13937 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/wintourope.jpg" alt="wintourope" width="960" height="354"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lanna&lt;/strong&gt;- “ How do you guys deal with the fame attribution that comes along with being at the top level within the sport?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scald&lt;/strong&gt;- “First of all, Fame is fleeting. What might be hot now might be day-old news next week. Saying that, I will always do my best regardless of status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The derby fame is something that you just have to deal with; I can still walk into a 7/11 and no one knows who I am, but you wouldn't see Lebron James walk into a 7/11. However, if I walk in to Rollercon, that’s a different story. Sometimes it’s hard to just make it to the bathroom and back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what I've really worked on is to put time aside and do what needs to be done but also make sure I have time to do what I need to do. It's great though: I am more than happy to have those interactions and I love it. It feels just like yesterday for me that I was waiting in line to get stuff signed and having people that I looked up to. I have a lot of patience for it and I love to do it”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trample&lt;/strong&gt;- “ One of the interesting things about, it is there is a level of responsibility, you have to be careful about what you put in the public eye. You are so accessible through social media. However, it also gives you a chance to do things for the community and opportunities to travel and share your knowledge, which I think Isn't really a thing you would see in other sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lanna&lt;/strong&gt;- “ Mental resilience is something that I personally have struggled with, how do you guys switch off that part of your brain and just get the job done?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trample&lt;/strong&gt;- “It’s something that comes with time; I had a really great coach this year and the main thing he would say to me is to back myself, so much so that I actually got a tattoo of it. It’s a nice memento that I can take with me to remind myself that I've worked hard and to trust my instincts, my pack, my offence, defence and my coaches. If your team are putting you on the line, they believe in you. It takes a little bit of self belief: I played some of my hardest games last year and once I got on that line I just had to remind myself that I've done all the training and to just let it all come into motion”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scald&lt;/strong&gt;- “I think that's where I'm at. In gameplay my cognitive part switches off and my instincts take over, I let my muscle memory do its thing. I don't know how often I have to actually tell myself to continue because it’s more like that's what I have to do, it's instinct. When I think about mental fortitude it’s about getting through practice week to week and living through the dynamics of my team at that level. When you're at that level you don't have the choice to just switch to the next team across town. If you want to play at that level I think the hardest part in my opinion is not figuring out how to deal with your opponents but how you can work well with your team mate”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lanna&lt;/strong&gt;- “ What have your highlights of the Winter Tour been so far ?”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scald&lt;/strong&gt;- “ (adopts an awkward Scottish accent) Shcotland! Och aye ye wee lass, We're in the land of Ootlander an' its ma favourite show and a cannae wait to be here. Its gonnae be a great time. (Back to American) I am super excited to be up here, I've been once before and I loved it. In the US we spent a lot of time re-visiting leagues that I had already been to so it was a lot about going and seeing old friends. We spent our time on the south west but I anticipate that next time round we will head along the east. As far as for the Wintourope Tour, my last name is Buschovik, so I’m really excited to go to Poland. I don't know much what it’s going to be like but it’s going to be an experience. The point of life is to experience new things so...”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trample&lt;/strong&gt;- “ I'm super excited to be in Europe because I've never been on this side of the world. I have a little bit of heritage in Scotland so it was cool to come and explore this place a little bit. Everywhere we are going is exciting to me and there's people who I've been talking to online for the past few years who I'm now getting to meet. They are all coming to our ramp camps and people are travelling all over the world to get to the different bootcamps. Chicks in Bowls is at close to 250 Chapters and it’s amazing I get to meet so many of the Chapter admins and members”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lanna&lt;/strong&gt;- “ And finally, What advice would you give to skaters who want to improve their game?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scald&lt;/strong&gt; - “I think that off skates training is really important, mostly from an injury prevention standpoint. You may not like going to the gym, but going to the ER is much less fun. Having strong quads helps you have strong knees and as women we have naturally weak knees so it's imperative that we strengthen the muscles around them so that they can withstand the torque we put them under. Same with ankles, there's so many baby ankle muscles and foot muscles that we need to look after. If you want to be a kick ass skater and be better than the person next to you then you need to start doing some squats with weight and different things like that. At Rose specifically one of the keys to our success, I believe, is that we have a required gym hour 2 hours a week where we all train together in the gym.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trample&lt;/strong&gt;- “ I don't really do off skates, I know, I'm bad. But I have recently been convinced by Scald that I should be hitting the gym especially to do Pre-hab. I rolled my ankle a while back and I'll do the rehab until its better but then I'm straight back on skates, and it’s not good because a few months later I'll roll my ankle again and it’s because I didn't build up the strength that I needed to help the muscles fully recover and be strong enough to stop the injury from happening again. So I am in a position now where I'm going to push myself to do it”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, there you have it. It was an absolute pleasure to interview these lovely ladies and hopefully you all take something away from my questions. Huge thanks to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GlasgowMensRollerDerby/"&gt;GMRD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for hosting a fantastic event and making sure the day was super fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Till next time
Much Love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next WinTourope is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1852698681626181/"&gt;WinTourope Poland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, this weekend (21-22nd Jan), followed by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/227698337655754/"&gt;Netherlands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/381880268819988/"&gt;France&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and finally &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/146844349126661/"&gt;England&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>articles</category><category>chicks in bowls</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>training</category><category>wintourope</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/16/lannthrax-talks-to-wintourope-glasgow-edition/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 19:25:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>