<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about wirral pack animals)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/wirral-pack-animals.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:24 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Glasgow ready to roar into action in a derby double-decker</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/25/glasgow-ready-to-roar-into-action-in-a-derby-double-decker/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow’s roller derby dudes will go roaring into action on Saturday, October 4, 2014 as they aim to be the leaders of the Pack against some of England’s top skaters.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city’s first men’s roller derby team – Mean City – are once again hosting a special double-decker featuring top male and female skaters from north and south of the border.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/mean-wirrals.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-3883 alignright" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/mean-wirrals.jpg?w=300" alt="Mean Wirrals" width="416" height="164"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby will be taking on Wirral’s Pack Animals in an all-male clash, while the all-female, all-awesome Cannie Gingers from Glasgow Roller Derby will go toestop to toestop with fellow Scots, the sensational Central Belters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s going to be a rock ‘n’ roll day out for sports fans of all ages – combining skills, thrills and spills … all on skates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenny Reid, Chairman of Mean City Roller Derby (MCRD), said: “We can’t wait for this very special double-header. Mean City is Glasgow’s first and only men’s roller derby league and has been going from strength to strength since it was formed in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re genuinely thrilled to be welcoming three amazing squads to Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Pack Animals are a great team and a terrific bunch of lads – we can’t wait to line up against them. Mean City features some of the best skaters in Scotland and we will be giving our all to ensure the super summer of sport continues in Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Pack Animals hail from the wilds of the Wirral and are coming north aiming to take Mean City’s scalp, but we’re aiming to be the leaders of this Pack.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City recorded their first ever victory in August against Teesside's Skate Invaders and are hungry for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meawhile, Glasgow Roller Derby (GRD) – Mean City’s all-female sister league – is renowned throughout the roller derby world. Its A team – the Irn Bruisers –stormed America earlier this year, while its B team – the Maiden Grrders – are also a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such is the strength in depth at GRD that a third travel team has been formed – the Cannie Gingers – and they are already making a name for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mighty Central Belters – part of Bairn City Rollers – all hail from Central Scotland and will be heading west aiming to pop the Gingers’ bubble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenny added: “This is the first team these four teams have clashed and it’s going to be awesome. You’ll be treated to two full-on games of roller derby for just £5 – free entry to under-14s with a paying adult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s going to be a great showcase of all that roller derby has to offer – an action-packed afternoon of skating, scoring, skills, thrills and spills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you’ve never been to a roller derby bout, get along to the ARC on October 4 – there will be action, fun, entertainment, refreshments and more.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The double-header takes place at The ARC, Glasgow Caledonian University, Cowcaddens Road, Glasgow, on Saturday, October 4, 2014 – from 11.30am&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby has been developing as a league since its formation in 2012. Men’s roller derby is a fledgling off-shoot of the modern day all-female sport of roller derby – with the game rising in popularity with people of all genders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City train regularly in the Glasgow area and new members are always welcome to give the sport a go in a supportive environment. Equipment can be provided – just get in touch in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby"&gt;www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby&lt;/a&gt; to buy tickets for the event and to find out more about joining the revolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>cannie gingers</category><category>central belters</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>in the news</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>wirral pack animals</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/25/glasgow-ready-to-roar-into-action-in-a-derby-double-decker/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 22:51:47 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>