<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts about york minxters)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/york-minxters.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>York Minxters update: British Champs T4 and beyond</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/19/york-minxters-update-british-champs-t4-and-beyond/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've been a little remiss with our &lt;a href="https://www.britishchamps.com"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;British Champs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Northern Divisions updates since the middle of the season, so we're back a with a special catchup with our teams from each Tier, starting with Tier 4 North's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/yorkrollerderby/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22663" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/10858530_804241242955870_3874820604520383031_n.jpg" alt="10858530_804241242955870_3874820604520383031_n" width="462" height="527"&gt; York Minxters Logo (Credit: York Minxters)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the season is closing out, the Minxters will be playing their last bout of their Division of the Tier on &lt;strong&gt;July 29th&lt;/strong&gt;. With three teams in the Division all with a single win (York, Grimsby and Durham Roller Derby), this bout will play an important part in deciding the final table ordering. Hosts Durham Roller Derby will play their fellow Durhamites, Durham City Rolling Angels, in the other decisive bout in the fixture (Wakey Wheeled Cats play Mansfield in the third bout... but Wakefield can't be knocked off the top spot according to the Champs table - and &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; teams will be promoted to Tier 3 regardless, as they have an unassailable grip on the top 2 places).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minxters Captain Gem O'Cide is excited about the bout, "Our final Champs game on July 29th is a triple header. We take on our lovely friends Grimsby and its a game we have been looking forward to - it's d always hard to hit the ones you love.. and I think war paint will be caked on so we can ignore the smiles... as a team we have decided on a theme.. AND we don't do things by halves!".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the rest of the team will be celebrating surviving their first ever tournament series the day after, &lt;strong&gt;July 30th&lt;/strong&gt;, with a closed, mixed scrim for skaters from all the teams in Tier 4 North, as well as other "Tier 4 level" teams.
The Minxters describe it as a "celebration of everything we've achieved competing in our first championships", "a super casual affair full of fun and welcoming newer skaters, refs and officials to mark the end of champs and the start of the next season".
Any skaters of the right level who are interested in joining in should do so quickly, as the event is almost at capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After recovering from this, the celebrations won't stop for York Minxters: a month later, August 20th, they'll be giving fans the chance to see the rising stars of the next season, as their last fresh meat intake hold their debut exhibition bout... as well as a "meet and greet" after the bout, for those interested in signing up themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An open-subscription bout for all rookie skaters, this has proven so popular that skater tickets sold out in just 3 days - although there is a reserve list for those still interested. The team are still looking for a full officiating crew, so Referees and NSOs are welcomed!
Gem O'Cide adds, "The theme is Disney vs Superhero* and we sold out much faster than we expected -  which we are super happy with; we're already planning part two! The current rostered skaters have a chance to bench and NSO to thank all the intake for all their hard work over the last 6 months.
These are just our first planned off-season scrims.. there will be much more from the Minxters in the rest of 2017!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22681" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/20106343_1479959558717365_7457452738007673460_n.jpg" alt="20106343_1479959558717365_7457452738007673460_n" width="960" height="425"&gt; The Minxters You Could Be Joining (Credit: Sir Snaps-A-Lot)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;British Champs Tier 4 North, final fixture (&lt;strong&gt;29th July, Durham&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1486265868090310/?ti=as&amp;amp;__mref=mb" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1486265868090310/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post-Champs Tier-4 Scrims (&lt;strong&gt;30th July, York&lt;/strong&gt;): private event - contact York Minxters directly to inquire about free spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rookie and Fresh Meat Debut Exhibition (&lt;strong&gt;20th August, York&lt;/strong&gt;): [sold out - keep checking for reserves] &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1949945005262074/?ti=cl&amp;amp;__mref=mb" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1949945005262074/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meet and Greet / Signup (&lt;strong&gt;20th August, York&lt;/strong&gt;): &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1910573672544381/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1910573672544381/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Given that Disney own Marvel now, this is something of an internal battle!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>british champs</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>tournament</category><category>york minxters</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/19/york-minxters-update-british-champs-t4-and-beyond/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 09:25:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs North Update 23 March:York Minxters, Whippin Hinnies and more</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/22/british-champs-north-update-23-marchyork-minxters-whippin-hinnies-and-more/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our second update on the Northern Tiers of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/"&gt;British Champs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. We're aiming to do approximately monthly updates on the Tier 1, Tier 2 North, Tier 3 North and Tier 4 North, partly through the lens of specific teams in each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the last update, the &lt;strong&gt;Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; saw our advertised bout between&lt;strong&gt; Leeds Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; and Tiger Bay Brawlers end in an impressive win for the Cardiff team (294:44). Performance stats show that at least some of this seems to have been "first game" syndrome for LeedsRD, who significantly improved their performance in the second period (scoring 70%  of their points in period 2, as well as taking less penalties). If they perform at their period 2 level, or continue to improve, they'll be a significant force in the Tier in future games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Tier 2 North&lt;/strong&gt; has seen another round of bouts, with our tracked team, Newcastle Roller Girls' &lt;strong&gt;Whippin Hinnies&lt;/strong&gt; facing the formidable Rainy City Tender Hooligans, with the Hooligans taking the win, 348:62. This is a approaching half the score ratio than Rainy B managed against Wirral, which looks promising for the Hinnies' next bout in the tier. Looking at the stats (not published yet), this was a tough game for the Hinnie's jammers, with only Ania Marx achieving lead jammer status against Rainy's exceptional blocking. Hosts Wirral also played, losing to Manchester Roller Derby with the score 101:248.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; saw our tracked team &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; win a pretty closely contended game against Halifax Bruising Banditas - finishing 130:117. The stats show particularly strong jamming performances by GCRD's Lizzie Rascal (75% Lead Jams!), Team Scotland's Udder Mayhem, and Kami-Tazzy; blocking-wise, high VTARs are with Crimson Chaos, Team Scotland's Rock'N Riot, and Pert Hits.
North Wales convincingly defeated hosts Furness Firecrackers in the other bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first &lt;strong&gt;Tier 4 North&lt;/strong&gt; bouts saw tier-champions favourites Mansfield crush Durham City Rolling Angels 398:38, and the second Durham team, Durham Roller Derby, lose to Grimsby Grim Reavers 198:110.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tier 4 North is coming around again for another set of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1002205086551977/"&gt;bouts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; this weekend, and features the &lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt;' first ever bout in British Champs (as well as hosts Mansfield versus Durham). In honour of the occasion, we caught up with their Captain, Gem O'Cide to see how they're feeling:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, let's start by talking about last year, which was a big year for the Minxters. After several years of just playing a few bouts, 2016 saw the team play 7 over the season, with some pretty challenging opponents. What lead to this surge in activity, and has it been a good thing for the team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016 was a year of practice, practice and more practice. We had a lot of changes in the team and a lot of up and coming skaters joining the rostered team- this meant our dynamics changed and we needed to learn how to play together. We very much wanted to take the "Win or Learn" approach and felt some real time game play - working as we would on game day- would be best to learn this. Everyone loves scrimming and it helped us grow confidence and learn how each other work, where our strengths lie and what we needed to improve on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After missing the first two years of British Champs, you're entering this year for the first time. Why now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to get started on the Champs journey! We've had a massive new skater intake and great retention and it would be awesome to get the ball rolling and have something yearly to aim for! Something to show everyone what we are working towards...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You're entering into the tournament in Tier 4 North. Flat Track Stats and us agree that you're pretty much in the middle of the Tier in terms of expected performance - but there's a lot of unknowns, as you've only played one of your competitors before (Grimsby's Grim Reavers). How are you preparing for the tournament&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off shout out to Reavers. We love those guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are playing and training to our strengths. We've had some great input from Rule 56, as well as other guest coaches who have analysed our play. This had helped massively in preparing by knowing what we focus on from A-team players and what direction to take our training in. This has given us concrete goals and really solidified our skills and tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your first bout in Champs looks like being a tough one - Wakey Wheeled Cats are one of the strongest teams in this Tier! What are your aims for this particular game?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Wakey game, we are going into a tough one! But this is a great challenge to practice what we have learnt, and are continuing to learn, in training. For me as Captain, all I ever want to see for my team is that they are working hard as a team and putting our training into practice. We go into and leave this as a team who wins or learns!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As well as British Champs itself, what other plans and events do York Minxters have in store for 2017?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have lots of fun things planned for our newer skaters after Champs - they have helped out with NSO roles and August will be and time of fun and folly for everyone! After Champs we will be having a bit of fun for the team, then looking at some more challenges to prepare for 2018!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upcoming bouts in other tiers are:
&lt;strong&gt;Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; - our tracked team, Leed Roller Derby, host a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/288187818265184/"&gt;massive triple header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;April 8th&lt;/strong&gt;, where they will play Bristol Roller Derby, London Brawl Saints will play Tiger Bay, and newly-rebranded Middlesbrough Roller Derby will take on Birmingham Blitz Dames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next &lt;strong&gt;Tier 2&lt;/strong&gt; bouts are on &lt;strong&gt;22nd April&lt;/strong&gt;, where Newcastle host a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1886091588294805/"&gt;double header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, with the Whippin Hinnies playing Manchester Roller Derby (which should be their closest bout yet), and Liverpool Roller Birds bouting Wirral Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tier 3&lt;/strong&gt; also plays next on &lt;strong&gt;22nd April&lt;/strong&gt;, with Aberdeen the venue, as hosts Granite City Roller Derby play the other Scottish team in the tier, Auld Reekie Roller Girls' Reserves; and Furness Firecrackers playing Halifax Bruising Banditas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>whippin hinnies</category><category>york minxters</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/22/british-champs-north-update-23-marchyork-minxters-whippin-hinnies-and-more/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 10:50:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs Schedule 2017</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/03/british-champs-schedule-2017/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, by now you're probably aware that the British Championships 2017 schedule is out (it's hosted here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.britishchamps.com/2017-british-roller-derby-champs-fixtures/"&gt;http://www.britishchamps.com/2017-british-roller-derby-champs-fixtures/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in a big, searchable, list).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the list is pretty long, we thought we'd pull out some key dates for you (and also tip our hand a bit as to teams and divisions we'll be focussing a little more on - Talk Derby To Me will be continuing their excellent overall Champs coverage this year for those who want to cover the whole thing):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; kicks off on the &lt;strong&gt;26th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Feb&lt;/strong&gt;ruary, with a double header featuring Tiger Bay Brawlers against newly-merged Leeds Roller Derby, and Birmingham Blitz Dames against Bristol Roller Derby hosted by TBB in Cardiff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 1&lt;/strong&gt; also begins a few weeks later in Wales, as South West Silures host the Crash Test Brummies on the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, by then, most of the other Tiers will have had their first bouts, with the whole British Champs schedule starting on the &lt;strong&gt;4th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Feb&lt;/strong&gt;ruary, as the &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 2&lt;/strong&gt; begins with Barrow Infernos hosting Southern Discomfort B (the first B team in the Men's tiers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friends of the blog, &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;, see their B-team, the Whippin' Hinnies, compete for the first time in &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 2 North&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;11th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch, in a battle of the B-teams against Rainy City Roller Derby's formidable Tender Hooligans; hosted by Wirral Roller Derby, this is also somewhat Manchester area themed, as the second bout of the fixture is hosts versus Manchester Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you'll have to wait until April to see some &lt;em&gt;Scottish Women&lt;/em&gt;'s action in the Champs, as &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; host a &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; double header on the &lt;strong&gt;22nd&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Apr&lt;/strong&gt;il. &lt;strong&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;' Reserves are travelling up to Aberdeen to take on the hosts, whilst Furness Firecrackers and Halifax Bruising Banditas will be coming up to play each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scottish Men&lt;/em&gt;'s Derby also has its first showing in Champs that month, as Men Behaving Derby host a &lt;strong&gt;Men's Tier 3 North&lt;/strong&gt; fixture on the &lt;strong&gt;16th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Apr&lt;/strong&gt;il; pitting &lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt;' Skelpies against the hosts, followed by Teeside Skate Invaders facing off against &lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, whilst the &lt;strong&gt;Women's Tier 4&lt;/strong&gt; North starts its series a few weeks earlier, we'll be following friends of the blog (and some of our first interviewees!) &lt;strong&gt;York Minxters&lt;/strong&gt; - their first bout is on the &lt;strong&gt;25th&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Mar&lt;/strong&gt;ch against Wakey Wheeled Cats, in Mansfield; the second bout is hosts against Durham Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>leeds roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>york minxters</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/03/british-champs-schedule-2017/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 09:44:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>"Brave New Faces" (The Writer's Cut)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/01/26/brave-new-faces-the-writers-cut/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;An edited version of this article was published in Issue 2 (December 2011) of &lt;a href="http://www.insidelinemagazine.co.uk/"&gt;Inside Line Magazine&lt;/a&gt;. Reprinted with permission. Issue 3 of Inside Line will be on sale from March 1st.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Since this article was written, &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; have had their first (closed) bout, against Fair City Rollers' Fear Maidens, which Chasing Katy covered for the blog &lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/02/bout-report-fcr-fear-maidens-vs-fvrg-parma-violents-301011/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The final score was 170 FCR to 55 for FVRG. FVRG's first open bout is against Dundee Roller Girls' Silvery Tayzers on Feb 18th, in Dundee.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/yorkrollerderby"&gt;York Minxters&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://nastynessiesrollergirls.wordpress.com/"&gt;Nasty Nessies Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; are both still working towards being fully mins-passed and bout-ready. The Minxters have a weekly practise and an online blog from one member &lt;a href="http://www.oneandother.com/articles/diary-of-a-minxter-part-2/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, while the Nasty Nessies are gaining lots of attention in their local media.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="http://tigerbaybrawlers.com/"&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers&lt;/a&gt; are also going from strength to strength, having recently launched a junior league; while the &lt;a href="http://www.norfolkbrawds.com/"&gt;Norfolk Brawds&lt;/a&gt; have only this week relaunched a fantastic new website, and announced sponsorship from famous East Anglian rockers, The Darkness!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/team1-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-821" title="The Nasty Nessies!" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/team1-1.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since the roller derby revival in Texas, back in 2001, new leagues have been forming all over the world, perhaps especially in the UK. Now, with the increased exposure from the World Cup, and mainstream media starting to take an interest, the rate at which new leagues are incorporating is higher than ever.
Two such brand new leagues are the York Minxters, and Nasty Nessies Roller Girls, one of two Inverness-based leagues recently founded.
Fierce Valley Roller Girls, founded in the Forth Valley area of Scotland late last year, have been moving towards bouting standard ever since. Their first (closed) bout is imminent at the time of writing.
By contrast, the Tiger Bay Brawlers have been bouting for Cardiff since the start of the year, and the Norfolk Brawds since March.
I caught up with the leagues to try to get a good view of the process of becoming the next big thing in Roller Derby.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;There are many reasons you might have for starting a new league, rather than joining an existing one. Aby Falkingham founded the York Minxters with no knowledge of roller derby at all, drawn to the inclusive nature of the sport as exemplified by the London Roller Girls.
“It was something I was always interested in from buying tattoo magazines. I’d seen the London Roller Girls in the magazine, and I decided it was something I wanted to be part of. So, I found that there were teams in Leeds, Middlesborough, Manchester, but all of these were far away. So, I made it my mission to start a league in York…“
If distance was a factor for the Minxters, how much more for the Nasty Nessies: ”Try being 100+ miles from any of the other leagues and you'll soon understand why”, NNRG Secretary T-balls of Fire notes.
Whatever your reasons, making the choice to start a league is the easy bit.Once you’ve decided that you want to take on the challenge of creating a whole new roller derby league, you have to battle with all the problems of new skaters, as well as discovering what you’re supposed to be doing at the same time.
As well as potentially learning to skate, and learning the rules, there’s also the difficulty of finding practice space, getting word out to recruit fresh meat, and finding essential skilled roles in referees, coaches and the array of NSOs that every league needs to be successful, as well as the basic issue of funding.
&lt;p&gt;In many ways, it’s easier to face these challenges now than it was back in 2006 when London Rollergirls were just getting started. There’s a vast array of established UK leagues, all keen to help those starting out. Every league has nothing but praise for the support they received from the existing roller derby community. “I definitely could not have done it without them,” says Aby of the Leeds and Manchester leagues. “They came to our first session, and they’ve set us out a training plan to get all of us who haven’t skated before to a good level.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girls’ Cilla Block has been one of those helpful skaters for the Scottish leagues. “I think it can be quite daunting starting up, so ff there’s anything I can do to help, Scotland’s not all that big, you you’re only an hour or two away on the train. For Inverness, with [Irn-Bruzer, NNRG chair] at the moment, we’re looking at helping them with their mins.” She’s quick to note that even established leagues are always looking to improve, “Even now Dundee Roller Girls is always looking for people to come and help us, and I think it’s important for us to share that with other people as well.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even without being able to visit, the online roller derby community is a vital resource for information and advice. The Nasty Nessies are over 100 miles from their nearest league, but, according to Team Rep Cherry Bow “…the internet has been our life line! We have had support via Facebook, Twitter and emails from other leagues as well as individual skaters from as far afield as the USA...”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/dsc05260.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-824" title="SONY DSC" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/dsc05260.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="411"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to be a league, you have to have somewhere to skate. Practice space (and, later, a bouting venue) is often the first difficult problem that a new league faces. Many sports halls are reluctant to host skate-based sports, as they can mark the floors. One solution to this can be to find a hall that already hosts roller hockey; both the York Minxters and Dundee Roller Girls found their practice space by this method.
The first site is can often be the hardest, as Fierce Valley’s Grizabelta discovered: “As far as finding practice space goes, whilst we hit every obstacle we could to start with, once we'd been at Bo'ness a few months I wrote to all the other halls with a massive spiel about how great derby is (boosts self esteem, gets non-sporty types active, great camaraderie etc) and thankfully it worked!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paying for the space, and the equipment, can be a challenge, even for established leagues. Most set up a subscription fee for skaters, or practice sessions, and the community can be helpful in lending equipment at the outset.
Without access to funds from stalls at bouts themselves, however, sometimes you need to be more innovative. Fierce Valley recently held a concert as a fundraiser, and, as founder Kirk Jammett promises, they have plans for further action: “The novelty of the fundraisers tends to come from our own skaters' hobbies – we just try and sell what we're good at! Our next event is going to be a cabaret night!“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other advantage of big fundraisers is in spreading the word, although most leagues find that the enthusiasm of their members makes for the best medium.
Tiger Bay Brawlers’ Lola Coaster enthuses that “the majority of our advertising comes from word of mouth promotions through skaters and our friends and families and I think that’s where the roller derby community really shines. Those who do love it are so passionate about it and that passion is infectious, whether you’re directly involved or not.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also worth talking to your local skate shops and seeing if they’re prepared to offer you deals on the basic kit. Both the Minxters and the Nasty Nessies managed to arrange discounts for their skaters; the Nessies even managed to gain a coach in one of the owners.
Although as new to roller derby as the rest of the team, he is learning on the job, and applying his experience in teaching skateboarding to the role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can find someone with more coaching experience, however, it can work wonders: Fierce Valley have gained tremendously from initial coaching by Auld Reekie skater Ella-Bella Bang-Bang. As Grizabelta explains, “we were put in touch with the amazing Ella-Bella Bang-Bang by a mutual friend. Ella-Bella lives in our neck of the woods so helped us with our training right up until we passed our mins.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/roller-derby-newport-8-october-064tiger-bay-brawlerssimon-ayre.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-822" title="Roller Derby Newport 8 October 064Tiger Bay Brawlers,Simon Ayre" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/roller-derby-newport-8-october-064tiger-bay-brawlerssimon-ayre.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="511"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiger Bay Brawlers have also benefited from having an experienced skater to help kickstart their coaching, BB Bombshell bringing experience from her time in Victorian Roller Derby League in Australia. “BB definitely pushed us as athletes which has contributed to how successful we’ve been so far” say coaches Billie Pistol and Judge Redd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have access to an experienced skater, it’s not the end of the world; the majority of TBB’s coaching team, including head coach Judge Redd, have built up their experience from scratch; “We get new drills from bootcamps, guest coaches and online and keep up to date with strategy by watching games both in the UK and online, quite often we'll see something we'd like to try and create an exercise around it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the point of those coaches is to bring you up to speed on the first challenge of all new skaters: minimum skills. Lola Coaster is keen to emphasize that they should be treated positively: “I think a lot of people are terrified by the ‘pressure’ of minimum skills, but I think they’re a really good way of measuring how far skaters have come since they first strapped on a pair of quads. They’re a really good way of identifying skater strengths and weaknesses so you know what you have to work on and have a defined focus and goal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not just your skaters you need to concentrate on, however; a new league can’t afford to ignore the need for training referees and NSOs. Fierce Valley and York Minxters might have lucked out by being co-founded by Referees-in-training, but not all leagues can be so lucky. NSOs, are a little easier to acquire, as the traditional role of injured or otherwise indisposed skaters. NNRG’s Cherry Bow is a case in point, “I am planning on starting a family soon and I know I can't skate when I'm pregnant so I want to train as a NSO and a ref so I will still be actively involved.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you do start to grow, there’s always the potential for drama; everyone knows at least one league that’s experienced some kind of major or minor conflict. The Norfolk Brawds’ Jessica Whackit advises: “Don't take it personally when people realise it's not for them.  We had a huge number leave us before Christmas and you just have to remember that whenever you get a large group of people together, personality clashes will happen. With this in mind, setting up a coherent committee structure will see you through absolutely ANYTHING.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/roller-derby-newport-8-october-113tiger-bay-brawlerssimon-ayre.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-823" title="Roller Derby Newport 8 October 113Tiger Bay Brawlers,Simon Ayre" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/01/roller-derby-newport-8-october-113tiger-bay-brawlerssimon-ayre.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="390"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When all your skaters have passed their mins, the next challenge for the league is the big one: the first bout. It’s understandable to be a bit nervous; despite it being a closed-bout, Fierce Valley’s Grizabelta admits: “we're still quite terrified! And yet really, really excited... I still struggle to get my head round what we've achieved – the bout will be 2 weeks short of our first birthday so it'll be the best celebration!” Kirk Jammett agrees “As one of the refs I'm terrified of messing up badly and also scared of some angry girls screaming at me! … And as Ella-Bella is being our Head Ref – we really don't want to let her down as she's been such a fundamental element to our success.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, if the nerves, and the inevitable disadvantage of facing much more experienced opponents gets to you, you shouldn’t be discouraged. The Norfolk Brawds’ first bout ended in a 23:188 loss, but Jessica Whackit took the best side to the experience: ”We were lucky enough to have a big loss, but still come out feeling on top. If you can lose well, you can win nicely. Towards the end of the game, a lot of the crowd were shouting for us, and we sold so many t-shirts! We came away with a lot of new fans, as well as our faith in our team intact. We played and lost as a team, so we won really.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, Tiger Bay Brawlers have had an enviably successful first year. Based on their experience, Lola Coaster offered this parting advice: “It’s really hard to give a single piece of advice; I could write a whole article on do’s or do not’s. If I am only allowed one then I think I would have to say “be positive”. Yes you’ll have bad sessions, yes you’ll have weeks/months where you feel roller derby is taking over your life, yes you’ll get hurt at some point, yes you’ll miss sessions, you’ll be left out of the game roster and a whole host of other things that can make you think negatively and wonder why you bother. But be positive and stick at it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>nasty nessies roller girls</category><category>norfolk brawds</category><category>tiger bay brawlers</category><category>york minxters</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/01/26/brave-new-faces-the-writers-cut/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 20:28:55 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>