<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts by aoanla)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/authors/aoanla.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 13:35:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Dundee go to Nantes 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/04/17/west-track-story-2019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's been an exciting few years for Dundee Roller Derby, amongst rebranding and
renaming, an increasing number of international fixtures, and regular British Championships
attendance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team are continuing their onward trend by attending their second tournament in
France, the 7th edition of Nantes' West Track Story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;West Track Story 7 will see 5 WFTDA teams compete in a full round-robin tournament
for a total of 10 games. As with previous years, the event is truly international,
with each team representing a different country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Munich Rolling Rebels representing Germany (WFTDA rating 96.52, FTS Global 552.6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Namur Roller Girls representing Belgium (WFTDA rating 123.31, FTS Global 648.3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zurich City Roller Derby representing Switzerland (WFTDA rating 152.73, FTS Global 629.7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and, of course, the hosts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nantes Derby Girls representing France, (WFTDA rating 185.91, FTS Global 617.3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in addition to Dundee (WFTDA rating 101.41, FTS Global 590.9) .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The total "strength ratio", the ratio of predicted scores between the highest
and lowest rated, for the attending teams is about 3 by WFTDA, or 2 by FTS Global
ratings.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby attended a previous West Track Story (the 5th edition, in
2017), so this could be seen as becoming almost a Scottish tradition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Silvery Tayzers have not played any of the other teams in the tournament before
and coming in as underdogs, near the bottom of the rating range, will be wanting
to prove themselves with some upsets. That said, the ratings from FTS and WFTDA disagree
about both the absolute rankings, and the relative ratings of all the attendees, so there
is a lot to play for, statistically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dundee have already played one game this season, a tense down-to-the-wire away game against
Brighton Rockers, which they won by a single point. Their closest opponent, Munich, has yet to
play this season, so it's hard to tell their form this season; playing your first games in the season
in a sanctioned tournament can be a risk. (Hosts Nantes, thanks to the
Championnat de France season; Zurich, thanks to already attending a tournament this year;
and Namur already have multiple games under their belts in 2019, and will definitely
be warmed up for the ecent.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-Captain G-Wrecks told us, "We are incredibly excited to be a part of such a well known tournament. It is going to be an amazing challenge for us, but we have been working so hard together as a team to get us ready!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present, we do not know if West Track Story 7 will be streamed (the team providing
streams in previous years is not available), but you can follow scores on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/285428915354699/"&gt;Facebook
event&lt;/a&gt;, and, of course, on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/108273/overview"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/04/17/west-track-story-2019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 13:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby without Borders: One year catchup</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/derby-without-borders-one-year-catchup/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, we brought you an &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/05/derby-without-borders-an-interview-with-founder-mae-dae/"&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with Mae Dae, to talk about their fantastic project, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://derbywithoutborders.org/"&gt;Derby Without Borders&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, less than a year later, the project has gone from strength to strength, helping more leagues in more countries across the world, in more ways. With so much happening, it is past time to write an update on events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby Without Borders was founded in 2017, as a project initially intended to help leagues in places where it was cost-prohibitive to get kit and other basic resources (sometimes because roller skating just wasn’t a thing in that country, often also because the cost of items was just much higher than the average wage allowed). The idea was, and still is, that donor leagues or individuals could donate “lightly used” or even new, kit to DwB, and the project would distribute items to leagues in need worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="All the places Derby without Borders has provided help to teams, so far. (Black: kit donations achieved, Blue: “start up” support, Green: advice and translation, Yellow: coaching bootcamps (and other additional support), Red: pending kit donation.)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/DwB2019.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;All the places Derby without Borders has provided help to teams, so far. (Black: kit donations achieved, Blue: “start up” support, Green: advice and translation, Yellow: coaching bootcamps (and other additional support), Red: pending kit donation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we talked to Mae back in 2018, DwB had already successfully helped Sailor City Rollers (Buenos Aires, Argentina), Golden City Roller Derby (Johannesburg, South Africa) and the Cairollers (Cairo, Egypt) with donation packs. They’ve also collected for Roller Derby Beirut (Beirut, Lebanon) (in collaboration with Quad Skate Shop), but have had difficulties getting the kit into Lebanon. Since then, they’ve also been able to support Bangkok Roller Derby (Bangkok, Thailand), Toxic Lima Roller Derby (Lima, Peru), Kyoto Roller Derby (Kyoto, Japan), and Roller Derby Beijing (Beijing, China)…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…but Derby without Borders have also been extending their goals in order to help Roller Derby in other ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, DwB is no longer just Mae Dae: since the last time we spoke, DwB has recruited a second body in the UK, in the form of Rosie Peacock (who has also set up a third donation collection point in the UK). They’ve been providing much needed support, Mae admitting “Rosie has been absolutely pivotal and an amazing addition to the team - I don’t think DwB would have gotten this far without their commitment to the project”.
The project has also grown an Advisory Board, positioned to steer the project in the right directions. In recruiting for the board, Mae tells us that they “reached out specifically to have Skaters of Colour on the board: they’re on the board to help steer the project in the direction it wants to be heading, which means engaging with intersectional, inclusionary and anti-oppressive practices.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rosie and Mae were both representing the cause at this year’s European Rollerderby Organisational Conference (EROC 2019) in Berlin with a stall, and a session on “Removing barriers to accessibility in roller derby”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“It was great to be able to talk with the theme of diversity and inclusivity, and how it relates to DwB, because it really is at the foundation of all of the work that we’re doing - this idea that we need to take down barriers to access in order to make this a more inclusive sport,”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;said Mae. In addition, every time DwB has a stall somewhere, more people learn about the project, and offer to support it. At EROC, one of the attending leagues offered to host a collection at their next bout, and to raise funds for the project.
That said, DwB and EROC in some senses were looking in different directions whilst supporting the same ethos. EROC is, intentionally, focused on improving Roller Derby within Europe; whilst Derby without Borders is inherently about looking outside, and working on how to support Roller Derby in other places, building in inclusivity and adapting culture to support other regions from the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- comment
Add images --&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Mae Dae on the Derby without Borders stall at EROC 2019 (Image copyright: Michael Wittig / Bear City Roller Derby)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/MaeDae-EROC.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Mae Dae on the Derby without Borders stall at EROC 2019 (Image copyright: Michael Wittig / Bear City Roller Derby)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that spirit, then, EROC was also the last event that Mae attended before leaving Europe themself. With Rosie positioned in the UK, Mae has courageously moved to Bangkok, Thailand, allowing them to be physically closer to one big region that would benefit significantly from DwB’s support – South East Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“Moving to Bangkok to help develop SE Asian roller derby has definitely been huge, and really pivotal.” Mae told us,  “I’m really understanding the needs of the region a lot better than I did before - and just how different the scale of roller derby is in all of Asia!”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since being closer to the action, they’ve launched an initiative to provide “consultation” services to newer leagues, giving them support and advice from the ground up (not just on how to start up a league, but also on developing local cultural competency). The first beneficiary of this is the first ever Roller Derby team in Bali: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/hotlavarollers/"&gt;Hot Lava Rollers&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with many of DwB’s new initiatives, this started with a conversation, as Mae relates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“Someone who used to skate with Crime [City Rollers] - Glitter Punch - reached out to me; she’d heard about the project, from Hanna P, and she said ‘I live in Bali now, and I’m so sad that there’s no Roller Derby. I really kinda want to make a team, and I was wondering if you could help me’”.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present, Hot Lava Rollers are just two people, and one set of kit (Glitter’s), and the team is just starting to recruit and look for spaces and other resources. Meanwhile, Mae is actively providing mentorship, on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“I’m trying to get them all the other resources that they would need, so helping them develop everything from bylaws, policies, through to making a logo, getting them social media, just… everything.”
“We’re trying to focus on consistent communication - we talk once a week, even if it’s just a 20 minute check-in. I think also it will be a learning experience in how to help support someone in starting a league without being there - I’m in Bangkok and it’s not far, only an hour’s time difference - but still, not being physically there to put in the work in the same way that I would / am with Bangkok [is a challenge].”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst advice and support is very important, when it comes to developing Derby-specific skills, there’s nothing better than a good coach. So, DwB has also been using its connections to organise specific Coaching Bootcamps in those regions involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 27th April, DwB and Bangkok Roller Derby are co-hosting a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2104905746467908/"&gt;bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; run by Canberra Roller Derby League (and Team Korea)’s ShortStop; on the 12 October, Atlanta Rollergirls (and Team USA)’s Baller Shot Caller will be running a DwB &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/781786125525096/"&gt;organised bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; in Bali! A future Bootcamp is also planned for Cairo (to be hosted by the Cairollers, with Zipblock and Freight Train), but dates and funding are still in progress on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Hot Lava Rollers founders, Rustamia Primanisa and Glitter Punch, after their first meeting with Mae [Thanks to Hot Lava Rollers &amp;amp; DwB]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/HotLavaRollers.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Hot Lava Rollers founders, Rustamia Primanisa and Glitter Punch, after their first meeting with Mae [Thanks to Hot Lava Rollers &amp;amp; DwB]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to run a bootcamp in Bali, in particular, came as a pleasant surprise even to Mae themself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“When Baller [Shot Caller] had reached out to me to ask what she could help the project with, I said, ‘well, here’s all the places I could use help with coaching’, and I let her pick.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
And she said, ‘If I have to choose one, I would say Bali. It seems more secluded, and they probably have less resources’!&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“I said, ‘it’s just two people - there’s the potential you could be teaching 5 people minimum skills’.
Baller was completely okay with that, as the gain in awareness, and value in increased representation was worth it. We did choose a date later in the year to give time for recruitment, though.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having already organised their first DwB bootcamp with Hong Kong Roller Derby (coached by Rosie Peacock and Optimus Grime of Glasgow Men’s Roller Derby), Mae is confident, however, that both bootcamps will have significant regional attendance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“The fact that we had 3 girls from the UAE travel all the way to HK just so they could attend a bootcamp and play a game , just goes to show you how isolated people are - but also how hungry they are for it. What I’m discovering about SE Asian roller derby, and Middle Eastern roller derby. is that when these things happen people will come from across the region to attend and come together.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Bali, though, the bootcamp in Bangkok will also be significant for another reason, being the first time that Bangkok Roller Derby will field a full team to compete. The bootcamp will see two games - the usual Pan-Asian Spring Rollers v Pan-Asian Spring Rollers setup, followed by the history-making Bangkok versus Hong Kong bout!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bout flyer for the next DwB bootcamp, hosted by Bangkok Roller Derby. [Image: Bangkok Roller Derby, photo by Teddy Tse]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/DwB-Bangkok-flyer.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bout flyer for the next DwB bootcamp, hosted by Bangkok Roller Derby. [Image: Bangkok Roller Derby, photo by Teddy Tse]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mae has also been active in providing resources and accessibility in other ways: at present, Roller Derby resources are overwhelmingly available in English (with Spanish probably the next largest). Whilst the WFTDA rules have a translation to the second most widely read language in the world (Chinese), there’s almost no availability in Hindi (the 3rd) and Arabic (the 6th – and 3rd most read as a second language) – and the most spoken Slavic language in the world, Russian, has a similar lack of support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DwB has projects underway to translate resources into under-represented languages to increase accessibility – in the case of Arabic, with the support of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/UAERollerDerby/"&gt;UAE Roller Derby All-Stars&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.cairollers.com/"&gt;Cairollers&lt;/a&gt;. (We’ll be catching up with the Cairollers shortly in another article, as they also have exciting news.) Russian translations of the Short Track Roller Derby ruleset have already been produced, thanks to efforts from the White Night Furies, and Abu Dhabi Roller Derby’s Spinky, as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, Mae dreams of having a “database of different resources for leagues, in all the languages; so if a league needs a framework for a code of conduct in Spanish, they can just go to the database and find something to base it on”. That’s for the future, however: the current effort is focused on getting basic rules and coaching resources translated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as translation, another issue, especially for countries with more filtered access to the Internet, can simply be access to resources at all. In China, for example, common hosts for Roller Derby resources like YouTube, Google Drive, Facebook, Twitter, Twitch, Medium and WordPress are all either permanently or irregularly blocked. Derby Without Borders is actively working with the Chinese Roller Derby community to provide access to the resources that the community needs, using hosts which are acceptable to the Chinese government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Derby without Borders continues to pursue its original goal of providing kit for skaters, as well. One of the first things that Mae noticed at Bangkok was that many of the skaters had inflexible, heavy mouthguards designed for Muay Thai. As theytold us, this isn’t really ideal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“you can’t really speak when you’re wearing them, and can barely breathe in them. So I just emailed SISU and said ‘hey, can you like just give us 20 mouthguards’ and they were like ‘yeah, sure, and just shipped them over’.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as SISU, other derby-related businesses - Steaks, Riedell, and Bont - have shown interest in supporting the project, especially as it has gained more visibility in the community. (Bont-sponsored skater Shortshop has managed to provide a set of wheels as a “prize” at her bootcamp in Bangkok, for example.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bangkok Roller Derby with SISU donated mouthguards, thanks to DwB [Image: Derby without Borders]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/Bangkok-SISU.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby with SISU donated mouthguards, thanks to DwB [Image: Derby without Borders]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this additional activity, however, is only sustainable if Derby without Borders continues to grow itself. Mae is currently working towards a new model for the organisation: regional “chapters” which can help to organise and manage the effort which DwB brings. (The Asia chapter will almost certainly be the first to be established, with recruitment happening now.)
The project is already growing fast enough to need this right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“One thing that I’m learning is understanding my own bandwidth and capability - how much I can do as one person.” Mae told us “Particularly, at this point, I’m doing all of this work because I want to do it - there’s no funding. Understanding my own bandwidth has been important because I’ve had two people reach out to me who were interested in doing the same thing in India, and whilst I absolutely want to help someone start a league in India, I think I might need to focus on one at a time, for now. I think with them I’m going to have to take a step back.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team India Roller Derby have since agreed to help support these potential seeds of Roller Derby, in collaboration with DwB, but the project still needs more people - and leagues - to join in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One Derby without Borders initiative which has been active for the start is the idea of “Sibling Leagues”: an opportunity for established leagues to pair up with specific leagues elsewhere in the world to offer them support. This support could be in terms of equipment donations, as the scheme was originally formulated with Texas collecting kit to donate directly to the Cairollers. However, as DwB evolves, it could equally be provided as knowledge exchange, guidance, and political and social support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“I would love to see that kind of Sibling league relationship develop with more leagues.” Mae told us, “instead of needing to come through DwB [to give support], it could be more like a mentorship: one league can mentor another league, and develop all their resources between the two of them. That’s what’s going to make it more sustainable in the long run [and] that’s the point of the project, creating these things for the sake of sustainability.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Quito, Ecuador’s Forajidas Roller Derby, post-recruitment in January. (Photo: Forajidas Roller Derby)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/04/Forajidas_roller_derby.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Quito, Ecuador’s Forajidas Roller Derby, post-recruitment in January. (Photo: Forajidas Roller Derby)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst we’ve mostly focused on activities in Asia in this update, that should not imply that DwB is not working for other regions as well. Mae told us that they have been in contact with Forajidas Roller Derby, who are currently trying to (re)establish the only league in Ecuador (in Quito, the capital).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst the Forajidas have a GoFundMe ( &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gofundme.com/help-bring-roller-derby-to-ecuador"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/help-bring-roller-derby-to-ecuador&lt;/a&gt; ), they also need guidance and support in forming their league. Mae is actively looking for either a Sibling League, or a coach, or both, who can help to support the new team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, as well as helping to nurture and advise new and developing leagues, DwB is also working to support Roller Derby in other ways. Derby Without Borders can host crowdfunders for such leagues to allow them to raise funds more easily: at present, they’re hosting a GoFundMe to support Buenos Aires’ 2×4 Roller Derby on their current international travel requirements. (You can donate here: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gofundme.com/2x4-international-tour-2019"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/2x4-international-tour-2019&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derby without Borders is open to assisting any league or team who need their support: regardless of if that’s in SE Asia where Mae is currently focused, or in Latin America, the Middle East, Eastern Europe or Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you, or your league, or your company, want to support Derby without Borders in any way mentioned in this article (or another way you can think of), we encourage you to join in. Derby without Borders can only get better as it gets bigger - and it can only get bigger with more of the community pitching in to support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can support DwB via their Donation page [ &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://derbywithoutborders.org/donate"&gt;https://derbywithoutborders.org/donate&lt;/a&gt; ] and by buying their merch (which also lets you raise awareness of the project by wearing it everywhere) [ &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://derbywithoutborders.org/merchandise"&gt;https://derbywithoutborders.org/merchandise&lt;/a&gt; ]. Mae Dae and DwB central can be contacted by email at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:maedae@skatingoutofbounds.com"&gt;maedae@skatingoutofbounds.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2x4 roller derby</category><category>argentina</category><category>bali</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>bootcamps</category><category>cairollers</category><category>china</category><category>crowdfunding</category><category>derby without borders</category><category>dubai roller derby</category><category>ecuador</category><category>egypt</category><category>forajidas roller derby</category><category>hot lava rollers</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>russia</category><category>thailand</category><category>uae roller derby all-stars</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/derby-without-borders-one-year-catchup/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 11:17:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UAE All-Stars: A National Team for the Emirates</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/03/20/uae-all-stars-a-national-team-for-the-emirates/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst we often talk about Roller Derby in North America, and Europe and Australasia, and somewhat less about Latin America (at least, in English - &lt;em&gt;en español,&lt;/em&gt; a lot is said) we speak much less about Roller Derby in the rest of the World. Part of this is because of a similar tendency to only talk about teams which compete internationally... of which there are much fewer outside of those above regions. This is a self-fulfilling prophecy, of course, since isolated teams, inherently, find it hard to find any local opponents: and they can't find international opponents if people don't talk about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United Arab Emirates has had two Roller Derby leagues: Dubai Roller Derby, and Abu Dhabi Roller Derby, for more than 6 years, the two forming within a few months of each other in late 2012. It's been hard for them to find opponents elsewhere, however, especially given the roster sizes for the two. 
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this year, members of both teams decided to collaborate on a bigger thing: a Emirates-wide Travel Team, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/UAERollerDerby/"&gt;UAE Roller Derby All-Stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, representing the country on the international stage. (Between them, Dubai and Abu Dhabi represent about 2/3s of the population of the UAE, but there are 5 other Emirates which could still develop teams.)
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spoke to two of the main agents of this initiative, Mean Curls and Inga Knee’her, about how this got organised, and what their plans are.
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27922} --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="UAE Roller Derby Logo (&amp;amp;quot;UAE All-Stars&amp;amp;quot; forming part of a circle in grey, with the Arabic name in green on top, designed to include the image of a roller skate in the negative space)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/fb/52672994_267004467546689_505072778026680320_n.jpg" title="UAE Roller Derby Logo ('UAE All-Stars' forming part of a circle in grey, with the Arabic name in green on top, designed to include the image of a roller skate in the negative space)"&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As long ago as 2013, Dubai and Abu Dhabi Roller Derby had discussed the possibility of forming a national, potentially WFTDA-sanctioned, joint team. However, with both leagues also organising their individual affairs, it wasn't possible to achieve this until recently: there wasn't enough time, or experience, in the teams to build the bigger plan.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018, however, Inga Knee'her became one of the most experienced new members of Dubai Roller Derby - transferring to the team after 10 years of experience in Steel City Roller Derby (at the time WFTDA D 1 team), and Tokyo Roller Derby. As well as spearheading the adoption of Rolla Skate Club's Short Track Roller Derby ruleset to enable Dubai to play more derby in more places, she's also become part of the trio behind the UAE All-Stars.
With Spinky (president of Abu Dhabi Roller Derby) and Mean Curls, the plan has gone from a discussion over ice-cream to reality.
As Inga and Mean Curls tell it: "In less than two months, we [] created the team, organized weekly practices focusing on Short Track coached by Inga, and played our first international game in Hong Kong as part of Pan Asian Spring Rollers (prompting the self-proclaimed name of the “Get Sh*t Done Team” :D)."
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Dubai and Abu Dhabi also the most populous cities in the UAE (and their eponymous emirates), and fairly closely located, the All-Stars can alternate training between the two easily, helping to build a sense of equal partnership in the national team.
At present, the team is working on helping to develop visibility and interest in Roller Derby - and Roller  skating - in the UAE, where historically there hasn't been much. (At present, all of Dubai and Abu Dhabi's kit comes from abroad via international shipping.)
One aim of this increased visibility is towards developing the skill levels for their member skaters, by providing opportunities for higher level play that would otherwise be inaccessible. 
Inga's contacts with the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers (the Roller Derby collaboration between Beijing, Shanghai, Hong-Kong and Bangkok &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/07/east-asian-derbys-new-spring-rollers/"&gt;we've covered previously&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) immediately paid off in this sense. Having played against the Spring Rollers as part of the Women's Roller Derby Japan team at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/19/the-tomodachi-derby-tournament-the-teams/"&gt;Tomodachi Roller Derby tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in Okinawa (2017), she was hoping for opponents to play Short Track derby with.
As it happens, the timing of the Spring Rollers bout against Hong-Kong was too good to pass up: Mean Curls, Spinky, and Inga were able to make the trip to join Pan Asia v. Hong Kong as members of the Spring Rollers team.
(Their team ended up winning too, 159 to HKRD's 127.)
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That bout also helped to build even more contacts: Derby Without Borders' founder Mae Dae has recently relocated to Bangkok, and was present as part of the Hong Kong event. We're promised future collaborations with Derby without Borders, supporting their mission in the Middle East and Asia so watch this space! (Mae themself has also been busy since moving to Bangkok, and we'll be catching up with them in a future article.) 
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27923,"width":561,"height":842} --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Two of UAE All-Stars' skaters (Mean Curls, Spinky) in blue as part of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers team against hosts Hong Kong Roller Derby. Photograph by Teddy Tse" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/fb/dsc_5798-2.jpg" title="Two of UAE All-Stars' skaters (Mean Curls, Spinky) in blue as part of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers team against hosts Hong Kong Roller Derby. Photograph by Teddy Tse"&gt;Two of UAE All-Stars' skaters (Mean Curls, Spinky) in blue as part of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers team against hosts Hong Kong Roller Derby. Photograph by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teddy.tse.12"&gt;Teddy Tse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At home, they're focusing on Short Track Roller Derby as it makes practice much more accessible: not only is it easier in terms of numbers, the smaller space needed (the Short Track track fits inside a standard basketball court) makes it much easier, and cheaper, to find spaces to practice in. 
With the UAE's regulations limiting other opportunities (public events need licenses, for example), having more options in hosting always helps. 
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, UAE All-Stars aren't limiting themselves to a single ruleset for future games. Inga and Mean Curls emphasised "we are interested in any and all roller derby opportunities for our skaters. We are lucky to live in a place with direct flights to so many cities, making it relatively easy for us to visit other teams as well as to host events in the future."  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, whilst the team has not ruled out applying to join the WFTDA in the future, they're also setting their sites on the most international of competitions. 
"Our ultimate goal is to represent the UAE at the next Roller Derby World Cup," the team told us, adding "Mean Curls is the only current Emirati roller derby skater (that we know of) and will represent us on the Nations Committee".
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>abu dhabi roller derby</category><category>articles</category><category>dubai roller derby</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><category>short track roller derby</category><category>uae all-stars roller derby</category><category>uae roller derby all-stars</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/03/20/uae-all-stars-a-national-team-for-the-emirates/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 12:27:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Short Track Worldwide Update (2019 Feb)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/03/01/short-track-worldwide-update-2019-feb/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/26/short-track-roller-derby-a-first-scottish-test/"&gt;first article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://rollaskateclub.com/lets-rolla/"&gt;Short Track Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, back in 2018, the new ruleset has continued to spread, in almost all the places in the world where Roller Derby is played.
As such, we thought we’d follow up, just 4 months later, with some of the exciting developments in Short Track worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, as readers of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://whataboutmagazine.com/"&gt;What A Bout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; magazine will already know, Short Track Roller Derby has spread further-and-wider than we could have hoped: to Russia, and Dubai, in the United Arab Emirates, already. You should read the full article in WAB &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://whataboutmagazine.com/2019/01/20/what-a-bout-issue-3-winter-2019/"&gt;Issue 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for full details, but look out for several Short Track tournaments in Moscow, and other Russian cities later in the year. Dubai’s interest in Short Track has also led to bigger things which we’ll get to later in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short Track is continuing to enable more teams to play derby, even now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Poland, Gdańsk’s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/551140512034275/"&gt;Chrome Sirens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are playing their first ever public game, thanks to Short Track rules enabling them to put together two competitive teams (and use more accessible venues). This double-header event will be coming to the city in the middle of next month - March 16th!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Americas, Short Track Derby is also taking off: ruleset creators Rolla Skate Club having provided initial impetus with a comprehensive series of trial sessions across Canada and the North-west of the USA. In Latin America, meanwhile, there is interest in Buenos Aires, Argentina, in exploring the ruleset, as it solves several of the challenges of the many teams in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27916,"width":600,"height":426,"linkDestination":"custom"} --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Illinois Valley Vixens Roller Derby during their first public bout under Short Track Rules.(Photo used by permission of Dave Schrader under license. [not covered by site CC license] )" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/fb/img_6131-crop-1.jpg" title="Illinois Valley Vixens Roller Derby during their first public bout under Short Track Rules.(Photo used by permission of Dave Schrader under license. [not covered by site CC license])"&gt;Illinois Valley Vixens Roller Derby during their first public bout under Short Track Rules.(Photo used by permission of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/korfan/collections/"&gt;Dave Schrader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; under license. [not covered by site CC license] )
&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the USA, though, public bouts have already started, with the ruleset enabling teams to play their first games in years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/IVVRD/"&gt;Illinois Valley Vixens Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, who played their first public bout for 3 years thanks to Short Track back in February, the ruleset has been a revelation. Whilst some venue issues meant that they had to modify the track slightly, the bout was a complete success - despite only using word of mouth and social media for advertising, they managed to fill all the available seating. Speaking for the league, Lemon Squeezer told us : “We now know that a smaller track definitely does not mean less exciting or intense, quite the opposite! I can't remember a time I have heard a crowd this engaged before and the feedback from spectators was that they are looking forward to the next one and bringing friends. We also had several former skaters come to check it out that are now interested in coming back.”. 
I.M.GROOT added, “The fact that all players have to both jam and block really takes you out of your comfort zone. It pushes you to use all the skills you have learned, not just the ones you prefer. Short Track has the ability to really push skaters to be stronger, better and more adaptable in game play.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an even more striking mode, the USA has also brought us the first ever “Short Track” league: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pstrollerderby.com/"&gt;Pittsburgh Short Track Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, founded by a group of skaters who retired from “competitive” Roller Derby, but still wanted to play a friendlier version of the sport. Their league aim, as expressed on their website and Facebook page, “We are a group of friends who wanted to create a safe, stress free environment to get together and skate. Community over competition.” encapsulates the entire point of Short Track as a ruleset and community. (You can find out more about them on social media and their website.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further in the future, there’s also exciting news of potentially the first ever international Short Track Roller Derby Tournament.  The newly created &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/UAERollerDerby/"&gt;UAE All-Stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the United Arab Emirates’ official travel team, are exploding onto the scene, and one of their first public plans is to play Short Track Derby! Formed of skaters from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DubaiRollerDerby/"&gt;Dubai Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ADRollerDerby/"&gt;Abu Dhabi Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the team plan to play all kinds of Derby, but Short Track is definitely a solid component of their goals. [We have more about UAE All-Stars themselves in another new article here, which we’re going to publish soon - and their first ever public game &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/495068457564329/"&gt;will be this weekend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, 2nd March, in Hong Kong, as part of the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27917,"width":576,"height":384} --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="UAE Roller Derby All-Stars practising on the Short Track [courtesy of UAE All-Stars]" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/fb/53180456_272367973677005_4491993895592263680_n-e1551445852446.jpg" title="UAE Roller Derby All-Stars practising on the Short Track [courtesy of UAE All-Stars]"&gt;UAE Roller Derby All-Stars practising on the Short Track [courtesy of UAE All-Stars]
&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the support of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gogogent.be/en/home-default/"&gt;GO-GO Gent Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, who had been investigating hosting an experimental Short Track clinic for several months, UAE All-Stars will be travelling to Belgium on the 1st and 2nd of June. The first day will be a Short Track Roller Derby training workshop, allowing the experienced skaters from Dubai’s testing of the rules (and potentially other skaters who’ve tried Short Track from the rest of Europe) to explain and demonstrate the potential of the ruleset to attendees.  
The second day will be a tournament event: the structure of which is still under development. Teams are welcome to participate from across Europe, and we know that there’s been interest from several regions already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even further in the future, there’s the possibility of Short Track bootcamps in other parts of Europe, including the UK, and other plans afoot about which we can’t speak at this time. Stay tuned for further updates as they occur!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dubai roller derby</category><category>in the news</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><category>polish roller derby</category><category>short format tournaments</category><category>short track roller derby</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/03/01/short-track-worldwide-update-2019-feb/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 13:12:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Victory or Valhalla returns: Waterford's annual derby tournament back for a second year.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/02/11/victory-or-valhalla-returns-waterfords-annual-derby-tournament-back-for-a-second-year/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously on this blog, we've written about Waterford ViQueens' innovative use of the PivotStar rules to hold a fast, efficient and &lt;strong&gt;fun&lt;/strong&gt; Roller Derby tournament in the south of Ireland: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/05/21/viqueens-victorious-valhalla-a-test-for-pivotstar-rules/"&gt;LINK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
After the success of the initial tournament, where 6 teams from across Ireland (and also a single team from France) competed in a faster-paced event, Waterford are doing it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27911,"align":"center"} --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Waterford ViQueens Logo" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/fb/waterfordviqueens.png" title="Waterford ViQueens Logo"&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/477884896068750/"&gt;Victory or Vahalla #2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; will be a &lt;strong&gt;WFTDA-gender policy&lt;/strong&gt; tournament held in Waterford on the &lt;strong&gt;27th April&lt;/strong&gt;, aimed at teams from around &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings/women/women_europe"&gt;FTS Women's Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;"&amp;gt; rating &lt;strong&gt;400&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;500&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tournament will be played under &lt;strong&gt;PivotStar&lt;/strong&gt; rules, a variant ruleset developed to allow efficient production of tournaments with less load on officials. This shouldn't put anyone off - the main things that change are: &lt;strong&gt;skaters score 1 point per pass&lt;/strong&gt; (not 1 per skater), there are &lt;strong&gt;no runbacks&lt;/strong&gt; (track cuts and returns are relative to where you left the track, not relative position of skaters), and games are &lt;strong&gt;20 minutes long&lt;/strong&gt; with no timeouts. 
This makes for a fun tournament event, with slightly faster play and different tactics than a WFTDA-standard bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be the first of several planned "non-standard rules" tournaments in Europe this year (there's at least two in Russia coming up, as well as one or two currently in planning), so we advise people to get in on the fun and not miss out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waterford is accessible for international travellers from the airports at Cork Shannon and Dublin, as well from the ferry terminal at Rosslare (for people travelling from Wales or France).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams can sign up via Google Forms here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScCs5srTnpBrSqkZpT_S8Ndnd5OLFJI9txHUXQruBMezWbSxQ/viewform"&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScCs5srTnpBrSqkZpT_S8Ndnd5OLFJI9txHUXQruBMezWbSxQ/viewform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>international derby</category><category>pivotstar rules</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>waterford viqueens</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/02/11/victory-or-valhalla-returns-waterfords-annual-derby-tournament-back-for-a-second-year/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 11:12:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>National Champions 2018 - a Review of the Year.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/01/09/national-champions-2018-a-review-of-the-year/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor's note: due to burn-out, and the increasingly obnoxious changes on the Wordpress backend, our end of year feature content has been delayed. We'll be releasing it over the next few weeks as we complete it. This is the first item in this content. We apologise for the delays incurred, and will update you all on the future of SRD when we know what that is.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the growth of Roller Derby worldwide, there has also come increasing regional organisation. Since 2010, and especially since the first Roller Derby World Cup in 2011 focussed thoughts on National structures, a number of nations, and nation-like entities, have begun organising various "National Tournaments" within themselves. At SRD, we consider these to be as important as any other large scale tournament - such as WFTDA or MRDA events - especially as they can also be more inclusive than such series due to reduced travel costs and membership requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, we'd like to highlight the winners of each such tournament series we're aware of in 2018 - and briefly cover the tournaments themselves. As a historical resource, we also host a summary of all of the winners of the tournaments (and some references for them) here: &lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/NationalTournaments.html"&gt;National Tournaments (2010-)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;We'll start with the two largest such events (it's hard to judge which is larger, as they have exchanged places on various metrics year to year):&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;UK&amp;amp;Ireland ("&lt;a href="https://www.britishchamps.com/"&gt;British Championships&lt;/a&gt;")&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;British Champs has been running since 2015, and has made various changes to its structure over the years (the most recent to improve inclusion and accessibility). It is structured as a multi-tiered divisional system, with each "skill level" tier divided into one or more geographical "divisions"; teams promote/relegate between tiers between seasons. Since 2016, Champs has officially run parallel tournaments for WFTDA- and MRDA- conforming teams, and has also allowed competition from non-A teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, the WFTDA-side tournament winners, topping Tier 1 convincingly were: &lt;strong&gt;Central City Roller Derby (Birmingham), &lt;/strong&gt;not only winning every game against their opponents, but also achieving a significantly higher points difference than the second spot team, Liverpool.
2018 has been a good year for Birmingham teams, as the city's other team, Birmingham Blitz Dames, also hosted the first ever WFTDA Continental Cup in Europe later in the season.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MRDA-side tournament  was topped extremely impressively by &lt;strong&gt;New Wheeled Order (Manchester M)&lt;/strong&gt;, also delivering a huge points-difference advantage over second place Tyne and Fear. New Wheeled Order have had a very good few years, and we expect even more from them in 2019.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;France ("Championnat de France Roller Derby")&lt;/h4&gt;
The French National tournament series is, like the similarly sized British Champs, organised into Tiers by strength, and also loosely divided into geographical regions. (Unlike British Champs, there is competition across regions within a tier; also unlike BC, the Championnat is run directly as part of the French NGB, the FFRS.) The Championnat de France has &lt;em&gt;Feminin&lt;/em&gt;- and &lt;em&gt;Masculin&lt;/em&gt;- parallel tournaments; some leagues submit teams to the tournament which differ from their Travel teams, and the relaxed structure of the tournament also allows for "combined" team submissions from cooperating leagues. Unusually, compared to many of the other tournaments listed here, the French Championnat is fitted to the French sporting season (roughly following the European school year), and so starts in the previous winter, and finishes in the early summer each year.
&lt;p&gt;Repeating their victory in 2017, &lt;strong&gt;Nothing Toulouse (Roller Derby Toulouse)&lt;/strong&gt; retained the French Championship this year. They remain one of the few non-WFTDA member leagues to hold a Championship position in their home country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Undefeated champions since the Championnat started in 2016, &lt;strong&gt;Quad Guards (Toulouse M)&lt;/strong&gt; continued their streak for another year in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Whilst the French and British tournaments are the largest, they are not the longest running National tournaments. Next, we're going to cover the longest running tournaments in modern Derby, the four which started in 2012:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Sweden (Swedish Roller Derby Seriespel)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Swedish National Tournament,  . Like larger tournaments, the Series is split into tiers ("serien"), with the Eliteserien being the top tier. More recently, Elite tier teams have been allowed to differ from the Travel teams for their league. There is only a WFTDA-gender tournament in Sweden, to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Crime City Rollers (Malmö)&lt;/strong&gt; retained their Championship title for the third year running, placing them one more victory behind Stockholm's streak of 4 wins (from 2012 to 2015).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Finland (Suomi Cup)&lt;/h4&gt;
Finland's National Tournament is structured rather like the Swedish version, including the tendency of Elite tier leagues to submit non-Travel team rosters to the tournament. For the first time, in 2019 the Suomi Cup will be open to non-Finnish teams (making it an interesting extension of "National"), as St Petersburg Roller Derby A, the White Night Furies, compete.
&lt;p&gt;For the first time in 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Oulu Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; achieved the Championship title, breaking a run of alternating wins by Helsinki and Kallio over the previous 6 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Northern Finland also holds its own tournament - the Pohjola Cup - which started the tradition of welcoming non-Finnish participants in previous years via St Petersburg. So, in some ways, it sets the trend for its higher-profile southern relative.]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Mexico (Torneo Nacional de Roller Derby)&lt;/h4&gt;
Mexico's National Tournament series has been organised by their national governing body, the Asociación Mexicana de Roller Derby, since it began in 2012. We've covered the leadup to the current season on the blog previously here: &lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/18/mexican-national-championships-2018/"&gt;Mexican National Tournament article&lt;/a&gt;. The series consists of a series of playoffs, selected by rating/ranking in the Mexican league tables (which work using the WFTDA rating scheme), with two divisions. As with many other nations, there are "varonil" and "femenil" parallel tournaments, corresponding to WFTDA- and MRDA- policies.
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Mexico City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; retained their title for a three-year streak of victories, despite&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Varonil side of the tournament, &lt;strong&gt;Disorder Roller Derby (Mexico City M)&lt;/strong&gt; also began a streak, retaining their title from 2017.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Colombia&lt;/h4&gt;
Whilst Colombia has run a National Tournament since 2012, the series has had a somewhat more complex past than the others in this category, with a couple of restructurings, and a hiatus from 2015 to 2016. In its current form, the Tournament consists of two parallel series - a multi-fixture tournament for Bogotá's many leagues (the "Torneo Distrito"), and a separate one for teams in the rest of Colombia (the "Western Region" tournament), with the top teams from both then competing at the Torneo Nacional finals. (&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/01/the-5th-colombian-national-tournament-2018-so-far/"&gt;We've written more about the 2018 series here.&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;p&gt;2018's Champions, &lt;strong&gt;Bogotá Bone Breakers&lt;/strong&gt;, also retained the Bogotá title in 2018, as well as continuing a three win streak in the national series (albeit across that 2 year gap).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Slightly less venerable than the oldest tournaments, but not in the size rank as Britain and France, our next grouping also covers a large geographical area.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Brazil (Brasileirão de Roller Derby)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brazil's national Championship, the Brasileirão, is a single-fixture event at present, which started as least as long ago as 2013 (there's some evidence it started earlier). Due to the distribution of teams in the country, it's semi-invitational, although the highest rated teams in Brazil always attend. (&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/11/the-brasileirao-brazils-national-championships-at-8/"&gt;We've written more about the history of the tournament here.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018's Brasileirão winners were &lt;strong&gt;Gray City Rebels (São Paulo)&lt;/strong&gt;, retaining the title from 2017 (and resisting Ladies of Helltown's attempts to take back the title from 2016).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Chile (Torneo X / Torneo X-Men)&lt;/h4&gt;
Chile has one of the youngest National Tournaments in Latin America, with the first Torneo X beginning in 2015. Year on year, it has gained more participants, and has had to change structure multiple times to accommodate this, currently using a playoffs and finals structure. For the first time in 2018, B teams have been allowed to compete, enabling Chile's strongest (and only WFTDA-member) league, Metropolitan Roller Derby, to compete with its Bayonetas.
Since 2017, there has also been a MRDA-gender tournament, the Torneo X-Men, run in parallel, and loosely associated with the original WFTDA-gender event.
(&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/26/chilean-national-championships-2018-torneo-x-returns/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We've covered an intro to this year's Torneo X earlier on the blog.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;p&gt;For the first time ever, 2018's winners are a B-team: &lt;strong&gt;Bayonetas (Metropolitan B | Santiago)&lt;/strong&gt;, taking a fairly commanding win in the final bout.
In the Torneo X-Men, which finished earlier in the year, &lt;strong&gt;Terror S-Quad (Santiago M)&lt;/strong&gt; were victorious for a second time in a row.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Germany (Bundesliga Roller Derby)&lt;/h4&gt;
The German National Tournament, or Bundesliga, formally started in 2015, as a multi-tier tournament run by the German NGB, Roller Derby Deutschland (RDD). In this form, its history has been tracked by Derbyposition.de since the beginning; the structure is much like the much larger French and British tournaments, but without the need for multiple geographical divisions, due to its smaller number of teams. (There were two previous events which might count as "German National Tournaments", in 2010 and 2013, but they are not part of the modern event.)
As with several other National series in nations with very high rated WFTDA-member leagues, those leagues have begun sending "non-Travel teams" to represent them in the tournament.
&lt;p&gt;For the first time in the tournament's history, &lt;strong&gt;Dresden Pioneers&lt;/strong&gt; comprehensively won the Bundesliga Division 1 in 2018.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Australia (Australian National Tournament &amp;amp; Australian Men's Nationals)&lt;/h4&gt;
Unusually, Australia has not had a formally denoted "National Tournament" for WFTDA leagues (although you could claim that the Great Southern Slam counts, given the scope of its attendance). The Australian Men's Roller Derby organisation, on the other hand, has organised an Australian Men's Nationals since 2015, as a single fixture tournament towards the end of the year.
More recently, an unusual "State-teams" style National Tournament has been launched (for the first time in 2018), with WFTDA- and MRDA- gender legs, but we're not sure if this counts as a National tournament in the same sense as the other events in this list.
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Victoria Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; won the Australian Men's Nationals, having lost it for the first time ever in 2017 (to Tasmania!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;For our final grouping, we have another eclectic selection of Nations, all united in having run a National series for 3 years or less.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;New Zealand (Top 10 Championships)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Zealand's "Top 10 Championships" have been running since 2016, although information on the second year of their organisation is a little patchy due to website bitrot. In general, the series is a flat round-robin style event, distributed across the year, with no tiering or geographical structure. As far as we are aware, there's only a WFTDA-gender version of the tournament so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Dead End Derby (Christchurch)&lt;/strong&gt; won the Top 10 Championships for the first time (ending Wellington's Richter City's streak of 2 years).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Spain (Campeonato Nacional de Roller Derby)&lt;/h4&gt;
The Spanish National tournament is a single event affair, due to the relatively small number of potential competitors in Spain at present. Organised by the Spanish National Governing body, the single tournament sees the top teams in the country play for victory in a single elimination structure. The event has run since 2016, with an additional MRDA parallel event introduced in 2017.
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Roller Derby Madrid&lt;/strong&gt; continued their unbroken win streak since the start of the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, 2018's winners in the other division were &lt;strong&gt;MadRiders (Madrid M)&lt;/strong&gt;, also continuing an unbroken win since last year.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Austria&lt;/h4&gt;
Austria's National tournament only started in 2017; before then, there was effectively only one sufficiently developed team in the country (Vienna Roller Derby), and so no way to hold such an event. Due to the small number of teams, the Austrian National Championship is a single fixture event; and due to the dearth of MRDA teams, it has only a WFTDA leg.
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Vienna Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; retained their title from 2017, although competition within the rest of the teams was strong, Vienna have a significant experience advantage in their country.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;South Africa (National Derby Fest)&lt;/h4&gt;
South Africa have held a National Championship event since 2016, although that first event included "home teams" from some of the leagues involved. As South Africa has very few leagues with travel teams, this event is a single fixture which also focuses on developing the sport within the nation. (&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/31/south-africas-national-derby-fest-2018-three-years-of-festivals/"&gt;We've written more about the history of the event here.&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, Johannesburg's &lt;strong&gt;Golden City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt; retained their win streak since the dawn of the tournament.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Belgium (Roller Derby Belgium National Tournament)&lt;/h4&gt;
Finally, we come to the newest National tournament in our list: Belgium. The Belgian national tournament, organised by rd.BE, the Belgian NGB, ran for the first time this year, as a year-long series of round-robin fixtures within tiers. (Initial tiers were drawn from FTS Europe ratings.) From the start, the rd.BE event has had a WFTDA- and an MRDA- leg.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antwerp Roller Derby (One Love Roller Dolls)&lt;/strong&gt; are the first ever holders of the rd.BE Championship title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the MRDA leg, Brussels' &lt;strong&gt;Manneken Beasts&lt;/strong&gt; achieved the first ever Championship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Special mention:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Japan (Derby Nights 4x4)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst it's structure is rather different to every other event in this list, we should note that Japan has also had a Tokyo-series first for the first time in 2018. The Derby Nights 4x4 ("DN4x4") series was a multi-fixture event with "womens" and "mens" legs, open to leagues of all affiliations in Japan. (As such, the women's division included both the World Skate/FIRS affiliated Spiral Cats, and all of the WFTDA-affiliated leagues in the Tokyo metropolitan area, from Tokyo Roller Derby to the independent Kamikaze Badass.) This was a unique ruleset, with, we believe, 4 skaters per competing team, and very short period and jam lengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;strong&gt;Neon Roller Monsters&lt;/strong&gt; (the submitted team from Tokyo Roller Derby) won the women's division.
The new-in-2018 team, &lt;strong&gt;Tokyo Bar Hoppers&lt;/strong&gt;, won the men's division (which had only 2 teams this year!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're excited to see what happens with this tournament format, and if it expands beyond the Tokyo region to the rest of Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>asociación mexicana de roller derby</category><category>australian men's nationals</category><category>austrian nationals</category><category>brasileirão de roller derby</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>bundesliga</category><category>campeonato nacional de roller derby</category><category>championnat de france</category><category>derby nights 4x4</category><category>international derby</category><category>national derby fest</category><category>rd.be</category><category>suomi cup</category><category>swedish seriespel</category><category>top 10 championships</category><category>torneo nacional de roller derby</category><category>torneo x</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/01/09/national-champions-2018-a-review-of-the-year/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 16:53:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-US/Canadian Derby Roundup: 22nd December to end of year Edition</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/18/non-us-canadian-derby-roundup-22nd-december-to-end-of-year-edition/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;We’re bringing you another roundup of the upcoming Roller Derby this weekend from across the world. As always, we’re using &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/" data-mce-href="http://flattrackstats.com/"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for much of this information – for regions with less good coverage, we also do a bit of intensive searching using a tool which scans the Facebook events of Roller Derby leagues known to &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://derbylisting.com/dl/grid/" data-mce-href="http://derbylisting.com/dl/grid/"&gt;Derby Listing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Predictions of bouts are from FTS, if possible, and from our own &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRankv2.html" data-mce-href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRankv2.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; where FTS cannot make predictions (for example: Latin America, or non-MRDA men’s bouts). (SRDRank also has recent WFTDA rankings, including the 31st June ranking, as well as SRDRank, and allows you to make predictions from them.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;If we’ve missed you from our roundup, please let us know! [Or add yourselves to FTS and/or Derbylisting]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We're trying a new colour coding this week, to differentiate &lt;span style="color:#800000;" data-mce-style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;BOUTS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; from &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;RECRUITMENTS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style="color:#993300;" data-mce-style="color: #993300;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;OPEN SCRIM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;s, and &lt;span style="color:#008000;" data-mce-style="color: #008000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BOOTCAMP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;s.
&lt;p&gt;This roundup is our end of year roundup, so covers everything until the new year (also because there's just not much stuff happening).&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/EUR_map-1.png?w=1024" alt="EUR_map" width="1024" height="768" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27893"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Scotland&lt;/h3&gt;
Scotland is still pretty full of skating this weekend before Christmas, with the Last Scrim of 2018 on Friday...
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Wed, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edinburgh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Edinburgh's first Junior Derby team, the Boardwalk Bombs  practices and recruits at The Boardwalk, every Wednesday [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/264021497777923/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/264021497777923/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;strong&gt;Dumbarton&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicks in Bowls Scotland host Quad Meet sessions [6-10pm, Unit23 Skatepark][&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/571664849967506/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/571664849967506/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Glasgow Men's Roller Derby's ongoing new skater intake continues every Friday, for the foreseeable future! [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/538450946579720/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/538450946579720/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#993300;" data-mce-style="color: #993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Glasgow Men's Roller Derby also see out the year with The Last Scrim of 2018, an Open To All scrimmage event [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2058400910894339/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2058400910894339/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grangemouth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Bairn City Rollers rolling recruitment continues in their Friday sessions. Open to all genders. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/290765008244029/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/290765008244029/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edinburgh&lt;/strong&gt;: The Boardwalk hosts a "Special Christmas Roller Disco" for all ages [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/340885586687429/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/340885586687429/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Resistance Roller Derby, Glasgow's Junior Roller Derby club for queer and trans young people continue their training sessions open to new skaters and existing. [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ResistanceRDG/posts/2188691664720225" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/ResistanceRDG/posts/2188691664720225"&gt;EVENT Flyer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kirkwall&lt;/strong&gt;: Orkney ViQueens host a festive Family Roller Disco for all ages. Fancy dress encouraged. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1288092327997647/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1288092327997647/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicks in Bowls Scotland host a Sunday Skate followed by a park skate outside [Transition Extreme Sports] [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/235245817133829/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/235245817133829/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Next Sat (29th), &lt;strong&gt;Edinburgh&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicks in Bowls Scotland host a Skatemanay Quad Skate night at the Transgression Park. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/797604653910341/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/797604653910341/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/h3&gt;
Christmas in the UK means... the final scrimmage of the year.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;span style="color:#993300;" data-mce-style="color: #993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carlisle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Border City Roller Derby host an Open Christmas Scrim, Open To All genders. Fancy dress encouraged. Referees and NSOs welcome. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2185180175028358/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2185180175028358/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;Scarborough&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Scarborough Slammers host a Christmas Roller Disco open to all ages. Fancy dress encouraged. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/454162931775690/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/454162931775690/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Europe&lt;/h3&gt;
Europe is still pretty busy, with both France and Belgium hosting public bouts (in Belgium's case, the last fixture in their first ever Championships!).
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prague&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Czech Republic: the Hard Breaking Dolls host the second of 5 open training sessions, for interested potential competitive skaters, referees or NSOs. (Skaters limited to WFTDA-gender policy.) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/536798893399081/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/536798893399081/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;Tallinn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Estonia: Tallinn Roller Girls continue to host their open training sessions on Fridays for all interested attendees. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2130649673675124/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2130649673675124/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tartu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Estonia: Tartu Roller Derby also continue their open training sessions for all interested attendees. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2102606236669992/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2102606236669992/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#993300;" data-mce-style="color: #993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Groningen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Netherlands: Roller Derby Groningen host an Open Scrimmage, Open To All genders (and ages, including juniors), both for the Holiday season, and also to bid farewall to their current hall space. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/341700253046775/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/341700253046775/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#993300;" data-mce-style="color: #993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rotterdam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Netherlands: Rotterdam Roller Derby host an "Open Holiday Scrimmage", the third of three (one each Friday before Christmas). We think these are OTA, and are also open to NSOs. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/316023082321334/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/316023082321334/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vienna&lt;/strong&gt;, Austria: Vienna Fearleaders present their release party for their current calendar, as well as an excuse to see them perform live! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1945031492200598/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1945031492200598/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;" data-mce-style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Melrand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: Roller Derby La Ferraille host a Christmas match [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/474210783103734/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/474210783103734/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;La Ferraille versus Les Sabordeuses (Brest B) [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a data-mce-href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/106158" href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/106158"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;" data-mce-style="color: #800000;"&gt;Antwerp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Belgium: Antwerp Roller Derby host the final Belgian Championship fixtures of the year, deciding Division 1 W.  [&lt;a data-mce-href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/104124/overview" href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/104124/overview"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2083881251922264/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2083881251922264/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;One Love Roller Dolls (Antwerp) versus GO-GO Gent Roller Derby [rd.be champs d 1]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Open scrimmage. (Against Antwerp B?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#993300;" data-mce-style="color: #993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lleida&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Spain: The Mediterranean Rollers (Barcelona O) and the Sicarias del Cierzo host an Open To All genders and abilities Christmas Open Scrimmage [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/307896600066112/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/307896600066112/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Mon, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warsaw&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Poland: Worst Warsaw's Open recruitment continues for interested potential members in any roles! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2024174427621904/?" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2024174427621904/?"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Wed, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;" data-mce-style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ostrava&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Czech Republic: Trojhali Ostrava Roller Derby continue their open training and rolling recruitment? [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1139929732833996/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1139929732833996/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pacific&lt;/h3&gt;
It seems very quiet in the Asia-Pacific region before the end of year.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Next Sat (29th), &lt;strong&gt;Eltham&lt;/strong&gt;, VIC, Australia: Diamond Valley Roller Derby Club host a "Sausage Sizzle and Bake Sale". [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1935206959861597/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1935206959861597/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/LA_map-5.png?w=1024" alt="LA_map" width="1024" height="768" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27894"&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Latin America&lt;/h3&gt;
The Latin American region is always the hardest for us to find things in. We'd appreciate any heads-up about things we've missed!
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sat, &lt;strong&gt;Bahía Blanca&lt;/strong&gt;, Argentina: Brujas Roller Girls are either holding or attending a Truco tournament (Truco being an Argentinean card game) today. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BahiaRD/photos/a.1053885397961848/2514381115245595/?type=3&amp;amp;theater" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/BahiaRD/photos/a.1053885397961848/2514381115245595/?type=3&amp;amp;theater"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT Flyer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#993300;" data-mce-style="color: #993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;San Salvador de Jujuy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Argentina: Mortal Kollas and Coquena's Fighter co-host a "Roller Derby Christmas" bout. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/305007883441118/" data-mce-href="https://www.facebook.com/events/305007883441118/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Quienes () versus Grinchs (exhibition/open subs game)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Africa and Middle East&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>weekly roundup</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/18/non-us-canadian-derby-roundup-22nd-december-to-end-of-year-edition/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 15:11:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Guest Post: TrackKarma : A brief review from a total technophobe</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/17/guest-post-trackkarma-a-brief-review-from-a-total-technophobe/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing our series of guest posts, we're keeping topical with a review of Namur Roller Girls' league management web app, TrackKarma by Glasgow Men's Roller Derby's Rosie Peacock.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.trackkarma.com/"&gt;TrackKarma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is completely free to use*, although it can only be used as a web application (there is no self-hosting option). The self-reporting on the website says that, at the time of publication, 376 leagues are currently using the service. At present, the service is available in both English and French, and has no user limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:separator --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator"&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:separator --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trackkarma (TK) is an app (well, a website that runs like an app) developed by Namur Roller Girls.&lt;br&gt;Their launching blurb is as follows….&lt;br&gt;“Ever dreamed of teams charters, training sessions, attendance, league agenda and directory all gathered in one single tool?&lt;br&gt;Here it is: TrackKarma, the application that will change the world (or at least your league).&lt;br&gt;In TrackKarma, members can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Manage their player profile and import a cute picture&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Check monthly agenda of games and training sessions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Inform of their absence at practice&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Communicate with their bench crews&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Visualize team charters and game rosters&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Register to coach at practice...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:list --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bench crews can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:list --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Organize players into teams&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Select players for game rosters&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add games and related information to the agenda&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Communicate with their players&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Check players' attendance...&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:list --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which sounds AMAZING, so Glasgow Men’s Roller Derby (GMRD) decided to give it a whirl.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Previously GMRD have tried alternatives to Facebook groups such as Slack, but we struggle to get everyone on board with using alternatives as although Facebook is handy for social media, it’s also the devil. [For a review of such options, we recommend &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@shredinger/software-tools-for-nonprofits-f2cc73deea49"&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Ed]&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We have been trialling TrackKarma for about 3 months now and these are my thoughts:&lt;br&gt;I am a terrible technophobe, and I find TK very easy to use. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It makes sense and I don’t feel stupid using it (yey!). &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It is incredibly useful for keeping record of training sessions, games and attendance; however, like most ‘extra’ bits of work we ask skaters to do on top of training, some folk are using it really well, and others haven’t logged on at all.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Initially we asked everyone to be responsible for updating and maintaining their own attendance, but this was a bit optimistic on our part and so now we ask coaches to update skaters’ attendance after each session they coach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:separator --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator"&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:separator --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TrackKarma service can be found at &lt;a href="https://www.trackkarma.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.trackkarma.com/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*TrackKarma is supported by a Patreon here: &lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/trackkarma"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.patreon.com/trackkarma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; . As well as supporting their hosting costs, this Patreon also pays for additional development work and feature support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>guest articles</category><category>league management</category><category>reviews</category><category>trackkarma</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/17/guest-post-trackkarma-a-brief-review-from-a-total-technophobe/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 22:27:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UK roller derby community reacts to NSO's child abuse images conviction: a roundup of current events.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/14/uk-roller-derby-community-reacts-to-nsos-child-abuse-images-conviction-a-roundup-of-current-events/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;i&gt;We don't normally comment on current events in roller derby on this blog. However, the current shocking events in the UK Roller Derby community have been spreading rapidly, and we felt it would be useful to have an objective location collating the information available. In the past 24 hours, there has been a lot of discussion and horrified reaction, and many responses from across the community; we would not want these to be missed. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK roller derby community has been shocked this week by revelations that a female NSO appeared in court to answer sexual offence charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laura Nixon-Corfield (known within the community as Sara Tonin) was sentenced after admitting to having and distributing images of child sexual abuse. Over 800 images were cited in the court report, with children picture aged between 1 and 12 years. She received a two year suspended jail sentence, and a 10 year registration on the Sex Offenders register.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The details are reported in the press here: (warning, descriptions of images and messages sent relating to the images have been included in reports):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manchester Evening News - &lt;a href="https://www.manchestereveningnews.co.uk/news/greater-manchester-news/nhs-worker-downloaded-images-children-15549518"&gt;https://www.manchestereveningnews.co.uk/news/greater-manchester-news/nhs-worker-downloaded-images-children-15549518&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daily Mirror - &lt;a href="https://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/nhs-workers-double-life-online-13729460"&gt;https://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/nhs-workers-double-life-online-13729460&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nixon-Corfield had NSO’d and THNSO’d a number of events, working with leagues in both the UK and global community, including the 2017 MRDA Championships in Wales, and National and International tournaments in the current year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leagues and organisations Nixon-Corfield has been affiliated with in the past published statements that detailed lifetime bans from leagues and events. Their statements unanimously stated that they were unaware that she was going through any legal proceedings, and did not know that she faced sexual offence charges relating to children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/RainyCityRollerDerby/posts/10156449538209681"&gt;In a post on Rainy City Roller Derby’s Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;, league president Evan Lawrence said: “The Board of RCRD wants to reassure the derby community and the public that we treat the safety of our members and fans incredibly seriously and on discovering this information we have taken immediate action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They have been immediately removed and banned from the league, permanently banned from our venue, and any events at which Rainy City is participating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have notified WFTDA, UKRDA, JRDA and British Champs and we are working with them to make sure that we are able to provide a safe space for everyone within the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are providing counselling for all our members and will also be consulting with local expert organisations for further advice on how to support the league and the derby community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ManchesterRollerDerby/posts/2119046081488805"&gt;Manchester Roller Derby made their own post,&lt;/a&gt; explaining that while Nixon-Corfield had previously been a member, they had left the league some time ago, although she had still NSO’d at some of their events, as a local official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The statement, in part, reads: “Manchester Roller Derby condemns their actions in the strongest possible terms. The safety of our members, their families, the wider derby community and anyone else who may be in attendance at our events is of the upmost importance to us and a priority for the league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We find it deeply regrettable that they continued to participate at our events despite having reported themselves to the authorities and despite consciously attending events where junior skaters were present.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It continues: “In light of the above, and as a safeguarding measure, Manchester Roller Derby have issued a permanent lifetime ban to prevent Laura Nixon-Corfield from attending any Manchester Roller Derby related activities or events.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ukrollerderbyassociation/posts/2237443319621953"&gt;the UKRDA has issued a lifetime&lt;/a&gt; ban from any events organised by a UKRDA member league, including British Championships. They also join the long list of entities which have contacted the WFTDA, MRDA and JRDA on this matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;British Championships also &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BritishRollerDerbyChamps/posts/1011802455673545"&gt;issued their own statement&lt;/a&gt;, confirming that Nixon-Corfield had been banned permanently "from participation in all WFTDA, MRDA, UKRDA, JRDA, and British Championships events and groups effective immediately." and affirming that "We are unified in our condemnation of these disgusting and harmful crimina&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;l act". &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/nottinghamrollerderby/posts/2325725211005984"&gt;Nottingham Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; confirmed that they have no ongoing relationship with her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is currently an ongoing process in several organisations concerning improvements in safeguarding and vetting procedures to limit the possibility of this occurring again, and to help protect children in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Update: the MRDA has &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/story.php?story_fbid=1963676190376371&amp;amp;id=114448265299182"&gt;also issued a statement&lt;/a&gt;, revoking Nixon-Corfield's registration, and banning her worldwide from their events. All MRDA leagues have been informed of this decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update (2): the WFTDA has now also &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/story.php?story_fbid=10156889296479111&amp;amp;id=88510014110"&gt;made a short statement&lt;/a&gt;, also confirming a WFTDA-wide ban, and affirming support for, and solidarity with, their member league Rainy City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;Here are the numbers of some organisations who can help if you, or someone you know, has been affected by this incident:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;Samaritans: 116 123 or 0845 790 9090&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;Counselling Directory: 0844 8030 240&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;National Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children (NSPCC): 0808 800 5000&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;If you are under 18 feel unsafe, or simply want advice, please contact the NSPCC’s Childline on 0800 1111&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;If you have been affected by sexual abuse and need help there are many great organisations that you can rely on for support.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Rape Crisis Centre Help line is 0161 273 4500.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;National Victims support help line is 0808168 9111&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;the Rape and Sexual Abuse (RASAC) support Centre national number is 0808 802 9999.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/14/uk-roller-derby-community-reacts-to-nsos-child-abuse-images-conviction-a-roundup-of-current-events/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 16:29:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-US/Canadian Derby Roundup: 15th/16th December Edition</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/12/non-us-canadian-derby-roundup-15th-16th-december-edition/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;We’re bringing you another roundup of the upcoming Roller Derby this weekend from across the world. As always, we’re using &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for much of this information – for regions with less good coverage, we also do a bit of intensive searching using a tool which scans the Facebook events of Roller Derby leagues known to &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://derbylisting.com/dl/grid/"&gt;Derby Listing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Predictions of bouts are from FTS, if possible, and from our own &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRankv2.html"&gt;SRD Rank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; where FTS cannot make predictions (for example: Latin America, or non-MRDA men’s bouts). (SRDRank also has recent WFTDA rankings, including the 31st June ranking, as well as SRDRank, and allows you to make predictions from them.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;If we’ve missed you from our roundup, please let us know! [Or add yourselves to FTS and/or Derbylisting]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We're trying a new colour coding this week, to differentiate &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;BOUTS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; from &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;RECRUITMENTS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;OPEN SCRIM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;s, and &lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BOOTCAMP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;s.
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/12/non-us-canadian-derby-roundup-15th-16th-december-edition/eur_map-32/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-27859"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter wp-image-27866 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/EUR_map.png?w=700" alt="" width="580" height="435"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scotland&lt;/h3&gt;
Scotland is surprisingly busy this close to Christmas, with Glasgow Men's Roller Derby hosting their MRDA-policy rookie skater game on the Saturday, and also their returning mini-bootcamp series.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Wed, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edinburgh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Edinburgh's first Junior Derby team, the Boardwalk Bombs  practices and recruits at The Boardwalk, every Wednesday [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/264021497777923/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;strong&gt;Dumbarton&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicks in Bowls Scotland host Quad Meet sessions [6-10pm, Unit23 Skatepark][&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/571664849967506/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Glasgow Men's Roller Derby's ongoing new skater intake continues every Friday, for the foreseeable future! [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/538450946579720/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grangemouth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Bairn City Rollers rolling recruitment continues in their Friday sessions. Open to all genders. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/290765008244029/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grangemouth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Bairn City Rollers combine the above with an Open Scrim (presumably Open To All genders), with a Christmas theme [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2240785815966781/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Resistance Roller Derby, Glasgow's Junior Roller Derby club for queer and trans young people continue their training sessions open to new skaters and existing. [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ResistanceRDG/posts/2188691664720225"&gt;EVENT Flyer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grangemouth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Glasgow Men's Roller Derby host an MRDA-policy centred Debut Skater game, aimed at encouraging and developing the MRDA side of the sport in Scotland. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/258084504904639/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicks in Bowls Scotland host a Sunday Skate followed by a park skate outside [Transition Extreme Sports] [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/235245817133829/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tues, &lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicks in Bowls Scotland host a regular Quad Meet (Transition Extreme) [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1770144559760410/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tues, &lt;span style="color:#008000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edinburgh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: Glasgow Men's Roller Derby host the 8th edition of Jammer Club, their irregular series of Jammer "mini-bootcamp"s, coached by Optimus Grime. Open To All genders. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/286597728865042/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/h3&gt;
Christmas in the UK as a whole means "scrimmage", and there's a huge number of open scrims of various gender policies across the country. The only actual public bout we know of is in Halifax, however.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Wed, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swansea&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Wales: Swansea City Roller Derby host a Christmas Open Scrim, open to WFTDA gender policy conforming skaters (and all referees, NSOs). [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/327947104668678/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leeds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Leeds Roller Derby host a Christmas Guest Skater night (essentially an open scrim and training), open to WFTDA-gender-policy conforming skaters. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1138538202970912/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;Middlesbrough&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Middlesbrough Roller Derby host a Christmas themed Open Scrimmage (team Santa v team Elf). No gender policy stated. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1935495183197611/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;Barrow-in-Furness&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Furness Roller Derby host a Christmas Roller Disco to close out the year. Appearance by Santa Claus guaranteed for the children attending. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1493371527462878/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;Stratford&lt;/strong&gt;, England: London Rockin' Rollers host a "meet the Rookies" event, as a social welcome to the league. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/359700001265488/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basingstoke&lt;/strong&gt;, England: The Basingstoke Bullets host a Xmas Fun Skate, open to all skaters of all abilities, fancy dress encouraged. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/252961858706066/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leeds&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Double Threat Skates host another of their regular Pop Up Shops "Up North", with a free open skate too. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1988543731179375/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lincoln&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Lincolnshire Bombinos host a Junior Derby open mixed scrim (open to Junior skaters, entry fee applies) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/280014262645530/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lincoln&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Lincolnshire Bombers also host a Christmas Roller Disco, raising funds for SANDS (Sillbirths And Neonatal DeathS) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/767019970314204/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nottingham&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Nottingham Hellfire Harlots host a Christmas Craft Fair (with free entry), supporting homemade and local crafts. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2212063269007184/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oldham&lt;/strong&gt;, England: The Knights of Oldham host a "Saturday Knight Fever" Roller disco... [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/263121284546342/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grimsby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Grimsby Roller Derby host "Home Alone" an Xmas Charity Scrim event. (Actually two scrims, both raising funds for the charity "Not Home Alone"). [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/257304228305240/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;WFTDA-gender-policy scrim&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;OTA genders scrim.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Halifax&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: The Bruising Banditas host a double header "Snow Brawl" [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/749425978734851/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;WFTDA-aligned Skater Debut bout: Jingle Belles versus Candy Canors&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Bruising Banditas (Halifax) versus Spa Town Roller Derby (Harrogate) [FTS]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;Manchester&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, England: Manchester Roller Derby host their End of Year, Mixed Level, Open To All genders Open Scrim! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/555927811509741/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nottingham&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Nottingham Hellfire Harlots follow up their Fair with an Open Christmas Scrim, open to WFTDA-gender-policy conforming skaters. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1408727432563803/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oadby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Leicestershire Dolly Rockit Rollers host "Propeh Scrimbo", an Open To All genders Open Scrim. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1108734799293052/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wallasey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Wirral Roller Derby and the Pack Animals co-host a Super Sunday Scrim, a scrim event Open To All genders, with WFTDA-gender and MRDA-gender policy lineups for max inclusivity [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/339395616808792/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tues, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sheffield&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, England: Sheffield Steel Rollergirls host their December Megascrim, 90-minutes of Open scrim, open to WFTDA-gender-policy conforming skaters. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/279606026224237/"&gt;EVENT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Europe&lt;/h3&gt;
Europe... and especially France... is very much still in bouting mood this close to Christmas. There's a huge number of tournaments (and single headers) across the continent, including Belgian Championship games and German Bundesliga fixtures.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prague&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Czech Republic: the Hard Breaking Dolls host the first of 5 open training sessions, for interested potential competitive skaters, referees or NSOs. (Skaters limited to WFTDA-gender policy.) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/536798893399081/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thurs, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toulouse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: Roller Derby Toulouse host the last of their Recruitment days for their Men's Derby component (QuadGuards et al). [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/330799877471861/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;Tallinn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Estonia: Tallinn Roller Girls continue to host their open training sessions on Fridays for all interested attendees. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2130649673675124/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tartu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Estonia: Tartu Roller Derby also continue their open training sessions for all interested attendees. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2102606236669992/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rotterdam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Netherlands: Rotterdam Roller Derby host an "Open Holiday Scrimmage", the second of three (one each Friday before Christmas). We think these are OTA, and are also open to NSOs. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/316023082321334/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Coruña&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Spain: As Brigantias host a Recruitment / Intro To Roller Derby outreach event, with the assistance of the City Council [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2401301499943991/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oulu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Finland: Oulu Roller Derby celebrate the festive season with a B teams single header [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/298449800779543/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Oulu B versus Tampere B [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/106216"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;Anglet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, France: Roller Derby Côte Basque host a Happy Derby Christmas event... [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/272417090081897/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Valient Bitchiz (Bayonne) versus Botxo Killers (Bilbo) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105359"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charleroi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Belgium: The Blackland Rockin' K-Rollers host a quadruple header as part of the Belgian Championships. [FTS tournament][&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/569425380158917/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Blackland Randy Devils (Charleroi M) versus RATM (Arras M) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/106008"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Atomium Kittens (Brussels B) versus Blackland Rockin K-Rollers [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/104125/overview"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RD.be D 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Brussels Derby Pixies (Brussels) versus Namur Roller Girls [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/104124/overview"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RD.be D 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Atomium Kittens versus Holy Wheels Menace (Leige) [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/104125/overview"&gt;RD.be D 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bordeaux&lt;/strong&gt;, France: Roller Derby Bordeaux Club co-hosts a weekend of open skating events, with skating from 2pm on Sat, and all day on Sun [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2364285910312090/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: B.M.O Roller Derby Girls host a single header for Xmas [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2170289309658658/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Toutes Étoiles (Brest) versus Les Duchesses (Nantes) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/106119"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;Cholet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, France: Cholet Roller Derby host an recruitment day as part of the Cholet Decathlon, including a demonstration [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/294801631133456/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clermont-Ferrand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: the Auver'Niaks host a festive double header("Le Père Noël est une jammeuse."). [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/304956910344529/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Auver'Niaks B (Clermont-Ferrand B) versus Bloody Angels (Melun) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105896"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Auver'Niaks A versus Reaper's Crew (Epinal) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105895"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sat+Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dijon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: The Velvet Owls host a weekend of Roller Derby, "Jammer is Coming". [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/260656024622294/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Namur Glorious Basterds (Namur M) versus La Raclée (Dijon M) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105689"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Zombeers (Calais M) versus Namur Glorious Basterds [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105690"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;La Raclée versus Zombeers [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105691"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dead Dragibus (Calais J) versus Les P'tits Bou'Niaks (Clermont-Ferrand J) [FTS?]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Velvet Must'Hard (Dijon B) versus Black Tagada (Calais) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/106215"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sainte Geneviève des Bois&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: The Psyko'Quads host a single header event with little fanfare [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2105784676150794/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Psyko'Quads (Sainte Geneviève des Bois) versus Knock'n'Roll Cannibals (Creil) [FTS]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sat+Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strasbourg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: Hell's Ass Derby Girls and Les Menneles co-host Bretz'Hell Battle, a "Coed" Grand Tournament, with several OTA teams competing. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/293310274785376/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Le Peine Capitale (Paris O) versus Strasbourg Roller Derby (Hell's Ass + Les Menneles | Strasbourg O)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;UB (open subs OTA team) versus Orcet (Orcet RD + Wolfgang | Orcet O)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;La Peine Capitale versus UB&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Strasbourg versus Orcet&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Le Peine Capitale versus Orcet&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Strasbourg versus UB&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;"final" and "3rd place?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;The Hague&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Netherlands: The Parliament of Pain host "The Fight Before Christmas: Onion Edition". This is a triple header of OTA derby, with open-subs teams, and a raffle! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/265162317599269/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;X-Mas Circus versus X-Mas on Ice&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;X-Mas on Ice versus X-Mas at Iron Mist's&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;X-Mas at Iron Mist's versus X-Mas Circus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sat-Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Candeán&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Spain: Lobishomes Men's Roller Derby host their first mixed tournament, Full Moon Showdown. There's not much public info about the teams attending, however. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/994366180754996/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Teams Attending:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jabatas Roller Derby (Ourense)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Lobishommes (Galicia/Vigo M)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;"Spanish mash-up team"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geneva&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Switzerland: Genève Roller Derby United host "Les Matchs del la marmite" (referring to the pot, not the savoury spread), a double header event. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/169854680568961/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Les Taxider'Biches (Léman A) versus Mères Royaume (Geneva) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105984"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Cannibal Marmots Cééé (Grenoble C) versus Black Votchkas (Neuchâtel + Fribourg mix)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Braine-le-Comte&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Belgium: Manneken Beasts host a triple header of MRDA derby games in the return of their "Merry Hitmas" event [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1805380902894444/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Manneken Beasts (Brussels M) versus Panam Squad (Paris M) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105154"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tampere Rollin' Bros (Tampere M) versus Panam Squad [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105155"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Manneken Beasts versus Tampere Rollin' Bros [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105153"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;Dijon&lt;/strong&gt;, France: Roller Derby Dijon (we assume) host a Round Table on the future of Junior Roller Derby in France. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/266594554206929/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ligugé&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: Les Broyeuses du Poitou host the third edition of their winter tournament, Winter is Rolling. This edition is a triple header [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/685226385198076/permalink/709059599481421/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Marcheuses Blanches versus La Garde de Nuit ("White Walkers" versus "Night's Watch"), mixed teams.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Broyeuses du Poitou (Poitiers) versus Pirnanas (Chateauroux) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/106159"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Grandes Goulges (Poitiers O?) versus Royales Mandales (Rennes O?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lille&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: Lomme Roller Girls host a triple header event to close the season, against all of Paris! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/283433205498718/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tétons Flingueurs (Lomme C) versus San Culottes (Paris C) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105090"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Glorious Bâtardes (Lomme B) versus Quedalles (Paris B) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105091"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Bad Bunnies (Lomme A) versus Paris All-stars (Paris A) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105092"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
&lt;p id="u_1z_0" class="_52c9"&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;Montpezat-sous-Bauzon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, France: The Criminal Nurses of Aubenas host a Christmas double-header, the 4th edition of "Track's Anatomy". [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/120149342195197/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Criminal Nurses (Aubenas) versus Head Hunters (Narbonne) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105804"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;White v Black UB (open subs) game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sainte Geneviève des Bois&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, France: The Psyko'Quads return with a second fixture, a Scrimmage/Friendly game  [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/197917064430842/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Psyko'Quads (Sainte Geneviève des Bois) versus Channibals Lecters (Creil B) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/105844"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;?}&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karlsruhe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Germany: The rocKArollers host one of the last sets of Bundesliga Div 2 fixtures in this season [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/tournaments/99250/overview"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS Tournament&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/551235075329922/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Delta Quads (Mannheim) versus Riot Rollers (Darmstadt) [Bundesliga D 2]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;rocKArollers (Karlsruhe) versus Demolition Derby Dolls (Hannover) [Bundesliga D 2]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Västerås&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Sweden: Västerås Roller Derby host "All I Want for Christmas is a Roller Derby Double Header"... a Roller Derby Double header. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/261405811190480/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Västerås Roller Derby versus LKPG Go'Rullaz (Linköping) [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/106141"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Västerås Roller Derby versus Sundsvall Demolition Rollers [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/node/106136"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Mon, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warsaw&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Poland: Worst Warsaw's Open recruitment continues for interested potential members in any roles! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2024174427621904/?"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Mon, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zürich&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Switzerland: Zürich City Roller Derby host their next open tryouts for those interested in joining the team, in any capacity. Open To All genders. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2086866721375900"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tues, &lt;strong&gt;A Coruña&lt;/strong&gt;, Spain: As Brigantias follow up their open recruitment day with an outreach event at Centro Social A Comuna [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2210725422538195/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Wed, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ostrava&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Czech Republic: Trojhali Ostrava Roller Derby continue their open training and rolling recruitment [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1139929732833996/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/?attachment_id=27860#main" rel="attachment wp-att-27860"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-27860" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/anz_map1.png?w=700" alt="" width="580" height="435"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pacific&lt;/h3&gt;
It... seems... very quiet in Australia, New Zealand and the Asia-Pacific region this weekend, but it's also possible we're missing events. Do let us know if we've missed you.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;Westbury&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, TAS, Australia: Devil State Derby League host their regular Monthly Scrim, Open To All skaters. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/804779056567723/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#993300;"&gt;California Gully&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, VIC, Australia: Dragon City Roller Derby host "Wreck the Halls", a Christmas Scrimmage event. Open to WFTDA-gender-policy conforming skaters, 16+ age. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/342318496574482/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Low contact Scrimmage&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full contact Scrimmage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/12/non-us-canadian-derby-roundup-15th-16th-december-edition/la_map-26/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-27861"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter wp-image-27885 size-large" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/12/LA_map-4.png?w=700" alt="" width="580" height="435"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Latin America&lt;/h3&gt;
The big event in Latin America is the Huiñas returning tournament Quad Beer II, covering teams across Argentina!
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fri, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Córdoba&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Argentina: Insubordinades Roller Derby Disidente host their third intraleague game with almost no notice (event announced the day before) [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/InsubordinadesRD/photos/a.334590297032649/498266763998334/?type=3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT Flyer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sat+Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bariloche&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Argentina: The Huiñas Roller Derby host their second Tournament, Quad Beer II. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/261378434507283/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Teams:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Huinas Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Hijas de Pantano&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ambulatory Derby Team&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Barderas Insurrectas (Neuquen)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Hienas de la Calle (Neuquen)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Moron Roller Derby (Moròn)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Zapala Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Day 1 schedule:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Huiñas versus Moron [FTS]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ambulatory versus Zapala&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Moron versus Barderas Insurrectas&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Zapala versus Hienas de la Calle&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Barderas Insurrectas versus Huiñas&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Hienas de la Calle versus Ambulatory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;Rio de Janeiro&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Brazil: Avas Roller Derby host a recruitment day for interested new skaters. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/avasrollerderby/photos/a.334188037153430/387727361799497/?type=3&amp;amp;theater"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valdivia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Chile: Roller Derby Valdivia celebrate their 3rd birthday with a triple header event! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/352057925558568/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Indomitas RD (Valdivia) vs Diosas Volcánicas (Puerto Montt)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Indomitos RD (Valdivia O) vs Coed Chillan (Chillan O)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Colusion Austral (Valdivia? M) vs Chillanrrolleros (Chillan M)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bogota&lt;/strong&gt;, Colombia: Rock N Roller Queens celebrate their 9th birthday with a "Tropical Queens" party event! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/931973800335033/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="_6int"&gt;
&lt;div class="_6f1m"&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class="_6euq"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;San Jose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Costa Rica: Panties Dinamita Roller Derby host an international game to finish their year! There's only a mysterious instagram post to confirm this... [&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BqYLu7FAUIx/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT Flyer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Panties Dinamita (Costa Rica/San Jose) versus Burdel Zombie (Mexico City) [FTS]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ciudad Juarez&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Mexico: Medias Rotas Juniors host their final home-teams game of the year [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Mediasrotasjunior/photos/a.1035789499791411/1971728366197515/?type=3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Grinch versus Santa Claus (Junior home teams)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;Buenos Aires&lt;/strong&gt;, Argentina: Kamikazes Roller Derby celebrate their 6th birthday with a party - which is also raising funds for local animal shelters. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/352726782181610/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#0000ff;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;São Paulo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Brazil: the Ladies of Helltown are hosting an "open training" session for any interested potential members who want to experience the sport. [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/2014103785337063/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;strong&gt;San Joaquín&lt;/strong&gt;, Chile: Unión Subversiva Roller Derby host a "Roller Derby Flea Market" as a fundraiser and source of unique festive gifts [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1999206777046397/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sun, &lt;span style="color:#800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mexico City&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;?, Mexico: Jaibronas Roller Derby are hosted for triple-header "friendly" against two of Mexico City Roller Derby's teams, which is a &lt;em&gt;debut&lt;/em&gt; for the Jaibronas! [&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/264684001065739/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jaibronas (Tampico Madero) versus Quadtlicues (Mexico City)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jaibronas versus Catrinas (Mexico City)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Quadtlicues versus Catrinas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Africa and Middle East&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>upcoming events</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/12/12/non-us-canadian-derby-roundup-15th-16th-december-edition/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 16:13:17 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>