<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts by aoanla)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/authors/aoanla.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 10:20:59 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 24 Nov 2019 (SUNDAY)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-24112019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the Sunday addendum to our weekly highlights, giving events on the 24th a bit of space to breathe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/24Nov-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-24112019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentine roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>costa rican roller derby</category><category>dutch roller derby</category><category>norwegian roller derby</category><category>south african roller derby</category><category>sunday addendum</category><category>swiss roller derby</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-24112019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 20:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Austrian Nationals 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/Austrian_Nat-2019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the National Tournaments we cover have been running for many years, but as Roller derby expands across the world, we see newer tournaments establishing themselves in additional Nations.
One such newer tournament is the &lt;strong&gt;Austrian Championship&lt;/strong&gt;, which enters its third year on the 30th of November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to 2019 hosts, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/fearlessbruisers"&gt;Fearless Bruisers&lt;/a&gt; of Roller Derby Innsbruck about the tournament, and how it is already growing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Austria has had Roller Derby for some time, with Vienna Roller Derby having been playing since 2011, including internationally. However, for much of that time, they were literally the only league in the country, with most of their bouts played across the borders in Switzerland or Germany (or further afield in Europe). It was only in 2015 that additional teams were founded, in Linz, followed in 2017 by Graz and Innsbruck, and most recently in Salzburg in 2018. In 2020, we expect to see even more leagues form, as the trend of Roller Derby in Central and Eastern Europe continues to point upward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of Austria, with logos of the 5 participating teams over the locations of their respective cities." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/AustrianChamps2019.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/Austrian_Nat-2019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>austrian roller derby</category><category>fearless bruisers</category><category>national tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/Austrian_Nat-2019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 07:47:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 23 Nov 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-23112019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You might think things would slow down in derby in late November, but this is still an exceptionally busy week, worldwide. There's multiple tournaments and international bouts: returning tournaments in Belgium, with Skate Around #3;  in Italy, with Scusa Mamma, Ma Sono Una Derby Girl; and in Argentina, with Juguemos Pué; in the UK, returing Roller Derby Sevens and Sur5al events; and continuing tournament series in Germany, France, and Japan (where Derby Nights 4x4's fixture is extra long due to the postponed bout in October).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/23Nov-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-23112019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentine roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>belgian roller derby</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>danish roller derby</category><category>emirates roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>italian roller derby</category><category>japanese roller derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>new zealand roller derby</category><category>norwegian roller derby</category><category>polish roller derby</category><category>refereeing clinic</category><category>roller derby sevens</category><category>spanish roller derby</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-23112019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 19:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 17 Nov 2019 (SUNDAY)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-17112019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the Sunday addendum for the coming weekend, allowing us to highlight a few other events in countries overshadowed by big tournaments. There's exciting derby everywhere, and it's important that we don't miss the smaller (but equally significant) things behind the larger flashier events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/17Nov-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-17112019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentine roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>sunday addendum</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-17112019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 19:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 16 Nov 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-16112019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is another exceptionally busy weekend - once again, as we come to the end of the year, each weekend has multiple National Tournaments in it. In this case, the 2019 Mexican National Championships are in Querétaro, and the Brasilian Nationals are in Blumenau. (Plus, of course, this is the weekend of WFTDA's Championships). In addition, the ongoing Finnish and French tournament fixtures recur again this weekend...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... and there are big tournaments in Kiel, Regensburg, Cambridge, Wiltshire, and Buenos Aires!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[We'd also like to shout out the bout in Japan, for Yokosuka Sushi Rollers versus Kamikaze Badass, and also Tel Aviv Roller Derby's open scrim!]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is busy enough that we're going to have a second, short, Sunday-only update later in the week so we can fit more geographical range in here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Plus, more that we've not got space to summarise up here, and you'll have to read down for!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/16Nov-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-16112019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (8 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentine roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>brazilian roller derby</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>finnish roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>israeli roller derby</category><category>japanese roller derby</category><category>mexican roller derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>roller derby sevens</category><category>swedish roller derby</category><category>weekend highlights</category><category>wftda championships</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-16112019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 19:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Australian Nationals 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/AusNat-2019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Entirely reasonably, Australian Roller Derby has tended to organise on the State level, more so than the National level. Almost every State has at least one State-level tournament (5x5 Roller Derby, Statewide Stampede, Boom State Clash!, and this year's Tasmanian Tournament etc), but a formal National tournament has been longer in development, on the WFTDA side of things. (The biannual Great Southern Slam, which remains the largest regular Roller Derby Tournament in existence, sort-of stood in for a National event, but we don't think it ever intended to.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The Australian National Roller Derby Championships Logo for 2019: a silhouette skater with jammer cover, inside a stylised yellow trophy cup, on a yellow-orange shield; the background is a deeper orange." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/ANRDC2019.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, Australia's unusual in that there's been an &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://amrdmarketing.wixsite.com/amrd"&gt;Australian Men's Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; Championships since 2014; but no Australian National Tournament for WFTDA-policy teams until last year! Even then, the Australians do things differently: the new &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nationalrdc.com/"&gt;Australian National Roller Derby Championships&lt;/a&gt; is organised on a State level itself; with teams representing Victoria, Queensland, New South Wales, the Australian Capital Territory, and a team representing the First Nations (the indigenous peoples of Australia). In this sense, it resembles, perhaps, the USA-based "State Wars" more than most other National tournaments. (In addition, the Australian Nationals has both adult, and Juniors tiers, with state-level teams in both.)
It's notable, and still disappointing to us, that the Northern Territory, South Australia, and Western Australia are still not represented in the "National" tournament (Perth Men's compete in the Australian Men's, and South Australia in the Juniors!), but we hope that with proper support, this can happen in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(By contrast, the Australian Men's is a more familiar design, with city-based teams competing for the Cup.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their first year of operation, the "Australian Nationals" was entirely separate from the "Australian Men's", but this year, the two events have co-located whilst maintaining separate branding and organisation. The venue supports two tracks, although the running order shows that only track 1 will be streamed. As Track 1 seems to mostly be hosting the AMRD games, this is unfortunate for anyone interested in the JRDA and WFTDA-gender State tournaments; only the first game in the WFTDA-gender event will be streamed, along with the finals of each.
(The schedule does appropriately offset the games on each track, so that one is "playing" whilst the other is in half-time or end of game break).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other changes from last year: in the Men's, New Zealand Men's Roller Derby is competing for the first time (making this... not really a National tournament any more...) &lt;strong&gt;EDIT: we've been informed that NZMRD did participate in the first Australian Men's in 2014&lt;/strong&gt;, and could potentially upset things as they play #1 seed, Victoria's Vanguard in their first game. We are confident that the Vanguard will win, but a National level team always has the potential to cause spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="the Australian Men's Roller Derby National Championships logo: a red rimmed circle encompassing an inner thick blue ring around a scene including the Brisbane skyline in silhouette (including the Wheel of Brisbane, the local large observation wheel), a large pineapple (symbolising the Big Pineapple, located in Woombye), and a overlayed by a cane toad surfing on waves." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/AMRDNC.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Nationals, the ACT team is new this year; with only two leagues in the ACT area (a bit like the USA's Washington DC, the ACT is essentially a tiny area surrounding the national capital, Canberra), it's pretty easy to guess who their skaters might be. (Even with their team's decision to go fully into a Duck theme, with every skater skating under the name of an anatine pun, their numbers remain the same.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the team representing the First Nations has changed: in 2018, "Team Indigenous Dreaming" represented, whilst this year, a new team called "First Nations and Accomplices" is in their stead. Team Indigenous Dreaming have clarified that the two teams are not related; First Nations and Accomplices, unlike Team Indigenous Dreaming, is open to "allies" of First Nations people, as well as First Nations people themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(We'd like to thank Team Victoria for being the only State team to label the league each skater comes from on their roster; this makes it much easier to see how diverse their intake was! Team VIC has skaters from 7 different leagues, and whilst VRDL are definitely represented, they're by far not the majority contributor.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a co-hosted event, all three National Tournaments share a THR, the very experienced Denominator, and a THNSO, Mama Panda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead to the tournament predictions: for the Men's side, it would be unwise to rule out another tournament victory for Victorian Men's Roller Derby. Since the AMRDC started, they've only lost once; in 2017 when Tasmania took a shock victory and broke their three-year streak. With a conventional single-elimination format (and two consolation games), the tournament design will tend to reinforce its own seeding, making it very likely that the Vanguard will win. The most likely team to upset them, based on current &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flattrackstats.com/predictortool/q/39917/41293"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt; ratings, is the host league, Brisbane's &lt;em&gt;Scartel&lt;/em&gt;. With only a smattering of rating points between the two teams, home team advantage could easily be enough to allow the hosts victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Schedule for the AMRDNC and ANRDC for 2019." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/A(M)RDNC2019sched.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WFTDA-gender and Juniors tiers are much harder to predict: State-level teams which exist for only a single event have very little history to base predictions on (and even a roster only gets you so far).
In 2018, (WFTDA-gender) Team Queensland won, with a strong (222:125) victory over Team Victoria in the final, whilst for the Juniors, Team NSW/ACT took an equally striking victory over Team South Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WFTDA-gender tournament is structured as a double-elimination tournament; as such, we're not as concerned for the First Nations team, who are drawn against Victoria for their first game, as they will have a chance to progress in the lower bracket. (Interestingly, this is the same draw (switching FN&amp;amp;A for TI:D) that was determined in 2018, although with an additional team in the mix, the brackets are otherwise different.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Junior tournament, with only three teams - South Australia, Queensland and "New South Wales + ACT" - has an interesting structure which seems designed to give them as many games as possible. A three game round robin (which would ordinarily supply an unambiguous champion in itself) selects into a "Grand Final" for the top 2 teams; but even then, the loser in the Final plays the remaining team in a "2nd Place playoff". This structure returns from the previous year, but we still remain unsure as to why the competition isn't simply running a double round robin (which would give all the teams an equal number of games, for the addition of just a single scheduled bout).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Australian National Roller Derby tournaments, all of them, will start on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 8th November&lt;/strong&gt;, at the &lt;strong&gt;Mt Warren Sports Centre&lt;/strong&gt;,
2 Milne Street, Mount Warren Park, QLD, Australia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>australian men's roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>national tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/AusNat-2019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 13:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 09 Nov 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-09112019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is another exceptionally busy weekend - with no less than two single-event national tournaments (Australia and South Africa), as well as fixtures from the Swedish, Finnish, French and German national series!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite apart from those, there are also international events in Newcastle (as Newcastle Roller Girls celebrate 10 years), Vienna,  and Vicenza; Short Track Roller Derby and referee clinics in Buenos Aires; and a National Meeting of minds in Manizales, Colombia!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Plus, more that we've not got space to summarise up here, and you'll have to read down for!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/09Nov-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-09112019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (8 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentine roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>austrian roller derby</category><category>belgian roller derby</category><category>brazilian roller derby</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>colombian roller derby</category><category>dutch roller derby</category><category>finnish roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>irish roller derby</category><category>italian roller derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>new zealand roller derby</category><category>portuguese roller derby</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><category>short track roller derby</category><category>south african roller derby</category><category>swedish roller derby</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-09112019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 16:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Brasileirão 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/brasileirao-102019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a brief pause, we're continuing with this year's review of upcoming national tournaments with a return to Brazil's almost-officially-national-tournament, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/brasileiraorollerderby/"&gt;Brasileirão&lt;/a&gt; (link to Facebook).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we discussed &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/10/11/the-brasileirao-brazils-national-championships-at-8/"&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt; , the Brasileirão is now in its 8th year, and continues to change with the changing of Roller Derby in Brazil itself. The 7th Brasileirão ended with the following final standings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gray City Rebels (São Paulo)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue Jay Rollers (Curitiba)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ladies of Helltown (São Paulo)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thunder Rats Derby Squad (Santos)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iron Ladies (Blumenau) / Capivaras Roller Derby (Piracicaba) [no placement game]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;img alt='the 8th Brasileirão flyer: green patterned background with Brasilian skater shown facing right in profile (head only), wearing helmet with yellow jammer cover and white star. Her head is tilted slightly up, and she has a mildly anticipatory expression, with eyes half closed. Above the head, and half obscured by it, a red flower with green leaves. Around the head in a 3/4s halo, a scroll reading "8º Brasileirão de Roller Derby".' src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/Brasileirao.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year's Brasileirão is hosted in Blumenau, by the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/ironladiesbnu/"&gt;Iron Ladies&lt;/a&gt; , as a three-day event, interleaving a 4 team round robin tournament with competitors from across Brazil, with mixed scrimmage events for other competitors. (This is a change to the previous tournament structures, which were run as single-elimination events.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, in a change from previous competition, there was no representation from Rio de Janeiro, with 6 competitors in total; this was, we assume, related to the formation of a second league in Rio around the time of applications (Avas Roller Derby). This year, whilst the number of competitors has reduced; with Santos and Piracicaba out of the list; there is renewed representation from Rio, as the newer team, Avas, is attending this year. (The field is still reduced by 2 in total, as out of the two leagues representing São Paulo in 2018, only Gray City Rebels are attending this year.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last several months, we've spoken to the Brazilian roller derby community on this, and other planned events, and unfortunately, this decrease in size is a marker for a more general difficulty for the sport in this country, and in other Latin American nations. As people are hopefully now more aware, the cost of Roller Derby - economically, and in other ways - in South America is much higher than it is in most of the USA and other wealthy Western countries. (This isn't just cost, it's also issues like practice space, accessibility of kit, and even accessibility of the bulk of writing about Roller Derby, which is mostly in English). The Copa Libertadoras, which would have been a second Brazil-hosted, Latin America scoped, tournament at the end of this year, recently announced that it was unable to proceed, and would be attempting a 2020 event instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These difficulties, however, are also why the continuing organisation of events like the Brasileirão are so important, to keep the roller derby community connected and part of something big.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 8th edition of the Brasileirão will run from &lt;strong&gt;15 - 17 November 2019&lt;/strong&gt;, in &lt;strong&gt;Blumenau, SC, Brazil&lt;/strong&gt;. ( EEB Professor João Widemann - Rua 4 de Fevereiro, 64 - Itoupava Norte, Blumenau/SC )&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>brasileirao</category><category>brazilian roller derby</category><category>iron ladies</category><category>national tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/10/brasileirao-102019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 13:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 02 Nov 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-02112019/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite being a bit busy, we're trying a new thing this week to give us more space, and are grouping all "National tournament" fixtures on a date for a given country into one entry - so here, Dijon and Saint-Gratien share a Championnat de France spot. With this being the week of Halloween, there's a lot of "spooky" events earlier in the week and on the weekend, but there's some very exciting other developments, including the first internal interleague bout in Uruguay, Liverpool Roller Birds' 10th anniversary, and the Rebellion tournament returning to Melbourne for another year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/2Nov-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-02112019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>argentine roller derby</category><category>australian roller derby</category><category>belgian roller derby</category><category>british roller derby</category><category>chilean roller derby</category><category>chinese roller derby</category><category>colombian roller derby</category><category>costa rican roller derby</category><category>estonian roller derby</category><category>french roller derby</category><category>german roller derby</category><category>mexican roller derby</category><category>sur5al</category><category>uruguayan roller derby</category><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-02112019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekend Highlights: 27 October 2019 (Sunday)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-20102027/</link><dc:creator>aoanla</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the Sunday addendum for this week's highlights; and it's a pretty busy Sunday, taking into account the several "whole weekend" events in our Saturday main highlight update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as Sunday, we have one event for next &lt;em&gt;Wednesday&lt;/em&gt;, in St Petersburg. Wednesday is a difficult date for our highlights, as Monday isn't really enough notice, so we're including it here for safe keeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules are, as usual: highlights limited to 1 event per country, with an "extra" event allowed for a different kind of fixture
(so, 1 tournament and 1 bootcamp), or if they involve Scottish leagues (since we are the &lt;em&gt;Scottish&lt;/em&gt; Roller Derby Blog).
Other notability might also allow the extra event - great posters, notable teams, etc. (League birthdays may count as "special" enough, at our discretion ;) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've bent the rules a bit this time, because it's important to highlight derby in regions which need more attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bid to make this list as useful as possible, we've avoided links to Facebook except where noted.
(Links to Teams are to non-Facebook resources - Instagram, or actual team pages - we'd strongly recommend that Teams
get themselves an actual webpage [we can help host one if you need help]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locations are roughly organised East-West (with things before the weekend out sequence at the start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of all events (coded by type)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/10/27Oct-wkly-map.png" style="width: 100%;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-20102027/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>weekend highlights</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/highlights/2019/weekendhighlights-20102027/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>