<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts by caleykapowski)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/authors/caleykapowski.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 12:47:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Granite City Roller Derby Home Teams and Rising Stars</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/27/granite-city-roller-derby-home-teams-and-rising-stars/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The dust has barely settled since Granite City Roller Derby's Northern Fights took their first win of 2018 and it's already time to play another game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time though, it's going to be a little bit different...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City Roller Derby are going to be hosting their first ever home teams game!  GCRD have never had the pleasure of hosting a home team game before.  We will have Team White versus Team Black.  Both teams will be made up mainly of GCRD skaters and will also feature some of our lovely friends from  further north.&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/gcrd.png"&gt;&lt;img width="2048" height="2048" alt="" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/gcrd.png" title="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-22709"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just because we're all pals, don't expect the teams to take it easy on each other. Considering the excellent results by both the Fight Hawks and the Northern Fights in 2017, this upcoming game promises to be interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before we even get to the home team game, we have one of my favourite things in the world. A Rising Stars game! A great opportunity for newer skaters to get some valuable game day experience. These games will let us see the new talent that northern Scottish roller derby has to offer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So come along to the Beach Leisure Centre in Aberdeen from 12.30 pm on Saturday 31st March 2018 for our first game of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are £4.00 with under 12s getting free entry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first whistle will be at 1pm&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/27/granite-city-roller-derby-home-teams-and-rising-stars/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 14:48:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City Brawlers make Derby History</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/26/granite-city-brawlers-make-derby-history/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/img_0069-1.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-24500" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/img_0069-1.png" alt="" width="275" height="392"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/img_0070-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-24501" title="" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/img_0070-1.jpg" alt="" width="360" height="360"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
September has been an awfully exciting month for the Granite City Brawlers (GCB); they became the first Scottish league to achieve MRDA membership AND won the first MRDA sanctioned game to be held in Scotland (against Nottingham's Super Smash Brollers, 209 to 190). Pretty exciting stuff!
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/img_0071-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-24502" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/img_0071-1.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
I had a wee chat with GCB chairperson Pudz about the league application to MRDA and what this means for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;
Can you tell me a little about the MRDA application process? &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application process involves playing 5 games with at least one of these against an MRDA opponent and 2 letters of recommendation from an MRDA league and an MRDA recognised official. There are a few other boxes to tick and then your application is sent to MRDA for review. Once reviewed the application is put to vote by MRDA leagues and officials to decide if you are to be admitted to membership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;
What made GCB decide to become MRDA affiliated?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years we have grown naturally as a league. Starting from scratch with getting skaters through mins up to having a bouting team playing at home. We set MRDA status as one of our goals at our AGM last year as it felt like the natural progression for the club and we are delighted to present this as a completed project at our upcoming AGM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;What does MRDA membership mean for the Brawlers? What changes can we expect? Fancy riders for game day?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means the world to Brawlers, we have put our country on the map as the first league in Scotland to achieve this status.
Hopefully this means we can play a wider range of teams as opponents look for sanctioned games for ranking and tournament purposes.
[Plus] A bottle of rum in the changing room after games maybe 😉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;
Who is your dream MRDA opponent?, let's make it happen.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd personally love to play an Australian MRDA team like Sydney SMASH as I love the way they play derby. We'd also love to play in a tournament like MEC [Tyne and Fear's Men's European Cup] one day, that’s the dream!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Pudz!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm sure you're wondering where you can watch Scotland’s premier MRDA league play. Well get your diary out and make sure you keep &lt;strong&gt;25 November&lt;/strong&gt; free for a cheeky home game. GCB will be hosting an International Double Header where GCB will take on &lt;strong&gt;Team Poland&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; will also take on Poland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GCB will be playing an away game on 28 October too, more details shall be announced soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granite City Brawlers are currently one of thirty clubs in Scotland competing for a Grassroots Giving Grant from Skipton Building Society. You can help them win by clicking the link&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skiptongrg.co.uk/apply-for-funding/2017-shortlisted-groups/Scotland/granite-city-brawlers"&gt;http://www.skiptongrg.co.uk/apply-for-funding/2017-shortlisted-groups/Scotland/granite-city-brawlers&lt;/a&gt;
Congratulations GCB on making history!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/img_0040.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22169" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/img_0040.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="682"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>international derby</category><category>international roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>mrda</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/26/granite-city-brawlers-make-derby-history/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 13:14:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>We're All Going on a Summer Brawliday</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/11/were-all-going-on-a-summer-brawliday/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/granitecitybrawlers/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (GCB) are preparing for their next game. This one promises to be extra special, not only is this the first Brawlers game outside of Scotland BUT it's also the first Brawlers game outside of the U.K.! The Brawlers are heading to Tenerife to play against &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Tibicenas-Mens-Roller-Derby-796092177146242/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tibicenas Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (TMRD).
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22166" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/img_0039.jpg" alt="" width="724" height="1024"&gt; Bout Poster courtesy of Tibicenas Men's Roller Derby&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to check  in with captains Pudz and Momo to ask about how the team are preparing for their next game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TMRD have previously played Madrid MadRiders but despite some serious snooping, I can't find any teams to link GCB to TMRD. Since this makes it super hard to make any predictions about the game, there is additional excitement. [&lt;a href="http://aoanla.pythonanywhere.com/SRDRankv2.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SRDRank&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; gives the Brawlers the advantage over their hosts, but with low certainty - Ed.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;You played Oldham earlier this year and were victorious, how are you feeling about taking on Tibicenas Men's Roller Derby? &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Have you seen them play before or met any of the players during your World Cup experiences?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pudz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nervous but excited at the same time. We've scoured the internet for footage to watch but come up short so are going into this game a little bit blind as to our opponent's style. Unless you count their uploads of the T Rex on skates, if the dinosaur gets rostered we'll be facing a new challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Momo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We trained really hard on the run up to the Oldham game, I think we stepped up drastically from our previous game last year. We went back through the previous game and pin-pointed every weakness and focused heavily on certain aspects that were lacking; we're not perfect yet but the guys really worked hard and for the first time at the Oldham game we had in all sense's of the word: a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tenerife is a complete wild card! None of us know what to expect from the team and I think a lot of the guys are underestimating how hot it's going to be; myself and Pudz have a good idea how hard it's going to be after playing in Canada [at MRDWC] last year. TMRD will have the advantage being used to playing in the heat, and I think we are only playing with 9* so it's going to be seriously tough. Whatever happens we'll do all we can do and have fun knowing we have a holiday after the game as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We haven't seen the roster yet and I'm not sure if anyone played in the World Cup but it's obviously quite possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*GCB will now be playing with 10 skaters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tell me about your fundraising efforts to get the team and crew over to Tenerife &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pudz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five of our Brawlers are doing a sponsored leg wax to help cover the costs of skater insurance and the bus to the game in Tenerife. Whichever Brawler has the most money against their name will be getting a nice pre holiday leg wax. #waxonwaxbrawff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoever has the highest funds against them is going to have an itchy time in the crazy heat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/img_0038-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22170" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/img_0038-1.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/waxonwaxbrawff"&gt;http://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/waxonwaxbrawff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;What sort of special preparation are you doing as a team/individual for playing in such a super warm place?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pudz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team have been doing "jumper scrims" in preparation for the game to try and adjust to the heat. These have been met with sad faces from our peely wally Brawlers but have been good fun and shown off Raffers' fine selection of Christmas Jumpers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also invited some guests to scrim against the Brawler Tenerife roster as a warm up which went very well. Our Brawlers' hard work is paying off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Momo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've been training with jumpers on during scrims to help with heat training and our scrims are generally quite intense, almost "iron man" if you like, so it's good for the endurance, especially since we're playing with 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a scrim with the "Tenerife 9" vs the rest of the Brawlers, some GCRD members, and some Bairn City members last weekend, a good mixed bunch to help us prepare. They were great, totally mixed it up and they didn't take it easy on us! It went well and gave us a few more things to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;How does preparation for an international game differ to preparing for a local game?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pudz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to think about things like jet lag [not to Tenerife though! - Ed], lower roster numbers due to the distance travelled and, most importantly, the bar order; "Tres sidras por favor!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a team we are very excited to represent Scottish roller derby on an international scale, strengthening the roller derby community even further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Momo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preparing for Tenerife seems a lot more labour intensive from an organising point of view. If it wasn't for Nikki, Brawlers' Bench Manager, sorting the entire thing out I think we'd be walking from one end of the island to the other to get to the game. I did my bit as well though: I organised a rainbow of the best beach towels Scotland's ever seen! We're obviously doing our heat training and some of us have been working on our after party stamina to last the entire holiday, I guess maybe some of the guys have been working on their beach bods, not likely but maybe....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've lost a few skaters at the start of this year/ tail end of last year but we've gained some new young blood with loads of potential and honestly the Brawlers are the strongest we've ever been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're looking forward to what we have planned for the rest of 2017 and can't wait to see what 2018 brings!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-22169" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/img_0040.jpg" alt="img_0040" width="1024" height="682"&gt; Photo Credit: Len Rizzo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge 'thank you' to Pudz and Momo for taking the time to answer my questions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, for one, am so excited for the first GCB international game and wish the team loads of luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, there's still time to donate and nominate your favourite brawler for a cheeky leg wax! &lt;a href="http://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/waxonwaxbrawff"&gt;http://www.justgiving.com/crowdfunding/waxonwaxbrawff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Brawlers/Tibicenas bout is in just 10 days - &lt;strong&gt;22 July&lt;/strong&gt;. The Facebook event is: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1910383885902598/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1910383885902598/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>tenerife</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/11/were-all-going-on-a-summer-brawliday/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 08:00:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City Brawlers Debut Home Game</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/12/granite-city-brawlers-debut-home-game/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's November, the winter duvet has been brought out of hibernation and it is rather chilly up here in Aberdeen. You may be thinking that the time for fun things is gone and that you will have to wait till next year for more roller derby up in Aberdeen (or south, I don't know who is reading this or from where, I'm hedging my bets here). Well, you are wrong. Very wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;b&gt;Saturday 19th &lt;/b&gt;November, Granite City Brawlers will take on Birmingham’s Crash Test Brummies B team for what promises to be a memorable game of roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11281" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/image.jpeg" alt="image" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why so special? Well...this is a very special game for a myriad of reasons, the biggest one being that it will be the FIRST EVER HOME GAME of GCB!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you may recognise a few faces and names, the brawlers have never played a public home game as a team. The brawlers did take on Bairn City Rollers’ Skelpies last year in Grangemouth but that was different, this time it's home turf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Brawlers have been preparing for their home debut for quite some time and a lot of people have been waiting eagerly. Well now the time is here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important facts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who? &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/662329417258500/?ti=cl"&gt;Granite City Brawlers vs Crash Test Brummies B&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What? Some first class roller derby. Considering the skaters taking part, I am expecting nippy footwork, hard hitting, near impenetrable walls and excellent sportsmanship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where? The &lt;b&gt;Beach Leisure Centre&lt;/b&gt;, Sea Beach, Aberdeen, AB24 5NR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When? Saturday 19th November 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at &lt;b&gt;2.15pm&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First Whistle at 2.45pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? Because roller derby is excellent and both of the teams playing are fabulous and it promises to be a good game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How? Entry is a bargain at £&lt;b&gt;4.00&lt;/b&gt; per human. Although under 12s get in free if accompanied by a paying adult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have heard rumours of there being a raffle...not rumours, it's totally true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So come and see some local roller derby history being made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11282" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/11/image1.jpeg" alt="image" width="665" height="960"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>crash test brummies</category><category>granite city brawlers</category><category>team scotland</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/11/12/granite-city-brawlers-debut-home-game/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 10:25:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Power of Scotland</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/29/mrdwc-2016-team-review-power-of-scotland/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And now to Team Scotland, who made us cry with national pride in 2014...was it just me? In the 2014 Men's Roller Derby World Cup Scotland were in Group Orange with Belgium, Canada and Japan. They were knocked out by our friends in Wales and shared 7th place with Argentina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1448576822432.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1448576822432.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1448576822432.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Power of Scotland logo 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spoke with Optimus Grime about Team Scotland in the run up to the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How are preparations going for the world cup?      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are going very well. We have had a list of targets to reach, both on and off the track and are on  course to achieve them all. There have been a few bumps here and there, but they have just been flawless adjusted and things have seemlessly carried on. We are very pleased thus far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How often do you train?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since day 1 we have known our training schedule which has been great for attendance. Huge credit to our training and management for sorting that out so early. We are training every 2nd sunday in Grangemouth. Turnouts are great, especially since 1/3 of the team live in areas of England. Each session has been really tough, but we are growing all the time and it gets better each time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off skates training varies. There are no set team off skates training due to everyone living so far apart, but all skaters are pushing themselves more and more on and off the track. I know everyone is taking this very seriously and doing everything they can to be in the best condition they can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From which leagues have your players been selected?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a very big geographical distance in the roster. The entire list includes;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granite City Brawlers - Aberdeen
Bairn City Rollers - Falkirk
Mean City Roller Derby - Glasgow
Capital City Roller Derby - Edinburgh
New Wheeled Order - Manchester
Inhuman League - Sheffield
Super Smash Brollers - Nottingham
Southern Discomfort - London
Wirrel Pack Animals - Liverpool
Kings of Block &amp;amp; Roll - Exeter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Management &amp;amp; Coaches:
Dundee Roller Girls
Auld Reekie Roller Girls
Granite City Brawlers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are your team goals for the World Cup?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite simply but realistically.....make it out of the group stages. Anything after that is a bonus. We are both fortunate and unfortunate to have a 6 team group. Fortunate for the chance to play so many teams from all over the world, but with that comes a higher chance of fatigue. We are very excited though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the group there is really only 1 slot available as USA will no doubt advance from the groups. With 5 teams battling for that space this will be extremely competitive, but we have the talent and desire to be that team that gets to the quarter finals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell me about your fundraising and sponsorship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have recieved some great sponsorship for the run up to the World Cup.
Mostly with our uniforms, merch and safety gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our sponsors are;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Datum360
MP Locums
S1 Helmets
Witness the Fitness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would also like to offer a huge thank you to;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interplanetary Print Syndicate
Roller Derby City
Power of Greyskull
EDF Energy
The Whisky Wolf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our fundraising has been a variety of coaching and event organisation.
We have had a sponsored; Beard shaves, Pub quizzes and Bungee jumps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest source of fundraising have been bootcamps and guest coach sessions which have been as wide spread as our roster and even abroad.
Such as Belfast, Malaga and France. The biggest of which was our Big Bootcamp in Dundee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can we expect to see from team Scotland at the World Cup?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically a huge improvement from our last world cup involvement. Not any less passionate, but far more strategic, skilled and patient, from both a jammer and blocker point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also alot of new faces, but plenty of previous ones too. Our roster is far more extensive than the last World Cup, just from the leagues people have come from. This has brought a big variety of skills to Power of Scotland this time around and has made for a very balanced team.
Finally, we hope to display a better performance &amp;amp; therefore ranking this time around. Moreover, show the world that we can still give the big boys a hard time on the track and be considered one of the better teams in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Scotland are indeed in a six team group for the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup. They are in Team Red with Finland, Ireland, Japan, Mexico and the USA. Their first game will be on Track 1 against Team USA at 11am Calgary time, 4am UK time...make some coffee although I'm sure the excitement will wake you up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466932874572.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466932874572.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466932874572.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>power of scotland</category><category>team scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/29/mrdwc-2016-team-review-power-of-scotland/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 20:50:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: All-Ireland Men's Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/26/mrdwc-2016-team-review-all-ireland-mens-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2014, All-Ireland Men's Roller Derby were in Group Blue along with Australia, France and Germany. In their final game they played against Finland who took the bowl. Ireland ended the inaugural Men's Roller Derby at number 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466933364081.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466933364081.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466933364081.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Ireland's logo 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very lovely Eoin Flynn was kind enough to answer some questions about how the team have been getting ready for the world cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are preparations going for the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With only weeks to before Calgary, we're fired up and as prepared as we ever could be. The work for MRDWC 2016 began almost immediately after the last World Cup so we've had plenty of time to build on what we learned there, as a nation very new to men's roller derby, and we'll be very different from what you saw in Birmingham. That team was expanded into a training squad from which the final roster was picked so everyone's now been training and playing together for over a year, everybody knows their job and that they can rely on the others to do their's too. We're ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How often do you train?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With players located anywhere from LA to Limerick, it's quite a job to get everyone together at the same time. But we've all put in the effort to train regularly, and collected the air miles along the way!
Since January 2014 we've had full squad training at least every two months for an entire weekend. There have been several home and away games in between too. Of course we'd all do this all day every day if we could!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any off-skates training?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our coach - Jessica Rammit - wouldn't have it any other way! Everyone does their own gym work, of course, but we're lucky to have a derby-specific off-skates stuff to work on courtesy of her. None of us will forget bleep-test day! And our off-skates warm-ups are part of our team bonding now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From which leagues have your players been selected?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Ireland: Men Behaving Derby (All-Irl), Pig Town Boys (Limerick), Cork City Firebirds, and Harland Wolves (Belfast)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From UK: New Wheeled Order, Southern Discomfort, Crash Test Brummies, Kings of Block N' Roll, Borderland Brawlers, Quads of War, and Lincolnshire Rolling Thunder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And from USA: Los Angeles' Drive-By City Rollers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your team goals for the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a team, we want to play as we know we can; calmly and together.
The worst thing would be to come away knowing we could have done better, we're determined to give it all on track, right from the first whistle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More specific goals include putting some decent points up against Team USA, but hey, doesn't everyone wanna do that? We also want to keep a grip on the top-ten slot that we earned in 2014, with so many more nations competing this time around, the rankings places are going to be hard fought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about your fundraising and sponsorship.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paying for this crazy sport of ours has been a lot harder this time around, getting everyone to Canada is not going to be cheap. So we've been very lucky to have great support from companies like S1 and Non-Universal Nuts. We've also just done a great deal with TwoTonMurphy.com who are printing, selling, and shipping all of our online merchandise - and all the profits go to our travel fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've also got a gofundme page: &lt;strong&gt;gofundme.com/merbyireland&lt;/strong&gt; , where people have been very generous in supporting us, every little bit helps immensely so we're very thankful. Local leagues have been helping out too, The Cork City Firebirds we very kind to raise funds for us at their 'Love Roller Derby' event recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can we expect to see from Team Ireland at the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll understand if we don't share any tactics here! Expect to see a well-drilled team far different from the 2014 one, back then there was essentially NO men's derby on the island of Ireland, we've come a long way. Expect dogged determination and playing to the final whistle. You might also expect some strong representation at the after-party! But most of all expect us to be one unit, The team motto is 'Ní neart go cur le chéile.' which means 'There is no strength without unity', we will be strong and we will be united.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time around, Ireland are in Group Red with Finland, Japan, Mexico, Scotland and the USA. They will play their first game of the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup against Finland (on track 1) at 1pm Calgary time, 6am in the UK and Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466937146038.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466937146038.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466937146038.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all ireland men's roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>team ireland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/26/mrdwc-2016-team-review-all-ireland-mens-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 20:43:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Wales Men's National Roller Derby Squad</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/26/mrdwc-2016-team-review-wales-mens-national-roller-derby-squad/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2014, Wales were in Group Red with Finland and USA. Their final game was against Australia with the winner taking the shiny plate. Australia took that win and Team Wales took 6th place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466933587792.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466933587792.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466933587792.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Wales' logo, retained from the 2014 MRDWC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spoke to team Wales skater Ben Phillips who was lovely enough to answer some questions for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;BENPHILLIPS!!!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are preparations going for the world cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prep is going well, we've been training quite regularly since the start of this squad's tenure. Coming from the previous squad, which was consisted more of a ragtag group of skaters, into a more structured system with a HR and a proper Head Coach in Oceanne Esparcieux, the benefits have been felt greatly.
A large number of the previous squad tried out again and made it so it feels similar to the old squad but with a much needed injection of new blood in the shape of the coaching and new players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How often do you train?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twice a week with South Wales Silures and twice a week with Cardiff Bay Crossbones (Roller Hockey team), Refereeing local women's teams when I feel the itch for skating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International duties are once a month training then games on top of that. We had a pretty good showing in 4 Nations and a friendly against Ireland so we feel like we should be firing on all cylinders come July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any off skates training?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to cycle to work as much as I can (17miles each way) as a form of cardio and try to get the gym when I have time in the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From which leagues have your players been selected?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly South Wales Silures but not as much as the 2014 squad, returning from the previous squad is the Underrated and outstanding Berserker from Southern Discomfort and Swifty from Milton Keynes. We've had some great new blood in the form of U-go Boss from NWO, J-Wrecks from Sons of Icarus, Tom Thump from Wirral Pack Animals, to name a few. We have a resident canadian in the form of Hung Solo who is with River City Riot in Calgary so hopefully he can give us the skinny with the Canadians when we meet them in our group match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your team goals for the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To rise in the world rankings, 6th last time round so anything above that would be a success. We're pretty confident we can qualify through our group with our biggest game is against the hosts Canada. Having played them in MRDWC14 I cant wait to meet them on track again, great bunch of guys with some fancy footwork to boot! My personal goal is to have Tim Horton's (Timmy H) for breakfast the entire time in Canada... Dem DoubleDoubles...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally believe, depending on how we do in the group stages, we can reach the semis but it'll all depend how we react to the transatlantic flight and Calgary altitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about your fundraising and sponsorship.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So our facebook page, &lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/Wales-Mens-National-Roller-Derby-Squad-278766772249805/&lt;/strong&gt; has been running a gofundme at &lt;strong&gt;www.gofundme.com/teamwalescalgary&lt;/strong&gt; as well as a helmet competition with Swift Customs &lt;strong&gt;https://www.facebook.com/Swiftcyclesandskates/&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the hopes of raising donations we have pitted each player against another in a series of 'hilarious' challenges ranging from funny to just a bit weird, the internet seems to like stuff like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can we expect to see from team Wales at the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some heavy hitting as is standard in our derby heritage but with much more control and swish than people may expect. We've got what it takes to be part of the big dogs in this World Cup and hopefully we can prove it. Thanks for listening/reading to my rambling answers and hope you enjoy Wales' games at MRDWC16!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup Wales are in Group Green with Canada, Colombia,  Spain and Germany.  Their first game will be on track 1 against Colombia at 10am Calgary time...which is like 5pm UK time, from the looks of both of these teams, it's definitely going to be a fantastic game to watch! [Due to Colombia dropping out of the Cup, Mexico replaces them - so Wales' first game is at the same time, but against Mexico...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466938690275.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466938690275.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466938690275.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>team wales</category><category>wales men's national roller derby squad</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/26/mrdwc-2016-team-review-wales-mens-national-roller-derby-squad/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 20:36:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: England Men's Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/26/mrdwc-2016-team-review-england-mens-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our coverage of the Men's Roller Derby World Cup has returned slightly closer to home, as the time has come to speak to the UK and Ireland. First up is the English National Team - England Men's Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014, England were in Group Green with Argentina, the Netherlands and Sweden. They made it to the final game to play against Team USA for the shiny, shiny cup and whilst Team USA took the win, England took the silver medal finishing second. I, for one am rather excited to see these chaps play in July!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466933286146.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466933286146.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466933286146.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team England logo 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Manager Niks Kent was kind enough to answer some questions about how the team have been getting ready for the world cup.Please note that I spoke to Niks before England held their sevens tournament, did you see it? It was most excellent!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are preparations going for the world cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really well! We're in the refining stage. We have a couple of warm up games, and a highly competitive red v white game as part of our upcoming sevens tournament before we leave for Calgary though, so still plenty to do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How often do you train?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've been training once a month since July, plus a few training games.
We're delighted to have been supported at all our training by world cup level officials, so there's been no getting away with any sneaky forearms or cut tracks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any off skates training? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each skater has their own individual fitness regime, depending on their personal goals.
We have also been working on our mental game, and the lovely Katie from The Treasure Hunt Company took us out for a rather competitive treasure hunt round Nottingham as a team building adventure - not even the monsoons could stop us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From which leagues have your players been selected? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our squad consists of players from across England Wales. We have representatives from Southern Discomfort, South Wales Silures, Crash Test Brummies, Lincolnshire rolling thunder, Manchester Roller Derby, Barrow Infernos and Tyne and Fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your team goals for the World Cup? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to play really good roller derby. REALLY GOOD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about your fundraising and sponsorship.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundraising and sponsorship in roller derby is really difficult. Over the past two to three years, the market has been flooded with teams competing for fans funds, which are finite, so everyone has had to become more creative. We've hosted tournaments, crowd funders and sold merch, but we won't make anywhere near our costs. We don't qualify for any funding from national bodies or charities either, so it's been hard. We have however been supported by our fantastic sponsors, in no particular order: Double Threat Skates - keeping our hardware working Roller derby City - our official kit and merch supplier Hoodlum Fang - creator of helmet covers and flags Bont- making our feet and compression clad legs do their thing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can we expect to see from team England at the World Cup? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An innovative and creative display of roller derby, by a skilled team of gentleman skaters.
And bowler hats. Lots of bowler hats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time around, England are in Group Orange with old pals Sweden and Argentina as well as Chile and Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their first game of the 2016 Men's Roller Derby World Cup will be against Sweden (tune to track 2 for this one) at 12pm which is 5am UK time. Make a nice cup of tea to wake you up for this one. In a nice cup with a saucer because it's the World Cup, you can be fancy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466935371393.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1466935371393.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/fb_img_1466935371393.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>england men's roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>men's roller derby world cup</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>team england</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/26/mrdwc-2016-team-review-england-mens-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 20:26:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Power of Scotland Fundraising for Calgary</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/02/15/power-of-scotland-fundraising-for-calgary/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Canada is very far away. This is fact. As a result, Power of Scotland have some pretty cool fundraising projects in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/11825045_700882493377553_2649629827109956984_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="11825045_700882493377553_2649629827109956984_n.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/02/11825045_700882493377553_2649629827109956984_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bungee Jumping for Funds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fionntán Ó Murchú aka the Real Scrim Shady plans to take to the skies to raise money for PoS,  take to the sky and then do a bungee jump. The mere concept of a bungee jump terrifies me so this chap is mega brave and deserving of a cheeky donation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The jump was initially scheduled to happen on 1st February 2016 but had to be rescheduled due to the weather (I'm looking at you Gertrude and Henry, who made it all windy and generally foul) as safety is important. A new date hasn't been announced yet but that does mean that there's still time to sponsor Fionntán.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/kskvy2sc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All Power No Bull Coed Bootcamp&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://i0.wp.com/www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/pos.jpg?w=656"&gt;&lt;img title="PoS" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://i0.wp.com/www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/pos.jpg?w=656?w=357"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 2nd April 2016, PoS are holding a bootcamp at Dundee International Sports Centre (aka the DISC).
This bootcamp is for everyone. EVERYONE!  Not only will there be a coed bootcamp for skaters but also a referee school and NSO workshop. These are all good things!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For skaters there will be an on skates and off skates portion. So not only will you learn some nifty jammer tricks and offensive skills but you will also learn about mental aand physical fitness. Oh and did I mention you can utilise your new skills in a scrimmage at the end? Oh yes! Scrim time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, who hasn't watched PoS skate and wonder 'how did he mow down the entire opposition?', 'did he apparate past the pack?' etc. This is your chance to learn directly from those skaters. Also, Milky, PoS skater and magical skater and ref extraordinaire will be joining in with the coaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The referee school will include positions, communication and you can pick the brains of ref legends Righteous Oxide and Faerie Nuff. Not literally of course, just soak up their skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NSO workshop will include NSO positions, people management and Head NSO responsibilities. All useful things. What better place to learn than at a bootcamp featuring two very experienced NSOs; Alix and Wendy (UKRDA affiliated Official )? If you are looking to improve your NSO skills, go learn from these experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Ticket Prices&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skater £30.00
Referee £15.00
NSO £10.00
Off skates coach spectators £10.00 (these are limited)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can go, then why would you not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://m.facebook.com/events/753462044787328/?ref=ts&amp;amp;fref=ts&amp;amp;__nodl&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coaching Opportunities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what if you can't make it to the bootcamp?  And you still want to bulk up your skills basket (you know, the metaphorical basket that you keep your skating skills in).  Don't be sad, you don't have to miss out! The members of PoS are available as coaches too. So if you're interested in having someone from PoS come to guest at your training session, this dream could happen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just contact PoS via their facebook page &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland/?ref=br_rs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Fundraising Coed Scrim&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 24th February 2016 PoS will be opening their doors for a coed scrimmage.  This will be held from 9-10.30pm in Grangemouth. Slush puppies and a scrimmage sounds like a mighty fine way to spend a weekday night!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual refs and NSOs are required and what better way to prepare yourself for the coed bootcamp?  It all links together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the bargain price of £5.00 per skater, you can get in on the action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, at the time of writing,  the teams were full and there is a reserves list so if you are interested and want to get your name on the reserves list...maybe pop on over to the event page&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://m.facebook.com/events/1663836440538824/?ref=3&amp;amp;ref_newsfeed_story_type=regular&amp;amp;feed_story_type=117&amp;amp;action_history=null&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/02/15/power-of-scotland-fundraising-for-calgary/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 18:15:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City Roller Derby- A Roundup of 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/21/granite-city-roller-derby-a-roundup-of-2015/</link><dc:creator>caleykapowski</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-wp-1447877216475.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img title="wp-1447877216475" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-wp-1447877216475.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2015 was a crazily busy and exciting year for Granite City roller Girls. We took part in British Championships for the first time, gained an accredited NSO, some of our members left to pursue new adventures, we expanded our league and at the end of 2015, we changed our name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Northern Fights took part in British Championships which was so exciting for the entire league! We were placed in Tier 3, Regional North; along with our good pals Dundee Roller Girls as well as Sheffield Steel Rollergirls, Furness Firecrackers, Liverpool Roller Birds and Halifax Bruising Banditas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first game in February saw us playing against Dundee Roller Girls. A fierce first game of the season and Champs! Dundee took the win with 366 to 58.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There wasn't long to wait until our next game in March where we were paired up against Sheffield Steel Rollergirls. The game was close and moments were tense, too tense. My poor wee heart! Final scores were GCRG 144 and SSRG 186.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June it was our turn to play Liverpool Roller Birds who scored 284 to our 111 with our next game just around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;July saw GCRG take on Furness Firecrackers who won our game with 325 to 112.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-fb_img_1447877829715.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1447877829715.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-fb_img_1447877829715.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo credit: the lovely  Ian McCreadie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August the Northern Fights played their last game of 2015 British Championships against Halifax Bruising Banditas. We won our final game of the year with a score of 226 to 72.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spoke to Berocca Bama, the Northern Fights co-captain for 2015, about taking part in British Championships.
&lt;em&gt;
"The Northern Fights had the privilege of taking part in the 2015 British Championships. It was an exciting year and although we started off with many skaters who were new to the team, every single one stepped up to the challenge and we went from strength to strength, surprising ourselves and others along the way. The dedication and drive of each sportswoman on the team makes me very proud to have played alongside them this season and fills me with excited anticipation for all that 2016 holds. Go Fights! "&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we had a record breaking, based on no fact at all other than it seemed a huge amount, number of skaters coming up from fresh meat together. One intake generated 12 new league skaters. 12! That’s almost an entire team. This increase in mins passed skaters is a combination of all of the hardwork put in by our fresh meat training squad (namely Shan, Krusty, Berocca Bama and Nikki) and the hardwork and determination that our ‘noobs’ bring with them to training each and every week. As a mentor I get to witness this first hand…and yes…I have cried many a proud tear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-wp-1447876987607.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img title="wp-1447876987607" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-wp-1447876987607.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo above: 11 of our 12 strong mins passed skaters from the start of the year, followed by 6 more later in the year &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This increase in mins passed skaters necessitated the need to introduce a second team. So, in 2015, Granite City Roller Girls welcomed their B Team. The Fight Hawks. Kakaw!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hawks played their first game in September against Lothian Derby Dolls. It was a tense game and I think we all learned never to start celebrating a win until the score says ‘Official’. A win was taken and fun was had all round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October the Hawks played Mean City. A loss was taken this time around but so much was learned and again, great times were had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spoke to Fight Hawks' co-captain Whips 'n' Lashes about our newest team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt; "2015 was an exciting year for GCRD with the creation of our B team – The Fight Hawks. Fierce and determined we rose to the challenge, with our first game together being a nail biting win. For a lot of our ladies this was their first ever public outing and the professionalism, attitude and energy they showed made our league and support very proud! 2016 is already looking like a good year and we hope to continue our development not only as a team but as a league and we are looking forward to the next lot of skaters coming up. Kakaw!"&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-fb_img_1447877532971.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="FB_IMG_1447877532971.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-fb_img_1447877532971.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo credit: the glorious Dave McAleavy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some say ‘you learn more in defeat that victory’, I can’t speak for everyone but I feel this is true. We may not have had an amazing win streak this year but after every game we have learned about ourselves and our team. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;December will see the annual GCRG Christmas ceildhi where we will celebrate our achievements of the year. Through the medium of dance and good times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision was made this year to rebrand. I, for one, am ridiculously excited about our new colour scheme. As a league and as skaters we are growing and we voted to change our name from Granite City Roller Girls to Granite City Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-bz4tbsp92ovcwuqx4vpjtodas6auvqgnsen4sztbxcw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img title="bZ4TBsp92oVCWUqx4VpjTODas6auVQgnsEN4SZtbxcw.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/11/wpid-bz4tbsp92ovcwuqx4vpjtodas6auvqgnsen4sztbxcw.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture above: our super amazingly fantastic new logos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge thank you goes out to everyone who has helped us to have an amazing 2015; referees and NSOs,  we couldn’t do any of this without you, announcers and photographers, our wonderful training team, everyone who has helped make bout days happen, our fans for never failing to keep our spirits high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here’s to 2016 and GRANITE CITY ROLLER DERBY!!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>gcrd</category><category>gcrg</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>granite city roller girls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/21/granite-city-roller-derby-a-roundup-of-2015/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 10:49:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>