<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts by camelondiaz)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/authors/camelondiaz.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs needs you!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/04/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-needs-you/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in being involved in the future of roller derby in Scotland? Now’s your chance; Fierce Valley Roller Cubs is looking for guest coaches from the wider world of Scottish roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-1833 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/10/cubs.jpg" alt="cubs" width="291" height="288"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based in Falkirk and training every Sunday, Fierce Valley Roller Cubs is open to all between the ages of 5 and 17, and currently has a range of skaters from beginners to advanced level. Cubs skaters have taken part in several intraleague games, the first of their kind in Scotland, and last year crossed the border to take part in their first external game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4611 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg" alt="10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n" width="530" height="376"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you could spare a couple of hours to share your knowledge and skills with the next generation of derby players and help take Fierce Valley Roller Cubs to the next level, please get in touch for more information: cubs@fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs was the first junior roller derby league in Scotland, and began training in September 2013.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/04/04/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-needs-you/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 10:47:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MENA's first ever public interleague - Abu Dhabi v CaiRollers.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/18/menas-first-ever-public-interleague-abu-dhabi-v-cairollers/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Friday 20th January, a little bit of roller derby history will be made when the CaiRollers host Abu Dhabi Roller Derby in the first ever public interleague game in the MENA region: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/403635766647515/"&gt;Arabian Fights: 1001 Jams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-13990" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/srd1.jpg" alt="srd1" width="640" height="238"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's taken both leagues several years to get to this point, and we spoke to Susan Nour (Nofearteti) of CaiRollers and Abu Dhabi Roller Derby's Milene Bizachi (Milificent) to find out more about the leagues and their thoughts on the upcoming game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-13991 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/srd2.jpg" alt="srd2" width="187" height="187"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did CaiRollers begin as a league, and how has it developed over the years?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We began in 2012 after two American expats met at work at a school in Cairo and realized that they had both previously played roller derby elsewhere. Shaneikiah Bickham (Naughty Ven Close) had played with the Big Easy Roller Girls and Angie Kaster (Indie Hannah) had played with the London Roller Girls. In that first year of their acquaintance they brainstormed on how to they could get a league started here in Egypt (because skates and gear are not available), and they started small with 8 players in September 2012. They had a vision that they wanted the league to be a more homegrown effort and not populated solely by expats in Egypt, and that has been the case. Today, our league is about 25 strong made up of Egyptian women and men from various social classes, with a handful of expats rounding out the numbers.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id="x_gmail-m_-4780500211593238315divtagdefaultwrapper" dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What difficulties have you faced in getting to this point?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main difficulties have been very similar to those faced by any other derby league in the world: finding suitable practice space, financing things and drumming up interest among people who have never heard of roller derby and have no idea what it's about. In addition to those issues we also still struggle with access to gear. While you can buy some basic protective gear in Cairo, it's not as durable as one would hope for roller derby. And while you can find in-line skates here, you can't find the kind of skates needed for derby. We've been wonderfully supported with gear donations from roller derby leagues around the world, and whenever one of our league travels we try to bring back gear for those who need it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id="x_gmail-m_-4780500211593238315divtagdefaultwrapper" dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CaiRollers is already a trailblazer, as the first roller derby league in Egypt.  How does it feel to be hosting the first ever roller derby game in the MENA region?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels fantastic! We are incredibly excited and proud to be hosting this game and cannot wait to face off against our sisters from Abu Dhabi. They have been incredible about organizing their members and self-funding to get here, and it has been great working with ADRD to get this thing off the ground. Our trainers and players have also been working so hard to get ready for game day. This has been the dream since the league started four years ago, so it definitely feels like a big achievement made all the better by the fact that so many people have come together across the two leagues to make this happen.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id="x_gmail-m_-4780500211593238315divtagdefaultwrapper" dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have you been preparing for the game?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from the practical things like securing a venue, boutfits, NSOs, volunteers etc. we've been working hard in practice on our strategy and teamwork, and devoting more time to conditioning out of regular practice times.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id="x_gmail-m_-4780500211593238315divtagdefaultwrapper" dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What has the local reaction been, both to the league in general and to this game?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since our inception, local reaction has been much more subdued than on the international scale. Although we've been around four years and have received wide media coverage both locally and internationally, we still remain relative unknowns within Egypt. Those who know us and are excited about what we're doing are mostly friends and colleagues. Having said that, among that subset people are really excited and see this game for the historic event that it is! As for reaction to the game in general - to know roller derby is to love it, and once people become familiar the game they generally become serious fans. We've been very lucky to have so much support at home and abroad.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id="x_gmail-m_-4780500211593238315divtagdefaultwrapper" dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are CaiRollers hopes and plans post-game, for 2017 and beyond? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we've come to this major milestone we hope to continue finding ways to play against leagues around the world. We've already got a game lined up with a team from Marseilles in April, and are having conversations here and there with other leagues around the world so we hope to see what comes out of those. At home, we hope to continue to grow both in numbers and skill and maintain the local, homegrown nature of our league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-13992 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/srd3.jpg" alt="srd3" width="201" height="201"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did Abu Dhabi Roller Derby begin as a league, and how has it developed over the years?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller derby was started in both Dubai and Abu Dhabi by expatriates with experience from playing roller derby in leagues from the USA, UK, Canada and Australia. Dubai has had a league since 2012. Abu Dhabi started skating regularly at Zayed Sports City and duForum in 2013.  Since then our league has grown to around 40 members, with 20 skating regularly. We still struggle to retain people as expats are often moving in and out of the country, but we have a great core team now of 12 girls, 2 refs and lots of volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does it feel to be taking part in the first ever roller derby game in the MENA region?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are exciting times. It's hard to train and keep yourself motivated without having a game or competition as a goal. The lack of other roller derby teams in the area is the main reason for this. So this game not only gave us a goal, but also raised the profile of the sport in the region, hopefully opening the doors for future games and the development of new roller derby teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have you been preparing for the game?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We train twice a week, outside, for about 2 hours. We have been working on reviewing the rules of the game, ensuring everyone knows the procedures, looking at and practising different strategy drills and playing against each other. We have also been testing a few new 'moves' and seeing what works. We have a few very experienced players, but also lots of people who have never taken part in a bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your hopes and plans post-game, for 2017 and beyond?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;We hope that the event will encourage more people to take part in the sport, raise the profile of roller derby in the region and our league to grow. We also plan to host the fabulous CaiRollers' Cleopatras in Abu Dhabi at some point this year. We want to spread the derby love in the region and hopefully get more of the public and local businesses on board.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Arabian Fights has a Facebook event &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/403635766647515/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.  &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Abu-Dhabi-Roller-Derby-153725484785780/"&gt;Abu Dhabi Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/CaiRollergirls/?fref=ts"&gt;CaiRollers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; can also be found on Facebook.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>abu dhabi roller derby</category><category>articles</category><category>cairollers</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>mena derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/01/18/menas-first-ever-public-interleague-abu-dhabi-v-cairollers/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 09:53:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cubs Take On New Opposition</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/07/cubs-take-on-new-opposition/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In September, Fierce Valley Roller Cubs celebrated their third birthday, and on Sunday October 9th, they will play their first game against other junior skaters. This mixed junior game will take place as part of a triple header hosted by Barnsley Black Heart Rollers and will feature skaters from Sheffield Steel Junior Rollers and Newcastle Junior Roller Derby League.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9210" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/13880228_1012374508875985_648255813429450617_n.jpg" alt="13880228_1012374508875985_648255813429450617_n" width="784" height="295"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cubs will be sending thirteen level 3 and advanced skaters to take part, some of whom will be playing in public for the first time, while others are veterans of several intraleagues. Needless to say, the level of excitement is high and the bus journey to Barnsley at 6.30am on Sunday promises to be a lively one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last word (as always), goes to the Cubs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s great to finally play against people that aren't in our own team. As good as it is to have bouts amongst our own team this bout against a different team gives a chance to see how well we are progressing. I'm really excited for the road trip and can't wait to get out on track” – Vanilla Crush.
“I am really happy and excited that we are getting to meet another junior team and play against them” – Lu Dog Millionaire.
“It’s not often that I see 6.30am at the weekend, the long journey will be worth it though, are we there yet?” – Purple Punisher.
“I am super chuffed to be captaining our first away game, it will be an eye opener for all involved I am sure” – Stunami.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Facebook event page can be found &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/583974361781762/"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;  Further information about Fierce Valley Roller Cubs is available &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/fiercevalleyrollercubs/?fref=ts"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/07/cubs-take-on-new-opposition/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 10:13:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Team Mexico</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/08/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-mexico/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As one of six teams new to the Men's Roller Derby World Cup, Team Mexico are something of an unknown quantity.  When the first MRDWC was held, the sport was still growing in Mexico, but now they're heading to Calgary and the Red Group, alongside Finland, Ireland, Japan, Scotland and defending champions USA. [After this article was written, Colombia dropped out of MRDWC 2016, and Mexico was moved to Group Green to even out the groups. They now face Canada, Spain, Germany and Wales.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corina Fischer told us more about bringing together the team, and its aims for the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-8087 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/mexico-logo.png" alt="Mexico logo" width="454" height="454"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*Team Mexico will make their debut at the Men's World Cup.  What are your aims in the tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of all, we want to let the world know about the talent we have in our country, we look forward to sharing the track with all the amazing teams that are attending such an important event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*You are in the largest group in the tournament, which also includes defending champions Team USA and last time's fan favourites NinJapan.  Which teams are you most looking forward to playing?  If you have time, who are you most looking forward to watching play?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Playing Team USA is a pleasure that not everyone has, so we are really looking forward to playing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*What's the level of interest in roller derby in Mexico?  How did you go about recruiting and selecting the team for the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's several men's roller derby teams in Mexico, so getting skaters interested in trying out for Team Mexico wasn't an issue.  We did two tryout dates, both with good attendance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*What have you been doing in terms of fundraising and preparation for the trip to Calgary?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a GoFundMe campaign, we've been selling merch, and of course we have been able to reach our goals with the support of our sponsors Mota Skates en Espanol, S1 Helmets, DerbySkinz, Latin Roller and Roller Rey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*This year, MRDWC are promoting the lead up to the Cup with the "Road to Calgary" tag.  In the spirit of this, what bouts and training have you been doing in preparation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've had scrimmages all year, along with a preparation game against the MRDA 3rd place team, Texas Men's Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*After the last World Cup, several national saw increased awareness and interest in roller derby. What are your hopes for the sport in Mexico?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a growing sport, the feeling of community is what makes it greater.  And now with our participation in the MRDWC 2016 more men will want to try this amazing sport.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Team Mexico's first game is against Japan - at 12 noon Calgary time - on Thursday on Track 1, followed by Ireland at 5pm on Track 2. The official MRDWC schedule is located &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  More information on Team Mexico can be found &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamMexicoMensRollerDerby/?fref=ts"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. [Due to schedule changes, Mexico now face Wales on Track 1 (9am) followed by Canada on Track 2 at 1pm.]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/08/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-mexico/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 09:51:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Team Canada</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/06/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-canada/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Birmingham in 2014, Team Canada produced a strong performance, losing only once, to Team USA in the semi-final, to finish in third place.  On home soil in Calgary, placed in the Green group alongside Colombia, Spain, Germany and Wales, can they go one step better this time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain Jeff Tichbourne shared his thoughts on Team Canada's preparation and aims for the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-8119 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/canada-logo.jpg" alt="Canada logo" width="358" height="358"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Canada will be fielding a strong team for the World Cup. How did you go about recruitment and selection this time?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Much like in 2014 we held open tryouts in the 3 areas with the largest concentration of players across Canada. Montreal, Red Deer and Vancouver were the 3 cities we held tryouts. Our Head Coach, Lime, was at all 3 tryouts so he got to have eyes on all the people trying out. Selection of our long list was done by the coaching staff and the short list was the same but with input from the players voted as captains by the team.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last time, Team Canada played very strongly, recording some big wins and finishing in third place. Two years later, what are your aims for the tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;We want to be in the Gold Medal game.  We have many smaller goals but they all lead to that one bigger goal, and we've got our eye on the prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your group features two returning teams (Wales and Germany) and two new to the tournament (Spain and Colombia). Which nations are you most looking forward to playing?  If you have time between games, who are you most looking forward to watching play?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We had a very physical game last World Cup versus Wales and we look forward to that again. The other 3 teams in our pool we haven't faced yet but we expect different styles from each of them so that's always exciting. If things work out the way we predict then the team we're most looking forward to playing is England. Between games expect to see us studying our next opponents.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last time around, you made the trip to England to compete.  How does it feel to be the host nation this year?  How has this affected your preparations?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We're thrilled to host so many players, officials, volunteers and fans from around the world. We really want to show them why Canada is known for its hospitality. Our preparation has been more thorough this time around and everyone is working harder than ever. We've got our nation behind us and that driving force will be with us for the whole tournament.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*This year, MRDWC are promoting the lead up to the Cup with the "Road to Calgary" tag. In the spirit of this, what bouts and training have you been doing since the last selection?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Training sessions have been happening across Canada with many players racking up air miles between cities just for the chance to skate together for a few hours.  We've had numerous high level WFTDA teams play our squad in preparation for the World Cup.  Being such a large country and not having access to each other all the time, we've used a lot of video sharing with our coaches for feedback and tips.  Our team will arrive early in Calgary to get as much skate time in as possible before the big event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Team Canada open the tournament by facing Germany at 9am - Calgary time - on Thursday on Track 1, followed by Colombia at 1pm on Track 2.  The official MRDWC schedule is located &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  More information on Team Canada can be found &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamCanadaMensRollerDerby/?fref=ts"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Arial;"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-8120 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/canada-roster.png" alt="Canada roster" width="386" height="484"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/06/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-canada/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 09:06:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Team USA</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/04/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-usa/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving across the Atlantic as we continue our look at MRDWC contenders, next up is a team that needs no introduction: Team USA.  The defending champions from 2014's inaugural MRDWC, will we see a repeat of this feat in Calgary?  Team USA have been placed in the Red group, alongside Finland, Japan, Mexico, and of particular interest, Ireland and Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spoke to Tony Muse, AKA Peter Pan, about the team's preparation and objectives for the tournament.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="rmTop t_mbgc"&gt; &lt;img class="wp-image-7932 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/usalogo.jpg" alt="USAlogo" width="334" height="333"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ReadMessageScrollableSection" class="rmMessages ClearBoth"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="rmSubject"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="rmButtons"&gt;&lt;span class="rmPrev"&gt;&lt;img class="i_rm_p" src="https://dub113.mail.live.com/ol/clear.gif"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; The Team USA selection is, as expected, very strong. How did you approach recruiting and selecting the team?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
For the selection of Team USA, we wanted to give as many skaters the opportunity to try out and be noticed as we possibly could. We held two separate try outs, one in Des Moines Iowa, home of Your Mom Men's Derby and a second in Deland Florida, home of the Magic City Misfits. There was no recruiting as everyone was invited and given the opportunity to show their skills against other top level skaters. After multiple rounds of blind voting from coaches and managers, the final squad was selected.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As defending champions from the first MRDWC, what are your aims in performance this World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Coming in to the second World Cup and as defending champions, we know we will have a large target on our team. Some of the players on Team USA are returning and others will be playing for their country for the first time. We think the passion that some of the new players will bring mixed with some of the experience some of the veterans will bring will be the perfect blend to keep us in the right frame of mind. As elite players, we are all looking to play the "perfect" game so every time we gather to play with such high level teammates, we aim for perfection.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your group features several European teams, plus one of the last World Cup’s fan favourites Japan and debutants Mexico - what teams are you most looking forward to playing? If you have time between games, who are you most looking forward to watching play?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We get excited about playing teams from all over the world because the teams tend to all skate a bit different and somewhat take on their own unique temperament. At the last World Cup, some of the fans were as excited to be at the event as the players so it added even an additional level of energy to the game with particular teams. We think the teams from Japan and Argentina will continue to be fan favorites but I imagine we may have new teams like the Italian or Mexican  squads stealing hearts this time around. The home team from Canada should be strong and well supported and of course England as the previous World Cup runner's up will be a solid squad to play against. We really look forward to the entire event both playing and watching as the World Cup can't be compared or matched to any other tournament in the sport.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The tournament is a lot closer for you this time around; how have you been fundraising and preparing for the trip?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Because the World Cup is so much closer this year, I think many members of the USA team will be bringing over more family, friends and support. Although Canada is right above us, many of the team members have not had the opportunity to travel much in Canada so the event is a great reason to do so. The team has been working with sponsors to help with some expenses but many of the fund raising ventures for Team USA have not started as we still have one big team camp before the event.
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*This year, MRDWC are promoting the lead up to the Cup with the "Road to Calgary" tag. In the spirit of this, what bouts and training have you been doing since the last selection?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
For our "Road to Calgary", Team USA has yet to compete against any other squad. That will all change soon as in mid May Team USA will be playing an exhibition bout against the reigning MRDA champions the St Louis Gatekeepers. This event will be accompanied by a training camp for the team.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Team USA's first game is against Scotland - at 11am Calgary time - on Thursday on Track 1, followed by Japan at 3pm on Track 2. The official MRDWC schedule is located &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  More information on Team USA can be found &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamusamensrollerderby/?fref=ts"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-7933 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/usaroster.jpg" alt="USAroster" width="960" height="960"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/04/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-usa/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 10:47:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>British Champs Tier 3: DRG vs FVRG</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/22/british-champs-tier-3-drg-vs-fvrg/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;23rd April will see the two Scottish teams in Tier 3 North face off as Fierce Valley Roller Girls, on home ground in Grangemouth, take on Dundee Roller Girls. Ahead of the fourth meeting between the teams (Dundee currently lead the head to head 2-1), we spoke to the captains, Laura Liston of DRG, and FVRG's Thump'her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/image2.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-7092 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/image2.jpeg?w=300" alt="image" width="300" height="172"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This will be the fourth meeting between DRG and FVRG; does knowing the opposition like this change how you prepare for the game?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laura&lt;/strong&gt;: I think it helps in some ways - knowing the biggest threats and the wall structures we'll face is a big asset. On the other hand it does mean you sometimes freak yourself out a bit knowing how skilled the opposition are.
&lt;strong&gt;Thump'her&lt;/strong&gt;: No, we have prepared for this game the same as any other. Of course it helps to have some knowledge of how the other team play and to know their strengths and any weaknesses but if we are to win on Saturday then we need to focus on playing our game and to our strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What, if anything, makes Champs games different from other games?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laura&lt;/strong&gt;: We go into Champs the same we would for any other game - we always aim to do the best we can and have an enjoyable time as a team, rather than focusing solely on the win. That being said, having a league table for champs and being able to see how we're comparing does bring out our competitive side!
&lt;b&gt; Thump'her&lt;/b&gt;: With Champs there is a little more pressure to perform at our best as so much work has gone into organising it. It's a massive competition and a fantastic opportunity to show the roller derby community what we are capable of. Plus, who enters a championship if they don't want to win it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/image1.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-7091 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/image1.jpeg?w=300" alt="image" width="300" height="166"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What have the team, and you as captain, learned from the Champs experience?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Laura&lt;/b&gt;: I think we've learned about the need to be flexible as a team. We've played such different opponents each game, so have had to change our plan each time. As a captain I've learned that the most important thing is that we as a league take something from every game to build on, and that we focus on just enjoying being on track together doing the best we can.
&lt;b&gt; Thump'her&lt;/b&gt;: Champs has taught us the importance of having a strong team bond, we are a small team but we know each other so well and that is what has carried us through it so far. We have all got to meet a lot of amazing people because of champs and it is one of the best aspects of it. Personally, I've had the opportunity to be captain to the best group of girls I've ever met who give it their all in each and every game and for that I am extremely grateful and proud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How have you prepared for the upcoming game?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Laura&lt;/b&gt;: We have looked back on our previous games and discussed what we have done well and what we need to work on. Hopefully we can put it into practice.
&lt;b&gt; Thump'her&lt;/b&gt;: We've prepared for the game the same way we do for any, by focusing on our strengths and continuing to work on any weaknesses we may have spotted from previous games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How does this season compare to last seasons champs experience?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Laura&lt;/b&gt;: This season feels a lot more structured for us - we've got a more consistent roster and have had a bit more time to plan properly for each game. We had a good season last year so we're keen to keep that momentum up.
&lt;b&gt; Thump'her&lt;/b&gt;: This season is a lot harder than last, we've came into this tier as an underdog facing some really good teams. We are looking forward to the challenge and the development that will come from playing such games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/image.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-7090 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/image.jpeg?w=300" alt="image" width="300" height="142"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Who do you admire from the opposing team?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laura: Calamity Jen - she's such a solid all round skater and really leads her packs on track.
Thump'her: It has to be Milky, she's came back so strong since her injury and that has to be something to admire. The whole team are strong and work incredibly well together so it should make for an exciting game!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>interviews</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/22/british-champs-tier-3-drg-vs-fvrg/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 18:23:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Cubs taster session</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/18/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-taster-session/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Cubs are recruiting!  Scotland's first junior roller derby league will be holding a fresh meat taster session on Sunday 24th April, from 13:30 - 14:30, in the Mariner Centre, Falkirk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4611" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/04/10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n.jpg" alt="10744964_366809973478799_46185807_n" width="960" height="681"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FVRC welcomes boys and girls aged 5-17, with no previous skating experience necessary.  We can provide kit to borrow for the session, with the exception of a mouthguard and helmet, so there is no commitment.  The taster will cover basic skating skills, most importantly, how to stop and fall safely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To register your interest, or for more information, please contact freshmeat@fiercevalleyrollercubs.co.uk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>fvrc</category><category>junior roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/18/fierce-valley-roller-cubs-taster-session/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 10:26:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Girls taster session</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/13/fierce-valley-roller-girls-taster-session/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Thursday 21st of April, Fierce Valley Roller Girls will be hosting a taster session in Grangemouth Sports Complex, from 9pm - 10.30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7044" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/04/new-skater-banner.jpg" alt="New Skater banner" width="851" height="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The taster is designed to let new skaters try roller derby – with no commitment – to see if this is the sport for them. FVRG welcomes anyone aged 18 and over, no previous skating experience necessary.&lt;span id="more-3116"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the session, participants will be buddied up with an experienced skater to learn the basics of skating (and stopping!) safely. Buddies will also loan their equipment for the taster. At the end of the session, the coaches will provide an overview of FVRG and what they do, and will answer any questions that anyone may have about roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New skaters will then be welcomed into a dedicated training program for beginners led by FVRG coaches. Once they progress through their training, regular assessments will be held to give the opportunity to climb the ranks into Intermediate, then Advanced training sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in joining Fierce Valley Roller Girls and are aged 18 or over, please complete the &lt;a href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/get-involved/join-fvrg/" target="_blank"&gt;Registration Form&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your place in this taster session.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>fvrg</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/04/13/fierce-valley-roller-girls-taster-session/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 08:14:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>International Roller Derby in the Forth Valley!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/23/international-roller-derby-in-the-forth-valley/</link><dc:creator>camelondiaz</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 9th of April, Fierce Valley Roller Girls will host their first home game of the year, and against international opposition in the shape of Zurich City Rollergirlz. The game will be the second in a double header, and marks just the second time that FVRG have faced an international league, after taking on Oslo Roller Derby back in October 2013.
Formed in 2009, Zurich City Rollergirlz was Switzerland’s first roller derby league and became a full WFTDA member league towards the end of 2015. Currently ranked at 95 in Europe by Flat Track Stats while FVRG sits at 127, this promises to be a close and hard fought game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6722" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/header.jpg" alt="header" width="960" height="352"&gt;
The double header will begin with a Rising Stars game featuring newer skaters from leagues across Scotland, many of whom will be making the public skating debut. The leagues represented include Ayrshire Roller Derby, Auld Reekie Roller Girls, Bairn City Rollers, Doonhame Derby Dolls, Dundee Roller Girls, Glasgow Roller Derby, Granite City Roller Girls, Inverness City Roller Derby, Lothian Derby Dolls and New Town Roller Girls.
The event takes place at Grangemouth Sports Centre with doors at 14:30 and the first whistle for the Rising Stars at 15:00. FVRG then take on Zurich from 17:15. Tickets are £5 (+ booking fee) in advance &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2514682"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, or £7 on the door.  Join the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/253213188342972/"&gt;Facebook event&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/23/international-roller-derby-in-the-forth-valley/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 09:51:38 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>