<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts by feemccartney)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/authors/feemccartney.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:34:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Fierce Valley Roller Girls - Round-up of 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/22/fierce-valley-roller-girls-round-up-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Lots of things have changed this past year for Fierce Valley Roller Girls. Their travel team - the Parma Violents - have climbed up the European rankings, and they also now feature on the UKRDA leader table after the league joined the UK Roller Derby Association in October 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;To hear more about it all, we caught up with one of FVRGs founding members and recently retired Chariperson: Grizabelta - who also officiated her 100th bout at the weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. 2014 has been an extremely eventful year for Fierce Valley Roller Girls: including having your Referrees and NSOs selected to officiate the Men's Roller Derby World Cup; beating Dundee Roller Girls in a 'third time lucky game'; and being asked to play against London Roller Girls. In amongst all of that activity, can you pick out your highlights from the past 12 months?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Wow... Yep it's certainly been a pretty good year for us! As the aforementioned NSO, being part of the MRDWC probably has to be my personal highlight – it was such an honour to get the chance to work with some of the best officials in the world, and to see the best men's derby skaters in the world too! I'm always amazed at just how far men's derby has come. But back to FVRG... It's always good to see our ladies being challenged and we've played some increasingly difficult teams this year, working up to our closed game against LRG's Batter C Power - that was pretty exciting!! We've also had a few Parma Violents debuts this year which are always a pleasure to see – Thump'Her, Johnny Hangover and CBoobies all proved that patience, some hard work and a lot of fun will pay off!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/11/1511901_730927216938384_949032229_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4415" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/11/1511901_730927216938384_949032229_n.jpg" alt="Officials at MRDWC (Griz in the left half) Photo courtesy of Roller Derby on Film" width="614" height="328"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Officials at MRDWC (Griz in the left half)&lt;br&gt;Photo courtesy of Roller Derby on Film
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Last year, FVRG achieved their goal of becoming a UKRDA member. How has this changed things in the league this year, and what can you hope to expect from this membership in the future?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I think this year has been mostly about finding our feet, we've gone from making decisions that only really affect ourselves, to having the chance to have a say on UK-wide roller derby and it's representation – and that can be a bit overwhelming. However it has given us the opportunity to take part in sanctioned gameplay for the first time – so we have a UKRDA ranking! We may only be 32nd but it's a start – and gives us something to aim to work our way up! As for the future, our new Chairperson WhoopAsh was lucky enough to attend UKROC with Dita von Cheeze – they brought back a huge amount of information and ideas, and as a result we plan to completely reassess how we run FVRG. It's an exciting time for us, but it will be challenging – however there is a wealth of knowledge and support available by being a UKRDA member so this will hopefully ease the strain a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The Parma Violents have hosted many home games this year and travelled for away games, and you've been alongside them - wearing a grey t-shirt and an impartial face! Which of these games stood out for you, either in terms of the teams performance or the excitement on the day itself?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Haha it's a case of 'have stopwatch, will travel' with me! Obviously during any game that I'm NSOing my focus is on my job at the time, so it's only really afterwards that I get to reflect on the team's performance. I've heard many great things about the GCRG game, which typically was the only one I wasn't able to make this year, so apart from that, probably the NRG game (or bout as it still was back then!) Although it was a re-match, I'd missed the original game last year so while I knew the score, I didn't really know how the teams had played beforehand, so I was really keen to see how the Violents had improved and if they could reduce the points differential – and they did! It was also my first outing as Head NSO for FVRG, so that in itself always brings a new combination of stress and excitement!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. You have recently stepped down as Chairperson of FVRG  - a role that you've held since the league's inception in November 2010. You'll have seen lots of changes in that time, not just in the Parma Violents but within the entire league. What league achivements are you most proud of over these past 4 years?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Oh jings... Every now and then, usually at a Fresh Meat session or some other big event, I take a step back and it just hits me – a little idea that came from three friends on a train has turned into a fully functioning, self sufficient roller derby league. It's been an absolute pleasure to see the league grow and help to steer it in its current direction, and I think we've achieved so much – from celebrating our first birthday with our closed bout against Fair City Rollers, to our third birthday with our first international bout against Oslo Roller Derby! I'm also always really proud of our connections with various community and charity events – we've done everything from supporting roller discos, stewarding firework displays and registering marathon runners to being part of the launch of the new Helix Park in Falkirk. And I have to give a special mention to the Fierce Valley Roller Cubs – so many of our members work so hard for both FVRG and FVRC, and I'm super excited for our double header intraleague game in December where we get to show off the talents of not only our newer FVRG skaters, but also the future of Scottish roller derby!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. What do you see as the next step for Fierce Valley Roller Girls in 2015... and beyond?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Well as I mentioned before, it's going to be all change in the next few months. We have a newly elected Board who are all buzzing with ideas about how we can improve FVRG for the better, and we're starting from the bottom – what are our goals and values and where do we want to be – the answers will be very different now to what they were four years ago! I'd love to see FVRG continue to challenge themselves with the teams that they play, and hopefully there will be opportunities for our newer skaters to play against new opponents too – I think the mixed 'cherry popper' games that we're seeing a lot more of are a great idea. In the very long term, it would be great to become part of WFTDA – a few years ago it seemed impossible, but with the amount of European teams we have now it's become... plausible! It's an exciting time for us – and while I may have taken a step down, I'm not going far – and I can't wait to see and be part of what's in store!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/11/img_0231-copy.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4413" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/11/img_0231-copy.jpg" alt="Parma Violents vs London's Batter C Power Photo courtesy of Laura MacDonald" width="614" height="409"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Parma Violents vs London's Batter C Power&lt;br&gt;Photo courtesy of Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>grizabelta</category><category>interviews</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/22/fierce-valley-roller-girls-round-up-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 11:00:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>FVRG Double-Header with The Cubs</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/17/fvrg-double-header-with-the-cubs/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 13th December, &lt;a title="FVRG Website" href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk" target="_blank"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; will be hosting a double-header event, featuring Scotland's only junior roller derby team - the Fierce Valley Roller Cubs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 4 teams playing in the event will represent the Hogwarts Houses from Harry Potter: The Cubs will be split between Hufflepuff and Ravenclaw, and the adult skaters will be in either Gryffindor or Slytherin.Both The Cubs and FVRG have competed in their own intra-league games earlier this year, but this is the first time that the two will play in the same event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The double-header will take place in Grangemouth Sports Complex. The hall doors will open at 3pm for a 3:30pm start - plenty of time to browse the stalls and the bake sale before the action starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are priced at £6 (+admin fee) from &lt;a title="Buy Tickets" href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/956261" target="_blank"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt;, and kids under 14s go free with a paying adult. If there are still tickets left on the day, they will be sold for £8 on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join the &lt;a title="Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/732876330125845/" target="_blank"&gt;FVRG Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt; for further details - and keep your eyes peeled for our Ticket Giveaway competition!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/11/10429276_884219831589870_6448227145220386816_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4212" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/11/10429276_884219831589870_6448227145220386816_n.jpg" alt="Poster designed by Mho McDougall from FVRG" width="614" height="515"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Poster designed by Mho McDougall from FVRG&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller cubs</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>junior roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/17/fvrg-double-header-with-the-cubs/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 21:58:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interviews: Scandinavia</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/27/world-cup-interviews-uk-ireland/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last week, we have interviewed the 4 teams from Scandinavia who will be taking part in the upcoming &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you missed any of them, here’s a recap:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Denmark" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/22/world-cup-interview-team-denmark/"&gt;Team Denmark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Norway" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/21/world-cup-interview-team-norway/"&gt;Team Norway&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Finland" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/23/world-cup-interview-team-finland/"&gt;Team Finland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World Cup Interview: Team Sweden" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/24/world-cup-interview-team-sweden/"&gt;Team Sweden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, we are heading over to North America to chat with two newcomers to the World Cup, and two who played in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team denmark</category><category>team finland</category><category>team norway</category><category>team sweden</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/27/world-cup-interviews-uk-ireland/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 11:53:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Sweden</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/24/world-cup-interview-team-sweden/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a title="Team Sweden on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/teamswedenrollerderby" target="_blank"&gt;Team Sweden &lt;/a&gt;are no strangers to playing as a national side, having competed in the 2011 Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup and also taking part in many preparation games for the 2014 World Cup.
&lt;p&gt;Swede Hurt and the team's media team very kindly took time out of their busy training schedule to tell us how they are feeling about their upcoming World Cup appearance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/10356690_917939274889367_1670650037814336947_n.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4035" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/10356690_917939274889367_1670650037814336947_n.png" alt="Team Sweden Logo" width="614" height="292"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Team Sweden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Team Sweden is filled with skaters from many different teams. How did you organise the team selection process since your skaters come from all over the country?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our team we have skaters from seven different leagues, both Swedish, English and American. During try outs there were even more leagues represented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone that was interested in trying out were asked to fill in an application, and out of the nearly 70 girls that applied we invited about 40 girls to the try-outs. The actual try-out was held in Gothenburg and people who didn't have the opportunity to be there were asked to send video footage of themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. How often are you able to meet up, and what do you focus on to make the best use of your training time together?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We practice together approximately every other month. During the spring we've had a couple of bouts and scrimmages against other teams as well. For example we played against Team USA, Team England, LRG Brawl Saints and Team Finland. When we practice together we aim to become more cohesive, and we really have been trying to mix up skaters from different leagues. Even though a lot of us know each other from before, we might not know how to play with each other. So that's one of the most important things we do: get to know our teammates on the track. We discuss different strategies and try what works for our team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Several of the other European national teams are participating in tournaments before the World Cup to get in some extra practice ahead of the World Cup. What does Team Sweden have planned?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As said earlier, we have a few bouts under our belt at this point. We have cut our training group down to the actual 19 people who will skate at the World Cup. We still have some training ahead of us, and maybe even a bout or scrimmage. We have a very skilled and fit team, and we are confident that all the time we have spent on trying to get to know each other will pay off in Dallas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. As a team which did participate in the 2011 World Cup, you already have experience of playing in a tournament. This must test your team mentally, as well as physically – how will you ensure that Team Sweden stays motivated throughout?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a lot of experienced players that have played tournaments before and will support each other the best we can. Our bench management and physiotherapist will also be a huge help to our mental game in Dallas. We anticipate that Dallas is going to be very different from Toronto, but we really learned that we need access to good food and sleep to be successful. But also time for the team to chill and to have a  game plan. We are going to Dallas to play kick-ass roller derby!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Given the expense of getting to Dallas for the World Cup, how are you raising funds and gaining sponsorship?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have reached out both locally and globally for sponsors and we are really happy to have Cheeseballs, Radar Wheels, Quad Skateshop, SISU mouthguards and hopefully some other sponsors with us. We also have had a fundraiser; we are &lt;a title="Buy Team Sweden Merchandise" href="http://teamsweden.tictail.com/" target="_blank"&gt;selling merch online &lt;/a&gt;(please buy some!); and we have a &lt;a title="Team Sweden's GoFundMe" href="http://www.gofundme.com/bzkdbk" target="_blank"&gt;'go fund me' &lt;/a&gt;for people who feel compelled to donate money to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. And just for fun, does your team have a mascot? If you don’t, what would type of mascot would symbolise your national team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the deepest forests of Sweden hides a great big animal that will horn all the competition away... Just you wait!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/ts-training-group-2014.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4037" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/ts-training-group-2014.jpg" alt="Team Sweden Training Group 2014" width="614" height="327"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Team Sweden Training Group 2014&lt;br&gt;Image courtesy of Team Sweden&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team sweden</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/24/world-cup-interview-team-sweden/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 10:00:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Finland</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/23/world-cup-interview-team-finland/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next team to be interviewed from Scandinavia are &lt;a title="Team Finland on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/teamfinlandrollerderby" target="_blank"&gt;Team Finland&lt;/a&gt;, who will be making a return appearance in the Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup this year. After finishing in a very respectable 5th place in 2011, Suvi Hokkanen - Head Coach for Team Finland- has shared how her team are preparing for Dallas later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/team-finland.png"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter wp-image-4113 size-medium" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/team-finland.png?w=300" alt="Team Finland Logo" width="300" height="263"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Team Finland is filled with skaters from 4 different Finnish teams, as well as skaters from Sweden; England and USA! How did you organise the team selection process since your skaters come from so many different countries?&lt;/strong&gt; We had our try-outs in August 2013 in Helsinki. Our skaters are very dedicated, and nearly all of them made it to the try-out weekend. There were only two skaters who couldn't come to the try-outs, but we were able to host an alternative try-out session for them. 60 skaters tried out, and after 2 days of skating we picked 30 skaters for the squad. All of the skaters were picked under the eyes of the coaching crew and we didn't need any video material in order to form our squad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. How often are you able to meet up, and what do you focus on to make the best use of your training time together?&lt;/strong&gt; We have Team Finland boot camps every 2 to 3 months. The boot camps are weekends filled with skating, strategy and also getting to know each other. Last spring we focused on forming the final team for the World Cup and now as the roster is out, we are focusing on the overall tool box that we need in order to play well together as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Several of the other European national teams have recently participated in tournaments to get in some extra practice ahead of the World Cup. What does Team Finland have planned?&lt;/strong&gt; We have already played against Team Sweden in February. On our next boot camp, we will play against Tampere Rollin Bros, one of the men's roller derby teams in Finland. Many of the Bros skated in the Men's World Cup in Birmingham back in March, so they'll be an appropriate opponent to test our skills on. We do have little something special planned, but I still need to keep our plans a secret. Unfortunately, we are quite isolated, and the flights to/from Finland are expensive. The skaters have to travel a lot with their home leagues, and the travel expenses to Dallas are massive. We are glad that Finland has such a talented derby community, and we get to practise against high level teams on home soil before the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. As a team which did participate in the 2011 World Cup, you already have experience of playing in a tournament. This must test your team mentally, as well as physically - how will you ensure that Team Finland stays motivated throughout the tournament?&lt;/strong&gt; I don't think that the national team skaters need to worry about being motivated when they are skating for their country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Given the expense of getting to Dallas for the World Cup, how are you raising funds and gaining sponsorship?&lt;/strong&gt; We have applied for a fund from a Finnish organisation. They picked us for their September campaign, and if we get the most votes on their website, well be getting the fund we applied for. All the local leagues and our fans have been active in promoting the campaign. We've also been selling Team Finland merchandise, and we will bring some with us to Dallas as well. We have teamed up with roller derby companies too: we all skate in S-One sponsored helmets, and Radar Wheels is providing us with new wheels. A local skater, Ysi Musta from Lahti Roller Derby is coming out with a line of protective garments designed for roller derby, and she's letting us try them out. We're open for other collaborations as well, so just shoot us a message!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. And just for fun, does your team have a mascot? If you don't, what would type of mascot would symbolise your national team?&lt;/strong&gt; Most of the national sports teams in Finland are named after animals. For example the basketball team is known as wolf pack;  ice-hockey as lions; footballers as owls. In the last World Cup we had silver shirts and people started to call us herrings. (BTW Herring is a really popular dish in Finland). We are our own mascots, power animals and heroes. Please bring your herring signs to Dallas, and cheer for us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/team-finland.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-3827 size-full" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/team-finland.jpg" alt="Team Finland in Action!" width="960" height="641"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Team Finland in action!&lt;br&gt; Image courtesy of Marko Niemela
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Team Finland Roster&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;OONA #00&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Only #1 CC&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Pygmi #101&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;MIA #156&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Elina Ruhoranta #18&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Super Maria # 1UP&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Nina Erwes #28 CC&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Maiju Rinne #39&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Iiris Suominen #404&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Doomey B. Hind #4444&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dominå F. Äkt #455&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The Blizzard #54&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A. M. Chaos #5&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Kira Horpi #56&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sara Ekholm #604&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Rita Hateworthy #8&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;T-Bag #9&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Linda #96&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tsubutex #99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Coach Crew:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Suvi Hokkanen - Head coach&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jori Hämäläinen - Assistant coach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Team Management:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Raisa Siivola&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Anna Miettinen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team finland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/23/world-cup-interview-team-finland/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 10:00:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Denmark</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/22/world-cup-interview-team-denmark/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next team to be interviewed from Scandinavia are &lt;a title="Team Denmark on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Team-Denmark-Roller-Derby/675984235754356" target="_blank"&gt;Team Denmark&lt;/a&gt;. This will be their first World Cup appearance, and they have already played in two tournaments recently to prepare for the challenge ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mai Olesen a.k.a Toxic Noir - Manager for Team Denmark - has been speaking to us to share how the team are preparing for the Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup in Dallas later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/team-denmark-logo.png"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-3911 size-medium" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/team-denmark-logo.png?w=300" alt="Team Denmark Logo" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Team Denmark&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Team Denmark is filled with skaters from 5 different Danish teams, and even a skater from Crime City Rollers in Sweden! How did you organise the team selection process since your skaters come from all over Denmark, and beyond?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First we had 4 training sessions where everyone that applied for a spot could come.  These training sessions also included an off-skates strength program and a strategy session. After these sessions we had the try-outs, where we tested them in strength, understanding, rules, technique and scrimmage. This format made it possible for us to get to see the skaters in action quite a bit before the day of try-outs. For us, Team Denmark is also an opportunity to spread the knowledge [learnt in training sessions] to all the leagues in Denmark and move the sport forward here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All try-outs and training sessions were held in Copenhagen. Organizing it all is a question of trying to make sure that the players and people involved know well in advance what dates to block out. Transportation is quite expensive in Denmark and as you pointed out the players come from all over the country + Sweden - and we also have our player Miss Mane who is from the Faroe Islands - so letting people know when and where is an important task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. How often are you able to meet up, and what do you focus on to make the best use of your training time together?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have an activity every month which could be a training weekend, a bout or a tournament.  At one of our activities we had the pleasure of having Olivia Coupe from London Rollergirls visit and coach us, which we really enjoyed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We focus on teamwork, building an understanding of some basic plays we do, and also spend time to get to know each other as skaters and coaches. On the side of this, we have a strength and endurance training program to step it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. I see that Team Denmark have recently played in a triple-header tournament with Team Norway and Team France, and you will soon be playing in a European tournament with 7 other teams. What are you hoping to learn from these experiences that you can take forward into the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was important for us to get some bout experience as a team so playing at the [triple-header] tournament was very useful for us. Many of the skaters had never played in a tournament before so it was great to get this opportunity. In this tournament our key focus was to learn to save energy and play smart, because after the first bout you´ll have another one to play! It was also an inspiring weekend to see how dedicated the other National Teams were and how they played. We got the chance to play people in different positions and to see how they reacted under pressure and with a loose schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European Roller Derby Tournament let us build on what we tested and established in Norway. It was an amazing tournament and we saw Team Denmark really coming together and getting some great learning experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After these experiences we feel much more prepared for what awaits us in Dallas - still exited, still a bit nervous, but definitely much better prepared:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Since Team Denmark did not participate in the 2011 World Cup, what are your aims for the tournament this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, we fully expect to get our butts kicked...Royally!! But in true derby style we are looking forward to that :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many teams playing in the World Cup that we simply have no idea how good they are. So we will get in there and compete hard for one jam at the time. Much has changed in the derby world since 2011, but our goal is to be one of the top 5 "new" teams that are participating in the tournament. And of course that we will get to play some good games. Other than that we are very committed to having the best time ever and soak up all everything that we learn. We want to bring this knowledge back home as a foundation for development in roller derby on a national level in Denmark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Given the expense of getting to Dallas for the World Cup, how are you raising funds and gaining sponsorship?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are doing what everyone else is doing I think: selling merchandise and hosting a &lt;a title="Donate to Team Denmark" href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/send-roller-derby-all-stars-denmark-to-world-cup" target="_blank"&gt;'crowd funding' &lt;/a&gt;page. Our latest plan is to organize a fundraising event with a scrimmage and a raffle or auction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have contacted a lot of Danish companies for sponsorships, but without luck. Denmark doesn't really have a great history or culture for sponsorships in upcoming sports (which roller derby is in DK) , but we will keep chasing money - so who knows, we might succeed yet. We also got a little bit of monetary support from the Danish Roller Skating Union. We had a raffle at the European Roller Derby Tournament so that also gave us a little money. We are currently sponsored by Atom Wheels and S-One helmets as well which is great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. And just for fun, does your team have a mascot? If you don’t, what would type of mascot would symbolise your national team?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don't have a mascot but if we did it would be either a lion, like the one we have on our uniform. Or maybe a hotdog or a Carlsberg beer mascot!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/team-denmark-skaters.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3912" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/team-denmark-skaters.png" alt="Team Denmark Skaters" width="614" height="227"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Team Denmark
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Denmark Roster&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Hald, Copenhagen Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Beastie Bob, Copenhagen Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Bay, Copenhagen Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Cater, Copenhagen Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Durakill Bunny, Copenhagen Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fjabbeline, Copenhagen Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Kimmer, Copenhagen Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Rode, Copenhagen Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jelly, Copenhagen Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;LOL, Copenhagen Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Miss Mane, Copenhagen Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Pedersen, Copenhagen Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Yaya Woosh, Copenhagen Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Arachna, Aarhus Derby Danes&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Kris, Aarhus Derby Danes&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Keller, Aarhus Derby Danes&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Panzer, Roller Derby Århus&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Deenfeldt, Crime City Rollers, Malmö&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Panini, Odense Rollergirls&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Möxie Crüel, Aalborg Roller Derby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Team Management&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Team manager: Mai Olesen&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Head coaches: Emma Hedman (Sabo) &amp;amp; Henrik Levinsson (Slutty Summers)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Assistant coach: Tore Brynaa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team denmark</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/22/world-cup-interview-team-denmark/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 10:00:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Norway</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/21/world-cup-interview-team-norway/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kicking off the Scandinavian interviews in our World Cup series, we caught up with &lt;a title="https://www.facebook.com/teamnorwayrollerderby" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/21/world-cup-interview-team-norway/Team%20Norway%20on%20Facebook" target="_blank"&gt;Team Norway&lt;/a&gt; right after they played in a European Roller Derby Tournament. Signe Sletmoen has kindly shared how her team are preparing for their first appearance in the Blood &amp;amp; Thunder World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/team-norway.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-3771 size-full" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/team-norway.jpg" alt="Team Norway Logo" width="614" height="226"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Team Norway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Team Norway is filled with skaters from 2 different Norwegian teams, as well as skaters from England and USA! How did you organise the team selection process since your skaters come from so many different countries?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we first started talking about gathering a national team, we asked around to locate Norwegian roller derby players in foreign countries. We also announced that we were looking for three further positions: two coaches and one Team Manager. We invited everyone that fitted the criteria along to two weekend sessions where we worked on skills, drills and scrimmages. We than had a two-day try out where the coaches and the team manager chose a roster of 20 players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. How often are you able to meet up, and what do you focus on to make the best use of your training time together?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately we have not meet up as often as we would have liked to. This is due to both travelling distance and economy [cost]. But we had the try out in February, and met once in April, and then again in August. Since we have such little [training] time together, we focus mainly on getting to know each other on track and playing together as one team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. I see that Team Norway have recently played in a triple-header tournament with Team Denmark and Team France. What did you learn from this experience that you can take forward into the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are skaters from different leagues and teams, with different tactics, track language and derby style. We wanted to use the tournament as an opportunity for us to play together as one team; get to know each other; and to figure out how we can make the most of our skills and players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the tournament, we played against Team Denmark and Team France for the first time. They had very different strategies so that diversity was a good learning experience for us. We constantly had to work on being able to switch it up, and to get used to the speed, strength and tactical qualities that more experienced teams possess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Since Team Norway did not participate in the 2011 World Cup, what are your aims for the tournament this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We go in to this tournament without focusing too much on rankings and results. Our goal will be to play our very best derby, learn a lot - and hopefully win several bouts! Since it is our first World Cup, we have to see it as a learning experience, but we do look forward to getting some  real fierce resistance and great challenges - both as individual players and as a team. This will be a great way to grow Norwegian roller derby as a sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Given the expense of getting to Dallas for the World Cup, how are you raising funds and gaining sponsorship?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a 'crowd funding' project,  &lt;a title="Team Norway Coupons" href="http://www.teamnorwayrollerderby.no/tickets/" target="_blank"&gt;set-up coupons to use when buying tickets online&lt;/a&gt;, and we have also managed to get some sponsors. A local tattoo studio - &lt;a title="Luck 7 on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Lucky-7/135423489860706" target="_blank"&gt;Lucky 7&lt;/a&gt; - have arranged a fundraiser for us. The &lt;a title="Norwegian Skating Association Website" href="http://www.n-s-f.no/english/about_nsa.htm" target="_blank"&gt;Norwegian Skating Association&lt;/a&gt; is also helping out with the finances, and that's only to mention some! But I think all of us are relying on getting a little bit extra from Santa this year. Hopefully everyone has behaved the last year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. And just for fun, does your team have a mascot? If you don’t, what would type of mascot would symbolise your national team?&lt;/strong&gt;
We don't have a mascot (yet), but I guess our mascot would be something like John Snow. We are after all the once defending the wall in the north! It could also be a really fluffy ice bear or a big, hairy musk. You'll see when we meet in December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/tn_roster_dallas4.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3769" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/tn_roster_dallas4.jpg" alt="Team Norway Roster - World Cup 2014" width="614" height="398"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Team Norway Roster - World Cup 2014&lt;br&gt;Image courtesy of Team Norway&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team norway</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/21/world-cup-interview-team-norway/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 10:00:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ARRG's Cannon Belles v Hamburg's Harbor Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/23/arrgs-cannon-belles-v-hamburgs-harbor-girls/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 27th September, &lt;a title="ARRG on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/auldreekierollergirls" target="_blank"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;' Cannon Belles will welcome &lt;a title="Harbor Girls on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/harborgirls" target="_blank"&gt;Harbor Girls&lt;/a&gt; from Hamburg at Meadowbank Sports Centre, Edinburgh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already this year the Cannon Belles have played against Newcastle's Whippin' Hinnies; Dirty River Roller Grrrls from Turku, Finland; and Birmingham Blitz Dames. The Belles have been growing from strength-to-strength, so this is a game not to be missed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 2pm, with the skate outs starting at 2:30pm. Tickets can be bought online from &lt;a title="Buy Tickets!" href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/856791" target="_blank"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt; for £7, or can be bought on the door if you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 'vendor village' will be open for business before the game and at half-time, selling a wide range of ARRG merchandise - including new Limited Edition lines - and of course, cake!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please join ARRG's &lt;a title="ARRG Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1417012465241631/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt; for more details on the event and how you can show your support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/arrg-v-hamburg.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3854" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/arrg-v-hamburg.jpg" alt="ARRG V HAMBURG" width="614" height="237"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>edinburgh</category><category>hamburg harbor girls</category><category>meadowbank sports centre</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/23/arrgs-cannon-belles-v-hamburgs-harbor-girls/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 19:01:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Parma Violents vs. Silvery Tayzers</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/26/parma-violents-vs-silvery-tayzers/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Saturday 6th September, FVRG's Parma Violents will take on DRG's Silvery Tayzers in Grangemouth Sports Complex. Doors open at 3:30pm, with the game starting at 4pm.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;The two teams first met in February 2012 in the Parma Violents first public game. Although the Silvery Tayzers took home the victory, the Parma Violents jumped at the chance for a rematch in November 2013, and again for the chance to play them again next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Tickets are available online from &lt;a title="Buy Tickets Online" href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/836544" target="_blank"&gt;Brown Paper Tickets&lt;/a&gt; for £5 (+ admin fee), or £7 on the door. Under 14s go free with a paying adult.  Join FVRG's &lt;a title="FVRG Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1515534441994379/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt; for more information - and details on their ticket give-away competition!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/header.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3632" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/header.jpg" alt="Image courtesy of Fierce Valley Roller Girls" width="614" height="292"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Fierce Valley Roller Girls
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><category>parma violents</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/26/parma-violents-vs-silvery-tayzers/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 18:50:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>FVRG Fresh Meat - 17th August</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/06/fvrg-fresh-meat-17th-august/</link><dc:creator>feemccartney</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;On Saturday 17th August, &lt;a title="FVRG Website" href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk" target="_blank"&gt;Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt; will be hosting a Fresh Meat taster session in Grangemouth Sports Complex to recruit new skaters into their roller derby league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;The taster session is designed to let you try roller derby - with no commitment - to see if this is the sport for you. You will be buddied up with an experienced skater to learn the basics. They will also loan you their equipment for the taster, so no need to buy any equipment just yet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;If you’re hooked after this first session, FVRG will welcome you into a dedicated training program for beginners. Once you progress through your training, regular assessments will be held to give you the opportunity to climb the ranks into the Intermediate, then Advanced training sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:justify;"&gt;If you are interested in joining Fierce Valley Roller Girls and are aged 18 or over, please complete their &lt;a title="Join FVRG" href="http://www.fvrg.co.uk/get-involved/join-fvrg/" target="_blank"&gt;Registration Form&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your place in this Fresh Meat intake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/1551467_829767823701738_6311318072421424699_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3569" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/1551467_829767823701738_6311318072421424699_n.jpg" alt="Image Courtesy of Fierce Valley Roller Girls" width="614" height="371"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image Courtesy of Fierce Valley Roller Girls&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>fvrg</category><category>grangemouth sports complex</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/06/fvrg-fresh-meat-17th-august/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 12:10:41 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>