<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts by jennifergelignite)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/authors/jennifergelignite.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:24 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>2015 was ARRGmazing!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/31/2015-was-arrgmazing/</link><dc:creator>jennifergelignite</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/arrg-banner.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5399"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-5399 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/arrg-banner.jpg?w=300" alt="ARRG-Banner" width="837" height="187"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a comedy gig with a famous guy (remember Dylan Moran back in January!).
The Reserves took on the Oxbridge double.
The All Stars came second in the first ever British Championships!
And we hosted THE best Champs day in May!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The All Stars took on Glasgow in June again, a month that also featured an excellent family fun day in Portobello!
We had a Hunger Games themed Bootcamp in July! Those May the Quads be Ever in your Favour tops were a popular choice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the Fringe, the All Star Reserves took on Glasgows Maiden Grrders, and then we held an awesome All Star Expo with skaters from across Scotland and Northern England!
Throughout the year we held some Taster Days and Fresh Meat intakes!
And of course the year has culminated in the Home Season and All Star Reserves season!
We've also said some sad goodbyes, but welcomed many awesome members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Home Season 2015 was won by THE LEITHAL WEAPONS!! In a very closely fought game against The Skatefast Club, with the score being extremely close throughout. Congratulations to the Cherry Bombers for taking the victory in the third place game against our guests, The Rolling Bones - what a win!
Thank you to ALL of everyone who helped at the Home Season, whether you skated, officiated, announced, helped as a member of the game crew, EVERYONE. THANKS!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also got the FIRST Certified officials in Scotland! Which is pretty huge! And we had official reps at some of the biggest tournaments/games around Europe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our All Star Reserves came back from an excellent trip to Copenhagen at the start of November!
They played both Copenhagen Roller Derby and Malmo's Crime City, in the one day! They did amazing for being pitted against such tough teams! So many giants. Hipster hostels. Team hang outs. Christmas. I think we can say it was still a successful trip!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now the Reserves have a couple more games in the new year! In January they will be taking on Dresden Roller Derby at home, and we can’t wait! And then another in March!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new rosters have also been announced, and the All Stars themselves have started training in time for, yes, THE BIG O! This is a fantastic opportunity and an amazing tournament. SO many amazing teams will also be there! Even the other ARRG (Arch Rival Roller Girls). And whether you can make it over to Portland (we wish), or can cheer and support from here, there is SUCH EXCITEMENT.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>leithal weapons</category><category>maiden grrders</category><category>review of the year</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/31/2015-was-arrgmazing/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 13:45:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls - Home Season Final 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/28/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-season-final-2015/</link><dc:creator>jennifergelignite</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="spotlight alignleft" src="https://scontent.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpl1/v/t35.0-12/12359395_10153180288466022_1192149624_o.jpg?oh=24e2550bb0d345849186b5816bf3ebeb&amp;amp;oe=56835C21" alt="" width="755" height="501"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A HEART-STOPPING home season final saw the Leithal Weapons swoop to victory by just two points.
Auld Reekie Roller Girls' (ARRG) three home teams - the Leithals, Skatefast Club and the Cherry Bombers - had battled throughout autumn for the chance to take home the 2015 trophy.
Skatefast had beaten the Leithals in the first home season head-to-head and, with the Leithals struggling to field a full team for the final due to injury and illness, looked like the stronger team at the first whistle.
Skill levels were closely-matched and the lead switched several times, as both teams pushed their opponents to pull out their very best performance.
Skatefast were leading by half-time and victory seemed likely, but the Leithals re-entered the track with renewed determination.
With five minutes to the end, Skatefast had pulled ahead by 20 points, leaving the Leithals praying for a power jam.
Suddenly, the opportunity opened up with excellent defensive work from the Leithals in the very last jam.
EmKarp blasted through the Skatefast blockers and the crowd held its breath and held back tears as the points gap closed.
A smart star pass to Tuna Lovegood for an extra energy kick sealed the deal... Or so the Leithals hoped.
The unofficial result was carefully checked as both teams teetered on the brink of celebration for a score that could have gone either way.
Finally those two crucial extra points were verified and the Leithal Weapons were officially declared the 2015 winners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="spotlight alignright" src="https://scontent.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpa1/v/t1.0-9/12299301_10156272236840224_1957699839736333339_n.jpg?oh=fddaf7b01dbf9fe3a6fba64e58b5d64f&amp;amp;oe=57194B21" alt="" width="480" height="360"&gt;
Leithals captain Prawncess Die said she was thrilled for her team.
She said: "We went in as the underdogs.
"We thought we had a good chance but we were playing short and we had lost the last game against them.
"It was so close - I kept looking at the score thinking we can still do this.
"We drifted down 20 points a few times and, in the last few minutes, I did think that was it.
"I thought 'at least we've put up a close game'.
"Then to actually win was just fantastic."
Prawncess Die added she was particularly proud of the newest players on the team.
She said: "Dani was just outstanding, especially as a jammer.
"Everybody was playing really well but she played every position and switched from one to the other, which was very impressive."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skatefast Club captain Trifecta Gadget said everyone was very emotional.
She said: "It was a really tight game through every single jam and we never really felt safe.
"It was good to be in the lead at the end of the first half but I knew we were going to have to bring our strongest game.
"The teams were very evenly matched and I think we lost it on just a couple of jams against some really amazing Leithals players."
Gadget also praised the newest skaters on her team.
She said: "We all kept our defence strong and stayed together really well.
"It was only because we played so well as a team the score was so close.
"I could see how much more confident everybody was by the end and I'm really proud of every skater."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>bout report</category><category>bout reports</category><category>edinburgh</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/28/auld-reekie-roller-girls-home-season-final-2015/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 13:12:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>InARRGuration</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/18/inarrguration/</link><dc:creator>jennifergelignite</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/nazgul.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4856" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/nazgul.jpg?w=225" alt="Nazgul" width="225" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AULD Reekie Roller Girls’ InARRGuration bout for the league’s newest competitive skaters and guests was a victory for all.
A close-run game saw Green Eggs and SLAM! Leading with 123 points to Team Nazgul’s 99 at half-time.
But the second half saw the Nazguls race back to score 223 to 184 for a stonking win.
Team Nazgul Captain Powerhouse said the pre-game secret weapon was team brownies.
She said: “We prepared by having a meeting over drinks in the Auld Hoose to discuss rules, default tactics, any worries or issues.
“Then we had many more chats on our Facebook group - I think this helped our guest skaters a lot, and helped them feel part of the team.
“On the day, the wonderful vice-captain, Radge of Honour made amazing brownies, and I made (equally as amazing, but less tasty) posters.
“These had some simple focuses for the bench (keep positive, calm and zen) and on track (have fun, communicate and stay together).
“There was also a pink elephant, amongst other beautiful artwork, which really got the point across.”
Green Eggs and Slam Captain Hex said fizz helped the green team bond.
She said: “We had loads of chat on Facebook and then we all met up at vice captain Dead Metal's house for a meeting where we talked rules and strategy and watched derby on the telly.
“We may also have drunk some fizzy drinks...”
Hoose and Hex both admitted in the thrill of the game they barely checked the score.
Hex said: “I wasn’t actually really looking at the score.
“I noticed we were in the lead at half time and yeah! It felt good!
“I felt like we were doing really well and the score reflected that.”
Hoose said: “Once both teams settled into the game, I felt we were well matched and I was having so much fun, I barely looked at the scoreboard!
“Our bench coach, the inimitable Collie, used our team time outs really wisely, when we were able to take a breath, refocus and get back out on track raring to go.
“I think the gap in points spurred us on, and the green team really forced us to bring our top game - they were incredibly strong, aggressive with some fantastic offence.”
Hex said the turning point was half-time, when four Green players fouled out.
She said: “Oh dear, I think the turning point was our penalties.
“Everyone was giving their all and sadly it was maybe a bit too much!
“Players started to foul out and the bench was getting shorter as people were tiring.
“Team Black were also totally amazing!!!”
The second half was where Hoose felt the team came into their own because of their focus.
She said: “There were a few jams in a row where more than one green player was in the bin.
“The black team managed to keep their cool, keep low, slow and strong (SO PROUD), and take total advantage of this.
“Our fantastic line up manager, Gerry, noticed this and put on some really smart line ups, with fast jammers.
“Once we pulled away, it was going to be difficult to catch us, and added to that, there were a few foul outs on the green side - that's always going to be exhausting!
“The boost of focus carried over into the rest of the game, raised the quality of derby, and the rest is history.”
After the game, both teams headed to the pub.
Hoose said there were many sweaty hugs and lots of beer to celebrate everyone’s hard work.
She said: “It was such a great experience, and I think everyone learned a huge amount.
“I'm incredibly proud of both teams, and so grateful to ARRG, and all the officials and volunteers on the day!
“It didn't matter who won or lost. As clichéd as it sounds, we all won - every single person now has the experience of a well matched, well played game under their belt. That's invaluable.
“We all developed skills, and tried things we never thought we could do - we are now better skaters, and have a bunch of new friends to talk derby with!
Hex agreed derby love was the order of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said: “There were lots of hugs and lots of derby love! It was great how close you get in a couple of hours!
“Then not so healthy food and drink with greens, blacks, refs, nsos -- all the best people you could hope to hang out with!
“There were incredible vibes - how much all the skaters put their heart and souls into it and what an amazing team we created having never met half of the skaters before, how much hard work the organisers had put into it, all the refs, nsos, announcers, audience - everyone involved! I just felt spoiled rotten to be a part of it all! best day EVA!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>auldreekierollergirls</category><category>bout reports</category><category>image</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/18/inarrguration/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 17:30:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ARRG newbies hit the Fringe</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/17/arrg-newbies-hit-the-fringe/</link><dc:creator>jennifergelignite</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/arrg-banner.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4809" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/07/arrg-banner.jpg?w=300" alt="ARRG-Banner" width="300" height="67"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
A RED-HOT new roller derby team will assemble for Auld Reekie Roller Girls’ first Edinburgh Festival Fringe game of 2015.
&lt;p&gt;Sparks are sure to fly as &lt;a href="https://tickets.edfringe.com/whats-on/auld-reekie-roller-girls-presents-live-roller-derby"&gt;Edinburgh’s All Star Reserves play Glasgow Roller Derby's Maiden Grrders&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team captain Mallory Powers said the new skaters will raise temperatures with the fastest crossovers, big hits and speedy whips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said: “We have a brand new team and are really looking forward to bringing everyone together and building on the excitement and atmosphere of the two recent All Star derby derbies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This will be the first time the Auld Reekie and Glasgow Roller Derby B teams have played each other in a while and the teams are very different now, so no-one really knows what to expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The focus will be on developing our newer skaters and working as a team to achieve our goals - but we'll bring the same level of gritty determination, cheery competitiveness and fun as our wonderful All Stars.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vice-captain Lady Scrapnell said she was looking forward to the new skaters playing their first festival game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said: “It's always exciting when new people skate on a team for the first time, and this time around we are lucky to have five new Reserves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We've all been working really hard in the All Star Reserves off-season, helping the All Stars train for their high level games, so lots of skaters have developed really quickly and we'll be really proud to be skating out with them at Meadowbank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Between us all we'll bring enthusiasm, athleticism and attitude, and will help to create one hell of a crowd atmosphere.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Families are welcome to watch this test of strength, speed and agility as skaters battle through their rivals’ team using only the power of their bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show rolls into town on &lt;a href="https://tickets.edfringe.com/whats-on/auld-reekie-roller-girls-presents-live-roller-derby"&gt;Saturday, August 8&lt;/a&gt;, at Meadowbank Sports Stadium on London Road from 2pm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/07/17/arrg-newbies-hit-the-fringe/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 15:33:19 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>