<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts by louisepants)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/authors/louisepants.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls vs Fierce Valley Roller Girls</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/13/dundee-roller-girls-vs-fierce-valley-roller-girls-2/</link><dc:creator>louisepants</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a busy weekend for Dundee Roller Girls travel team, The Silvery Tayzers. Sunday 17th November sees them take on Fierce Valley Roller Girls travel team, The Parma Violents. It has been over a year and half since these 2 teams met, both having refreshed their rosters and experience since then. Come along to the DISC, Dundee to see who will win in what is sure to be a most exciting bout. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doors open at 1.30pm with the bout beginning at 2pm. Tickets are available in advance for the reduced price of £5 (£6 on the door on the day). There will be merchandise from both teams available and beautiful cakes baked by the skaters/refs/NSO's themselves! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is absolutely not to be missed. See you trackside for some Live Action Roller Derby!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/fvrg.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-3036" alt="Image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/fvrg.png?w=650"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>disc</category><category>drg</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fierce valley roller girls</category><category>fvrg</category><category>parma violents</category><category>roller derby</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/13/dundee-roller-girls-vs-fierce-valley-roller-girls-2/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 16:02:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New WFTDA Minimum Skills - A skater and referee point of view</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/05/13/new-wftda-minimum-skills-a-skater-and-referee-point-of-view/</link><dc:creator>louisepants</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The WFTDA have released the latest version of their minimum skills, and have split opinion within Derby. In this Article Go-Go-Gadget-Skates and Buffy Boiler will look at the implications from the perspective of a skater and a referee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Buffy: First of all, I'd like to address what the new minimum skills actually mean for non-WFTDA leagues. Basically, they are as big a deal as your league wants them to be. The first page of the document has some interesting stuff to say that I think a lot of people are forgetting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The minimum skills are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;- Required for charter team skaters playing WFTDA sanctioned games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;- Strongly recommended for skaters playing in interleague scrimmage or games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;- Strongly recommended for skaters playing in intraleague (home) scrimmages or games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;- Recommended for new skaters to graduate to contact drills and intraleague (home league) scrimmages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;What this means is that if you're a new league or for whatever reason just don't yet have a sufficient number of skaters to field a team who all meet the new minimums you can still scrimmage, and even bout, as long as you agree it in advance with any prospective opponents.  The goal of this update is not to turn Derby into a game for only elite-level skaters, but it is definitely a move to ensure that WFTDA tournaments and games between WFTDA members represent a good standard of play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;I do expect that in the near future the new minimums will become the standard for interleague competition, as more and more teams are able to meet them - but remember that as the standard of play rises so will the standard of coaching available. The way up for a new league hasn't suddenly become longer, but it does maybe need a little more thought now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Gadget: So early April saw the release of the updated WFTDA Minimum skills assessment to a very mixed review from my fellow skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;First and foremost, I’d like to echo what Buffy has so rightly pointed out, these minimums are only compulsory for WFTDA leagues! Of course they are strongly recommended for all others. If a league plays under the WFTDA ruleset, it would make sense for that same league to start updating their minimum skills for the league as a whole, whether WFTDA or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Buffy: The old minimums were built primarily with safety in mind; though I think it's fair to say that was never their sole purpose. For instance 25 in 5 was not a safety requirement, but it helped ensure a base standard of athletic ability which was necessary for competitive play. Just as 27 in 5 represents the increase in the general athleticism of the sport today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Gadget: Lets look at what’s been added and taken away. We see the addition and subtraction of various skills. Like so many other skaters, I am glad to see the back of the unnecessary baseball slide fall. I don’t think I’ve ever seen anyone use this fall in active gameplay. The new minimums focus very much on specific skills that, if you were brought up on the old minimums, you very quickly learned you needed to succeed in the game. As well as skill, it is upping the expectation of speed from the skaters, with the addition of 27 in 5 and being able to complete one lap in 13 seconds from standstill. Other skills that have been introduced are reverse crossovers, transitions. A lot of the minimums now have clearer descriptions on what is expected, thus making it far easier for leagues to interpret and teach to their aspiring future derby players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Buffy: Derby is no longer simply a game about skating fast and turning left. The sport has evolved in ways few people could have anticipated in 2009, when the minimums were last updated, and as a result the modern game changes pace and even direction very quickly. So I think it's right that things like transitions are now seen as part of the core skill-set. As many of us will have seen, a poorly executed transition can lead to serious injury. Putting too much torque on the ankles can lead to anything from strains and sprains to spiral fractures (where the bone is broken by twisting it, not snapping - which almost always requires surgery). To say nothing of the obvious risks to suddenly changing direction and falling in front of other skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;This aside, the bulk of the minimums have actually been streamlined - the section on "sticky skating" (or skullcrushing as some called it) has been condensed to one line: "Propels self while keeping all 8 wheels on the floor." Skaters now simply have to be able to competently land legal hip and body checks while skating at a decent speed. It's less about box ticking and more about ensuring that people are comfortable and, most importantly, safe on skates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Gadget: Personally, at first I was disheartened at seeing the addition of 27 in 5, particularly because I remember how long it took me to achieve in the first place then again when returning from injury. However after some reflection, I think it’s a great addition. Having 25 in 5 before wasn’t really that good of an indication of a skaters endurance. Yes they can skate fast for 5 minutes, but could they skate fast for multiple jams in a row? Most of a period? A game? Unfortunately for some skaters, the answers to these questions are no. I also feel that new and old skaters alike will benefit greatly from the inclusion of these skills, making them better, more skilled derby players in the long run. I love that I can transition, not particularly fast, but I can. And I look forward to the day that I do this on track without having to think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Buffy It's probably been apparent that I'm all for this change, especially as the WFTDA have been careful to be inclusive in their approach. They are not saying you must be able to skate this well to play, they are simply saying that this is the standard expected in their own competitions. I've seen skaters who could technically pass their minimums thrown into bouts well before they were ready, this is disheartening for the person concerned - it's easy to keep a nice strong stance when you're asked to do so for a minute or two in order to be assessed on it, it's quite another to be able to maintain it while keeping up with a fast pack and trying to not be taken out by an opponent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;As a referee I technically do not need to be able to pass minimum skills, the required standard of skating for referees is entirely up to the leagues they train with. Most leagues will use the minimums for skaters as the basis for referee training, and there will be a level that each league expects before allowing a new official to start refereeing scrimmages and then later bouts. Personally, I'm an advocate of strong skating skills for referees. We need to be fast at OPR and able to quickly change pace to follow the skaters from the inside, this is particularly true of Jam Refs. We also all need to be confident enough to do all this without thinking about what our skates are doing, while making decisions which can drastically alter the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Buffy: The old minimum skills really were the minimum required. Some may find it disheartening to hear this but very few established skaters were struggling with any of the old skills. A skater who can pass these is actually pretty good, not merely safe to share a track with. This means that when new skaters do pass, they'll know that they're at a higher standard than the generation of skaters before them was when they first took to the track. Our sport is evolving and improving, which I think we can all agree is a very good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Gadget: Yes it will take time to be able to do all of these skills. Chances are, you can probably achieve most of them, if not all already. Don’t be disheartened if you can’t. Everyone else had to learn and you can too. You need to work hard, the same as you did for your original minimums. Your league will thank you for it as you will become a better skater who is more agile, fast and overall more skilled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;My final thought is that I’d like to echo what Buffy has said, these new skills will make new skaters joining bouting ranks more equipped to deal with the state of play that is now happening at scrimmages and bouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>ref's corner</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/05/13/new-wftda-minimum-skills-a-skater-and-referee-point-of-view/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 13:53:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls Pub Quiz!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/30/dundee-roller-girls-pub-quiz/</link><dc:creator>louisepants</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="" src="https://sphotos-a.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ash3/68571_10151440549208753_435878522_n.jpg" width="679" height="960"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get yourself along to The Mercantile in Dundee for Dundee Roller Girls pub quiz on 9th May at 7.30pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams of up to 5 people and £3 per head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First prize is a cash prize, with prizes for 2nd and 3rd place too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What better way to start your weekend than with a pub quiz on a Thursday night! And you get to help raise some cash for your friendly local derby team at the same time. It'll be a fun filled night and not to be missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event page can be located here &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/579555658735459/579575915400100/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/579555658735459/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>quiz</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/04/30/dundee-roller-girls-pub-quiz/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 17:19:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls Want You!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/09/23/dundee-roller-girls-want-you/</link><dc:creator>louisepants</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/09/fresh-meat-2012.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/09/fresh-meat-2012.png?w=487" alt="Image"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's that time again. Yes that's right ladies and gents, Dundee Roller Girls are opening their doors to everyone over the age of 18 to come and try out roller derby. Why not come and check out the fastest growing sport in Scotland? DRG will be hosting 3 open fresh meat nights, which is open to both men and women of all abilities and ages (over 18 only!). Full kit needed will be provided, all you need to do is turn up! The three nights of Fresh Meat kicks off on 26th September, second session 3rd October, ending on 10th October. Session starts at 7pm until 9pm at the DISC, Mains Loan, Dundee. We hope to see all your smiling faces there!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>drg</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fresh meat</category><category>pictures</category><category>roller derby</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/09/23/dundee-roller-girls-want-you/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 12:33:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Roller Girls vs Belfast Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/06/05/dundee-roller-girls-vs-belfast-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>louisepants</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/06/belfastfinished.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2012/06/belfastfinished.jpg?w=487" alt="Image"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Saturday, Dundee Roller Girls bring back roller derby to Dundee in a bout which sees them welcoming friends from across the water, Belfast Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two teams have never met before, so the results are sure to be interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors are at 2, with the game itself starting at 2.30, however we advise you arrive before this, as there will be plenty of stalls and cakes and other such lovely things to be enjoyed. You also wouldnt want to miss out on a seat at the suicide line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are £5 in advance &lt;a href="https://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/247739" rel="nofollow nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/247739&lt;/a&gt; or £6 on the door.
Under 14's admitted free when accompanied by a paying adult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come support your local team and embrace the full contact female sport that is Roller Derby!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>belfast roller derby</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2012/06/05/dundee-roller-girls-vs-belfast-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 15:19:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to prepare for that first bout.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/25/how-to-prepare-for-that-first-bout/</link><dc:creator>louisepants</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Congratulations, you've been selected to play for your league in your first bout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is nerve-wracking and exciting all at the same time. You've worked so hard to make it on to the team and you deserve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you'll be lucky enough to have experienced skaters on your team with you, if not, then you are all in the same boat. Don't panic. Preparation is key. Read the rules, and ask questions about anything you are unsure of. It will save you penalties in the long run as you'll understand how to avoid then and if you do pick any up, why you got them in the first place. Watch other teams tactics at games then go and introduce them to your team. Every team does things slightly differently and it can help to see a more experienced team play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breathe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It certainly is an exciting time, and now is definitely your time to prove yourself. All eyes will be on you, the opposition have never seen you skate before, they don't know what to expect. Be confident in your ability, you wouldn't of been picked for the team if your team captain didn't believe you could do it. If there is anything you are unsure of, anything at all, ask. Chances are captains have heard it all before so will be able to help, and if they don't, they'll find out. At training sessions, try and play all positions to get a feel for them. Line-up managers always start with a few line-ups thought out but they usually get binned depending on how the game is going and what the team needs. You need to be able to play with everyone on your team. Get to know them on and off track. It is a well known fact that teams that get on well away from training play well together on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breathe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pay attention at training. Make notes if you need to afterwards and read them to get the theory of the tactic into your head, then when you go on track again, the knowledge of what to do will already be there. Make sure you understand why you do certain tactics depending on what is happening in the jam. Don't be afraid to ask questions, you aren't expected just to know these things without ever having been taught it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally......&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy it. Don't get too caught up in the nerves, self-doubt, fear of injury. You've prepared well for this day and so has your team. Go out there and play to the best of your ability. That's all anyone can ask. Get a good nights sleep the night before and pack your kit the night before with everything you think you might need. The basics you definitely need to pack, skates, knee pads, elbow pads, wrist guards, helmet, mouthguard, skate tool, tape, scissors, water, fruit, team t-shirt, boutfit plus anything else you want to pack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have fun and hit them in the tit. I'll see you on the track.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/11/25/how-to-prepare-for-that-first-bout/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2011 14:14:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Injury, it's not the end.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/10/14/injury-its-not-the-end/</link><dc:creator>louisepants</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Injury. Every skater’s worst nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, playing a high impact contact sport, you have to expect that you will pick up injuries along the way. What shows real strength of character is how you bounce back from that. No injury should be taken lightly, no matter how small you think it may be. Listen to your doctor, they might not know/understand roller derby but they do know what is best in order for your injury to heal properly. Only you can know if your body will handle being back on 8 wheels. Do your physio, it will help immensely with you getting back on your skates. Even after you’ve recovered, keep doing the physio, it will help to continue to strengthen the muscles in the area of injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having been seriously injured myself; I know how frustrating it can be not to be skating. But fear not, there is a way to stay involved with derby while you aren’t skating. I went to practice every week when I was injured, it may sound ridiculous, you’re thinking “Why the hell am I bothering, I can’t skate!” but it does make sense. You’ll be surprised how much you pick up just by watching. You’ll learn how your team works with one another, things for improvement etc. So get someone to drag your broken ass to practice, and more often than not, your league will be over the moon to see you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch as much derby as you can. Make notes of interesting tactics and bouts that you see. Research. Take what you have learned back to your league, everyone sees things from different vantage points, so make yours heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A trick that an injured skater from Dundee Roller Girls used was to keep a journal of her progress throughout her recovery. You don’t have to write in it every day, but write down significant things about your recovery, even if you feel it’s as trivial as “Today I managed to take a bath by myself”. Whenever you feel blue about your perceived lack of progress, look back on the journal and you’ll see how far you’ve come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being injured does not mean the end of your skating career. If playing derby is not an option, why not look into becoming a referee? They are just as important in derby as the skaters and play a pivotal role in the smooth running of any bout. Ask to get involved with training, you will be super vigilant as to how to avoid picking up the injury that you suffered, pass it on to other skaters, they will thank you for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are lots of committees within each league, some that are not directly related to skating but are important in the continued progress of the league. Join as many committees as you physically can. You might not be able to make every meeting, but this will ensure that your voice is still heard. An injured skaters opinion is just as valid as any other skater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can and will bounce back from any injury you suffer in the span of your derby lifetime. Want to know how I know? Cause I did and so have many others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>drg</category><category>roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2011/10/14/injury-its-not-the-end/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 11:12:58 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>