<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts by meancityrollerderby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/authors/meancityrollerderby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 12:29:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Mean City Roller Derby: Relaunch 2017</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/17/mean-city-roller-derby-relaunch-2017/</link><dc:creator>meancityrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-19258" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/received_10158754925150594.jpeg?w=300" alt="received_10158754925150594" width="300" height="300"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;Roller derby is a very DIY sport, so people at different levels will always be looking to achieve different goals within the sport. For some, their purpose is to advance as far as their body will allow. For others, it’s a great way to get out a couple of nights per week and let off some steam in a fun, friendly environment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby fall somewhere in the middle, as we're made up of a wide variety of different people and personalities – we have actors, students, scientists and even a Thai masseur! It's our members that make our league special. Although we have lives outside of derby, we'll always be there for each other, both on and off the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we're looking to continue to build upon progress we've made as a league and as a group of friends. Next Saturday&lt;strong&gt;, 20th May 2017&lt;/strong&gt;, will be our first bout of the year and we are hoping to capitalise on the hard work we've put into our training. Not only that, we are rebranding and will be debuting our new logo and team tops for the first time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logo really captures the good humour of the league and the spirit of Glasgow, Mean City's home and stomping ground.  We don't want to give too much away until game day, but we can say the logo is indeed still purple! This has been a long time in the making, but we can proudly say it looks fantastic. A big thank you to our Design Team and to Roller Derby City for our awesome new uniforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are facing tough opposition. Our ladies' team are playing the Granite City Fight Hawks from Aberdeen. We played them up north in &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/85548"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and were narrowly defeated, so we will be looking to make the most of the home advantage! Our co-ed/open team will then be playing the Portsmouth Scurvy Wenches who are travelling up to Glasgow for the bout. They are more unknown to us, so should make exciting opponents. We also hear they like a good after party, as do we!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-19259" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/received_10158754874915594.jpeg?w=300" alt="received_10158754874915594" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The action starts at &lt;strong&gt;12pm&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662012,-4.2516905,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8661982!4d-4.2494965"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARC: Health &amp;amp; Fitness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Glasgow Caledonian University, Cowcaddens Road, Glasgow, G4 0BA. Entry is &lt;strong&gt;£5&lt;/strong&gt; per person/under 14s free,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets available from the Facebook event page here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1288036437909237/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/1288036437909237/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>annoucements</category><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>pictures</category><category>scottish roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/17/mean-city-roller-derby-relaunch-2017/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 14:08:10 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>