<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts by muir74)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/authors/muir74.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:41:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Glasgow ready to rock as British Champs T3 goes down to the wire</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/06/glasgow-ready-to-rock-as-british-champs-t3-goes-down-to-the-wire/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't stop believing&lt;/strong&gt; - that's the tune blasting out at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GlasgowMensRollerDerby/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; HQ where the Irn Brn are plotting a derby escape act which would make Houdini hop the apex with delight.
&lt;p&gt;This Saturday, GMRD play host to the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/133440747209468/?acontext=%7B%22ref%22%3A%222%22%2C%22ref_dashboard_filter%22%3A%22upcoming%22%2C%22action_history%22%3A%22%5B%7B%5C%22surface%5C%22%3A%5C%22dashboard%5C%22%2C%5C%22mechanism%5C%22%3A%5C%22main_list%5C%22%2C%5C%22extra_data%5C%22%3A%5B%5D%7D%5D%22%7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;final fixtures in the British Championships' Men's Tier 3 - Regional North group&lt;/a&gt; (at Glasgow's ARC Sports Centre).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD will be taking on their Celtic cousins, Men Behaving Derby (MBD), while Bairn City Rollers' Skelpies will be setting blasters to stun against Teesside Skate Invaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a decidedly Scottish-type twist, only a specific combination of results can now see GMRD qualify for the play-offs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the uninitiated, here's the short story:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April, GMRD travelled to Dublin to play the Skate Invaders, winning by 234 points to 167. GMRD were later denuded of victory due to an eligibility malfunction, with the score becoming 200-0 in favour of the Invaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD's next game against the Skelpies was then forfeited by the Falkirk team due to lack of numbers - a 200-0 win in favour of GMRD - leaving the table looking like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-20255 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/brd-table.jpg" alt="BRD table" width="1014" height="650"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, GMRD need to beat MBD on Saturday - that's a pre-requisite if GMRD want a play-off place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regardless of what flavour that victory lollipop is, the Irn Brn need to be sucking on it by Saturday evening.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Skelpies win against the Invaders then victory of any variety will be enough for the Glasgow mob.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if the Invaders win &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; GMRD win then the three top teams will be tied on six points and it goes down to scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD would need to have a better points differential than MBD to qualify for the play-offs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't worry about crunching the numbers, SRD Blog has done it for you - &lt;strong&gt;GMRD need to beat MBD by over 123 points to be certain of a play-off place.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That isn't going to be any kind of easy as MBD have already beaten both the Skelpies and the Skate Invaders this season, the latter with just 6 players!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's why Hugs &amp;amp; Kisses - GMRD's President - is sounding the rallying horn to the Irn Brn faithful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We need everyone in the West of Scotland and beyond to come out and support Saturday's double-header," he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-20254" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/18768309_10209728094985432_4231219290125343973_o.jpg" alt="18768309_10209728094985432_4231219290125343973_o" width="1600" height="1067"&gt; The Irn Brn - photo by Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"This is an amazing first for our city - a British Champs men's game at the home of Glasgow derby, the ARC sportscentre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"You are going to see two gallus games of roller derby, with the fate of three teams hanging in the balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Come out and support the Irn Brn as we attempt the great escape. We're confident we can put on a great show - don't stop believing, ken?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* Doors open at the ARC sportscentre, Glasgow, on Saturday (10 June) at 11.30am. Tickets cost £7. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/133440747209468/?acontext=%7B%22ref%22%3A%222%22%2C%22ref_dashboard_filter%22%3A%22upcoming%22%2C%22action_history%22%3A%22%5B%7B%5C%22surface%5C%22%3A%5C%22dashboard%5C%22%2C%5C%22mechanism%5C%22%3A%5C%22main_list%5C%22%2C%5C%22extra_data%5C%22%3A%5B%5D%7D%5D%22%7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Click here for more information.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teeside Skate Invaders vs Bairn City Skelpies - first whistle at 11:45&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby vs Men Behaving Derby - first whistle at 2pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>announcements</category><category>articles</category><category>british championship</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><category>men behaving derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>teeside skate invaders</category><category>the skelpies</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/06/glasgow-ready-to-rock-as-british-champs-t3-goes-down-to-the-wire/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 16:02:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire, steel and friendship - Irn Brn set sail for uncharted waters</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/22/fire-steel-and-friendship-irn-brn-set-sail-for-uncharted-waters/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The West of Scotland is renowned for forging some of the most iconic vessels and cultural objects in the world - from the QE2 to red phone boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should come as no surprise then that UK roller derby's newest team should have its roots in the industrial heart of Scotland - where history was literally forged from fire and steel - or that they call themselves the Irn Brn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Men's Roller Derby (GMRD) have already gone on a remarkable journey since they first sparked into life last summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16509" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/16825840_1347219638657375_3488843192256158535_o.jpg" alt="16825840_1347219638657375_3488843192256158535_o" width="1500" height="991"&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Duncolm-Sports-Photography-199762020069815/" target="_blank"&gt;Photo by Duncolm Sports Photography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone involved in roller derby will know that the tectonic plates beneath our sport are always moving - teams rise, teams fall, legacies are secured, old legends fade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some skaters drift away from the sport for good - others depart teams to form new alliances as they seek different horizons and chase different goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the case with the founding fathers - and mothers - of GMRD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the centre of the league is an ethos - like the nucleus at the heart of an atom - attracting skaters to it like toe-stop-hopping protons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skate, create, innovate - work hard together with friends to take on the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD pride themselves on being more than the sum of their talented parts (the roster includes a range of international-standard skaters - including seven members of the Power of Scotland training squad).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than a league, more than a team - this is a family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Irn Brn set sail next month for uncharted territory for a Scottish men's team - the 2017 British Roller Derby Championships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD will play in Men's Tier 3 North - alongside the Bairn City Skelpies (also breaking new ground for Scottish dudes), Teesside Skate Invaders and Men Behaving Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up on April 16 is a trip to the Emerald Isle, where GMRD take on the Skate Invaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD Managing Director Hugs and Kisses (aka JR) said: "We can't wait to get on track at the British Champs - it's going to be an adventure for everyone associated with GMRD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Teesside will be tough opponents and we are preparing for a very competitive game against a talented team of top skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"However, we know we have a strong team and have been training hard. It's going to be a great opening day of derby for Tier 3 North."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of GMRD have played Teesside before as members of other teams, but there have been line-up changes since then and the standard of derby is forever climbing skywards, so it will be an intriguing match-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GMRD will be buoyed by a good run of form which saw them beat Crash Test Brummies B (Beta Test Brummies) 199-135 and Barrow Infernos 226-159.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the double-header in Dublin, the action will move to Grangemouth on May 13, when GMRD take on the Skelpies at Grangemouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third double-header will be hosted by GMRD at the ARC Sportscentre in Glasgow on June 10, with GMRD completing their fixtures with a game against Men Behaving Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top two teams in Tier 3 North will then play the two teams in Tier 3 South, with the victors of each game promoted to Tier 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugs added: "We're under no illusions - this is going to be a tough series of games, but we really can't wait. This is what we've been working hard towards since we formed the league last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Teamwork will be key. We have some very skilled individuals within the team, but our goal is to be a cohesive unit firing on all cylinders - forged in the heat of intense training sessions, scrims and games."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/GlasgowMensRollerDerby" target="_blank"&gt;Check out GMRD on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for all the latest information on games, bootcamps and special events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-16516 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/16807827_10212367238320133_3797769164188759663_n.jpg" alt="16807827_10212367238320133_3797769164188759663_n" width="960" height="424"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><category>glasgow men's roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/22/fire-steel-and-friendship-irn-brn-set-sail-for-uncharted-waters/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 13:28:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Are you ready for a skating spooktacular?</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/19/are-you-ready-for-a-skating-spooktacular/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9817" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/fb-hallowmean-a.jpg" alt="fb-hallowmean-a" width="3545" height="1305"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tricks or treats? Why choose when you can have both – and a whole lot more – at Mean City’s closing home game of the year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow’s only coed league will be hosting a devilish double dunt of derby delights on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 29 October&lt;/strong&gt; at the Dear Mean Place – aka the &lt;strong&gt;ARC Sportscentre in Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hallowe'en is when things go bump in the night - &lt;strong&gt;HallowMean&lt;/strong&gt; is when things go bump on the track and there are trick and treats for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, the &lt;strong&gt;Mean City ladies&lt;/strong&gt; – fresh from a gallus bout against Granite’s Fight Hawks and looking to maintain their forward momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Meanies have been reaping the benefits of a greater emphasis on tactics, fitness and skills – with fresh recruits bolstering the settled squad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their opponents on 29 October will be the out-of-this-world &lt;strong&gt;ASTROs (Auld Reekie All Star Rookies)&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s going to be a stern test of the Mean City ladies’ resolve, as well as a showcase for some of Scotland’s finest up and coming skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second game will see &lt;strong&gt;Mean City's coed team&lt;/strong&gt; ghosting to the track to take on &lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers' Belter Skelpers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tis the season to be fearful and while there’s no fear among the Mean City ranks, there will be some trepidation given the excellent form the Belter Skelpers have been in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bairn City Rollers’ coed team recently played a mix of Aberdeen and Dundee skaters – the Brawler Buddies – and really brought their A game, winning with a well-oiled performance combining offence, defence and excellent tactics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City’s coed team may lack the experience of their opponents, but they have spirit, guts and tenacity in abundance and will match them skate for skate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City President Elaine Hunter – aka Roller Dobby - said: “We can’t wait to round off our home season in style with a spook-tacular thriller for all the family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Trick or treat – why choose when you can have both? There will be skating, fun, cakes and cracking tunes – what else are Saturdays made for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Tickets are just &lt;b&gt;£4&lt;/b&gt; in advance – that’s just £2 per game – or &lt;b&gt;£5&lt;/b&gt; on the door. It’s a bargain and you’ll be supporting grassroots sport at the same time. Under-14s get in free.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean City presents HallowMean - Saturday 29 October 2016 - doors open at the ARC Sportscentre at noon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;For more information on the event – &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/312912055752880/"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;For tickets – &lt;a href="http://www.meancityrollerderby.com/tickets.php"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all-gender roller derby</category><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>coed</category><category>in the news</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/19/are-you-ready-for-a-skating-spooktacular/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 15:36:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Team Spain</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/17/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-spain/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spain’s top male derby players hope to inspire a skating revolution as they make their World Cup debut in Calgary this summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Men’s roller derby may still be in its infancy in the Spanish slice of the Iberian Peninsula, but it’s growing stronger all the time and competing in Canada will help put the flat-track matadors on the map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-7852 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/11754605_131554247184070_805994326635319235_o.jpg?w=680" alt="11754605_131554247184070_805994326635319235_o" width="388" height="384"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They could well prove to be the surprise package at this year’s World Cup, with rival countries unsure of exactly what to expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s certain is that Men’s Roller Derby Spain will play with pride and passion – win, lose or draw – and they will play as a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Pamies - aka The Spaniard - took a break from training to share some secrets ahead of the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* How was your selection process for this year's World Cup? Did you find there were different factors you were looking for in skaters? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was really difficult to decide how to do it. When we were organising the trials, we had just started three teams (Tibicenas, Rockanrollaz and Madriders), and they had only been playing derby for around three months … so we didn’t know how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was crazy. We had two trials - one in Barcelona and another in Madrid - and got a total of 14 skaters. However, during the way we lost some of them because they didn’t have the money to go to Calgary or the practice, so we did one more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we defined the selection we were looking for skaters with potential - people who knew how to skate and were motivated to work hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* Spain didn't take compete at the last MRDWC. Was it a case of waiting until you felt the skaters were ready or was it more to do with logistics and cost? Why did you decide to get involved in 2016?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well in the first World Cup nobody was playing in Spain. There was basically no men’s roller derby at all. Only Perez (Emperor Miro) and myself were playing in USA. A few months after the World Cup I was playing in a competition in USA (I play for Harm City in Baltimore) when Ramiro Perez (Jersey Boys RD) told me he had Spanish family and asked if I would like to start a Spanish team with American players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I thought, why don’t we start men’s roller derby in Spain? So I went to Spain to try to find everyone who skated and has some interest in derby, and started MRDS (Men’s Roller Derby Spain) to try to bring everyone together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From then we started trying to organise different teams and so on. There were many people putting in lot of effort to start new teams in the different cities, such as Dann Vader, Ra, Kalavera, QBO and Diego y Paco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* How has the team been fundraising for the trip to Canada? Any unusual ways you have used to gain support?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been trying - I guess like everyone - selling t-shirts and so on, but we couldn’t find any sponsors. Nobody really knows the sport in Spain. We have used Facebook, Twitter and Instagram to raise awareness – trying to make videos and so on. Loreto (fun number one) started a fun club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; * How are you finding your team training in the run up to the World Cup? With only a few months left how is that affecting your training schedule?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been trying to practice together every month. It has been difficult for some of the guys due to the economic situation in Spain, but most have been able to make practice. One of the greatest experiences was at Christmas when we rented a house in the middle of nowhere with access to a track and we were all together for the full weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We played a tournament in Orcet and it was so great to see that - even for our first games together - we didn’t do so terrible! We lost against Team France by 200 points, but still it was a victory for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is not much time left. We will have a practice in June and a practice one day before the World Cup. I hope everyone is working hard by themselves [laughs].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* You have a pretty mixed group at Calgary - including Canada, Columbia, Germany and our Celtic cousins, Wales. Is there anyone you are really excited to play against in your group?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am excited to play them all. I love every single people in my team and I am sure they all love each other. Playing with them against anyone will be great. I think we have a strong group, but we are not scared. We are going to the MRDWC to learn as much as we can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; * Do you have any specific aims for Calgary that you are willing to share with us? (We're okay if there are any closely guarded secrets you don't want to give up yet!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to give a good show – even though most of our people have only been playing one year and some of them have not much experience playing. I want to show that they can break our bodies and beat us, but we will rise again!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Team-Spain-114586202214208/?fref=ts" target="_blank"&gt;Team Spain&lt;/a&gt;’s first bout is against Germany - at 2pm Calgary - local time - on Thursday on Track 2, followed by Columbia at 6pm on Track 1. Click here for more information on the team. &lt;/em&gt;The official MRDWC schedule is located &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-7853 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13346897_293873427618817_6592332194147481971_n.jpg" alt="13346897_293873427618817_6592332194147481971_n" width="575" height="960"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/17/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-spain/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 17:22:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Team Germany</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/15/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-germany/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Germany will be packing something a little special among their skating gear when they head to Canada for the Men’s Roller Derby World Cup.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deutschland’s most dazzling derby players will be bringing energy, style, fun and camaraderie to Calgary as they look to build on their 2014 adventures.&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-7841 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/10376305_1013820945367964_6493158984827436504_n.jpg" alt="10376305_1013820945367964_6493158984827436504_n" width="390" height="390"&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Back then, Team Germany finished a respectable 11&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, with bruising games against Australia, France and Ireland – as well as a win over Belgium.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since then, the team have been working hard – despite being spread out across Europe – and will be a force to be reckoned with at the World Cup.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We caught up with Bench Coach Bella Karloffa to talk try-outs, training and Teutonic talent.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
* How was your selection process for this year's World Cup compared to 2014? Did you find there were different factors you were looking for in skaters?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014 men’s roller derby in Germany was quite small, so we brought all players who had the time and could afford the trip to England. This time we had to do try-outs because more people applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was important for us that we got to know the players and that all of them had the chance to train together as a team and to grow. So it meant that boys from Switzerland and England came over to attend training weekends. In general we were looking for the normal stuff like skating skills, game understanding, communication skills, teamwork and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time we had the chance to organise seven training weekends - try-outs - with the whole team. The players live so far away from each other that this was the best option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* Team Germany had a memorable win over Belgium in the 2014 World Cup, as well as tough games against the likes of Australia, France and Ireland - finishing 11th overall. What did you learn from the 2014 World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all that we had to learn quite a lot!  The event was overwhelming and the spirit just amazing, so our decision to go on with Team Germany and to stay together as a team came very quickly. It was a big motivation to take part at the next one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* How has the team been fundraising for the trip to Canada? Any unusual ways you have used to gain support?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are quite late with that, but in general we pay our trips by ourselves. There will be some money from the RDD (Roller Derby Deutschland) Association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* How are you finding your team training in the run up to the World Cup? With only a few weeks left, how is that affecting your training schedule?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started our trainings weekends and try-outs last summer and tried to have a training session every two months. Since May 2016, we’ve had a training weekend every month. We work hard and try to use the time we have as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* You have a pretty mixed group at Calgary - including Canada, Columbia, Spain and our Celtic cousins, Wales. Is there anyone you are really excited to play against in your group?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact we are looking forward to every one of them. We got to know Team Canada at the last World Cup as our neighbours in the dressing room - and they were quite nice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was coaching some teams in Spain last year so I know them quite well and I am looking forward to playing them very much.  We never played Wales as Team Germany - they are strong and it will be an interesting game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Columbia - so exotic for us, bring it on! At the last World Cup everybody was surprised about Argentina.  We are very happy that more South American teams are taking part this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* Do you have any specific aims for Calgary that you are willing to share with us? (We’re okay if there are any closely guarded secrets you don’t want to give up yet!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to show our best derby and even more. We worked so hard the last time and love to be challenged by great teams. It’s a chance to see how we are in comparison to the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun for sure is very important for us and we are looking forward to another unforgettable event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamGermanyMensRollerDerby/"&gt;Team Germany&lt;/a&gt; play hosts Canada in the first game - on Track 1 - at 9am  Calgary-local-time on Thursday, followed by Spain at 2pm on Track 2. &lt;/em&gt;The official MRDWC schedule is located &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7842 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13147384_1050905511659507_8538085274324425586_o.jpg" alt="13147384_1050905511659507_8538085274324425586_o" width="2048" height="1721"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/15/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-germany/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 16:59:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Equipe de France de Roller Derby Masculine</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/13/mrdwc-2016-team-review-equipe-de-france-de-roller-derby-masculine/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forget football - France might be hosting the European Championships this year, but the Men’s Roller Derby World Cup is very much the focus for a tight-knit group of French skaters.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Equipe de France de Roller Derby Masculine – aka Team France – proved to be one of the most popular squads at the 2014 World Cup - finishing fourth and winning a lot of hearts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7764 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13414444_10209862275657632_146867596_n.jpg" alt="13414444_10209862275657632_146867596_n" width="497" height="497"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;They triumphed in a memorable game over Argentina, and were narrowly pipped in the semi-final and then the third-place play-off, so hopes are high that they can repeat their heroics in Calgary.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We caught up with Jammer Coach and Line-Up Manager Pepe le Punch - aka Laura Sanchez – for the latest from the French camp.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* How was your selection process for this year's World Cup compared to 2014? Did you find there were different factors you were looking for in skaters?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest difference for the selection this year was that it happened more than a year before the World Cup. We also had a lot more skaters trying out so we did two different try-out sessions (one north and one south).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014, the selections were done six months before and a group of around 30 skaters were selected to train. This year, we picked around 30 skaters as well, but they trained together for over a year, forming a very tight team. The most important factors for the coaching staff are adaptability and teamwork (in addition, of course, to individual skills).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* It's fair to say that Team France were one of the most popular teams at the 2014 World Cup and one of the most successful - finishing fourth. France won all three group games, triumphed in a memorable game over Argentina and were narrowly pipped in the semi-final and then the third-place play-off. What did you learn from the 2014 World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coaching staff are all new for this World Cup, but all four of us were players at the women's World Cup - so we had the opportunity to experience what the players have and will be experiencing. This is a big strength for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The players who were at the last World Cup had the opportunity to experience high-level derby and tournament settings. The level has risen a lot since the last world cup and we are mostly focusing on our game play in order to bring the best team possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* How has the team been fundraising for the trip to Canada?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did a Crowdfunding campaign that ended recently and we are selling merch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* How are you finding your team training in the run up to the World Cup? With only a few weeks left, how is that affecting your training schedule?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We announced our 20-player roster in early March, but continued training with the full training squad plus some players that we called up as sparring partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-7763 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/french-team.jpg" alt="French team" width="1449" height="960"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Equipe de France de Roller Derby Masculine - photo by Mickael Boitel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We train all together once a month for a full weekend. Training is going well - we learned a lot from the 4 Nations tournament and are adjusting our strategies to be the best we can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have four days of training planned in July with only the 20 Calgary players in order to take care of details in our defence and offence.  So far, I would say we are looking pretty good :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* You have a pretty mixed group at Calgary - including Australia, Belgium, Netherlands and Puerto Rico. Is there anyone you are really excited to play against in your group?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to play everybody. It is true that this group is a bit mixed, but we are not under-estimating anyone. We will be facing two non-European teams and will have to adapt very quickly to different blocking/jamming styles. I think this is a very interesting, open group. I honestly couldn't tell you for sure who will place 1st or 2nd. The one thing I can say is that we are hungry and ready to take on everyone in the group!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* Do you have any specific aims for Calgary that you are willing to share with us? (We're okay if there are any closely guarded secrets you don't want to give up yet!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well … :-) All I can say is our main goal is to play OUR game every single time. The players have spent a lot of time and energy to create strategies that work for us so we won't let other teams impose their game play on us.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamFranceMensRollerDerby/?fref=ts" target="_blank"&gt;Equipe de France de Roller Derby Masculine's&lt;/a&gt; first bout is against Puerto Rico at 10am Calgary-local-time on Thursday on Track 2, followed by the Netherlands at 7pm on Track 2. &lt;span style="line-height:1.7;"&gt;The official MRDWC schedule is located &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a style="line-height:1.7;" href="http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7765" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/13453553_10209862275817636_873495865_o.jpg" alt="13453553_10209862275817636_873495865_o" width="1448" height="2048"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/13/mrdwc-2016-team-review-equipe-de-france-de-roller-derby-masculine/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 11:44:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2015 - the force awakens at Mean City Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/05/2015-the-force-awakens-at-mean-city-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not that long ago in a derby galaxy not that far away, a group of skaters took a momentous decision…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the tail end of 2014, Glasgow’s Mean City Roller Derby became the&lt;img class="  wp-image-5526 alignright" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/01/1498887_403382076464885_1005980319_o.png?w=559" alt="1498887_403382076464885_1005980319_o" width="156" height="156"&gt; first co-ed league in the West of Scotland and only the second in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a huge (toe)step for the league – which had hitherto only accepted men as full members – and not a decision taken lightly, but it was an essential one and it’s fair to say that 2015 validated that vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then some…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final whistle has just sounded on 2015 and what a year it has been for Mean City – a year that has seen the league, its members and its supporters roll from strength to strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision to accept everyone into the league as full participating members – regardless of the junk in their trunk – was met with jubilation and determination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year began with simple goals – grow the membership, get more games for the men’s team and form a women’s team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the course of the year all of those goals were not only met – they were surpassed in style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New members flooded into the league – more than doubling the numbers - as word spread about Mean City’s inclusive and friendly ethos, excellent coaching, supportive structure and determination to get better with every session and every game while still having fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the year, Mean City’s male and female skaters flew the flag for the league and Scotland at a variety of events, scrims and games – including charity bouts and special fundraisers – and also provided guests for a number of leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only that, three Mean City skaters – Optimus Grime, Konanbourg and Tea – were selected for Power of Scotland – the men’s national team - and will compete at the Men’s Roller Derby World Cup in Canada this summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first game of the year took place on February 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; when Mean City’s men took on Tyne &amp;amp; Fear’s Inglorious B*Stars. The Geordies trumped the Jocks on that occasion, but it was a cracking match and terrific experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next on the calendar for the purple peeps was a double-header on April 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; – featuring Mean City’s men vs Manchester Roller Derby’s Chaos Engine, and Glasgow Roller Derby’s Cannie Gingers vs Team Metal Legs. It was a fiesta of fun, fine derby and friendships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite losing in the final jam, the men held their heads high. Meanwhile, in the background an influx of females saw the Mean City’s women’s team begin to take shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5519" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/01/11212641_636788599790897_5074502996060559980_o.jpg" alt="11212641_636788599790897_5074502996060559980_o" width="2048" height="1328"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Mean City welcomed Bairn City’s Skelpies to Glasgow as part of the Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals. It was a great occasion and a fantastic advert for the sport, with the Skelpies taking the win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a week later, history was made as Mean City’s women took to the track competitively for the first time at Glasgow Roller Derby’s Sur5al tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MCRD’s fab females took third place overall, with the men’s team winning the male tournament – marking a momentous day for the Mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No-one was resting on any laurels though, with a lot of hard work underway on strategy, fitness and continuing to grow the membership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;August 22&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; was another historic day for the league as Mean City hosted Mad Macs, with the league’s co-ed team making their competitive debut against Furiosa’s Furies – a Scottish select featuring some of the country’s top talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a winning debut for the co-ed team, but the real winner was derby as the revolution rolled on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;September saw Mean City’s men travel through to Edinburgh to take on Capital City in the last Scottish Men's Roller Derby Nationals game. Mean City duly claimed victory and second place overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block to the Future was hosted by Mean City on October 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; – a Back to the Future-themed double header which was rather appropriate as it made yet more history for the league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby's women's team made their competitive debut against Granite City's mighty Fight Hawks, while Mean City's men took on Aire Force One from Leeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a double celebration as both teams won – with the women especially convincing as they skated home with the victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5521" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/01/12186671_10100490742826464_8609723365762312596_o.jpg" alt="12186671_10100490742826464_8609723365762312596_o" width="1200" height="800"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November there was more success for Mean City as the men shone at the Furness Firecrackers’ Sur5al tournament in Blackpool. Mean City’s men came in fifth out of 16 – a remarkable result given the quality of the 16 teams present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, Mean City were the only team not to be beaten by Southern Discomfort and defeated last year’s winners, Lincolnshire Roller Thunder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5520" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/01/12232803_10100492169617164_8167493614430129374_o.jpg" alt="12232803_10100492169617164_8167493614430129374_o" width="1200" height="800"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That capped a terrific year for the league and President Elaine Hunter is looking forward to an even greater 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m so proud of everyone involved with the league for the amazing efforts they put in during 2015,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was a momentous year for the league, with everyone pulling together to cement our place as one of the best places to train and play roller derby in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s not been easy at times, but we’ve overcome every challenge by sticking together and working hard. We’re very much a family at Mean City Roller Derby – no-one left out, no-one left behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m looking forward to another year of growth in terms of membership, but also growth in terms of how our teams play roller derby – with strategy, fitness, friendship and fun at the heart of our flat-track adventures.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby/" target="_blank"&gt;Join the revolution – find out more about Mean City Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
 
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team pics by Laura MacDonald&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/01/05/2015-the-force-awakens-at-mean-city-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 13:33:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>History in the making with Mad Macs in Glasgow</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/12/history-in-the-making-with-mad-macs-in-glasgow/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What a day - what a lovely day!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean City Roller Derby’s coed team will make their competitive debut on Saturday, August 22, at the ARC sports centre in Glasgow.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The Glasgow league – which is open to people of all genders and none – are rostering a team of men and women for the first time in a public game.&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/11754374_670745089728581_5681492131485587611_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-4852 alignright" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/11754374_670745089728581_5681492131485587611_o.jpg?w=300" alt="11754374_670745089728581_5681492131485587611_o" width="482" height="330"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
It comes less than a year after the league voted to become coed – with Mean City's membership on the rise.
&lt;p&gt;The event on August 22 has a distinctly dystopian feel – entitled Mad Macs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain Gordon Hendry said: “According to Fury Road, the future belongs to the Mad - but we reckon it belongs to the Mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To celebrate Mean City becoming the first coed league in the West of Scotland, we have got together with some lovely skaters across the country to present a coed bout with class written through it like a stick of rock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In the purple and silver corner, wearing battered leather and a grizzled grin are the men and women of Mean City Roller Derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And in the blood-splattered white corner are Furiosa's Furies - some of Scotland's most talented - and toughest - skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s going to be marvellous, mad and – above all – it’s going to be Mean. We've been training hard for this and genuinely can't wait. Get your tickets now."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since becoming a coed league, Mean City Roller Derby’s membership has grown and grown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, demand is so strong that the league has organised another fresh skater intake – Tuesday, September 1 at the ARC – 7.15-9pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit www.facebook.com/MeanCityRollerDerby&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/12/history-in-the-making-with-mad-macs-in-glasgow/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 20:35:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Power of Scotland ready to get a moo-ve on!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/12/power-of-scotland-ready-to-get-a-moo-ve-on/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scotland's top skaters and their tartan army will really be getting a moo-ve on at the Men's Roller Derby World Cup in Canada – thanks to an amazing new logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Power of Scotland - the men’s national roller derby team – has a stunning new look featuring a Caledonian icon.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;A plethora of prospective logos were submitted for the contest to help brand Power of Scotland’s push towards the World Cup in Calgary next summer.&lt;/p&gt;
The logos were put to the vote and the top two sent into the orbit of professional designer Admiral Attackbar - of Interplanetary Print Syndicate.&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-4845 alignright" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/08/pos.jpg?w=300" alt="PoS" width="300" height="280"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The winning logo can now be revealed and the Power of Scotland team can’t wait to rock (and roll) it with pride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manager Nikki Morris said: “We’re delighted to finally be able to show the world the amazing new Power of Scotland logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We hope everyone loves it as much as we do. The new logo is the perfect expression of the Scots’ legendary spirit, strength, style and attitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We can’t wait to hear what people think of the latest addition to the Scottish team – which is the culmination of months of hard work and difficult decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We received dozens of excellent designs initially and the feedback from skaters and fans was incredible. The vote was very close between the top two so we asked Admiral Attackbar to help us finalise the new logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“She did a fabulous job. We want to thank her and everyone who took the time to contribute their ideas – especially the winner, Andy Morris - and to vote for their favourite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The passion and creativity shown by all the people involved with Power of Scotland is a genuine thrill.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new range of merchandise – featuring the new logo – will be on sale soon, with t-shirts, hats and more going up for sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the PoS training squad is working hard in preparation for Canada, with Head Coach Hannah Grant (aka Ginge) pleased by the inspiration and perspiration on show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said: “The attitude, energy and effort from the selected skaters has been excellent, with many travelling long distances to be put through their paces in drills and scrims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Everyone is giving everything they have in pursuit of their Power of Scotland dream – from the coaches to the skaters to the fundraisers to the fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As well as working with their own leagues, our skaters are training and scrimming together once a month. I think we’re seeing the start of something very special.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The selection committee will come together on Hallowe’en to watch a Scotland vs Scotland game made up of the training squad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there the 20-man squad for Calgary will be selected and will go on to train till the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland"&gt;www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland&lt;/a&gt; for more information on how you can help the team on its journey to the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>power of scotland</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/08/12/power-of-scotland-ready-to-get-a-moo-ve-on/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 08:31:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Drawing inspiration for Power of Scotland</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/24/drawing-inspiration-for-power-of-scotland/</link><dc:creator>muir74</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From Caledonian skulls and Claymores to Highland cows and Nessie on skates – the race to design the new logo for Scotland’s men’s roller derby team has been a runaway success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A plethora of prospective logos were submitted for the contest to help brand Power of Scotland’s push towards Men’s Roller Derby World Cup in Canada next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the entries were put to the vote and two have emerged as clear favourites, with the margin separating them closer than a sudden-death jam between Gotham and Rose City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/1899339_449090048556800_2001698922_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-4723 size-medium" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/06/1899339_449090048556800_2001698922_o.jpg?w=300" alt="1899339_449090048556800_2001698922_o" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The current Power of Scotland logo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, they are so close that the PoS management team has decided to seek expert advice to help ensure Scotland has the perfect logo to rock the world in Calgary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim is to ask a professional designer to look at the two logos which proved the most popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manager Nikki Morris said: “We can't wait to publically unveil our logo, but we want to take this extra time to ensure it’s as amazing as the skaters who are going to proudly wear it on their chests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“All of the designs received were excellent and the feedback from skaters and fans has been amazing. The vote was incredibly close between the two most popular designs so we thought in the interests of fairness we should ask a professional to have the casting vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our hope is that the chosen design will be refined and posted as soon as it’s finalised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We would like – once again – to thank everyone who took the time to contribute their ideas and to vote for their favourite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The passion and creativity shown by everyone who supports Power of Scotland is a genuine inspiration for everyone associated with the team.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the PoS training squad was recently announced, with 30 skaters involved from all over the British Isles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head Coach Hannah Grant (aka Ginge) said: “We held two try-outs and the attendance for both was incredible, with all the skaters involved giving everything they had in pursuit of their Power of Scotland dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Narrowing it down to just 30 was extremely difficult and one of the hardest things I have personally been involved in as regards derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“However, after a lot of hard work we have been able to announce the squad … and now the hard work really begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As well as training with their own leagues, our skaters will train together once a month and scrimmage until October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The selection committee will then come together again to watch a Scotland vs Scotland game made up of the training squad. From here the 20-man squad for Calgary will be selected and will go on to train till the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The coaches can’t wait to work with this fantastic group of skaters – we’re determined to show the derby world what Scotland has to offer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland"&gt;www.facebook.com/PowerOfScotland&lt;/a&gt; for more information on how you can help the team on its journey to the World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>men's roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/06/24/drawing-inspiration-for-power-of-scotland/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 17:54:38 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>