<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts by oneknownashaze)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/authors/oneknownashaze.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:34:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Team Finland</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/11/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-finland/</link><dc:creator>oneknownashaze</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our round up of the MRDWC teams continues with Team Finland! Here they tell us all about how they have prepared for Calgary and their thoughts going in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-8214 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/finland.jpg?w=300" alt="finland" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Answers from:
Menstruella - TFMRD head coach 2016
Domino F. Äkt - TFMRD head coach 2014
MIika Karttunen - TFMRD skater 2014-2016&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Questions:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;-How did your selection process for this year's World Cup differ from the 2014 selection? Did you find there were different factors you were looking for in skaters?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Dominå F. Äkt:
Since we didn’t have that much men’s roller derby activity in Finland, the first 2014 try outs were more of a minimum skills test assessing if we even had enough skaters to form a team. At the first try outs session, there was max 12 skaters and only one player that knew how to plough stop. We had to have multiple try out sessions for new skaters that had joined Tampere Rollin’ Bros (first men’s league in Finland, established 2013) after the first try outs, and by the World Cup in March 2014 we had a solid charter of almost 20 skaters and we did really well placing as number 9 in the world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Menstruella:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;All in all the level of individuals and teams has gone forward, but the numbers of participants haven’t gone up much, and while we now have new and dedicated players, many skaters from 2014 have stopped playing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;This time we encouraged everyone eligible to sign up and accepted all applicants in the training squad. The first training consisted of physical (off skates), skating skills and gameplay evaluations. The idea being to assess where were individuals at and what we needed to work on as a group. We started with about 25-30 applicants, some of them joining a few months into training. The levels ranged between non completed minimum skills to advanced players. Men’s Roller Derby in Finland is still very much in its beginning with only two teams, and only one, Tampere Rollin’ Bros, has played games so far. In February we selected our 20 players squad, and two of the main things we looked for and that made the difference between people were availability to attend upcoming trainings and motivation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;-At the last MRDWC you came a solid 9th which placed you the 5th highest European country which is definitely something to be proud of! What did you learn from the 2014 world cup?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Miika:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;As were said before we didn’t really have to qualify and drop people but the selection process was more like “do we even have 20 people that can afford to travel?”. Almost everyone had at least some kind of background in ice hockey so we knew how to skate but playing derby was a whole different thing. I went to the MRDWC really unsure since I had only played one small tournament against men’s teams before in Malmö, Sweden.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;I learned from my first MRDWC experience that a lot had to be done but we were on a good starting platform.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;-Compared to the last MRDWC you have a lot further to travel than before. How has the team been fundraising for the trip to Canada? Any unusual ways you have used to gain support?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Miika:
I’m also a photographer so I made a seminude calendar for our fundraiser which turned out really great. All 200 calendars sold out but you can still order postcards from those photos from our GoFundMe account that we are using to sell merch and get more funds to travel to Calgary.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gofundme.com/TFMRDtoCalgary2016" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#0068cf;"&gt;www.gofundme.com/TFMRDtoCalgary2016&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;-How are you finding your team training in the run up to the World Cup? With only a few months left how is that affecting your training schedule?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Menstruella:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;We have been training every month or month and half since March 2015, and the only thing different in 2016 is that all of our practices are full weekends, where before we alternated full weekends with single days. We’re now focusing mainly on building cohesion and teamwork in our line-ups and pairs, as well as fine tuning a few things. We’ve been scrimmaging regularly against Kallio Rolling Rainbow and Helsinki Roller Derby, they’ve been really supportive and we’re honoured to train against such strong opponents.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;-You have a pretty mixed group this year with the number one seed from 2014 (USA) being in the mix as well as the last placed seed (Japan). Is there anyone you are really excited to play against in your group?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Menstruella:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;I think it’s safe to say we’re keen to take on Ireland again! We won against them in 2014 but lost last summer by a few points in a rematch, so we’re really excited to face them again, they’re a great bunch. We’re also looking forward to play USA, we’re thrilled at the chance to go against the best in the world. We’re really happy with our group and looking forward to play all of those teams, we’re sure they’ll all bring interesting challenges and we’re ready to take on them!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;-Do you have any specific aims for Calgary that you are willing to share with us? (We're okay if there is any closely guarded secrets you don't want to give up yet!)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;Menstruella:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;font-family:'Calibri', 'sans-serif';color:#444444;"&gt;We want to show that Finland is up and coming! Despite lacking the means in term of weekly trainings or game opportunities, our players are skilled and work hard, they’re smart and have been building a real team in this past year. I’m extremely proud of how long they’ve come as individuals and as team, their constant progress keeps humbling me and they’re a joy to coach and work with. We’re gonna bring our best game and make the best out of this experience, and we’re sure we’ll learn a lot about ourselves as well. We’re hoping the tournament will boost motivation and interest to help men’s roller derby develop in Finland. We’re really stoked about this event and can’t wait to meet new and old friends!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8213" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/07/finland-roster.jpg" alt="finland roster" width="679" height="960"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Finland's first fixture will be against Ireland at 13:00 local time. For the full MRDWC schedule visit: http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/07/11/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-finland/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 09:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Preparing for Team Scotland Tryouts?</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/29/preparing-for-team-scotland-tryouts/</link><dc:creator>oneknownashaze</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the first Tryout for the Scottish (Women's) National Team this weekend (&lt;strong&gt;2nd July 2016&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Disc+Dundee+International+Sports+Centre/@56.4762665,-2.9611212,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x48865cfd69198245:0x74e93fd03837f5ac!8m2!3d56.4762665!4d-2.9589272"&gt;DISC, Dundee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, starting &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt;), and the second not far behind (&lt;strong&gt;9th July 2016&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/ARC:+Health+and+Fitness/@55.8662153,-4.2519289,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x4888441f10416197:0x3a9426f40d4b58b7!8m2!3d55.8662153!4d-4.2497349"&gt;ARC, Glasgow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, starting at &lt;strong&gt;1pm&lt;/strong&gt;), there's a lot of things that applicants might be worrying about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This unofficial guide will try to give some answers, based on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://ukrda.org.uk"&gt;UKRDA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s policies, and the positions in the Team Scotland &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1yayP8ZeUBCrIUqDjsqTuY_CdDMVo7SKM8FOnlymxFvw/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1"&gt;applications documents&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;(still open until &lt;strong&gt;midnight&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;30th&lt;/strong&gt;.):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the Tryouts for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
The Tryouts are for selection into the Team Scotland Training Squad. This team will later be further selected into the final competition roster for the World Cup and other competitions, on the basis of performance during training.
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Will skaters joining Team Scotland be playing in the next World Cup (and where and when will that be)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The intent of Team Scotland is definitely to provide a team to play in the next World Cup (and presumably other international bouts). However, no-one has any knowledge of when or where the next World Cup will be - Blood &amp;amp; Thunder have not, at the time of writing, made a final decision on a host country or city.
&lt;p&gt;We do have one piece of information: sources have implied that the World Cup will not be hosted in North America. Given the geographical distribution of teams, it seems this makes it most likely to be somewhere in Europe...
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;How long will Team Scotland be selected for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
UKRDA requires that teams are selected for 2 years, after the point that the selection is announced. So, 2 years from when you find out that you're in.
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;4.&lt;strong&gt; I can't make either Tryout - can I try out by Video?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yes&lt;/em&gt;. The Team Scotland requirements for video tryout submissions are that you submit enough footage to demonstrate all of the aspects that will be tested and also that you include enough bout footage to show your actual performance in game.
&lt;p&gt;The application lists the areas that will be evaluated as: "Attitude and Coachability", "Athleticism", "Individual skating skill and ability", "Jammer awareness", "Blocking skills and pack work" and "Strategy and rules/game knowledge". We believe that these will be evaluated at an international level, so pick footage appropriately.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;5. &lt;strong&gt;Will the actual Tryout sessions themselves be videoed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yes&lt;/em&gt;. Both Tryouts will be videoed, but footage will only be used for the purposes of selection. Video material will be made available to the Team Scotland Coaching and Management team, to the Selectors outwith that team, and to UKRDA National Squads Observers.
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;6. &lt;strong&gt;I can make both Tryouts, how will my performance be evaluated if I go to both?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
The Selectors intend to evaluate skaters on the &lt;em&gt;average&lt;/em&gt; performance over all Tryouts they attend. So, your performance in both Tryouts will count &lt;em&gt;equally&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;7. &lt;strong&gt;What should I bring to Tryouts?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Black and white scrimmage tops. (UKRDA &lt;em&gt;recommends&lt;/em&gt; that, in the interests of avoiding bias, skaters try to &lt;em&gt;avoid&lt;/em&gt; tops which emphasise their team membership).
&lt;p&gt;Anything you would take to a 3 hour long practice session - there will be both skills demonstration and scrimmage, so: food &amp;amp; water, medicines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will also need (copies of) documents necessary to prove your eligibility to represent Scotland, under &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1wsj7GJ7NTXcT-DpQJs1Zn4BfzvWAqnXXZ3yimg-CJcI/edit"&gt;UKRDA advisory guidelines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Depending on how you are eligible, these will be some of:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;UK Passport (or other proof of British Citizenship)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Leave to Remain / Residence document (if not using passport)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;If not born in Scotland as evidenced by Passport or otherwise:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Birth certificate [parent or grandparent's, or spouse/civil partners', depending] showing birth in Scotland
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Marriage/Civil Partnership certificate (if partners' birth certificate)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Birth certificates to show descent from person (if parent/grandparent's birth certificate)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; Proof of residence in Scotland for at least 3 years (utility bills, for example) [if not eligible via birth certificates]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; letter from home league stating that you've been with them for 3+ years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
You will also need to bring £10 cash to pay for your application (if you're trying out both dates, you only need to pay once).
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;8. &lt;strong&gt;Who are the Selectors?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
To our knowledge, the Selectors are: Team Scotland Assistant Coach 5-Star Sylk, Team Scotland Line-Up Rufi-Ohh, Team Scotland Manager Hazzard, Bairn City Rollers' and Power of Scotland's rEd Baron, and The Inhuman League / Power of Scotland's Nuke.
&lt;p&gt;Team Scotland Head Coach, Rosie Peacock, is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a Selector, as she is also trying out for selection to the team as a skater.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;9. &lt;strong&gt;Who else will be present?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
As well as the Selectors, there will also be several Observers from UKRDA. They are present to ensure that Tryouts are conducted in a fair and unbiased manner.
&lt;p&gt;There will also be a videographer and photographer, and sufficient NSO and referees to run the scrimmage part of the evaluation.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;10.  &lt;strong&gt;What are the plans and policies for skaters who make the Team Scotland training squad?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
At this point, the detailed policies and plans for Team Scotland's Training Squad are not public (although we are advised that they are well developed). Team Manager Hazzard told us, however, that the team have "exciting opportunities lined up already for those who make the training squad".
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/29/preparing-for-team-scotland-tryouts/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 11:23:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Team Belgium</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/25/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-belgium/</link><dc:creator>oneknownashaze</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today we take a look at another of the Northern European teams in the form of Team Belgium. We talk to their head coach about how they have been preparing for this year's MRDWC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-7898 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/team-bel.jpg?w=300" alt="team bel" width="300" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did your selection process for this year's World Cup differ from the 2014 selection? Did you find there were different factors you were looking for in skaters?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014 Men's Roller Derby was still in an experimental phase. Most of our skaters were referees already familiar with the game. Men's teams in Belgium were rare. This made the selection process pretty simple: everyone who could and wanted to skate, was welcome to join our journey to Birmingham. Even though we were very competitive already, in Birmingham we wanted to put Belgium men's derby on the map. We wanted to inspire more men to take the step to join in so our national team would grow even better and more competitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right around Birmingham, Men's Roller Derby got more popular. Therefor the amount of skaters who wanted to work hard to earn that spot on the roster for the World Cup grew. Back then (in Birmingham) it was more about having enough players to have a full roster to go to the UK, now it is more about having enough skills, being a bigger athlete and derby player. Our team had to work hard to be part of this adventure. For me this is the big difference comparing Birmingham 2014 to Calgary 2016. Even though I must admit we were already pretty awesome in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did we handle skaters selections? We started out with 35 players out of the very small country of Belgium. After about 8 trainings and scrimmages, we made a selection. We didn't only focus on skating and derby skills, but also on team spirit: Team Belgium is famous for being a fun team, we have no spots open for big ego's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that does stand out in comparison with Birmingham 2014 is back then the team was mostly composed of skaters from the Flemish part of Belgium and now... I, Humpme, the bench coach, am the only flemish person in the entire team. This is rather strange because the Flemish part of Belgium has more citizens than the French-speaking part. But, I'll stand my ground ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the 2014 MRDWC you came 13th just a head of Team Sweden. Is there anything that you have learned from your performance last time that you are taking forward for the 2016 world cup? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training is necessary to become ONE team. We have to know each other’s strengths to play out the right ones in the right situation, we train to get to know each other’s gameplay, who is sensitive for certain penalties, how to handle frustrations from yourself or other skaters on the team. Basically... Who needs what and when and be the best teammates for one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the most important thing we learned: Belgium always wins the afterparty!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This year you have a bigger distance to travel to compete in the MRDWC. How have you been fundraising to get the team over to Calgary?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you look at what other teams do, we more or less do the same: we sell t-shirts, we organize games, bootcamps and even a very awesome Sur5all! I'm very proud of our handsome team and the muscles we have built during practice, that's why I'm still waiting on their nude calendar ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compared to the last world cup how do you think your training schedule has evolved? Is there any new training techniques you hope will give you the edge in the competition? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the preparation of Birmingham 2014 there wasn't too much training involved. It was rather non-committal. For the road to Calgary 2016 this is completely different: we train two times a month. Belgium, with its 30 500km², is very small, which makes it very easy for us to come together and practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, not only the quantity of practices and skaters is different in 2016, but quality comes first. Men are powerful, our men have always been powerful, but with power itself you can't make it... other teams will be powerful and full of testosterone as well. We want to play smart and make the difference by doing this. For me, as a coach, it is important for my team they know MY strengths as well. In the 5 years of playing derby, I managed to collect a lot of strategical insight. This is something where players had still room to learn, seems only fair for the amount (or lack) of experience they had one year ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, next to the typical skating skills, endurance drills, … it is very imortant to talk a lot about strategies and create your own: which position do you usually skate within your home league? What works for women and why wouldn't this work for men? What are the strenghts of our team? …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are up against quite a mixed group this year with the number 4 and 5 seeds being in your group as well as a few newcomers to the MRDWC. Who are you really looking forward to playing this year? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being in the group with Australia and France is definitely NOT a blessing. We are really curious about Puerto Rico in our group, we don't know them at all so it should be a really interesting game. It looks like we might meet Finland or Scotland IF we end third of the group which would be definitely a hard battle. And that’s what we’re doing it for!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any specific aims for Calgary that you are willing to share with us? (We're okay if there is any closely guarded secrets you don't want to give up yet!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our most important goal is to have a perfect balance between competition and having fun. We are a team that plays very clean and who are not going for sneaky things that the refs don’t see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a team wins by suicide hits, grabbing, tackling, high blocking,… resulting in penalties, we prefer loosing with proud. But again: the after party is ours!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Humpme&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
Head coach Team Belgium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7899" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/bel-2.jpg" alt="bel 2" width="960" height="678"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belgium's first fixture will be against Team Australia  at 09:00 local time. For the full schedule please visit &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/" target="_blank"&gt;http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/25/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-belgium/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 07:07:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Swedish Men's Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/22/mrdwc-2016-team-review-swedish-mens-roller-derby/</link><dc:creator>oneknownashaze</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today brings another addition to our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/"&gt;Men's Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; series, in the form of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/SwedishMensRollerDerby"&gt;Swedish Men's Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;! We talk to Krutsson #61 about how they've grown since the last MRDWC and how they are preparing for Calgary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-7879 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/sweden.jpg?w=280" alt="sweden" width="280" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 2014 Men's Roller Derby World Cup, Sweden had a fairly difficult group, placed with England, Netherlands and Argentina. While they won convincingly against Argentina, England defeated them as easily as they defeated almost everyone else in the tournament, and a hard-fought game against the Dutch ended in defeat. In the lower bracket of the tournament, the Swedes couldn't stand against the Finns, or the Belgians, ending up in 14th position on the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/"&gt;time around&lt;/a&gt;, Team Sweden resides in Group Orange, where they'll be facing England and Argentina again, along with new faces Chile and Italy. While England is a strong bet for the first of the two top spots in the group, it's hard to predict who could take the second - Sweden are certainly in with a good chance!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked to Krutsson (#61) about how they've grown since the last MRDWC and how they are preparing for Calgary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has your selection process this year differed from the selection of your last MRDWC team? Did you find that there were many factors that changed from the last selection after your experience in 2014?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;At the last MRDWC you came 14th out of 15th. With even more teams competing this year how do you think the experience of the 2014 World cup will shape how you play this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014, we didn't really have to select skaters. We were just happy to be there. It was just a question about getting enough skaters, that met the requirements, on the roster. We were allowed to put skaters on the roster that hadn't passed the minimum skills test, with the condition that they passed them before the tournament. We managed to roster 14 skaters for Birmingham. This time we had a few skaters on an early stage that decided not to apply, due to various reasons, but who probably would have made the roster. We ended up selecting 17 skaters for Calgary, and we think they can perform at a pretty high level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compared to the last World Cup, how do you think your training schedule has evolved? Is there any new factors that you have in place that you hope will give you the edge in the competition?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014, it was more about learning the basics. This time we have leagues that play roller derby games and scrimmages at a regular basis. We've got more experience and skills within the leagues and a stronger foundation to build on. The schedule is about the same but the focus is more on tactics, than actually learning the core basics of the game. The problem in Sweden is that we are pretty spread out and there is a lot of travelling involved to get the team together.
We are still very few male skaters in Sweden compared to the number of female skaters. The teams competing under WFTDA in Sweden have taken a huge leap the last few years. Two teams qualified to WFTDA division 1 playoffs last year and the new national Swedish division play has helped spreading knowledge about the sport, and has really given the Swedish roller derby community a push forward. I think we have a strong roller derby community in Sweden with knowledge about high level roller derby and this time we have a team with skills enough to benefit from that. Now it's just about getting everyone's skills together for the men's national team. We have a good and experienced coach team to lead us too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The last MRDWC was pretty close by compared to this year with a trip to Canada to prepare for! How have you been fundraising to get the team to Calgary? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were a bit late in the start-up so most European teams had already made their game schedules, so we have had difficulties in finding opponents for games. So the fundraising will be mostly from selling merchandise having sponsors. The skaters will still have to pay a part themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This year, your group is pretty mixed with quite a few new teams in the mix as well as the number 2 seed from 2014. Is there anyone in your group you're really excited to play?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had both England and Argentina in our group in Birmingham in 2014. I think we are looking forward to those two games the most. England will be very difficult to beat. When we met them in Birmingham it was a complete blowout. They didn't even let us score a single point. Our performance against them will be better this time. I can promise you that much. Argentina played really well in Birmingham and we expect them to have improved. Our team captain played a in mixed team with some of them, against Team Italy, so we know a little about how they play. When it comes to Chile, we don't know much, but after the experience with Argentina last time we won't underestimate any South American team even if they show up with only 8 skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you got any specific aims for Calgary that you would be willing to share? (Don't worry we understand if you have any secret plays you don't want to share just yet!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're aiming to end as high up in our group as possible. The key will be the game against Argentina. In Birmingham they beat us, but this time we come better prepared and we think we can give them a real challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7878" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/sweden-2.jpg" alt="sweden 2" width="960" height="914"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweden's first fixture will be against Team England at 12:00 local time. For the full schedule please visit &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/" target="_blank"&gt;http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/22/mrdwc-2016-team-review-swedish-mens-roller-derby/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 11:19:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MRDWC 2016 Team Review: Team Netherlands</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/20/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-netherlands/</link><dc:creator>oneknownashaze</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Team Netherlands - Men's Derby are up next in our series of articles about the competing teams in the 2016 MRDWC. Here we find out how they have been preparing for Calgary and what they want to achieve whilst over there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-7860 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/netherlands.jpg?w=300" alt="netherlands" width="300" height="286"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 2014 World Cup, Team Netherlands finished a creditable joint 11th, tied with Team Germany, after losing to Finland in the knockout stage.
This time, they're placed in Group Blue, where the formidable France looks like dominating. The second spot in the group for the top tier of knockouts will be hotly contested, and Netherlands will have to contend with Australia and Belgium for it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught up with Johnny B Rude to learn how Netherlands are preparing for Calgary!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has your selection process this year differed from the selection of your last MRDWC team? Did you find there were different factors you were looking for in skaters?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We started out with quite a big pool of skaters to choose from but due to circumstances we were down to 14 players ready to come to the MRDWC. We still had a bout and a try-out session to make sure everyone fitted well in the team. Sadly, one more player had to drop out due to an injury, leaving us with a team of 13 players going to Calgary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the last MRDWC you came joint 11th with Team Germany. Is there anything that you have learned from your performance last time that you are taking forward for the 2016 world cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We learned that we still have a lot to learn :). The way derby has evolved, we feel there is more focus on teamwork than on individual skills, and this is something we've worked on a lot. On the other hand, with the more compact walls used...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This World Cup is being hosted in Calgary, Canada which is a bit further than the last edition which was in the UK! How has the team been fundraising to get themselves over the Atlantic?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest our fundraising has been quite minimal, and currently everyone is paying everything out of their own pockets. A lot of people are combining the trip with holiday in North America to make the most out of it. We do have a go fund me page: &lt;a href="https://www.gofundme.com/nlmrdwc"&gt;https://www.gofundme.com/nlmrdwc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compared to the last World Cup how do you think your training schedule has evolved? With only a few months left how is that affecting your training schedule?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We grew from only having a few practices before the world cup to having a monthly practice for the last year, which I think helped us to get used to each other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are up against quite a mixed group this year with the number 4 and 5 seeds being in your group as well as a few new comers to the MRDWC. Is there anyone you are really excited to play against in your group?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are a lot of things to look forward to. France and Australia because I think we can learn a lot from them, and we get to play against some world class skaters (Ballistic Whistle, Mr. Furieux aka Kilian David). Belgium will be exciting since this is going to be the 4th time we play each other, and it’s always a lot of fun to play the neighbours. Two players of my own league in Liege play for Belgium. Puerto Rico is a bit of a mystery for everyone, and it would be great if we can make an exciting game out of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the run up to Calgary is there any specific goals you are aiming for whilst you are there? (If there's anything you would rather keep to yourselves for now we understand!) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The aim of this MRDWC for Team NL is mainly to gain experience, have fun, and hopefully win a game in the process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-7869 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/06/netherlands-2.jpg" alt="netherlands 2" width="480" height="360"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Netherlands first fixture will be against Team Australia at 14:00 local time. For the full schedule please visit &lt;a href="http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/" target="_blank"&gt;http://mrdwc.com/schedule-2016/&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>mrdwc2016</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/06/20/mrdwc-2016-team-review-team-netherlands/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 16:31:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Town Roller Girls Year in Review - 2015</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/31/new-town-roller-girls-year-in-review-2015/</link><dc:creator>oneknownashaze</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Heart, Soul and a Whole Lotta Roll&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a very small league we found ourselves at the beginning of 2015 looking forward to a full year. Unsure of what to expect from the British Championships and excited about the prospect of bouts, scrims, and expanding our numbers through fresh meat sessions and recruitment drives, we couldn’t wait to see how it would unfold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full of hope and promise we saw ourselves compete in the Highland Rampage as our very first team effort without the help of guest skaters, and playing with only 10 of a team we did ourselves proud. We lost all our games in the competition but as a team we were excited at the enthusiasm and dedication that was shown by its members. Still full of hope and spirit little did we know this was to prove to be what would define us throughout the entire year. 2015 would gift us with a new and inspirational coach, would see us lose and gain great team members, would take us on multiple adventures within the UK and Europe, and would herald a new baby or two into the fold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rampage behind us we headed into the British Championships with the same guts and determination. We secured funding, did a sponsored skate, car boot sales and other funding drives in an attempt to transport us across the country just to participate. Many tears and much laughter was dispensed along the way, and the courage of team mates shone through, as the novices amongst us played alongside the more experienced. Battling in most bouts with 8 to 9 players we never gave up, we always found a way to play, looking exhaustion, illness and injury square on and walling up regardless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the statistics and having lost all of our 4 British Championship bouts and 2 friendlies, some would say that 2015 was an unsuccessful year for us, but I would have to disagree. Having fought alongside the ladies and gentlemen that make up our league, counting family, friends and team mates in the mix, I would say that we in many ways secured the win. Hosting our very first home bout and bringing Roller Derby into the news and home to West Lothian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller derby is more than just a sport, it is a community, an all encompassing family that highlights everything you are and everything that you aspire to be. Being part of NTRG has seen me challenge myself physically and emotionally and with the support of team members has helped me to reach personal goals and slay inner demons. Like many families we have our differences but I know that when our combined strength is needed we pull together and support each other on and off track. NTRG has come to represent hope, hard work, and determination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5389" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/article-1.jpg" alt="article 1" width="900" height="596"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking to the ladies and gentlemen of our league this sentiment is echoed, when asked to say what NTRG has meant to them common themes of family, friends, and fun shone through:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Who you spend time with is who you become. It’s not what we get that makes us happy, it’s who we become. Then what we can give to become more. New Town has helped me to grow into the player I am today and embodies the heart and spirit of the sport I love. I will always strive to repay this kindness”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“NTRG is the first time I have been part of a team, I have been there for a full year and even though I have other priorities everyone is so friendly and allow me to feel part of the team. Being part of NTRG is like having another family on skates”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Pleasure, pain, team, and family, win or lose, most of all fun”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Before joining NTRG I was extremely unfit and over the last year I have seen my fitness level increase 10 fold, which was one of my main reasons for signing up! However having said that I have found that I have loved being part of a team and making new friendships with a diverse group of people. I have also learned new things about myself such as how resilient I am, how determined I can be when I put my mind to something, realising that with a bit of hard work and effort I am an alright skater. Learning to skate and play derby has been a great challenge for me and also a great escape from the everyday pressures of life”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Derby girls got me through this year, just by being there. It’s the support you get with Derby that I love ….(and exercise and men in tights)”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“NTRG means friendship – I have loved getting to know everyone and feeling part of a team. Everyone is super lovely and there is always someone there with a hug or motivational words of encouragement to drive your determination forward”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Watching the first roller derby event my wife participated in was a dual experience. Firstly you have the fear of her getting hurt and being injured. You know what will happen, you know what to expect but wait with trepidation for the first jam to start. Then it all kicks off and after you watch your loved one get up after being hip checked by a blocker, the adrenaline starts pumping and you're up on your feet shouting for your team. Discussing the merits of the game with your 7 year old son who is grinning inanely because mum has a star on her helmet. You shout cheer, holler and scream for the team, willing each and every point. They are out on track, sweating, panting and bleeding for a sport they love and you couldn’t be prouder. Roller derby is family. Roller derby is fantastic.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5390" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/12/ntrg-article.jpg" alt="ntrg article" width="900" height="596"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So looking forward to 2016 we face the year with pride, pride of everything we have achieved, pride in every member, pride of our spirit and determination. Hopeful and excited to usher in new members, new experiences and increase out knowledge. Full of determination, motivation and the work ethic to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AuROARa 812&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>british roller derby championships</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/12/31/new-town-roller-girls-year-in-review-2015/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 15:30:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Town Roller Girls - Round up of 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/19/new-town-roller-girls-round-up-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>oneknownashaze</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year one of our newly mins passed skaters interviews one of our long time skaters who is on the clutch of finishing off her own mins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introductions! Who are you?
&lt;/strong&gt;I’m Alison aka Woolly Thumper and I’ll have been with NTRG for 2 years in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What made you join roller derby and how long have you been playing?
&lt;/strong&gt;I was introduced to derby by my boss whose girlfriend was going through fresh meat with ARRG. He showed me some videos; I went to watch a couple of bouts and was hooked. I had a taster session with ARRG but their training venues and times didn’t work for me so derby went on the back burner until about a year later when I found out about NTRG. I met the team at a getting-to-know you night in the pub and strapped on a pair of skates the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What has NTRG been up to so far this year? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we have been working on running our fresh meat program in a more formal, organised way which has been very effective and the impact can be seen in the amazing progress our freshies have made. Although we haven't really bouted as a league, our skaters have been bouting as guests for other leagues, in charity bouts and mixed teams and the whole league has benefited from what they have learned. We also took part in the Sur5ors tournament in October which was an amazing experience. We really enjoyed skating against some much more experienced skaters and I think we represented ourselves well. We have had a lot of support from skaters from other leagues, Mean City and Dundee especially, giving up their time to help coach us. We have learned loads and are so grateful, hopefully next year we will be able to pay it forward to other leagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What have been the highlights for the team &amp;amp; your own personal highlights?
&lt;/strong&gt;Highlights for the team would probably have to be Sur5ors and the great crop of new skaters we have coming through. I am making my way slowly through my mins so every extra lap on my 27/5 and every new skill nailed or fear faced is a highlight for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are this year's fresh meat shaping up?
&lt;/strong&gt;AWESOME, lots of talent, determination and a lovely bunch too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's next for NTRG?
&lt;/strong&gt;2015 is shaping up to be a pretty exciting year for us; in February we are taking part in Voodoo's Highland Rampage tournament which features 8 teams from across Scotland. We are also taking part in Tier 4 of the British Roller Derby Championships which will keep us busy throughout the year. We are not big enough to have our own home season (yet) so we are working to arrange some more bouts with other leagues both local and further afield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any final words?
&lt;/strong&gt;I'm really looking forward to 2015. Next year should see me popping my bouting cherry and skating out alongside my fantastic NTRG teammates. I consider myself very lucky to be part of such a lovely bunch of folk and I'm very proud to call myself a New Town Roller Girl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo Courtesy of Rudi Pateluch&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/ntrg-61.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4465" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/ntrg-61.jpg?w=660" alt="Courtesy of Rudi Pateluch" width="660" height="440"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>interviews</category><category>new town roller girls</category><category>ntrg</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/19/new-town-roller-girls-round-up-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 19:13:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sur5ors: A Week On</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/25/sur5ors-a-week-on/</link><dc:creator>oneknownashaze</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Saturday 18th October saw 12 teams from around the UK come together to sur5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alison Renton's event 'sur5ors' was a massive success just as her previous charity driven derby events have been. This event was for the Benefit of both Glendrick Roost Animal Welfare Centre and St Andrew's First Aid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the day started, and set up and formalities concluded, the audience was let in and the real buzz started. With the 12 teams lacing up their skates and slipping on pads anticipation was in the air. As the first whistle blew for the first heat and teams started clashing it was clear there was a vast spectrum of skating talent on show. From ARRG and GRD dominating the skating down to NTRG and VRD representing the newer leagues everyone displayed their talent with gusto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day went on with jam after jam holding the audience on the edges of their seats. Where some jams saw some teams dominate where others brought the audience to uproars as they saw teams comeback from the brink of losing only to climb up the rankings ladder of the tournament. Each team was nothing but lovely to one another before and after they faced each other. Generally the atmosphere between skaters was extremely friendly with the teams mingling between heats and chatting on the benches between jams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearing the end of the tournament excitement was running at its peak with the last few jams of the day tearing up some parts of the rankings and seeing some of the newer teams come to equal blows with some of the harder skating teams.In the end the results came in and each team was put on the rankings board in the positions they had proudly earned throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For us over at NTRG the day was everything we wanted it to be. Having our girls win two jams and finish 11th was a massive boost for us. Not to mention how encouraging our cheering section in the crowd was! It gave us some perspective of where we stand in the wider derby community and it's an event that we'll cherish as a building block to our success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the skaters provided entertainment on track the day was held up by the vast scores of NSOs, referees and tournament crew who tirelessly worked away to keep the event running smoothly. Without them the day would have not been the success it was and the skaters who took part felt their benefit immensely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results are as followed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/10606063_10153275885608079_8291095240425177450_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4124" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/10606063_10153275885608079_8291095240425177450_n.jpg?w=300" alt="10606063_10153275885608079_8291095240425177450_n" width="300" height="110"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bout reports</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>sur5al</category><category>tournament</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/25/sur5ors-a-week-on/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 19:34:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Town Roller Girls present MURDERDROME</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/18/new-town-roller-girls-present-murderdrome/</link><dc:creator>oneknownashaze</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the 6th of September New Town Roller Girls play host to blood curdling display of roller derby as they put on showing of &lt;em&gt;'Murderdrome'. &lt;/em&gt;An Australian slasher film with strong roots in roller derby and horror film culture that was released in Britain earlier in the year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New Town Roller Girls were very lucky to have a member with a keen eye on Facebook who caught a post from '&lt;em&gt;Murderdrome&lt;/em&gt;'  saying they were looking for leagues to show their film for fundraising events within their own leagues. The event is also going to be held at Livingston's key theatre Howden Park Centre who are very supportive of local groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The doors open at 7:45pm with the film starting at 8. Tickets will be £5 on the door and the event will be 18+ only and attendees will be provided with a NTRG wrist band.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The event also boasts a rich display of raffle prizes from roller derby paraphernalia to special deals with local restaurants.  &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To check out the event, the film and New Town Roller Girls head on over to; &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/702042726509548/"&gt;NTRG present MURDERDROME&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/poss-banner-murderdrome.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter wp-image-3600 size-full" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/08/poss-banner-murderdrome.jpg" alt="poss banner murderdrome" width="860" height="314"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>murderdrome</category><category>new town roller girls</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/08/18/new-town-roller-girls-present-murderdrome/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 18:05:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>