<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts by paingrrl666)</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/authors/paingrrl666.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:54:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Glasgow Roller Derby:  Next Level Bootcamp &amp; Guest Coaching Available</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/02/02/glasgow-roller-derby-next-level-bootcamp-guest-coaching-available/</link><dc:creator>paingrrl666</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img id="featured-image" class=" aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/getattachment.jpg" alt="Featured image" width="273" height="163"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby had an exciting year last year, and now we are looking to share our learning with other leagues!
We have lots on offer, both for leagues and for individual skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sat 21st March, we are hosting our ‘Next Level Bootcamp.  This is a fully co-ed bootcamp, which is aimed at two levels – people wishing to learn basic skills for passing minimums (stops/stride/laterals), and then people who have passed minimum skills and are aiming to become bout ready (agility, edge work, hockey stops etc).   The bootcamp is being offered at the super reasonable price of £25 on-skates, and £15 off-skates.  We will also have our very special Roller Grrls t-shirts available for sale which are unavailable for general purchase, as well as a range of other Grd merch.  You can book a place on the bootcamp &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/787419911313296/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also available to leagues who would like some guest coaching, and have developed a training menu which will cater for league at any level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have coaches available to cover sessions such as:-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;all levels of skills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;all levels of strategy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nutrition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;off skates fitness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mental conditioning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;league morale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;team building&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;scrimmage/bout footage reviewing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to take advantage of this opportunity, please contact &lt;a href="mailto:interleagueliaison@glasgowrollerderby.com"&gt;interleagueliaison@glasgowrollerderby.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to meeting you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/grd.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-4565 aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/grd.jpg?w=300" alt="grd" width="310" height="119"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>grd</category><category>roller derby bootcamp</category><category>roller derby bootcamps</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/02/02/glasgow-roller-derby-next-level-bootcamp-guest-coaching-available/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 15:57:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow Roller Derby:  Round-Up of 2014</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/29/glasgow-roller-derby-round-up-of-2014/</link><dc:creator>paingrrl666</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img id="featured-image" class=" aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/grd-logo.jpg?w=300" alt="Featured image" width="166" height="166"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby have had quite possibly our busiest year to date, and are already working hard on plans to make 2015 even better if possible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;2014 saw GRD firmly establish our C team, the Cannie Gingers, and fully integrate them into Scottish Roller Derby with 4 amazing bouts spread throughout the year.   Our B Team, the Maiden Grrders, trained hard, culminating in a super win against London’s Batter C Power.  And our super A Team, the Irn Bruisers, took America by storm at Spring Roll, as well as capturing home wins against Middlesborough and Dublin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img id="featured-image" class=" aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/maidens.jpg?w=300" alt="Featured image"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;Our 4 home teams battled throughout the year, culminating in the Bad Omens recapturing the winners trophy for Home Team Season 2014.  And many of our skaters represented at mixed games and tournaments across the UK.  This included 8 of our skaters playing for Vagine Regime UK throughout the year; 9 of our skaters representing their home countries at the World Cup in Dallas; as well as skaters representing at Sur5al, Skate of Ages and various other mixed charity games.  We love the enthusiasm and passion our skaters demonstrate for roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img id="featured-image" class=" aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/world-cup.jpg?w=300" alt="Featured image"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;Our fundraising and events teams have been hard at work raising funds and events to allow GRD to do what we do best.  Successes included our awesome GoFundMe t-shirt campaign, with fantastic custom artwork by Gary Erskine.  There was also an American-themed fundraising bout, which saw our mini-bruisers defeat mini-America.  Lots of good fun!  And none of this could be possible without our wonderful PR committee, who spread the good word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;Our skaters have also been hard at work off track, with some amazing league accomplishments.  Mistress Malicious, co-founder of Glasgow Roller Derby and UKRDA, organised the first UK-ROC in October 2014.  This was a huge success, bringing together skaters from across the UK to attend workshops and learn from the most experienced skaters in the world about roller derby infrastructure.  2 of our skaters were also involved in the UKRDA’s development of a fully inclusive Transgender Policy and Guidance, which has been voted in as operational for every member league in the UK.  And our WFTDA reps have been hard at work, with tireless Bruisers captain and WFTDA rep Rogue Runner assisting in strategic development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;What next for GRD?  We plan to train even harder, and play even harder.  Each of our travel teams has their own goals in sight, and as a league we plan to get even stronger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;We will be kicking the year off with a fantastically diverse fundraising bout on Sat 31&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; Jan at the Arc, showcasing a mixed Glasgow team playing against the highly skilled Vagine Regime UK.  The bout will be followed by a drag party, where everyone is encouraged to leave the confines of socially constructed gender behind and just have a jolly good time exploring gender expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;Our Bruisers will be competing in Tier 1 of the British Championships, showcasing UK derby at its best.  Our Maiden Grrders will be hosting a B-level Scottish tournament, and our Cannie Gingers will be appearing in the Highland Rampage tournament.  Invites are flooding in for each of our teams to skate, and our games schedule is looking very exciting!  We shall also be announcing new team captains for each team, as well as looking to optimise on our events schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;&lt;img id="featured-image" class=" aligncenter" src="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/12/bruisers.jpg?w=300" alt="Featured image"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;If this sounds like something you want to get in on, then Glasgow Roller Derby are holding a new intake on Sunday, January 11&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; 2015 – and we would love to see you there! If you are interested in signing up and changing your life, sign up at recruiting@glasgowrollerderby.com. Find out more on our &lt;a title="GRD Facebook Event" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/645457582240839/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Event&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="ecxMsoNormal"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 in review</category><category>an interview with...</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>review of the year</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/12/29/glasgow-roller-derby-round-up-of-2014/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 11:56:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow Roller Derby battle Dundee Roller Girls - followed by battling the gender binary!</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/30/glasgow-roller-derby-battle-dundee-roller-girls-followed-by-battling-the-gender-binary/</link><dc:creator>paingrrl666</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/banner.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-3925 aligncenter" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/banner.jpg?w=300" alt="banner" width="300" height="111"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, 25th October &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/content/grds-maiden-grrders-vs-dundee-roller-girls"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby's Maiden Grrders take on Dundee Roller Girls' Silvery Tayzers&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Maiden Grrders are very excited about this challenge, following their recent win against London's Batter C Power.  Several new Maidens made their debut appearance in that game, and are raring to make an impact on their second appearance.  Dundee will be travelling from the East Coast to the Arc, to fight it out on Glasgow's home turf.  Dundee will be keen to make a mark against the Maidens after their recent defeat by Fierce Valley, and with both teams fielding a wealth of skater experience, strategy and skills, anything could happen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/maidens.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-3928 aligncenter" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/maidens.jpg?w=300" alt="maidens" width="300" height="168"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will also be the first time that Dundee come up against several of their former team-mates, who have swapped their pink shirts for black due to relocation - adding another interesting twist to this game!  Glasgow's Maiden Grrders are currently ranked 39th in Europe, with Dundee's Silvery Tayzers ranked at 102nd (correct at time of writing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whatever happens on track, the after party is set to be a belter - Glasgow Roller Derby's fundraising committee are pulling it all out of the bag with a fantastic drag party.  Fun, games and gender bending will be the order of the evening, with drag accessories, singing and dancing all set to the theme of screwing the binary.  For more details, check out Glasgow Roller Derby's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GlasgowRollerDerby"&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt; page. &lt;/em&gt;(Due to circumstances outside GRD's control, this afterparty event has been postponed. The afterparty is now at the Solid Rock Cafe.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby also offer a fantastic promo deal for other derby leagues - pay for 4 derby skaters from your team, and a 5th skater gets in free! (skaters must all be from the same league).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/poster.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-3929 aligncenter" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/poster.jpg?w=212" alt="poster" width="212" height="300"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>annoucements</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>interleagues</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/30/glasgow-roller-derby-battle-dundee-roller-girls-followed-by-battling-the-gender-binary/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 13:46:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow Roller Derby Season 5 Opener</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/04/16/glasgow-roller-derby-season-5-opener/</link><dc:creator>paingrrl666</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/04/home-teams.jpg"&gt;&lt;img id="i-3375" class="size-full wp-image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/04/home-teams.jpg?w=650" alt="Image"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even hotter than the release date of the new OITNB, we're now hotting up for SEASON 5 of Glasgow Roller Derby's Home Teams!!! Saturday 26th April sees Glasgow's 4 home teams come together in a fantastic season opener, aiming to rack up some serious points that will put 2 lucky teams in good stead for a place in the much-coveted final!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;Doors open at 11.30am, so get down early to secure a suicide line seat and purchase some yummy cake/merch/raffle tickets and watch what promises to two full bouts of stunning derby strategy, skills and strength.  And just to mix things up a bit for you, there have been some roster changes that will keep you on the edge of your seats!Bout 1 sees the Bad Omens take on the T-Wrecks - a mighty clash indeed, as the Omens took 4th place last season and the T-Wrecks claimed second place.  The Omens are out to show they are no one's number 4, whilst the T-Wrecks will be going all out to scoop the illustrious first place this year.  This bout will be made particularly interesting as there has been a skater swap -  the powerful Splat, formerly a T-Wreck, is now playing for the Omens - and the jukey Suffra Jett will be donning green and playing for the Wrecks! It's all to play for - this is going to be rivetting!!Bout 2 will see the Helles Belles play the Death Stars.  Again, this will be a fight to the finish as the Death Stars will be fighting to keep a firm hold of their win over the last season, whilst the Belles will be anxious to beat their third place position from Season 4.  The Death Stars will feature some new faces to Grd's home teams, as will the Hells Belles - so watch out for some awesome new talent to admire!  Everyone loves a dark horse!
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are available in advance, however if you're flying by the seat of your pants, they will also be available on the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>home teams</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/04/16/glasgow-roller-derby-season-5-opener/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 12:21:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hell Hath No Fury!</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/18/hell-hath-no-fury/</link><dc:creator>paingrrl666</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/hell-hath1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-3048" alt="Image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/hell-hath1.jpg?w=470"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feminism and roller derby – two great life passions will be combined for many Scottish skaters on Saturday 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Dec!  As many of the country’s leagues commence their ‘off season’, this is a great way to mark the end of what has been a monumental year for all Scottish leagues in one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ‘Hell Hath No Fury’ charity bout is the brain child of Glasgow Roller Derby’s Maiden Grrders skater, Trucks Norris.  The bout will raise awareness of the &lt;i&gt;16 Days of Action for the Elimination of Violence Against Women&lt;/i&gt; campaign; a global phenomenon which runs from 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Nov to 10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Dec.  Organisations across the world will organise events during this period to raise awareness of violence against women. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All proceeds of this bout will go toward local Glasgow organisation ‘&lt;i&gt;Womens Support Project’&lt;/i&gt;, a feminist voluntary organisation which works to raise awareness of the extent, causes and effect of male violence against women.  It also works to provide improved services to those affected by violence, and highlights the links between different forms of male violence and promoting interagency responses to the abuse of women and children.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bout will take place at the Arc Sport Centre in Glasgow, and will feature skaters from Glasgow Roller Derby, Granite City, Fierce Valley, Dundee, Lothian Derby Dolls and Auld Reekie.  The bout also takes place on the same day as Team Scotland Try-Out 2, so if you do find yourself at a loose end then show your support for this great cause and go see some killer roller derby into the bargain!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sat 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Dec, doors at 12.30pm    &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/212345205605145/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/212345205605145/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/trucks.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-3050" alt="Image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/11/trucks.jpg?w=324"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This bout is the brainchild of former Womens Support Project Worker Trucks Norris (above)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/11/18/hell-hath-no-fury/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 10:23:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Watch Glasgow's Home Teams Fight For a Place in the Final!</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/08/28/watch-glasgows-home-teams-fight-for-a-place-in-the-final/</link><dc:creator>paingrrl666</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://paingrrl666.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/banner.jpg"&gt;&lt;img id="i-17" alt="Image" src="http://paingrrl666.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/banner.jpg?w=650"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Saturday, (31st August) a very important double header will be played out … The 3rd bout of the 2013 Glasgow Home Teams Season, this is the decider which determines which two teams will earn a coveted spot in the Home Teams Final in November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything is at stake – as the winning teams get to fight it out in the spectacular finale, and the losing teams will be relegated until the 2014 Home Team Season!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://paingrrl666.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/wrecks-team-shot.jpg"&gt;&lt;img id="i-19" alt="Image" src="http://paingrrl666.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/wrecks-team-shot.jpg?w=650"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First bout will see the hot rockin’ Helles Belles up against GRD’s newest home team, the T-Wrecks.  So far this season, each of these teams has won one and lost one.  Each are going in with a fantastic roster of skaters with only one thought on their minds – WINNING! So who shall be victorious?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://paingrrl666.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/belles-team-shot.jpg"&gt;&lt;img id="i-23" alt="Image" src="http://paingrrl666.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/belles-team-shot.jpg?w=650"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://paingrrl666.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/omens-team-shot.jpg"&gt;&lt;img id="i-25" alt="Image" src="http://paingrrl666.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/omens-team-shot.jpg?w=650"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second bout sees the ever-smiling Bad Omens up against the formidable Death Stars.  The Bad Omens have so far lost both bouts played, with the Death Stars winning both of theirs.  As is the case with roller derby though, anything can happen – and both of these teams will fight with equal fire for a space in the final!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://paingrrl666.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/death-stars-team-shot.jpg"&gt;&lt;img id="i-26" alt="Image" src="http://paingrrl666.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/death-stars-team-shot.jpg?w=630"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the outcome, you are guaranteed two fast-paced bouts with the skill and strategy that Glasgow Roller Derby never fails to deliver, with all the fun and frolics that are afforded by Home Teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come along and meet these 4 fantastic teams, featuring those vets you know and love, as well as the debut of some of GRD’s newest league members.  Buy merch! Buy cake! And buy your tickets in advance to avoid disappointment &lt;img alt=":)" src="http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif?m=1129645325g"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/content/home-teams-3-2013-31st-august"&gt;http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/content/home-teams-3-2013-31st-august&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(all pics by Dave McAleavy, boutday.com)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://paingrrl666.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/bad-omens-zoe.jpg"&gt;&lt;img id="i-31" alt="Image" src="http://paingrrl666.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/bad-omens-zoe.jpg?w=523"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bad omens</category><category>death stars</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>grd</category><category>hell's belles</category><category>home teams</category><category>tyrannosaurus wrecks</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/08/28/watch-glasgows-home-teams-fight-for-a-place-in-the-final/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 11:12:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow Roller Derby and Auld Reekie Roller Girls Go Global!</title><link>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/05/10/glasgow-roller-derby-and-auld-reekie-roller-girls-go-global/</link><dc:creator>paingrrl666</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/glasgow-team-shot2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-2582" alt="Image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/glasgow-team-shot2.jpg?w=487"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, ECDX is now less than 8 weeks away! How ready is the team?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; Cider (ARRG):&lt;/strong&gt;  We bout all year round, so we're always ready to play Roller Derby.  We just need to remember to pack party hats and sun block and we're there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rogue (GRD): &lt;/strong&gt; As ready as we’ve ever been, I reckon! It was important to us to plan and train far in advance for this event so we’ve been working very hard at playing as a solid unit for a while now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there any specific training that your team have been doing to prepare, eg extra scrimmage/off skates training/teambuilding?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Rogue (GRD): &lt;/strong&gt; Yes, everyone on the team has taken on some sort of off skates training. This has taken many forms. Some people are going to the gym, some do Cross-fit, running, strength training or even Parkour! This means that everyone has been making a huge commitment, as the team already train 3-4 times a week. It’s a lot of work and time for everyone. This team is dedicated!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crazy (ARRG): &lt;/strong&gt; Yes - lots of intense off skates, focus on team work and a lot of work on our technical skating skills lately -  we jumped at LRG's invite to go play at Anarchy in the UK III because we knew that would give us a couple of really challenging games and bring the team together just before ECDX.  And the lovely Hot Wheels invited us down for a bout the week afterwards, which was great in consolidating our team work a bit more. For the next few weeks we have booked in a lot visiting teams to scrimmage against us, so that we can do as much as we can to raise level of the ARRG teamwork dream work!  We also have an exciting scrimmage with Gotham, and a pre ECDX bout with another WFTDA league organised for when we get to the States to acclimatise us before ECDX starts. Bouting in New York AND Philly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/arrg11.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-2585" alt="Image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/arrg11.jpg?w=487"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the team/wider league doing to help with finances for this international opportunity?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rogue &lt;/strong&gt; (GRD): &lt;/strong&gt; The whole league, as well as our families and friends, have been amazing in helping us to raise funds for this. To try to list the ways that people have helped would be to miss something out. Fundraising efforts have been as diverse as bag-packing at a local supermarket;  a photo exhibition at a local café run by our own Phoenix; and a Grd Auction.  I’m grateful to everyone who has helped us and I hope we can make them proud.    Click here if you’d like to help out!  &lt;a href="http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/get-in-touch/donate"&gt;http://www.glasgowrollerderby.com/get-in-touch/donate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cider (ARRG): &lt;/strong&gt; So much! It's unreal -  I think everyone in the league has helped in some way which is a bit single teary for us as a team.  We feel really supported, and a bit overwhelmed by the sacrifices people have made for us.  Our limited edition merch, designed by Admiral Attackbar, has been a huge bonus because not only does it raise money for us, but it's also amazing quality.  We love the designs! You can buy them here:   &lt;a href="http://auldreekierollergirls.bigcartel.com/products"&gt;http://auldreekierollergirls.bigcartel.com/products&lt;/a&gt;.       Our Sponsorship and Advertising Committee have pulled off some brilliant and fun fundraising events for us this year too – like our huge 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; birthday party which will be happening this Saturday, which has lots of lovely surprises happening on the night. This will help us raise further travel funds.  You can find our more here:          &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/193068510841007/" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.facebook.com/events/193068510841007/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you know anything about the teams you’re up against?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; Crazy (ARRG):&lt;/strong&gt;  Of course! We did some fairly intensive research as soon as the sanctioned teams were announced by ECDX Organisers - it's frightening how organised our team was at online research or &lt;em&gt;creeping&lt;/em&gt; as we call it.  There was a 12 hour overnight 'ARRG mass creep' period where the whole team did this massive impressive feat of internet stalking and voting to suss out who we wanted to play!  We've been keeping an eye on both teams - Ithaca and Dominion - and where they are appearing in rankings; who they're playing and who they're beating; but I guess it's really only when we get there that we'll get a real sense of the level of play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rogue (GRD):&lt;/strong&gt;  Long island are ranked 93rd, and Columbia 39&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, in the WFTDA rankings but who knows what that means? Teams don’t tend to give much away and it’s hard to find recent footage online. However Columbia are playing against Charm City (17th) this weekend and I’ll be watching the results of that one very closely! I also know from being in touch with members of both teams that they will play hard and play to win, but that they are lovely people and I can’t wait to meet them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/grd-brrd1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-2586" alt="Image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/grd-brrd1.jpg?w=470"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you think the team will perform?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rogue&lt;/strong&gt; (GRD):&lt;/strong&gt; The team have all been reminded to pack our A game. We’ll be playing to win!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cider (ARRG):&lt;/strong&gt;  I think that we've been performing well lately as a team and consistently improving with each bout or tournament, so if we keep our focus I know we can perform well.  It just all depends on how well the other teams perform against us I guess.  We've trained hard and we'll go in with the usual 100% and see where that gets us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you most excited about?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crazy (ARRG):&lt;/strong&gt;How long have you got?! It's ECDX!!! Roller Derby in America! Food in Philly! Rocky steps! Team Sauna! And most exciting, is knowing the rest of ARRG will be watching and cheering for us. We want to make them all proud. Hopefully squeeze a bit of shopping in also...  And also, just to say it is such a great chance for two Scottish teams to represent themselves in the States … and if the Team Scotland after-party was anything to go by (from the World Cup) we should have fun doing it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rogue (GRD):&lt;/strong&gt;  Oh, so many things! I’m excited to get there and play with the team and see all of our hard work pay off. I’m excited about the opportunities that this could create for us. I’m excited about the future of GRD. I rarely stop being excited about roller derby!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/group-2-21.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-2588" alt="Image" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/group-2-21.jpg?w=487"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>arrg</category><category>articles</category><category>ecdx</category><category>grd</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/05/10/glasgow-roller-derby-and-auld-reekie-roller-girls-go-global/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 08:33:24 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>