<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts by scottishrollerderby)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/authors/scottishrollerderby.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:34:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Guest Post: Roller Derby — Bangkok Style!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/22/guest-post-roller-derby-bangkok-style/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In another guest post, we're bringing you a report on Bangkok Roller Derby's recent bout against Pan-Asian travel team, the Spring Rollers, by Mouth Almighty; Mouth recently moved to Bangkok (after being deeply involved in UK derby), and this was her first experience of the East-Asian implementation of the sport. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, 2 weeks ago I moved from the UK to Bangkok as part of a change of employment. As a former skater with Wolverhampton Honor Rollers and  a former director of UKRDA (United Kingdom Roller Derby Association) back in Britain, I was eager to see what Roller Derby in Bangkok had to offer. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As luck would have it, within my first week of moving to Thailand, Bangkok Roller Derby were hosting an event: "Monsoon Mayhem".&lt;br&gt; So, at 7pm on Saturday 17th of November, I had my very first taste of Roller Derby, Bangkok-style. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Most Roller Derby bouts or events in the UK tend to be set in the morning or mid afternoon, in a local leisure centre or school (or whatever venue a team can manage to find that is big enough to host a game and is willing to allow teams to actually skate).&lt;br&gt;Here, Bangkok Roller Derby have the luxury of an actual Roller Dome and an evening start time (I can see why, as it had been 34°C most of the day, with a huge rainstorm in the afternoon, so the humidity factor meant that it was still about 30 degrees at 7pm). &lt;br&gt;These factors put together surely helped bring what was very close to a capacity crowd to this event, something that I fear very few Roller Derby teams in the UK have the joy of seeing at their events. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:heading {"level":4} --&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby versus Pan-Asian Spring Rollers&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:heading --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27781} --&gt;

&lt;figure class="wp-block-image"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/11/bangkok-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-27781"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/gjsheehan"&gt;Gareth Sheehan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gameplay itself was fast paced and aggressive, not violent, simply aggressive, passionate gameplay. The  girls on track seemed to truly enjoy the fun, frantic pace of the game, as did the people watching it.&lt;br&gt;An injury early on in the first half bought to my attention that first aid here in Bangkok is not at the same level as bouts in the UK. (However, this was a friendly game). A single first-aider dealt with the injured player before she was eventually taken off the track in a wheelchair (temporary, I’m sure!) to rapturous applause from both players and spectators.&lt;br&gt;The game continued at a fast pace, with fast jams but with relatively low scoring from both teams; some heavy blocks and hits but thankfully no more injuries.&lt;br&gt;The second half continued at the same frantic pace, some very fast jammers up against some skilled blocking on both teams. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Noticeable differences between UK and Bangkok Roller Derby included less referees and NSOs (this may have been due to lack of volunteers perhaps &lt;em&gt;[something which affects Roller Derby everywhere - Ed])&lt;/em&gt; but as Bangkok Roller Derby grows, and as roller derby in Asia grows in general, this will surely stop being the case. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:image {"id":27782} --&gt;

&lt;figure class="wp-block-image"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/11/bangkok-2.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-27782"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/gjsheehan"&gt;Gareth Sheehan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:image --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Announcing was minimal, but with a team made up of English, American, Canadian, French &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Thai players, and with a truly multicultural audience watching, perhaps announcing would have simply been lost in translation... &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also no music playing during the game, something that as a follower of UK roller derby I have become used to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing Bangkok Roller Derby did that is not the norm in UK (although is becoming more common for the big tournaments) is half time entertainment: three inline skaters (one in a dinosaur costume) dancing and doing tricks, followed by throwing cuddly toys out into the crowd, which the audience loved. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; The game finished and it was evident that the players on track, the spectators and everyone involved had enjoyed a great evening of roller derby&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;!-- wp:separator --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator"&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:separator --&gt;
&lt;!-- wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bangkok Roller Derby can be found here: &lt;a href="https://bangkokrollerderby.weebly.com/"&gt;https://bangkokrollerderby.weebly.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Their opponents, the Pan-Asian Spring Rollers, are a travel team composed of members of Beijing Roller Derby, Shanghai Roller Derby, Hong Kong Roller Derby and Bangkok Roller Derby (but are open to other Asian teams). They can be found here: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Pan-Asian-Spring-Rollers-448887468791803/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/Pan-Asian-Spring-Rollers-448887468791803/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- /wp:paragraph --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bangkok roller derby</category><category>bout reports</category><category>guest posts</category><category>international derby</category><category>pan-asian spring rollers</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/11/22/guest-post-roller-derby-bangkok-style/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 14:04:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UK Coaching: Derby Form Check</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/05/uk-coaching-derby-form-check/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;One of the hot topics in Roller Derby, always, is Coaching. In recent times, since the Derby Stance Coaching Summit, we've seen even more collaboration and discussion in the area of UK Coaching - with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rulefiftysix.com"&gt;Rule56&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;'s Coaching Webinars a direct follow on from this. However, there's initiatives happening even in the furthest reaches of the UK's geography... as our guest writer, and founder of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/403911146657994/"&gt;Derby Form Check&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Ronie Walters (of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/OrkneyViqueens/"&gt;Orkney ViQueens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) explains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-18605" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/05/derbyformcheck.jpg?w=300" alt="DerbyFormCheck" width="300" height="210"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the great things about roller derby is the grassroots ethos. We all know the ethos: "by the skaters for the skaters". You don’t need to jump through a lot of hoops and regulations to set up a roller derby league, you can just have the idea and get going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly what we did in Orkney. Orkney is a small group of islands, off the North coast of Scotland. To get to us you need to get either a plane or a ferry. Obviously travelling to train with a local league is not really an option in this situation, so when we wanted to get started, we had to start from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roller Derby Community is lovely. Everyone is really supportive and I’ve made some great contacts whom I consider friends I’ve just not met yet, which has been awesome. But... it kind of feels like everyone is re-inventing the wheel.
Every single league I’ve encountered is using the WFTDA min-skills in some form as their standard for knowing when a skater is safe to play.
Every single league runs some form of “fresh meat” training program to get their skaters through those min skills.
Yet trying to find a training program to use as a template has been almost impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went to join the UKRDA to use that as a resource, yet, at present, you have to have been skating for 6 months as a team to be eligible to join – leaving you alone to muddle through until that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were lucky enough to manage to get a couple of people to do the BRSF [British Roller Sports Federation] level 2 coaching course recently in Luton (from what I can gather, it’s not been run for a while) so that was amazing for us, and we learnt a lot from it in terms of coaching cues and coaching skills. We also attended the Rule 56 online coaching pilot, and are excited for the next sessions coming up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule 56, like us, are looking for more joined up approaches to Roller Derby Coaching. They also believe we have some incredibly awesome coaches and skaters amongst us, we just need a more effective way to share them. The more we can share resources and skills, the faster we can progress as a sport, and the better the experience for those coming into the sport as new skaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be nice if, one day, new leagues starting in the UK could simply go to one place, and find all the information they needed.
This could be something as simple as UKRDA offering an associate membership so leagues can have access to the resources they need for that six month waiting period. This could then offer things like policies and constitutions, a clearly laid out min skills program, information on how to test a min skill and tell if your skater has mastered it, a resource for learning how to coach effectively, and access to a library of videos of real skaters complete with feedback on where they can improve, as well as video of ideal form to know what you are looking to get your skaters to.
The latter part of this has taken a step forward recently, with the introduction of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCoWo7DaL7OZGmG6gijWd7SQ"&gt;WFTDA Ed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; min skills videos. For the first time, there is some standardised indication of what a skill should look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, how do you get from where you are now, to that perfect form? Something I read recently in PEAK, when it was being discussed in the roller derby book club, was the notion of deliberate practice. Peak posits that there is no such thing as people with innate talent or ability. Even the likes of Beethoven or Tiger Woods are great because they have put in a lot of practice.
But this is not just about spending time; it’s about deliberate practice. Taking a skill and breaking it down into its elements, then practicing the elements making use of effective feedback to help you master the different parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a new club, we are learning together. We have some skilled skaters, but no-one with roller derby experience, or with experience in how to observe a skater and break the skill down for them with feedback to allow them to practice the elements and build it back up. It occurred to me that if we as a wider roller derby community could share video footage of us skating, we could all benefit from the feedback experienced skaters could provide. We are all individual, and we all learn differently. Sometimes the way someone explains something just clicks for you and, all of a sudden, you master that tricky bit you have been stuck on for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roller Derby Form Check&lt;/em&gt; aims to provide this opportunity. As a new Facebook group, it only has a few videos at present, but with over 370 members, it has the potential to be a very powerful resource. The hope is that gradually people will start to post a video of themselves doing a skill they are struggling with. So rather than a written post of how you're struggling with your 27/5 or you just can’t get transitions but don’t know why, you can film yourself. You will then get personalised feedback, rather than generic answers, or written descriptions which can be hard to visualise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our dream for the group is that over time we build a library of people demonstrating common issues with the minimum skills, with a whole range of ways of explaining how they can work to improve from different people.
Some of those explanations will hopefully also come with a video of them demonstrating the techniques they are suggesting. Using this, coupled with the “perfect” examples from WFTDA Ed, will really allow for some really powerful coaching resources to develop. We can already see that coaches are finding it helpful to learn additional ways to explain things and break skills down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you are stuck on a skill you just can’t seem to master, no matter how often your coach explains it, post a video. Maybe someone else’s tips will help you. If you are a coach and you have one skater that you just can’t figure out how to help, ask them if they are OK with posting a video and see if other people’s explanations can help them break through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Derby Form Check is a (closed) Facebook Group, open for registration: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/403911146657994/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/groups/403911146657994/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coaching</category><category>orkney viqueens</category><category>rule56</category><category>video</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/05/05/uk-coaching-derby-form-check/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 09:36:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Creative Commons and For the Skater, By The Skater</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/26/creative-commons-and-for-the-skater-by-the-skater/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the release of WFTDA's new bout stats management / collection project, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/WFTDA/bouttime"&gt;bouttime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (or BoutTime) as "Open Source", we wrote an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/10/19/bouttime-open-source-what-is-it-and-why-is-it-relevant-to-roller-derby-and-wftda/"&gt;Explainer (linked)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to let the less technical members of the derby community in on why this was exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the points we made was the "Open Source" is essentially the tech world's equivalent of "For the Skater, By the Skater": it's an encapsulation of the community spirit that says we should all collaborate and share to make things better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, far from being a property unique to Roller Derby, this community spirit lives on in many groups. The creative arts community, for example, has a concept and movement called "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/"&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;", formed from the concept that modern restrictive copyright is actively against the spirit of collaboration and improvement of works by the community. Such bodies as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wikipedia.org"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/"&gt;TED Talks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://ocw.mit.edu/"&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brooklynmuseum.org/"&gt;Brooklyn Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (as well as many more: including this very blog) release some or all of their works under Creative Commons. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/"&gt;Flikr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/"&gt;SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and many other content hosts, also recognise Creative Commons, and support their users in adopting these licenses if they wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creative Commons understands that, however, the amount of "sharing" you might want to do can vary, for entirely legitimate reasons. So, if you put something into the Creative Commons, you get to choose from a palette of options concerning what rights you want to give to the world, and which you want to limit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic level of Creative Commons* is &lt;strong&gt;Attribution&lt;/strong&gt; (CC:BY):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Releasing as CC:BY means that you're giving everyone the right to do anything with your work at all (including using bits of it for their own work), &lt;em&gt;as long as they give you credit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
CC:BY is nice, but it lets people make things with your stuff which is not in the Creative Commons itself. You might morally object to this (since the point of Creative Commons is to enrich the community), in which case you want to add the &lt;strong&gt;Share-Alike&lt;/strong&gt; (SA) property:
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Adding SA to your Creative Commons license means that anything that anyone else makes using your work must &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; be released under the same Creative Commons terms.&lt;/p&gt;
You might also have a moral (or legal) objection to people making money off of your work, or things using your work. (For example, American 501c3 non-profits, like WFTDA, can't allow people to use their work for profit.) In this case, you want to add the &lt;strong&gt;Non-Commercial&lt;/strong&gt; (NC) property:
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Adding NC to your Creative Commons license means that anything anyone else does with your work &lt;em&gt;cannot be sold&lt;/em&gt; or used for commercial gain. [Donations etc are of course acceptable]&lt;/p&gt;
Finally, there are some kinds of work which (for practical or moral reasons) that you might want to let people copy and redistribute... but not make anything different out of. (This is generally the most controversial kind of CC limitation, given that Creative Commons wants to enrich the creative community, but it can make sense for, say authoritative rules sets or specifications.) This is what you want the &lt;strong&gt;No-Derivatives&lt;/strong&gt; (ND) property for:
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Adding ND to your Creative Commons license means that all people can do with it is to share it freely (via making copies, printing them out, email, or whatever). [If you don't specify NC as well, they're also allowed to &lt;em&gt;sell&lt;/em&gt; copies, of course.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We at the Scottish Roller Derby Blog believe that the Creative Commons is fundamentally compatible with the core spirit of Roller Derby (as expressed as "For the Skater, By the Skater"), in a way which traditional copyright is not.
Given that WFTDA seems to be realising that the "open sharing" community is a reflection of the same spirit, we'd like to see the organisation take this additional step of applying appropriate Creative Commons licenses to their non-software work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, the "&lt;em&gt;Rules of Flat Track Roller Derby&lt;/em&gt;" are currently explicitly Copyrighted (the license on the website reads: "©2014 Women’s Flat Track Derby Association (WFTDA). The Rules of Flat Track Roller Derby may not be reproduced or translated in whole or in part in any manner without the permission of the WFTDA."). Technically, this means that anyone at all (especially non-WFTDA leagues) who even &lt;em&gt;prints out&lt;/em&gt; a copy of the WFTDA rules (or &lt;em&gt;makes a copy&lt;/em&gt; of the PDF) is potentially breaking the law. (We're also vexed by the explicit translation restriction, as we're aware of unofficial translations to many languages which WFTDA has not officially addressed, and all of these are also potentially forbidden under the current license; although of course we understand WFTDA's concern about the accuracy of translation in complex rules sets.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that, given that a huge community of Roller Derby, outside the set of WFTDA member leagues, use the WFTDA rules, that this kind of heavy-handed Copyright is both unwarranted and unneeded.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Given the options available for Creative Commons licenses, we believe that the true spirit of Roller Derby would be better reflected by releasing the next version of "The Rules of Flat Track Roller Derby" (due in December this year) under a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/"&gt;CC:BY-NC-ND&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; license. This would, unlike conventional Copyright, allow the free sharing of the Rules across the entire community. It would prevent anyone from profiting from doing so, and would prevent anyone from releasing modified copies. (This would also prevent translation of the Rules, but we believe that WFTDA can address that by directly inviting potential translators to engage with them, which we believe is something in progress at the moment.)&lt;/p&gt;
The second aspect where we think that WFTDA might work to improve their use of modern collaborative community spirit is in the reuse and support of common repositories for statistics. Historically, the WFTDA has maintained its own "silo" of statistics for Sanctioned Games, hosted in the WFTDA Stats Repository. Whilst we understand that part of the draw for WFTDA membership is the "official" Sanctioning of games, we don't see how this warrants siloing off their statistics into a separate location.
The FlatTrackStats website has been maintaining Roller Derby statistics for the &lt;em&gt;entire&lt;/em&gt; Flat Track Roller Derby community, for longer (we believe) than WFTDA has had a Stats Repository. (FTS dates from &lt;em&gt;2008&lt;/em&gt;, whereas the Stats Repository copyright is from &lt;em&gt;2012&lt;/em&gt;). In addition, FlatTrackStats is already a member of the Creative Commons community - the entire website, and all of the statistics collected within, are licensed &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/"&gt;CC:BY-NC-SA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;p style="padding-left:30px;"&gt;Given that the community benefits from the sharing of resources (rather than their splintering apart), and given the existence of a prior community resource suitable for the purpose: we believe that the true spirit of Roller Derby would be better reflected by WFTDA working directly with FlatTrackStats to act as a host for the WFTDA Stats Repository, and that the Stats Repository should therefore be licensed under the same &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/"&gt;CC:BY-NC-SA&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Strictly, there's also CC0 "Creative Commons Zero", which doesn't even have &lt;em&gt;Attribution&lt;/em&gt; attached to it, but this actually has less effect than you might think, as many countries have laws which &lt;em&gt;prevent&lt;/em&gt; you from waiving your right to Attribution! So, effectively, CC0 acts a lot like CC:BY, in most Western countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/" rel="license"&gt;&lt;img style="border-width:0;" src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png" alt="Creative Commons License"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
This work is licensed under a &lt;a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/" rel="license"&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;, because anything else would be hypocritical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>by the skater</category><category>creative commons</category><category>for the skater</category><category>international derby</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/10/26/creative-commons-and-for-the-skater-by-the-skater/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 08:39:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Auld Reekie Roller Girls All Star Reserves Vs Cambridge Rollerbillies</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/02/17/auld-reekie-roller-girls-all-star-reserves-vs-cambridge-rollerbillies/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/arrg-cambridge.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-4576" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2015/02/arrg-cambridge.jpg" alt="Image courtesy of Auld Reekie Roller Girls." width="614" height="227"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Auld Reekie Roller Girls.
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://arrg.co.uk/"&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/a&gt;, All Star Reserves take on &lt;a href="http://rollerbillies.com/"&gt;Cambridge Rollerbillies&lt;/a&gt; in their second game of the year. Having beat Oxford in the first match of he new season, the All Star Reserves will be keen to make it an Oxbridge double victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks set to be an interesting match, Cambridge are a strong team, turning in nine victories out of twelve games last year...and six out of nine in the 2013 season. Last season they lost only to LRG, Plymouth and a narrow 4 point nailbiter against Belfast. Cambridge were also finalists in the 2013 Heartland Series and winners of the 2014 Series, and are ranked 32nd in Europe, as opposed to the All Stars ranked at 61st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ARRG All Star Reserves had a loss heavy season in 2014, winning only two games out of seven. They did play an extremely international season, against a broad selection of European teams, and produced impressive wins over Newcastle and Crime City.
&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/59567/rankings"&gt;Flat Track Stats&lt;/a&gt; predicts a strong win for Cambridge with a 31:23 score ratio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bout takes place at Meadowbank Sports Centre, Saturday 28th February, &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/1220016"&gt;tickets&lt;/a&gt; are available in advance and more information can be found on the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/749991648420675/?ref_dashboard_filter=upcoming&amp;amp;unit_ref=popular_with_friends"&gt;Facebook Event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>all star reserves</category><category>arrg</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2015/02/17/auld-reekie-roller-girls-all-star-reserves-vs-cambridge-rollerbillies/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 04:07:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Glasgow Roller Derby: Home Season Final 2014</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/19/glasgow-roller-derby-home-season-final-2014/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/11/grd-htf.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/11/grd-htf.jpg" alt="Image courtesy of Glasgow Roller Derby" width="614" height="230" class="size-full wp-image-4215"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image courtesy of Glasgow Roller Derby
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 22nd of November, &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/"&gt;Glasgow Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; will host their fifth Home Season final. The two teams competing for first position this time around are the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/GRD-Bad-Omens/364804600294675?fref=ts"&gt;Bad Omens&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/GRD-Death-Stars/139266509578582?fref=ts"&gt;Death Stars&lt;/a&gt;. The Bad Omens have an unbeaten record so far this season, including a win over the Death Stars, which should make for an interesting battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event takes place at The Arc Sports Centre. Doors open at 12;30pm for a 1pm start. &lt;a href="http://glasgowrollerderby.com/catalog/tickets"&gt;Tickets&lt;/a&gt; are £5 in advance or £7 on the door, under 14's free with paying adult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep an eye on the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/808918889137444/"&gt;Facebook Event page&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>bad omens</category><category>death stars</category><category>glasgow roller derby</category><category>home season tournament</category><category>home teams</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/11/19/glasgow-roller-derby-home-season-final-2014/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 02:13:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interviews: South America</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/13/world-cup-interviews-south-america/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last week, our &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt;  tour covered the South American nations taking part in the upcoming competition.
If you missed any of them, here's a recap...
&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/07/world-cup-interview-team-brasil/"&gt;Team Brasil&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/08/world-cup-interview-team-columbia/"&gt;Team Colombia&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/09/world-cup-interview-team-argentina/"&gt;Team Argentina&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/10/world-cup-interview-team-chile/"&gt;Team Chile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week we jump back over the Atlantic to cover the UK nations taking part.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team argentina</category><category>team brasil</category><category>team chile</category><category>team colombia</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/13/world-cup-interviews-south-america/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 11:40:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Chile</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/10/world-cup-interview-team-chile/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We bring our coverage of the South American nations taking part in the &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; to an end, with &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TeamChileRollerDerby?fref=ts"&gt;Team Chile&lt;/a&gt;. Like Colombia, Chile are entering the competition for the first time.
We talked to team spokesperson Endorfina, Metropolitan Roller Derby and Team Chile skater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/logo-team-chile.png"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3834" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/logo-team-chile.png" alt="Team Chile Logo design by Tali and Chela Navaja" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Team Chile Logo design by Tali and Chela Navaja&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are the team preparing for the the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided late to go to the World Cup, so the preparation started in May of this year after doing tryouts to select the skaters with the best level in our country. Just one skater, from Canada, lives abroad, the rest are skaters from leagues in Chile (Metropolitan Roller Derby, Complot Derby Club and Chillanrolleras).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Chile has been promoted mainly by the league Metropolitan Roller Derby and Team Chile is using their training facilities, hours and coaches to prepare the national selection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the lack of funds does not allow us to have warm up bouts with nearby countries (such as Argentina) and we are only scrimmaging with the rest of Chilean players twice a month. The rest is mainly theory and practice developed by the Team Chile coach, Nino Rodríguez.(Speed Knight)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dallas is a long way away, how have the team been raising funds to get there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To date, we do not have any sponsors. We are having meetings and contact with some derby brands and other brands in our country. Chile is young in roller derby, very few people know us or have seen us play, so we think that is one of the reasons why maybe we are no so attractive to brands. Derby is also little known in Chile beyond the usual “girls who hit each other in skates”, but we are working to change that vision to a sport way of seeing us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, participating in the world cup has been mainly a personal endeavor of the skaters. We are asking for credits in banks, and taking donations from friends or family. At this point, every skater and coach is paying for their own travel, accommodation, and all other expenses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we also are motivating people to collaborate. For example we started a gofundme project where people from abroad Chile can donate. &lt;a href="http://www.gofundme.com/Chile-Roller-Derby"&gt;http://www.gofundme.com/Chile-Roller-Derby&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This will be the first time Chile has taken part in the World Cup, What are the Teams aims going into the competition?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main aim is to live the experience of playing at a high level. We believe that going to the World Cup is going give the skaters participating in it a lot of tools that we can share with our leagues here in Chile. We also wanna show that we have real derby here, that we are good skaters and that we can be an interesting county to visit and play with, we want to promote more visits of skaters from other countries, teams, referees, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a roller derby scene in Chile and we want it to be known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you give us an idea of how big that Roller Derby scene is?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first league, Metropolitan Roller Derby, has been running a little over three years. It is a league resident in Santiago, the capitol of Chile, and is the first of many now growing all over the country. We know of about 16 leagues, but every month in a different city there is interest to form a team. Today we have a lot of inter-league collaboration, we do things together among the leagues, we share tips at training, gather to scrimmage, among other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do think the team competing in Dallas will do for Roller Derby in Chile?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We totally think it will increase the competitiveness of roller derby in Chile. Today, leagues with A-level skaters, like Metropolitan and Complot have to get out of the country to play. We hope that living this experience in the World Cup will help increase the interest not only in people interested in skating, but also will help leagues and derby in Chile to get more sponsors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We actually look at this participation with a lot of hope, we know there is not much expected from us, but we have something to show and we believe we are going to display good derby and good skating in Dallas. People are now starting to consider Chile in the derby scene and we are proud to be the reason why that is happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Team Chile roster is..
Annimal -Chillanrolleras Derby Club
Killer Cat -Chillanrolleras Derby Club
Pink Cat -Complot Derby Club
La Chilenita -Complot Derby Club
Pequeña Maravilla -Complot Derby Club
Chela Navaja -Metropolitan Roller Derby
Endorfina -Metropolitan Roller Derby
Teluri-K -Metropolitan Roller Derby
Estigia -Metropolitan Roller Derby
Rapaz -Metropolitan Roller Derby
Chica Ye-yé -Metropolitan Roller Derby
Verotika Fearless -Metropolitan Roller Derby
Dulce BooP -Metropolitan Roller Derby
Madame Peligro -Metropolitan Roller Derby
Zatanna -Metropolitan Roller Derby
Tali -Metropolitan Roller Derby
Bunny Kill -Metropolitan Roller Derby
Mamasita Muerte -Calgary Roller Derby&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coaches.
Negro P-Metropolitan Roller Derby
Speed Knight-Metropolitan Roller Derby&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team chile</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/10/world-cup-interview-team-chile/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 09:24:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Argentina</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/09/world-cup-interview-team-argentina/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next up from among the four South American teams taking part in the &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Roller-Derby-Argentina/460486460649633?ref=profile"&gt;Team Argentina&lt;/a&gt;. Like Brasil, Argentina are returning to the competition, after placing 13th in Toronto in 2011.
We talked to Head Coach of Team Argentina, Martin Blousson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/logo-alta-color.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3946" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/logo-alta-color.jpg" alt="Team Argentina logo by  Leonel Yamil Escobar" width="614" height="578"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Team Argentina logo by Leonel Yamil Escobar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you tell us how your team selection process worked, for both skaters and coaching staff?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was invited to be coach of the team last november. The team was facing a new try out to start a new period and then I worked along on the selection process with five other players from the most important teams/leagues in the country.
The try out involved the participation of more than fifty players, some of them sent videos from outside Argentina, and some of them traveled to Buenos Aires from different cities of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are the team preparing for the the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays we're training two days a week. From the roster selected to play in Dallas we only have Sargentina away from us, but she visited us two months ago and we had the time to share some derby time with her.
If everything goes well we'll have a couple of bouts in the US on the previous days to the world cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dallas is a long way away, how have the team been raising funds to get there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been working all this year to collect enough money to cover all the hotel and food expenses during our days in Dallas. Each player has to pay for her own ticket, which is a huge cost for all of us, some of them are even taking two jobs to get enough money for that trip.
We've done some bootcamps for local players, we have some merchandise on sale at almost every derby event; we also have been doing some crowdfunding. (We still have this one going: &lt;a href="http://www.gofundme.com/cfuaqg"&gt;http://www.gofundme.com/cfuaqg&lt;/a&gt;
We've received a lot of help of all the derby leagues and teams in Argentina, the people here have been most supportive with the team.
We've also got the help of some sponsors. Atomatrix has helped us a lot through NistevoUSA.com, the local Traful On Ice, Traveling Skates, Magma Pro, and also Sisu and Derbyskinz from outside the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the time of the last World Cup, Roller Derby was only just beginning to be established in Argentina. How does that compare with now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experience of the national team in that world cup was of a great importance for the whole local derby, for all that learning expanded to all the teams through time. Roller Derby is still working hard to build it's own place in the country. In most of the cities we're still dealing with the problems of finding where to train properly, for example. But the level has increase considerably, most of the teams have been growing a lot and trying to improve the organization of the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Having entered the 2011 World Cup as an unknown, what are Team Argentina's aims going into this year's competition?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will win bouts, we will fight for a place in the podium. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team argentina</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/09/world-cup-interview-team-argentina/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 08:12:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Colombia</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/08/world-cup-interview-team-columbia/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Working our way around the South American teams taking part in the &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Blood &amp;amp; Thunder Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/a&gt; we come to &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/colombiarollerderby?ref=profile"&gt;Team Colombia&lt;/a&gt;. Along with Chile, Colombia are entering the competition as newcomers, the two new 'dark horses' of Roller Derby in South America.
We talked to Team Colombia Head Coach, Cesar Cuervo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/photo-28.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/10/photo-28.jpg" alt="Team Columbia logo by Yuya Mancilla  and Maria Paola Hernandez" width="614" height="621" class="size-full wp-image-3944"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Team Columbia logo by Yuya Mancilla  and Maria Paola Hernandez&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are the team preparing for the the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team has been together since a few months ago, we have practices twice a month in Bogota the capital…The girls have practices 3 or 4 times per week with their own home teams.
We have a few bouts planned but not enough, because there is not too many teams with the level that we are expecting to see in Dallas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dallas is a long way away, how have the team been raising funds to get there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are working very hard trying to raise funds for our team, we have designed and produced a few products like  shirts, stickers, etc. Also organize events to raise some funds, and we have two sponsors : ATOM and MATCH RACE .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This will be the first time Colombia has taken part in the World Cup, What are the Teams aims going into the competition?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like you said, this is our first World Cup and we are really excited to be part of such an event and meet the best teams around the world, we have a lot to learn and then share with all the roller derby people in Colombia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you give us an idea of how big Roller Derby is in Colombia?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roller derby started in Colombia in 2009 with Rock and Roller Queens in Bogota and has been growing since then, today we have 17 teams from all around the country. They are in different cities, just in Bogota we have 7 teams.
So the Roller derby is getting more and more fans and this is because the tournaments and all the enthusiasm of our people involved in the sport.
During the last years we organized the Roller Derby Nationals with the participation of teams from the main cities: Bogota, Medellin, Pereira, Bucaramanga, Manizales, Cali, Palmira, Armenia And Ibague.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do think the team competing in Dallas will do for Roller Derby in Colombia?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participation in World Cup is the chance to see the best teams in action and learn from them many things that we can share with all the roller derby people in Colombia and this will be great to get the level that we are looking for. Also this is the chance to see how we are doing and what we have to do to be a better Team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Team Colombia roster..
Rathalia-001
MoonSun-2
Lucky Ale-03
Jackota-06
Fer Mortishian-007
Karma-13
Peli-Grosa-16
Nuza-25
Maraña Pony-29
Yayita Plop-83
Lilith-90
Tsunami…-92
Guillotina Pagana-100%
Minerva-296
Mapi-333
Kitsch Mutante-404
Gatho-666
Colors-828
Collete Funk-911
Splatter-986&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head Coach: Cesar Cuervo ( MATADOR)     &lt;br&gt;
Bench coach: Valentina Restrepo
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team colombia</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/08/world-cup-interview-team-columbia/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 09:06:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Brasil</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/07/world-cup-interview-team-brasil/</link><dc:creator>scottishrollerderby</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving around the globe from Europe to South America, the next team taking part in the &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Blood And Thunder World Cup&lt;/a&gt; to be interviewed, is &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/rollerderbybrasil/timeline"&gt;Team Brasil&lt;/a&gt;. The team are returnees to the competition, having placed 12th in Toronto back in 2011.
We interviewed Lara Raineri on behalf of Team Brasil. Lara is a skater with the São Paulo league, Gray City Rebels, and handles PR and coaching duties for the national team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/tb-logo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3785" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/tb-logo.jpg" alt="Team Brasil logo art and design: Fernanda Correa" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Team Brasil logo art and design: Fernanda Correa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are the team preparing for the World Cup?...have you played an warm up bouts?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are training once a month. Players are traveling to the practice, most of the team is from São Paulo, so we get together there. Yes, we already did 6 games only this year.( Team Brasil have been playing mainly composite/exhibition teams every few weeks since January)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dallas is a long way away, how have the team been raising funds to get there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We receive donations from all over the world here: &lt;a href="http://www.gofundme.com/6rmfco"&gt;http://www.gofundme.com/6rmfco&lt;/a&gt;. We are making merchandise, raffles and these kinds of things to help, &lt;span class="_5yl5"&gt;&lt;span class="null"&gt;but each player will have to contribute to their costs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. We have Atom Wheels(as a sponsor)and we are searching and trying others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlike almost all other skaters in the world,the skaters from Brasil don't tend to use skater names when they represent their country,(although there is a growing trend towards legal names) Why does Brasil differ in this respect?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It´s a tradition that Brasilian players use the first name, or nickname in their career, especially in soccer, so we decided to maintain the tradition. It´s a truly Brasilian thing... it´s rare to call someone by their last name, but it´s really normal to give nicknames to someone. Also, when we are playing we call each other by the nicknames or first names, so it´s easier for us to communicate like that, they are short, strong and we are 100% sure that "OH! THAT´S ME!".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back in 2011, Roller Derby already seemed fairly well established in Brasil, what effect did the Team competing in the first World Cup have?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, it wasn´t. We picked only players that could stand in skates in Brasil and could pay for the ticket. Most of the team played for the first time at the world cup. After the first world cup the sport grew a lot here and more girls started doing it and devoting more time to derby.&lt;span class="_5yl5"&gt;&lt;span class="null"&gt;We gained a LOT of experience in the transition from what Derby in Brasil was like before the World Cup and after the World Cup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, because we understand the sport and saw how beautiful it is all over the world, so they came back home with fresh energy to make it better here.
In 2011 we had 5 leagues, and maybe 50 players in Brasil, now we have 25 all over the country and something like 600 players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the experience of competing in the 2011 World Cup shaped the team this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we came back from the world cup in 2011, we started to wait for the next one.
All the experience and learning was shared with the others players in Brasil made us wait for this moment. At the first game in 2011 we had no idea what we were doing, where we were and the size of everything. By the last game in 2011, we made Scotland work hard, and we wanted to come back home, to start working here as soon as possible.
We have waited for this for a long time, we want to show everybody how much we learned and that we are not the underdogs anymore. GET READY!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Team Brasil roster..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;107 Andrea Carlsson-Gray City Rebels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1972 Amira Dutra Mello- Bleeding Heartland Rollergirls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;13 Bá Lisboa-Ladies of Hell Town&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;33 Camila Stocco-Maui Roller Girls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is9 Chu – Chiara Abreu-Wheel of Fire Roller Derby&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;80 Fernanda Ezabella-Los Angeles Derby Dolls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;16 Fernanda Correa-Philly Roller Girls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;87 Gilda Guimarães-Gray City Rebels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;55 Julia Magalhaes Beirao-Ladies of Hell Town&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;181 Lara Raineri (COACH)-Gray City Rebels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;16t Manu Vasconcelos-Ladies of Hell Town&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;86 Mariana Leal-Gray City Rebels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1949 Mariana Teixeira-Gray City Rebels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;72 Patricia Correia-Rio Riot Roller Derby&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;505 Paula Mitie-Ladies of Hell Town&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;20 Roxane Velozo-Boston Derby Dames&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;208 Shyrlei Braith-Ladies of Hell Town&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;23 Tati Goes-Gray City Rebels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;07 Bianca&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2014 blood &amp; thunder roller derby world cup</category><category>an interview with...</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team brasil</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/10/07/world-cup-interview-team-brasil/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 08:13:53 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>