<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts by SRD)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/authors/srd.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:07:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Roller Derby comes to Kyoto! ローラーダービーが京都に来る。</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/12/roller-derby-comes-to-kyoto-roradabigajing-du-nilai-ru/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here at SRD, we always like to see Roller Derby expanding into new places; especially places where there's been no roller derby before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst Roller Derby has been in Japan (in Okinawa and Tokyo, and, until this year, Misawa), there's been little growth outside of those regions. (Tokyo Roller Derby have expanded to contain teams based in the surrounding cities, such as Yokohama, but not outside the Kantō region; the most recent independent team, Kamikaze Badass, is also based in Tokyo.) So, it was particularly exciting to see the announcement this year of a new league, based in Kyōto, in the Kansai region!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught up with Kyoto Roller Derby's founders, Kat and Josie, to find out a bit more about them, and what inspired them to seed more roller derby in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-26824 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/kyotord.jpg" alt="KyotoRD" width="621" height="480"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's been a while since the last Roller Derby league was founded in Japan. Can you tell us a bit about yourselves as founders? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Kat: I skated with Bath Roller Derby Girls in the U.K. and I absolutely loved it! The team was in its early stages back then and it was so nice to be a part of something at the ground level. After moving to Japan and being really far away from any teams here, I kept writing messages of desperation on Facebook forums hoping to pique some interest. Eventually someone replied! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Josie: That would be me! I had been living in Japan for two years, teaching English and loving life up in the mountains, but every day I was still pining for the outlet that is derby. I messaged Kat having seen a plea of hers, and was thrilled to meet another skater out here. At the time we lived a few hours apart, so it wasn’t easy to meet up. But quickly we realised that a derby team was needed in the Kansai area. I began skating first at drop-in sessions with Bristol back in 2012, then for Severn Roller Torrent in Gloucester. I skated with SRT for two years, before moving to Japan in 2015. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;The moment we met we couldn’t help reminiscing about all the things that derby meant to us. It’s such an important space and community that we felt could really bring a lot to Kyoto. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All but two Roller Derby leagues in Japan were founded by non-Japanese skaters; how are you reaching out to the people of Kyoto to grow the league? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Josie: We’ve been fortunate enough to work with and become friends with some amazing people out here, and we are really keen for all of our practices, future events and bouts to be a community thing. We are committed to using Japanese and English in all of our communications on social media and really strive to be as inclusive as possible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Kat: This is definitely really important to both of us, and we want to encourage as many new Japanese members to join us as possible. I recently watched the animation Aggretsuko, and couldn’t ignore the parallels between that and derby as a form of stress release. The show is about an awesome red panda who works in a sh&lt;em&gt;tty office, full of sh&lt;/em&gt;tty male bosses who talk down to her all day, and although she is sweet during working hours, at night she blasts out thrash metal karaoke to release her stress. I basically feel like derby could be this for so many of my friends! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kamikaze Badass Roller Derby Tokyo found that one issue they've had is with the conflation of Roller Game and Roller Derby in the minds of potential recruits. In the short time you've been in existence, have you identified any specific issues to deal with?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Often staff at venues have a negative view of it and think it’s going to be too dangerous, because of the associations with Roller Game.  Also a lot of younger people see roller skating as very dated, and don’t consider it as a sport for the modern age. We’ve reached out to a lot of leagues for help and guidance on this type of thing, as we are aiming to be as transparent and respectful as possible, whilst also smashing any preconceptions, as respectfully as possible of course.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting a league off the ground also needs resources as well as people power. How can the Community help Kyoto Roller Derby - and how are you planning to grow your resources? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We’ve actually just announced our first fundraiser at our local Japanese-run burrito joint, where we’ll be selling baked goods and our first official merch &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;[&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/162229187965089/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;see here for this event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;. Ideally we hope to hold a number of fundraisers throughout the year in order to spread the word and purchase essential kit for our fresh meat team. We’ve also been in touch with the wonderful Derby Without Borders &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;[&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/05/derby-without-borders-an-interview-with-founder-mae-dae/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;see our interview here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; who provide second hand kits for up and coming leagues across the globe, and that was after a tip from you, and from another within the Tokyo derby community. Worldwide derby spirit is definitely already pushing us in the right direction and we are so grateful, so we hope that as many people as possible will want to help us get going. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where do you see Kyoto Roller Derby in the future? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;We want to see Kyoto Roller Derby as an active league in Japan, visiting teams around the country as well as worldwide! We want to have a really positive influence within the local community, with as many people as possible coming to watch our games, and feeling encouraged and empowered to get involved. Roller derby has had such an incredible impact on both of our lives and we can’t wait to watch it grow in Kyoto.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about Kyoto Roller Derby, and support them, on their social media platforms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/kyotorollerderbyjapan"&gt;www.facebook.com/kyotorollerderbyjapan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;Instagram: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.instagram.com/kyotorollerderbyjapan"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;www.instagram.com/kyotorollerderby&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;You can also email them at:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; &lt;a href="mailto:kyotorollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;kyotorollerderby@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt;And support them via GoFundMe here:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:400;"&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.gofundme.com/kyotorollerderby"&gt;www.gofundme.com/kyotorollerderby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>fundraising events</category><category>international</category><category>international derby</category><category>interviews</category><category>japan</category><category>kyoto roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/12/roller-derby-comes-to-kyoto-roradabigajing-du-nilai-ru/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 18:39:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Tomodachi Cup: Team Women's Roller Derby Japan [トモダチダービートーナメント:チームWRDJ]</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/09/the-tomodachi-cup-team-womens-roller-derby-japan-tomodachidabitonamentochi/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1785628121710300/"&gt;Tomodachi Derby Tournament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; approaches, we're interviewing another team - the last team in the non-Sanctioned tier of the tournament. This article will be in both Japanese and English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-full wp-image-14030 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/01/teamwrdj-sm.jpg" alt="teamwrdj-sm" width="250" height="154"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/WRDJapan/"&gt;Women's Roller Derby Japan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [Team WRDJ] is a mixed subscription team, which was open to anyone applying to join. It was organised by Women's Roller Derby Japan, the body which organises the Japanese Women's National Team. チームウィメンズローラーダービージャパン[チームWRDJは]への参加を適用する誰にでも開かれていた混成チーム、です。 これは、日本女子代表チームを組織しているウィメンズローラーダービージャパンが主催したものです。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its roster consists of:
名簿には次のものが含まれます：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From (Tokyo Roller Girls Home Team): Neon Roller Monsters (Yokohama)
[横浜のローラーダービーチーム から]
・Thunder BELL #950
・Where's The Fire #75
・Inga Knee'her #235
・Rice Rocket #278
・Savage Dragon #5360
・Lisa Slamtimes #413
From Tokyo Three Rollers (Tokyo)
[東京のローラーダービー・チーム Tokyo3Rollersから]
・Red Eye #88
From Kokeshi Roller Dolls (Okinawa)
[沖縄のコケシローラードルスから]
・Loveless #0
・Lil N. Gin #9
・Lemmy Killmisstress #1975
・PurpleHaze #21
・Atomic Jenny #88
From Devil Dog Derby Dames (Okinawa)
[沖縄のデヴィゥドグダービダメスから]
・Madam Vice #7
・Christine Westbrook
・Mermaid Mayhem #20
From Echo City Knockouts (Hawaii)
[ハワイのエコシチノクアウツから]
・Bandit Angel #18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Captain Thunder BELL was good enough to answer questions for us.　チームキャプテンThunder BELLが私たちの質問に答えて&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="popup" title="くれる - to give"&gt;くれた。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did the idea for Team WRDJ occur? (チームWRDJのアイデアはどうやって起こったのですか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tomodachi Tournament originally had only a method to participate with full teams, and we felt this was a little sad. We looked for a good way to allow the opportunity for domestic skaters who can't join as their team, or players from foreign countries who are visiting without their team, to participate. We hit on the idea of making Team WRDJ. We hope that this team will help enjoyment of the tournament.
当初トモダチトーナメントにはチーム単位で参加する方法しかなく、それはとても限定的だと少し残念に思いました。トーナメントに参加しないチームの国内選手や海外から来日する選手達など、もっと沢山の人達に日本でダービーをプレイできる機会を作りたくて、Team WRDJを作るアイディアを思いつきました。このチームがより多くの人が友達トーナメントを楽しむ為に役に立つ事を願ってます。
&lt;strong&gt;The Women's Roller Derby Japan Team contains a lot of skaters from Neon Roller Monsters - Tokyo Roller Girls' "Japanese" team. With the experience you have playing the Sushi Rollers already, do you think this will be an advantage in the tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(Team WRDJには、東京ローラーガールズの「日本人」チームであるネオンローラーモンスターのスケーターがたくさん含まれています。すでに寿司ローラーを経験している経験があれば、これがトーナメントで有利になると思いますか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team WRDJ is a mixed team, so I think it is stronger than Neon Roller Monsters. If there is something to be advantageous, if we use Japanese language during the game, they can't understand our strategy...But Sushi Rollers is smart and very strong team, so it might not matter!
Team WRDJはミックスチームなので、ネオンローラーモンスターズよりも強いと思います。有利になる事があるとしたら、私達が日本語を使用すれば作戦が彼らにバレない事です。しかしスシローラーズはとても強いチームなので、そんな事は関係ないかもしれません…笑
&lt;strong&gt;With skaters from Honshu, Okinawa and Hawai'i, how have Team WRDJ been practising together before the Tomodachi Tournament?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(本州、沖縄、ハワイの選手と一緒に、チームWRDJはTomodachiトーナメントの前にどのように練習していましたか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can not practice together as Team WRDJ. We will think about our strategy.
チームWRDJとして皆んなで一緒に練習する事出来ません。これから作戦を考えます。
&lt;strong&gt;Outside of your own division, there's a lot of other Roller Derby to watch at the tournament: which teams, or games, are you most looking forward to seeing?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(自身の部門外には、トーナメントで観戦できる多くのローラーダービーがあります。どのチームや試合が最も楽しみですか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I'm looking forward to the Pan-Asian match. I'm very interested in how Asian players will play derby. WRDJ would like Roller Derby to spread further across Asia in the future.
Pan-Asianの試合が最も楽しみです。
アジアの選手達がどんなプレイをするのかとても興味があります。これからもっとアジア全域にローラーダービーが広がっていってほしいです。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After the Tournament, will Team WRDJ continue in other events? &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(トーナメント終了後、WRDJチームは他のイベントを続行しますか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is undecided right now, but we would like to do it again if we have good opportunities.
今のところ未定ですが、良い機会があればまたやりたいです。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Women's Roller Derby Japan also has a mandate to manage the National Japanese team. Looking towards 2018's Roller Derby World Cup, how is this going, what are your plans?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(ウィメンズローラーダービージャパンには、日本人のチームを統括する権限もあります。 2018年のローラーダービーワールドカップを目指していかがですか、予定はどんな感じですか？)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started new Team Japan for World Cup 2018. Twenty-five skaters from all over the world have applied for this time. Last time, our major goal was [just] participation in the World Cup, but this time, our new major goal is getting &lt;em&gt;victories&lt;/em&gt; at the World Cup! Team practice has started in Japan. We need figure out how we work together with overseas skaters, but we are sure that new Team Japan will be stronger than last time. Please expect the Team Japan 2018!!
私達は2018年の為のチームジャパンを結成しました。今回は世界中から25人の選手達が応募をしてきました。前回はワールドカップに出場する事が私達の大きな目標でしたが、今回は勝つ事を大きな目標において、チーム作りをすると決めています。日本国内ではチーム練習が始まりました。パワーアップしたチームジャパンを是非期待していて下さい。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tomodachi Derby Tournament will be held between the 24th and 26th of March, in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/%E6%B2%96%E7%B8%84%E7%9C%8C%E7%B7%8F%E5%90%88%E9%81%8B%E5%8B%95%E5%85%AC%E5%9C%92+%E4%BD%93%E8%82%B2%E9%A4%A8/@26.3104722,127.8208903,18.72z/data=!4m8!1m2!2m1!1sOkinawa+Comprehensive+Park!3m4!1s0x0:0xd83f29f95619b3f0!8m2!3d26.3106488!4d127.8200047"&gt;Okinawa Comprehensive Sports Park&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Okinawa.トモダチダービートーナメントは３月２４日から３月２６日まで&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/%E6%B2%96%E7%B8%84%E7%9C%8C%E7%B7%8F%E5%90%88%E9%81%8B%E5%8B%95%E5%85%AC%E5%9C%92+%E4%BD%93%E8%82%B2%E9%A4%A8/@26.3104722,127.8208903,18.72z/data=!4m8!1m2!2m1!1sOkinawa+Comprehensive+Park!3m4!1s0x0:0xd83f29f95619b3f0!8m2!3d26.3106488!4d127.8200047"&gt;沖縄県総合運動公園 体育館&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;で開催されます。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>international derby</category><category>team wrdj</category><category>tomodachi derby tournament</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>women's roller derby japan</category><category>日本語</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/03/09/the-tomodachi-cup-team-womens-roller-derby-japan-tomodachidabitonamentochi/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 12:03:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ジャパンオープン トーナメント</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/24/ziyapanopun-tonamento/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/808335735910721/"&gt;ジャパンオープン トーナメント&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;は、アジア太平洋地域で開催される初のローラーダービートーナメントです。
&lt;strong&gt;3月25日と26日&lt;/strong&gt;に、&lt;strong&gt;沖縄&lt;/strong&gt;で、オーストラリア、ニュージーランド、日本、デンマーク、アラスカ（米国）らのチームがさんかし開催されます。
&lt;p&gt;主催者は、Kokeshi Roller Dollsで、ウーマンフラットトラックローラーダービー協会（&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/"&gt;WFTDA&lt;/a&gt;）は、このトーナメントを認可し、 WFTDAのルールが適用されます。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ローラーダービーは日本でも、真新しい競技と言う訳ではありません。とは言え21世紀の新しいローラーダービーは、日本で、2010年に始まりました。
東京と沖縄の米軍基地内のアメリカ人がTokyo Roller Girls と、Kokeshi Roller Dollsを設立しました。
2016年現在では、東京、三沢、沖縄にローラーダービーのチームがあります。
ちなみに、東京ローラーガールズは日本人のスケーターを募集しています！
他にも、東京にKAMIKAZE BADASSと呼ばれるチームもあります。
これらのチームのすべてがWFTDAのルールを使用し、Kokeshi Roller Dolls、Devil Dogs Derby Dames、Tokyo Roller Girls はWFTDAメンバーです。
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2016/03/11/the-japan-open-schedule-timezones/6"&gt;時間割&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;トーナメントに参加するチームは以下の通りです：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adelaide Roller Derby.&lt;/strong&gt;
オーストラリア、アデレード、のチームです。2007年に設立されました。WFTDAのメンバーであります。
統計では、彼らがトーナメントで最強のチームであると思われます。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pirate City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt;
ニュージーランド、オークランドの、チームです。2006年に設立南半球で設立された最初のチームです。彼らもまWFTDAのメンバーです。なお、このトーナメントに参加するのは、B-チームです。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Devil Dog Derby Dames と Kokeshi Roller Dolls&lt;/strong&gt;
この２チームは、沖縄のチームで、米軍基地でアメリカ人によって設立されました。両チームともWFTDAメンバーです。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tokyo Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;
東京を拠点としています。彼女達は多くのチームを持っています。例えば、日本人だけのチーム「neon roller monsters」。彼らもまたWFTDAのメンバーです。A-チームが参加します。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Misawa Killa Geishas&lt;/strong&gt;
アメリカ人によって設立された、Misawa Killa Geishas、Aーチームが参加します。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copenhagen Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;
デンマーク、コペンハーゲン、のチームです。このトーナメントは、彼女達に取って、初めてのヨーロッパ以外への、遠征です。彼女達も又WFTDAのメンバーです。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Juneau Roller Girls&lt;/strong&gt;
米国アラスカ州、ジュノーのチームです。わずか6名のスケーターで、参加します。 （通常は10〜15人！）WFTDAのメンバーです。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;一般社団法人日本ローラーダービー協会(JRDA)&lt;/strong&gt;
一般社団法人日本ローラーダービー協会を後援しています。
また、日本選抜がこのチームが、参加します。このチームについては、詳しい事は分かりません。
他の日本のチームはJRDAのメンバーでは、ありません。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HELL OH KITTY と Nip in Éire: 助けてもらいありがとう。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>japan open roller derby tournament</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>ジャパンオープン トーナメント</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2016/03/24/ziyapanopun-tonamento/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 11:03:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Cup Interview: Team Japan [ローラーデービーのワールドカップ：日本のチーム]</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/15/world-cup-interview-team-japan-roradebinowarudokatsupuri/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like most of the Roller Derby community, we at the Scottish Roller Derby blog are increasingly excited by the prospect of seeing a whole 30 nations competing at the &lt;a href="http://rollerderbyworldcup.com/"&gt;Blood and Thunder World Cup&lt;/a&gt; in December. In fact, we're so excited, we've been following up with all of those national teams to learn a little about their plans and progression towards that important meet up in Dallas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because there are so many teams, we've grouped them together into regions, roughly geographically, which we'll be devoting a week each to. We're starting with the "Africa and Asia-Pacific" region, and with one of the new entrants to the World Cup - Team Japan!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/10448746_1467216233517248_5449562808216430157_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-3754" src="http://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2014/09/10448746_1467216233517248_5449562808216430157_n.jpg" alt="The excellent Team Japan logo." width="516" height="516"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The excellent Team Japan logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This interview is in both Japanese and English. I apologise to Japanese readers for my poor Japanese. 「私の日本語が下手です。すみません。」The interview was conducted about a month ago, and I've inserted some updates accordingly.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Captain Hiroe Somekawa 「染川 ヒロエ」(who skates as Thunder BELL) was kind enough to answer our questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class="im"&gt;1) On your website, I see that you have really started in June! How are things progressing?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;日本代表チームの ウェブサイトは  6月から 始めた と言う. ドのように進んでいます?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;はい、私達は今年の6月に日本チームを結成したばかりです。
きっと参加国の中で一番最後に結成されたチームですね。
日本人選手はまだ非常に人数が少ないので、私達は8月31日まで選手の募集をしています。
そして日本の男性選手(Ninjapanの選手達)が協力をしてくれて、現在は男女混合で練習を行っています。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, we just formed a team for Japan in June of this year.
We think team Japan is probably the last team that was formed out of the participating countries.
Japan has fewer number of female derby players, so we are recruiting Team Japan members until August 31.
And we are getting a lot of cooperation from male players of Japan (Ninjapan players) and practicing in mixed-gender with them now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) There are many teams in Japan, but they seem to have many Americans in them (Kokeshi Roller Dolls, and the others from Okinawa, for example). How are you recruiting skaters for Team Japan? Will you be requiring Japanese nationals?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 日本に多くのチームでますでも多くのアメリカの スケーターデスやら。&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; など　オ機縄のKokeshi Roller Dolls).ドのように 日本代表チームの スケーターを募集している。&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; 日本人要求したいるか.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;確かに日本には多くのチームがありますが、その99%はアメリカ人の選手です。
現在、日本人選手はTokyo Roller Girlsリーグにだけ在籍します。
初心者を合わせても、全員で15人程度です。
私達はインターネーット等で日本国外に住んでいる日本人選手を探して連絡を取り、
4名のアメリカ在住者が日本チームに参加する事になりました。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exactly, there are a lot of teams in Japan. But 99% of players are Americans.
Actually, Japanese Nationals players are in only Tokyo Roller Girls league now.
There are about 15 people in all Japanese Nationals including fresh meat.
We were looking for Japanese players who live outside of Japan in Internet
and referral from derby sisters, and made contact with them.
And Team Japan has four players who live outside of Japan now.　[These skaters are from El Paso Roller Derby, San Diego Derby Dolls and Green Mountain Derby Dames.]
&lt;span class="im"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;3) Most of Roller Derby is conducted in English. Does language cause problems for Roller Derby in Japan?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; ローラーダービー イギリスごで 実施すっている　は 問題ですか.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;日本に居るほとんどのスケーターはアメリカ人なので、通常は特に問題なく試合が行われていますが、
私達日本人スケーターにとって、英語で行われている状況は非常に厳しいものです。
しかし、Tokyo Roller Girlsリーグの全てのアメリカ人選手達は、英語が理解出来ない私達日本人選手に
ジェスチャーを使いながらとても親切にローラーダービーのルールや作戦を教えてくれています。
私達は彼女達に本当に感謝しています。しかし、やはり実際はまだ、日本人がローラーダービーをやりたくても
英語を理解出来ないとローラーダービーをする事が難しいです。
特にルールブックは、内容がとても複雑なので、私達はそれを理解するのがとても大変です。
日本語のルールブックが発表されたら、日本人選手も増えると思います。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually the game has been held without any particular problem because most derby players who live in Japan are Americans.
But for Japanese skaters like us, the situation that derby is carried out in English is really hard.
However, the American players of all of Tokyo Roller Girls league are very kindly telling us the strategy and rules of roller derby while using gestures for us who doesn't understand English. We are really grateful to them.
Actually, even if some Japanese girl want to play roller derby, they can't do it without understanding English.
The rule book has such very complex contents in particular, it's really hard to understand it for us.
We think that Japanese players will be increased if an official Japanese rule book was announced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) How are you raising money and finding sponsors?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; ドのように金銭をやスポンサーを 募集している？&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;寄付金については、私達はGofundmeで世界中からの寄付を集めようとしましたが、
日本のPaypalでは寄付を受け取る事が出来ないそうです。
なので現在、違う方法を考えています。現在の日本では、
シンプルに日本チームのオリジナル商品を販売し、それを資金にする方法しか無さそうです。
これから商品作りを始めてオンラインショップを立ち上げる予定です。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;スポンサーについては、ローラーコンで私達のスポンサーになってくれるメーカーと出会う事が出来ました。
あとは日本国内の企業に資料を持って周る活動をこれからしていきます。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About donations, we tried to collect donations from all over the world in Gofundme.
But we could not receive a donation via Paypal in Japan by Japanese law.
So now, I am thinking a different way. We can have only simple way for gather money. That is selling team Japan merchandise.
We are planning to launch an online shop for the first time, and are creating products now.
About sponsors, I was able to meet with manufacturers who will become our sponsor at RollerCon.
We will visit to companies to found our sponsors in Japan.
&lt;span class="im"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;5) As a relatively unknown team, what are your aims going into the World Cup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; チーム 若い ですは 私の目的が 何 World Cupに します？&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;私達のワールドカップでの最大の目標は
今後日本中にスポーツとしてのローラーダービー、
更にその背景にある文化(カルチャー)としてのローラーダービーを広める為に
世界に認識されるチームへの成長を遂げることです。
そして....トーナメントで3回くらいは勝ちたいな、とも思っています。笑&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our biggest goal at the World Cup is that team Japan grow to be gained world recognition for roller derby.
If we can do it, we can spread Roller Derby in Japan.
We would like to spread Roller Derby as a sport, and the great culture also.
And... we wish that we get at least three wins at the World Cup tournament if possible(!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since our interview, Team Japan has gained a sponsor in Atom Wheels, and begun &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/289173411265953/"&gt;regular&lt;/a&gt; practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Japan can be followed at their &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/teamjapanrollerderby?fref=ts"&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt; page and the &lt;a href="http://wrdjapan.com/"&gt;Women's Roller Derby Japan&lt;/a&gt; website. Merchandise will be available soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Japan's Roster is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slamurai #7
HELL OH KITTY #13
AYAMI #17
NOBUE #30
Chee Fighter #31
YUMI #52
AYA #54
Axel Managarmr #75
Ninja Plz #143
Secret Asian Slam #303
MARK #229
MIHO #555
chikai #719
Oscar Little Wild #831
Thunder BELL #950
Vagichael Jakson # 5umo
Mocha Panic # pa29&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their gofundme (running since the last week in September) is: &lt;a href="http://gofundme.com/ewvvng"&gt;http://gofundme.com/ewvvng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>an interview with...</category><category>blood and thunder world cup 2014</category><category>interviews</category><category>roller derby world cup</category><category>roller derby world cup 2014</category><category>team japan</category><category>world cup</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2014/09/15/world-cup-interview-team-japan-roradebinowarudokatsupuri/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 10:36:01 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>