<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts by SRD)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/authors/srd.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 12:45:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>EuroClash 2020: Newcastle Roller Derby's first tournament</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/03/EuroClash2020/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Roller Derby Firsts, technically this weekend marks the first ever tournament hosted by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.newcastlerollerderby.co.uk/"&gt;Newcastle Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; (UK). This is a very technical point,
as Newcastle's finest Roller Derby league have hosted EuroClash before - just under their previous name of Newcastle Roller Girls - but it's a good enough excuse for us to
write a quick lead in article...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year's EuroClash is just as international as previous years, but is running as a 1 day event at Newcastle's famous Walker Activity Dome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt='The EuroClash 2020 flyer image: EuroClash logo (text EUROCLASH 2020 and silhouette skater) with glass-shattering effect applied, the "WFTDA Recognised Tournament" logo, and additional glass shatter effects at the corners of the image.' src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2020/03/EuroClash2020.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 5 teams attending, and 5 games in total, this is a tournament in the looser sense of "a number of games in one place"; no overall winner will be decided. As with most WFTDA-Recognised tournaments,
the point is to make it easier for all the teams to achieve their WFTDA Sanctioned Games quota by having several at once (and also get to do that by playing interesting teams in a nice place).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/03/EuroClash2020/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>derbystats.eu</category><category>euroclash</category><category>flattrackstats</category><category>newcastle roller derby</category><category>newcastle roller girls</category><category>tournaments</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/03/EuroClash2020/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Guest Series: "The Road To Playoffs - March 2020 edition"</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/03/guest-series-the-road-to-playoffs-march-2020-edition/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, we ran a series of "&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/categories/road-to-playoffs/"&gt;Road To Playoffs&lt;/a&gt;" posts, providing an alternative view of the WFTDA Rankings as a way to predict which teams are likely to make Playoffs. We're happy with how this went, so we're going ahead with the same plan this year...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speedy Convalesce, one of the two primary Derby Scoreboard Developers, and founder of the Star Track "league without skaters" in Germany, has recalculated the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://stats.wftda.com/rankings?r=2986"&gt;ratings&lt;/a&gt; for every team in WFTDA - as if their rating was calculated at &lt;strong&gt;June 30th 2020&lt;/strong&gt; [the ranking which will be used to decide Qualifications and seedings into both WFTDA Playoffs, and the Continental Cups].. (Aficionados of the WFTDA rating will know that it applies a "decay factor" to older games, which is what we're tweaking here.) This helps to give a feel for how important the games each team has played in the season are, so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="All the locations with teams in our top 100 (larger stars mean more than one team is in the list in that location)" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2020/03/RoadToPlayoffs-100320.png"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;All the locations with teams in our top 100 (larger stars mean more than one team is in the list in that location)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst we can't predict the future, this will give the best guess of what teams need to do to qualify, based on what they've already done. This means that this will be the penultimate edition of the Road to Playoffs series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as attaining a minimum ranking, teams also need to play at least 4 bouts within the eligibility period (December 2019 to June 2029), and we'll be tracking their progress on this measure, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/03/guest-series-the-road-to-playoffs-march-2020-edition/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (5 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>guest posts</category><category>international derby</category><category>rankings</category><category>road to playoffs</category><category>statistics</category><category>tournament</category><category>wftda</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/03/guest-series-the-road-to-playoffs-march-2020-edition/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>African Good Time: The most important Roller Derby tournament this year.</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/03/AfricanGoodTimePre/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's always exciting Roller Derby firsts, and international match ups every year in the calendar, and we can usually argue about just which event was the highlight of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020, though, we already have a very strong candidate, as Egypt's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cairollers.com"&gt;CaiRollers&lt;/a&gt; and South Africa's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.goldencityrollers.com/"&gt;Golden City Rollers&lt;/a&gt; make history with the first every intra-African Roller Derby tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we've written about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/06/rollerderby-za-2019/"&gt;previously&lt;/a&gt;, South African roller derby exists in its own geographical bubble, far from other nations; but the CaiRollers have had almost as much trouble finding regular opponents (despite being just across the Mediterranean from Greece, and not that far from Italy and Austria). After making history with the first MENA game (against Abu Dhabi Roller Derby in January 2017), and playing Marseille's Bloody Skulls in mid 2017, the CaiRollers have had no other international opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The 'A Frican Good Time' Flyer, large text of the event name in block capitals over diagonally divided field of red (top left) and gold (bottom right). Red part of field has subtle ancient Egyptian hieroglyph pattern, gold part of field has subtle Zulu-style geometric patterning. To the left of the text is a jammer, whose flesh is invisible, but whose clothing and kit are red, black and gold." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2020/03/africangoodtimeflyer.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, since October 2018, they've been planning something more audacious: raising funds to travel themselves, down to Johannesburg. Readers will remember their &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/cairollers-to-south-africa/#"&gt;Indiegogo&lt;/a&gt; fundraiser, which did not reach its target, to achieve this by 2019... but the funds that were raised there have been the basis of further money-raising within Cairo itself. Profits from local events, including a recent home teams game at the start of February, have all been funnelled into the venture, and individual skaters have spent personal funds on making their flight bookings. This will be the CaiRollers' first ever away bout, and it's a huge step to make in addition to the usual issues that come with playing away!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has always been a collaborative effort between Golden City Rollers and the CaiRollers, but as GCR told us, it's grown since the initial plan of just a single game:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
"CaiRollers first contacted us with the idea for this event in October 2018, and we have literally been counting the days since! Last year, GCR and CaiRollers decided to run a tournament instead of just one game and we invited other South African leagues to participate. With travel costs being a challenge, Durban Roller Derby and Cape Town Rollergirls opted to form a mixed team, along with some players from UAE All Stars, where an ex-GCR-skater currently lives. They'll compete together as the Pan-African Rollers. It's been both challenging and exciting pulling together our first international tournament, but we've learned a lot along the way and we're hoping this will be the first of many more to come. Only days to go now...we can't wait to have all the teams here and on the track!"&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also makes this the first year that South Africa will host two tournaments with teams from across their own country: normally this happens just the once, in their end-of-year Derbyfest. As with Derbyfest last year, this will be a three-teams round-robin, followed by a "finals" playoff for the top two teams from that stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire tournament will be streamed on the GCR &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChpT56bZ-6bgrZL1slDXNVA"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; channel. (We'd keep an eye on GCR's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/228775404810943/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; event page for more info.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;caption&gt;Schedule for Sunday 15 March&lt;/caption&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="25%"&gt;
&lt;col width="25%"&gt;
&lt;col width="25%"&gt;
&lt;col width="25%"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead valign="bottom"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class="head"&gt;Time (SA)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Time (UTC)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Team 1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Team 2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CaiRollers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pan-African Rollers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1130&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0930&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pan-African Rollers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Golden City Rollers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CaiRollers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Golden City Rollers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Top 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Top 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the public schedule, there will also be an all-day bootcamp on the Saturday, providing maximum benefit to all attending teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope to bring you a longer article as a post-mortem on the whole event, in a few weeks' time, but for now: put a pin in this for your diary!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a frican good time</category><category>cairollers</category><category>egyptian roller derby</category><category>emirates roller derby</category><category>golden city rollers</category><category>south african roller derby</category><category>uae roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/03/AfricanGoodTimePre/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 08:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Danish Champs - All Sevens and...</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/02/DanishChamps2020/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Roller Derby grows across a country, inevitably people start thinking about having a National Tournament (usually around the time they think about needing a National Governing Body). So, whilst some Nationals - in, say Mexico or Sweden - have been running for a very long time - there's always new National tournaments forming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 1st of February, Denmark held its first &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/764179684037734/"&gt;National Tournament&lt;/a&gt; in 4 years, taking the unusual (worldwide) step of using the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1rsdpDACXou9PL_wIZgPhZltHvF0ScWmlcyfhH6uWTC4/"&gt;Roller Derby Sevens&lt;/a&gt; ruleset.
This tournament was the result of both conception and huge commitment by one person - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://aalborgrollerderby.dk/"&gt;Aalborg Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; 's Möxie Crüel, so we caught up with her to discuss the genesis of the tournament, it's aims and plans for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Roskilde (in golden and black) versus O-Town (in purple), dramatic shot with Roskilde's jammer mid-fall after hit from O-Town blocker. Other skaters arrayed around them." src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2020/02/RoskildeVOTown.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Roskilde versus O-Town (Odense) in the DM, first game [Photo by BrknRib Photo and Artwork]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/02/DanishChamps2020/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (8 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>danish roller derby</category><category>national tournament</category><category>roller derby sevens</category><category>tournaments</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/02/DanishChamps2020/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 07:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Toxic Lima: Roller Derby in Peru 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/01/TXL-Peru2019/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst 2x4 and Sailor City have made Argentine Roller Derby more familiar to the kind of audiences who only follow Division 1, there's been Roller Derby &lt;em&gt;across&lt;/em&gt; South America for longer than they might expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2010, Perú has hosted Roller Derby in the form of its only league, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/toxiclimarollerderby/"&gt;Toxic Lima Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; . We have been lucky enough to be able to talk to one of their longer-standing members, Twerkin Pony, about the history, and present, of Roller Derby in Perú.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt='The Toxic Lima Roller Derby logo: all in black and white with no shading. stylised head wearing full-face gas mask, and WW1 style helmet, with TXL displayed on the helmet crown. Behind, a ring with "Toxic Lima Roller Derby" curving within it.' src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/12/TXL.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/01/TXL-Peru2019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (11 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>latin american roller derby</category><category>peruvian roller derby</category><category>team peru</category><category>toxic lima roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/01/TXL-Peru2019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Derby Drama: Role Playing Roller Derby</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/02/DerbyDrama2020/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This document is licenced CC:BY-SA 4.0, the authors are Libby Horacek and Sam Skipsey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst they might seem superficially different, Roller Derby and Role Playing Games have a surprising amount in common, including having experienced more than one resurgence of popular interest driven by pop cultural reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Roller Derby has &lt;em&gt;Whip It&lt;/em&gt;, and now &lt;em&gt;Birds of Prey&lt;/em&gt;; RPGs (and especially their most famous example, Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons), have appearances in &lt;em&gt;E.T.&lt;/em&gt; (and their own cartoon) in the 80s and &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt; in the present day, as well as increasing popularity through “actual play”, role playing game campaigns streamed live, or recorded, on Twitch, YouTube or as podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Libby Horacek has made the, perhaps obvious in retrospect, step of connecting the two, via an RPG set in the context of Roller Derby itself… a game of tactics on track and management and feelings off track, which can only have one name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="derby-drama"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://derbydrama.com"&gt;Derby Drama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="The Derby Drama kickstarter logo" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2020/02/derbydrama_original.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here at SRD we like both Roller Derby and RPGs, and we know that there’s a huge crossover between D&amp;amp;D players and skaters, so we thought it was worth catching up with Libby to talk about all things Derby, RPGs and anything else, starting with how this all started for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/02/DerbyDrama2020/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (11 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>derby drama</category><category>games</category><category>ohio valley roller girls</category><category>role playing games</category><category>roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/02/DerbyDrama2020/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The First SRDB Awards - RESULTS</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/01/srdbawards-awards-2019/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt='The SRDB Award Logo: the Scottish Roller Derby Blog Logo (concentric circles, outer circle containing words "Scottish Roller Derby" all-capitals, separated by five-pointed stars, and an inner ring of stars just outside the boundary of the inner circle; inner circle containing a modification of the "lion of scotland", a heraldic lion, facing right, rampant, with a jammer cover on its head), but with a gold/bronze colour scheme applied.' src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/SRDB-Award.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the AWARDS page for the first ever SRDB Awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ground-rules for the Awards are covered in the launch post &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/srdbawards-nom-2019/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in that link, voting was by &lt;em&gt;approval voting&lt;/em&gt;.
This means that you could, and should, tick boxes for all of the nominees you thought would deserve to win. You could tick all the boxes, if you thought they're all deserving; you could tick no boxes if you think none were deserving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the winners of each award, some statistics on the voting: we let you choose which categories to vote on, so some categories were voted on more than others.
In general, the categories with the longest list of nominees were the ones with the most votes, predictably; the category with the fewest votes &lt;strong&gt;BOOTCAMP&lt;/strong&gt; had about 7.5% of the votes cast on the category with the most, &lt;strong&gt;SKATER&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fraction of voters voting for more than one nominee varied significantly across the categories: with only two nominees, only 1 voter voted for both &lt;strong&gt;BOOTCAMP&lt;/strong&gt; nominees; whilst 38% of voters voted for more than one &lt;strong&gt;HALL OF FAME&lt;/strong&gt; nominee. Overall, (ignoring the &lt;strong&gt;RISING STAR&lt;/strong&gt; category as it had additional voting rules), 17% of votes were cast for multiple nominees, across the categories - this is a little higher than the average for this voting scheme in other deployments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also let you cast a vote for &lt;em&gt;no-one&lt;/em&gt;, if you didn't think any nominee deserved it in a category. Again, ignoring RISING STAR, only 4 such null votes were cast, around 0.2% of votes in total. This is a little lower than the average for systems which let you place null votes, which is encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that statistical interlude out of the way, lets get on with the main matter, the winners in each category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="awards"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;AWARDS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="skater"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SKATER&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Skater award had the largest number of votes of any category in the awards. Despite this, the clear winner, with more than 50% of the voters, was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ELO C RAPTOR&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Harpies Roller Derby Milano&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="coach"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;COACH&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Coaching award was both popular (with more than 200 voters casting opinions), and very tightly contested, with the top 4 by votes all within 7 votes of each other. The winner, pipping the others to the post was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROSIE PEACOCK&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;New Wheeled Order&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Power of Scotland&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="referee"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;REFEREE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Referee award was also very popular, with more than 200 voters, but had a very clear margin for the winner (although still short of an overall majority)...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NICOLA'S RAGE&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Crimson Vipers Roller Derby Bergamo&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="non-skating-official"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NON-SKATING OFFICIAL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NSO award was not quite as heavily voted on, with more than 100 votes cast in total. The runaway winner, just 1% short of an overall majority, and with twice the votes of the next highest placed nominee...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEDROG&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="announcer"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;ANNOUNCER&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With only 3 nominees, the Announcer category had some interesting voting patterns... and a very clear winner. With a majority of the vote, the winning announcer was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GRAEME MCPHAIL&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Bairn City Rollers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="photographer"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PHOTOGRAPHER&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Photographer category was the second most voted on category of all in the awards, with almost 250 votes cast in total. Despite this, it was also a very tightly contested category between the top 3, who remained within 10 votes of each other for the entire voting period (and changed position more than once).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, the winning photographer was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VINCIANE PIÉRART&lt;/strong&gt; (NSP189)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="volunteer"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;VOLUNTEER&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Volunteer category, with only 3 candidates, was another with interesting patterns of voting. The overwhelming winner, with a supermajority of votes, was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AUDREY&lt;/strong&gt; ... ex-Dundee Roller Derby, and sort of semi-retired volunteer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="league"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;LEAGUE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;League was another popular category, with more than 200 voters casting overall. It was also a very convincingly won category, with the margin between 1st and 2nd place being larger than the total votes cast for 2nd. Despite this, winning by a plurality:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE ANGUANAS&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Vicenza, Italy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tournament"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TOURNAMENT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tournament category saw only just shy of 200 votes cast... and the overall winner had the support of a supermajority of those! It's...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SKATE IM RING 2019&lt;/strong&gt; hosted by &lt;strong&gt;Alp'n Rockets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="non-regulation-tournament"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NON-REGULATION TOURNAMENT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Non-Regulation Tournament category should probably have been called the "Roller Derby Sevens" category, as all three candidates used that ruleset. This was a pretty tight contest between all three, with the winner by plurality:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KRUSTFEST 2019&lt;/strong&gt; hosted independently, in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="bootcamp"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;BOOTCAMP&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With only two candidates this category went, convincingly, to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"LILY GASKELL AND FAIRY QUAKE'S BOOTCAMPS"&lt;/strong&gt; hosted by &lt;strong&gt;Rainy City Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="media"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MEDIA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Media award was one of our less voted on categories, despite having a bunch of nominations, and the winning candidate changed over the course of voting... taking a win with a majority of voters when voting closed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The MRDA EUROPEAN QUALIFIERS LIVESTREAM&lt;/strong&gt; hosted on &lt;strong&gt;YouTube&lt;/strong&gt;, run with &lt;strong&gt;Granite City Brawlers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="hall-of-fame"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;HALL OF FAME&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hall of Fame category is something of a wildcard category, and had an eclectic range of nominees. This might explain why almost two-fifths of voters voted for more than one candidate in this category! Despite this, there was a clear winner, only just shy of an overall majority...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first Hall of Fame member is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5TH BLOCKER SKATES&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Glasgow&lt;/strong&gt;'s own Roller Derby shop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rising-star"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;RISING STAR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we come to the Rising Star category, for junior skaters, or up-and-coming younger skaters in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to some anomalies in the nomination process, and also to especially encourage voters in this category to vote on the basis of deserving, rather than just popularity, this category required you to vote for 2 or more nominees. (Votes for a single nominee were considered the same as a vote for no-one.) Despite this being clearly described on both the Nominees page, and on the actual voting form (in two places on the latter), a number of voters still voted for a single candidate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, including these single votes would not have changed the overall winner (although it would change the margin of win, and the ordering of all the other positions). The Winner, with a significant margin in terms of valid votes, was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;red OWEch (Owen Squires)&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Newcastle Junior Roller Derby (Australia)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst there's no official prize for winning an SRDB Award (and we consider being Nominated to be the real point), we'd be happy to work with any of the winners on a "Winners Profile" to be published later in the month or year. Please get in touch with us if you are a winner (or the nominee of a winner) if you want to work with us on this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>announcer</category><category>awards</category><category>bootcamp</category><category>coach</category><category>end of year</category><category>hall of fame</category><category>league</category><category>media</category><category>non-regulation tournament</category><category>non-skating official</category><category>photographer</category><category>referee</category><category>rising star</category><category>scottish roller derby blog</category><category>skater</category><category>tournament</category><category>volunteer</category><category>votes</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2020/01/srdbawards-awards-2019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 11:26:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The First SRDB Awards - HUB</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/12/srdbawards-hub-2019/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt='The SRDB Award Logo: the Scottish Roller Derby Blog Logo (concentric circles, outer circle containing words "Scottish Roller Derby" all-capitals, separated by five-pointed stars, and an inner ring of stars just outside the boundary of the inner circle; inner circle containing a modification of the "lion of scotland", a heraldic lion, facing right, rampant, with a jammer cover on its head), but with a gold/bronze colour scheme applied.' src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/SRDB-Award.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the HUB page for the first ever SRDB Awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ground-rules for the Awards are covered in the launch post &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/srdbawards-nom-2019/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in that link, voting is by &lt;em&gt;approval voting&lt;/em&gt;.
This means that you can, and should, tick boxes for all of the nominees you think would deserve to win. You can tick all the boxes, if you think they're all deserving; you can tick no boxes if you think none are deserving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone gets &lt;em&gt;a single submission&lt;/em&gt; per category (with as many boxes ticked as they want); we have enabled detection of multiple submissions on these forms, and will also be taking action against unusual voting patterns which get past this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The individual links for each nomination are below: Each Nomination is listed along with the reasons for their nomination, as supplied by their nominator. For submissions in a language other than English, we've supplied a translation into English (errors are ours). For multiple nominations for a single nominee, we've combined the reasons together (we've edited where needed, and removed repetition that results).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-skater-2019/"&gt;[SKATER]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-coach-2019/"&gt;[COACH]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-referee-2019/"&gt;[REFEREE]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-nso-2019/"&gt;[NON-SKATING OFFICIAL]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-announcer-2019/"&gt;[ANNOUNCER]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-photographer-2019/"&gt;[PHOTOGRAPHER]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-volunteer-2019/"&gt;[VOLUNTEER]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-league-2019/"&gt;[LEAGUE]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-tournament-2019/"&gt;[TOURNAMENT]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-nonregtournament-2019/"&gt;[NON-REGULATION TOURNAMENT]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-bootcamp-2019/"&gt;[BOOTCAMP]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-media-2019/"&gt;[MEDIA]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-halloffame-2019/"&gt;[HALL OF FAME]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/pages/2019/srdbawards-risingstar-2019/"&gt;[RISING STAR]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>announcer</category><category>awards</category><category>bootcamp</category><category>coach</category><category>end of year</category><category>hall of fame</category><category>league</category><category>media</category><category>non-regulation tournament</category><category>non-skating official</category><category>photographer</category><category>referee</category><category>rising star</category><category>scottish roller derby blog</category><category>skater</category><category>tournament</category><category>volunteer</category><category>votes</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/12/srdbawards-hub-2019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 09:46:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>RNR 2019</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/RNR-102019/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A little delayed, due to there being so much stuff, we'd like to celebrate the 10th anniversary of the first Roller Derby League in Colombia: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.instagram.com/rollerqueens"&gt;Rock N Roller Queens&lt;/a&gt; . Starting back in 2009, RRQ were the start of a rapid swell of Colombian roller derby - over the following two years, a full 10 leagues had come into existence, many (including RRQ) based in the capital, Bogotá, but also across the other cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt='The Rock N Roller Queens tenth-anniversary logo: team in background in desaturated colour, overlayed by red/orange/yellow stylised "RRQ AÑOS" across a large X, with stylised crown atop, and "REINANDO" below.' src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/RnRQ-X.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rapid growth of Roller Derby in Colombia, their first National Tournament was held in 2012, and the Rock n Roller Queens won, defeating second place Bogotá Bone Breakers (who were also the second league to form in the country). The following month, July 2012, they also made history by being accepted as the first ever South American league to join the WFTDA Apprentice program. They were also one of the few leagues in Colombia to have both A and B teams, with their Queens forming soon after their membership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of RRQ's teams were also founding members of Bogotá's "District Tournament", which has run from 2014 to 2018 so far. The District Tournament has been one of two tournaments feeding into Colombia's National Tournament (the other being their Regional Tournament covering the areas outside Bogotá), and RRQ have never failed to qualify for that event, in years in which it has run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2014 to 2016, as full WFTDA members, RRQ's travel team actively participated in WFTDA Sanctioned Play, with a consistent performance (taking into account the rapid growth of leagues, and the inherent inflationary nature of WFTDA Ratings year-on-year). In the last few years, no Colombian team has achieved a WFTDA ranking...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...however, on their 10th anniversary, RRQ told us that they have plans to change this. Over their lifespan, the Rock n Roller Queens have undergone what they refer to as "important generational changes", and the new league are planning to make a splash on the WFTDA Sanctioned tournament circuit in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of this, Rock n Roller Queens are also planning a rebranding exercise, which will be open to artists across the world. (We &lt;em&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt; that this won't be expecting the artists to work for free...).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're looking forward to RRQ's 2020... but before that, they're hosting their annual " &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/events/465425780743863/"&gt;Derbynaldos&lt;/a&gt; " [link to Facebook] end of year contest this weekend, which has a special resonance in this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>colombian roller derby</category><category>rock n roller queens</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/RNR-102019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The First SRDB Awards - Nominations Open!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/srdbawards-nom-2019/</link><dc:creator>SRD</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;End of Year awards are a tradition in a lot of communities, and they're one way to highlight and recognise contribution within that community. For the last several years, the Talk Derby To Me podcast ran them for Roller Derby. With TDTM in a quiescent state currently, we reached out to the podcast's founder to get permission to take on the mantle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you might guess from this post existing, he agreed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this article will introduce the ground-rules for the first ever &lt;strong&gt;SRDB Awards&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="srdb-awards-2019"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SRDB AWARDS 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt='The SRDB Award Logo: the Scottish Roller Derby Blog Logo (concentric circles, outer circle containing words "Scottish Roller Derby" all-capitals, separated by five-pointed stars, and an inner ring of stars just outside the boundary of the inner circle; inner circle containing a modification of the "lion of scotland", a heraldic lion, facing right, rampant, with a jammer cover on its head), but with a gold/bronze colour scheme applied.' src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/images/2019/11/SRDB-Award.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SRDB Awards, as with the TDTM Awards before them, are entirely delivered by the &lt;strong&gt;community&lt;/strong&gt;, and provide a chance to recognise contributions to Roller Derby in a range of categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anyone can nominate&lt;/strong&gt; any number of candidates for each and any of our categories: you must, however, provide a suitable reason for why they should win. This reason will be shown to voters when voting, so try to make it convincing! You can nominate for any reason, as long as you explain it. You may nominate in any language, and we will translate [but we may need to talk to you to confirm - please specify your contact details if you want to be contacted].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Even being nominated will give your nominee visibility, so please do nominate even if you are worried about them &lt;em&gt;winning&lt;/em&gt; - winning isn't everything, and being nominated is really the core thing here.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(SRDB reserves the right to remove obviously trolling nominations, but we promise to have a light touch here; we will also remove or recategorise nominations which don't match their category.) SRDB will &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; nominate anyone for any categories themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/srdbawards-nom-2019/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>awards</category><category>end of year</category><category>nominations</category><category>scottish roller derby blog</category><category>talk derby to me</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2019/11/srdbawards-nom-2019/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 09:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>