<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts by thejammingpony)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/authors/thejammingpony.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 13:22:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>National Mens Roller Derby is here................</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/05/20/national-mens-roller-derby-is-here/</link><dc:creator>thejammingpony</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/922300_306876932778113_274698937_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-2623 aligncenter" alt="922300_306876932778113_274698937_o" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/922300_306876932778113_274698937_o.jpg?w=300" width="180" height="180"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span style="font-family:Arial, sans-serif;"&gt;Everyone remembers the excitement of the last roller derby world cup, when a group of our best female skaters made the trip to Canada to take on the rest of the world. Well now its the boys turn. With an all male Roller Derby World Cup in the pipeline for 2014 its time to get the wheels in motion, and that is exactly what they are doing.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Arial, sans-serif;"&gt;Already sporting the team title 'The Power Of Scotland' the team are now looking to start recruiting. Not only skaters but NSO's, a Team Manager and Coaches.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Arial, sans-serif;"&gt;The first training session is planned for the 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; of June and anyone who would like to be a part of the team, whether on skates or off is urged to make it along to the session at the Grangemouth Sports Complex, They're even going to treat you to an after party! All of the details are posted below as well as links you can follow if you would like to apply to skate, coach or manage.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Arial, sans-serif;"&gt;This is sure to be a huge event so get the date in your calendar and come show the boys some support!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;" align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#333333;"&gt;The first training session for potential team members will be on:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#333333;"&gt;01/06/2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Arial, sans-serif;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#333333;"&gt;13.30-18.00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#333333;"&gt;Grangemouth Sports Complex (Hall 2),&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Arial, sans-serif;"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://tinyurl.com/c6jq592" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#3b5998;"&gt;http://tinyurl.com/c6jq592&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#333333;"&gt;Session cost: £10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#333333;"&gt;1. ALL skaters and support staff who wish to attend the session should fill out the registration form located here: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/l.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Ftinyurl.com%2Fcjvhd2h&amp;amp;h=HAQEGrI4IAQEVcvRHOlNO8nBGS1XDGGRULMzOK8tF9x_FJA&amp;amp;s=1" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#3b5998;"&gt;http://tinyurl.com/cjvhd2h&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#333333;"&gt;2. We will require a Head Coach, Assistant Coach and Team Manager. If this interests you then please fill out the separate application form here:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://tinyurl.com/cednotc" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#3b5998;"&gt;http://tinyurl.com/cednotc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#333333;"&gt;3. We will require NSOs, Referees, First Aiders and general support staff at all stages of the training event and further try-out dates. If you are interested in helping then please fill out the general registration form in section 1.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#333333;"&gt;4. Everyone attending the event in an official or skating capacity should try to arrive 30 minutes before the practice time to ensure you are registered correctly and to kit up.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#333333;"&gt;5. If skating, please bring your own supply of water/drinks. There are vending machines and a café at the venue. All skaters should bring a black and white numbered t-shirt.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#333333;"&gt;6. All skaters should be at mins passed level and over 18.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#333333;"&gt;After the first session there will be an after party at Stenhousemuir Cricket Club (Time:TBD), cost for entry: £3 per person:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.pitchero.com/clubs/stenhousemuircricketclub/location/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#3b5998;"&gt;http://www.pitchero.com/clubs/stenhousemuircricketclub/location/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#333333;"&gt;If you have any questions then please contact powerofscotland@gmail.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/922300_306876932778113_274698937_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image aligncenter" id="i-2623" alt="Image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/05/922300_306876932778113_274698937_o.jpg?w=650" width="650" height="650"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>men's roller derby</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/05/20/national-mens-roller-derby-is-here/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 19:40:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In The Presence of Legends!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/20/in-the-presence-of-legends/</link><dc:creator>thejammingpony</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Personal Reflection of Team Steve vs. Gael Force. &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past 2 and a half years derby has been my life, I can honestly say I put my heart and soul into my skating and I’m sure most skaters can relate with this. 2012 saw an amazing year of bouting for me and my team mates and a real year of growth for me personally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However the pinnacle of my skating career so far happened very recently, March 10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; to be precise. On this date I was honored to have the opportunity to skate with Team Steve, a.k.a The best of the rest in Scotland. I was absolutely blown away to have been selected and to have the chance to skate with some of the legends of the Scottish roller derby scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thejammingpony.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/steve.jpg"&gt;&lt;img id="i-6" title="TEAM STEVE (Photo Courtesy of Steven Frew)" src="http://thejammingpony.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/steve.jpg?w=650" alt="Image" width="650" height="432"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; TEAM STEVE (Photo Courtesy of Steven Frew)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to actually take this opportunity I had to make it to Birmingham first. So I and some of my fellow DRG team mates who had also made the team, embarked on a 6 hour journey to Birmingham, crammed into the back of a mini bus. Luckily we are used to being in close proximity with each other on a regular and often sweaty basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a completely unrelated but amazing note we ended up in the same hotel as all the Crufts dogs that were competing at the Birmingham NEC that weekend! Seriously best hotel stay of my life. I’d like to think the competitive spirit and prowess of a group of dogs in trainers with rollers in their hair gave me a sense of confidence and drive for the bout ahead…………. (Yes, I just said that!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a wholly athletic breakfast of Croissants and pain au chocolate we made our way to The Futsal Arena to take on the Mighty Gael Force. It had not slipped our notice that this team consisted of two Gotham skaters, An LRG skater and some of our own amazing Glasgow girls……Intimidating to say the least. I mean Suzy Hotrod skates with Gotham right? And she’s like derby royalty!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donning our Gold bottoms and Team Steve vests felt good, I always feel a little more confident when I have my kit on, the floor was ok if a little different but I felt quite good during the warm up. Skating beside Bunny McBones (Gotham) questions raced through my mind, have you met Bonny Thunders!? What does she smell like!? Have you been to her house!?  However I reeled it in and before we knew it the first line up was on track!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thejammingpony.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/team-talks.jpg"&gt;&lt;img id="i-8" title="Pre - Bout Talk (Photo Courtesy of Steven Frew)" src="http://thejammingpony.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/team-talks.jpg?w=650" alt="Image" width="650" height="432"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Pre - Bout Talk (Photo Courtesy of Steven Frew)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit I felt a bit overwhelmed but as soon as I got on track I was ready. I’m sure a lot of skaters can relate with this, sometimes it really is like flicking a switch. Now I can’t remember much of the details, At DRG we like to call this ‘Jamnesia’. I do however remember Jamming, Scoring some points and being annihilated at least twice by an amazing Gael Force offense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both teams played well, It was quite a strategically minded bout, Steve went out with Defense at first but Gael Force’s offensive play meant we had to hit back with some offense of our own. There were powerjams for both sides and the packs were very fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Teams started close to the Jam line, adjusting to having the front and back line accordingly. Default strategy was very evident and seems to be making a marked come back since the introduction of the new rule set. Get to the Front; Get a goat, Inside Sausage and Outside Sausage were all in force on the day. We didn’t squeeze a peggasist in but there were some amazing Apex jumps on the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final score saw Gael Force take victory 228 – 154. Feelings were good all around. The bout was completely different to skating in a league game. Different skaters were adjusting to different styles of play and it was all around a very fun bout to play. We wanted to win but there wasn't major pressure on us.  It was a fantastic experience and I learned a lot from it. I jammed in public and everyone on my team was supportive and amazing! I think it has given me a bit of encouragement in that, even if you don’t think you are the best skater in the world, just try your best and no one can really ask any more of you than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It gave me some brilliant experience of exceptional offensive plays. In our home league we are a very defensive team and our currently working on our offense so it was really good to see it in play and also to have a chance to action it myself. I have a lot of things to take back to practice with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Steve really is a Derby Institution and I hope to be able to skate with them again someday, I really like wearing gold!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thejammingpony.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gael-force-and-steve.jpg"&gt;&lt;img id="i-10" title="I Did Bunny ears to Bunny McBones!! Ha! (Photo courtesy of Steven Frew)" src="http://thejammingpony.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gael-force-and-steve.jpg?w=650" alt="Image" width="650" height="433"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I Did Bunny ears to Bunny McBones!! Ha! (Photo courtesy of Steven Frew)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Photographs taken by Steven Frew.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/20/in-the-presence-of-legends/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 15:21:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Do you believe....................?</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/08/do-you-believe/</link><dc:creator>thejammingpony</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just when &lt;a class="zem_slink" title="Scotland" href="http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=55.95,-3.18333333333&amp;amp;spn=10.0,10.0&amp;amp;q=55.95,-3.18333333333%20(Scotland)&amp;amp;t=h" target="_blank" rel="geolocation"&gt;Scotland&lt;/a&gt; needs them the most, Steve return…………&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/481490_3234527556141_1324023583_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image aligncenter" id="i-2305" alt="Image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/481490_3234527556141_1324023583_n.jpg?w=487" width="600" height="324"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Born of &lt;a class="zem_slink" title="Roller derby" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roller_derby" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia"&gt;Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; legend Team Steve rise again! This &lt;a class="zem_slink" title="Mothering Sunday" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mothering_Sunday" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia"&gt;Mothering Sunday&lt;/a&gt; they do battle against the mighty all Irish Gael Force exhibition team.
&lt;p&gt;But who are the elusive Team Steve and what are they all about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Steve was founded by Scottish Derby skaters who tried out for the word cup and made it to the top 30 but didn't get selected to play for &lt;a class="zem_slink" title="Team Scotland Roller Derby" href="http://teamscotlandrollerderby.com/" target="_blank" rel="homepage"&gt;Team Scotland&lt;/a&gt;. Originally there were 10 and 4 more were invited to play in their first bout against Team Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Steve is essentially a for the skaters by the skaters team. You must be selected and invited to play, there may be a number of skaters put forward but essentially a vote will decide who makes the team should a space become available. You have to be Scottish to be on the team; although not an official National body we are still a nationally based team. The girls who skate on Steve represent a variety of leagues across Scotland coming together for the love of the sport and of course a good time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gael Force is an Irish equivalent of Team Steve, you have to be Irish to play but those keen eyes may recognize a couple of our own homegrown players with Irish lineage. Chemikill Hazzard and Lilo and Stitches will be bouting with Gael force as well as a couple of &lt;a class="zem_slink" title="Gotham Girls" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gotham_Girls" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia"&gt;Gotham girls&lt;/a&gt; to boot. Their line up is undoubtedly impressive and this bout promises to be a proverbial clash of the titans.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/gael-force.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image aligncenter" id="i-2309" alt="Image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/gael-force.jpg?w=487" width="292" height="350"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 The bout will be held @ The Futsal Arena in &lt;a class="zem_slink" title="Birmingham" href="http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=52.4830555556,-1.89361111111&amp;amp;spn=0.1,0.1&amp;amp;q=52.4830555556,-1.89361111111%20(Birmingham)&amp;amp;t=h" target="_blank" rel="geolocation"&gt;Birmingham&lt;/a&gt; this Sunday. Gael Force are holding a series of boot camps down there this weekend (check their event page on &lt;a class="zem_slink" title="Facebook" href="http://facebook.com" target="_blank" rel="homepage"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; for tickets) and rounding off with the Team Steve bout. If you have the chance to get down to Birmingham this promises to be a bout that will not disappoint and a chance to see some of the best skaters in Scotland and &lt;a class="zem_slink" title="Ireland" href="http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=53.3333333333,-8.0&amp;amp;spn=10.0,10.0&amp;amp;q=53.3333333333,-8.0%20(Ireland)&amp;amp;t=h" target="_blank" rel="geolocation"&gt;Ireland&lt;/a&gt; compete for the love of the game.
&lt;p&gt;http://www.facebook.com/events/204490849693423/ (&lt;a class="zem_slink" title="Gael Force" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gael_Force" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia"&gt;GAEL FORCE&lt;/a&gt; VS. STEVE)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve is a team for the people; starting out as the underdogs they have made a name for themselves as a fun-loving and skillful team who always give their competitors a cheeky run for their money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; WE BELIEVE IN STEVE!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/steve.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image aligncenter" id="i-2315" alt="Image" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/steve.jpg?w=470" width="470" height="353"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>in the news</category><category>team scotland</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/08/do-you-believe/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 17:19:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lets hear it for the boys!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/08/lets-hear-it-for-the-boys/</link><dc:creator>thejammingpony</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A female perspective on Merby and CO-ED Roller Derby.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until the past couple of years Roller Derby has been a sport ‘rolled’ out on a predominantly female playing field. There have always been men around, be it in an official capacity or those of the infamous derby widow - ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However those who wished to play on a competitive level have taken the proverbial bull by the horns with Merby leagues are popping up all over the UK. Scotland in Particular has no less than 4 up and coming all male leagues. Their collective bouting team the Jakey Bites have been established for over a year now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arrival of Men’s Roller Derby has been met with mixed reaction on roller derby scene, some embracing it fully and others feeling a little put out that the male specimen are perhaps trying to steal our feminine thunder………God can’t they let us have anything!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being part of a league who have taken to Integrating with open arms, I have had a fantastic opportunity to skate and compete with the some of the Jakey Bites in the past year, skating in the Uk’s first ever CO-ED derby bout with The Jakey Tayzers last September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result I have become a keen supporter for CO-ED and men’s roller derby. The thought of this might seem a bit overwhelming for some but I believe it can make you a more rounded and skilled skater in the long run. I have skated for 2 years now, predominantly in all female training and bout situations and I thought I would take this opportunity to answer some of the questions or allay some of the fears people might have about Male and Co-Ed roller derby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;DO THEY HIT HARDER?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate to emasculate anyone here but the answer to this is not really. I have found that taking a hit from a guy is no different from being hit by the girls. The fact that they don’t really have hips takes a bit of getting used to but the impact of the hit isn't as scary as it might seem.  Put it this way, if you have ever been hit by Cider from Auld Reekie then you have nothing to worry about and are fully prepared…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;ARE THEIR TACTICS DIFFERENT?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever we first started training for the CO – ED bout this was definitely one of our questions, in all honesty we thought for some reason they were going to be all offence and no discipline (not sure why, guess we were stereotyping). This wasn't the case at all; for the most part their tactics are exactly the same as what we are doing on the female side of things. They are definitely very skilled and know their stuff; I didn't find it any different from skating with my female team mates. They have had to adjust to the new rule set exactly the same as we have. From watching various Merby bouts last year there really wasn't much difference in the tactics played and there certainly wasn't any less glitter surprisingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;IS IT AWKWARD?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we all know, roller derby can be a very 'handsy' sport, it is full contact and I suppose it would be normal to wonder if it gets a bit awkward when playing CO-ED. This one is really in the eyes of the beholder to be honest, I personally haven’t ever felt awkward or anything likes that whilst skating. Whether that comes from knowing them quite well or from being in the zone on track I’m not sure but it certainly has never been an issue. You know the bond you have with your team mates on track, well that bond is completely possible in CO-ED as well and it is a pretty gratifying experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;ARE THEY BETTER THAN US?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer to this hangs on the word better; it’s not so much a case of better as different. Roller derby caters for differences; it’s one of the most appealing aspects of the sport which is known for celebrating individuality. In some cases they may be a little stronger and taller than us but……being a big player or a hard hitter isn't the be all and end all if you are smaller and faster. In truth they are as varied and unique as we are on the female side of things. Tall, small, fast, strong, hard-hitting, positional and/or agile everyone has strength it's just finding out how they compliment each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;ARE THEY JUST A BUNCH OF “LADS?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cracking dirty jokes and messing around? As for the dirty jokes I know some female skaters who could make them blush……….But in all seriousness the answer here is no. They are 100% dedicated to the sport and the progression of their regional leagues, the passion they have for the sport is no less than we have in the female leagues and the drive they have shown in starting from scratch has been nothing short of impressive. As a female skater they have always been nothing less than welcoming and supportive of me and since skating with them I have seen a real improvement in certain areas of my skating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a personal perspective I am fully in support of Merby in the UK. I would urge everyone to support their local Merby league alongside their local derby league, Capital City in Edinburgh, Mean City in Glasgow, The Skelpies in the Central Belt and The Tayminators in Tayside. I have had the pleasure of knowing people from most of these teams and can tell you they are a cracking bunch of guys, we should be proud to have them as a part of the Scottish Roller Derby scene. I hope to see a lot more CO-ED action in the future with my Jakey Tayzers. The Skelpies League, Bairn City are already establishing a Co -Ed league so it is onward and upward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to make up your own mind or have a male friend you’d like to wrangle into taking up the sport, the Jakey Bites (Comprising of members from 3 out of 4 of the aforementioned teams) have a bout coming up against The South Wales Silures on April the 6&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; in Grangemouth. Check their Facebook page for event details and ticket sales. The venue only holds 100 so buy in advance to avoid disappointment. Bairn City men’s team will also be playing South Wales the day after on the 7&lt;sup&gt;th &lt;/sup&gt;at the same venue, for more details and ticket sales check their Facebook pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.facebook.com/events/122071404642449/      (SKELPIES VS. SILURES)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.facebook.com/events/432929060108875/     (JAKEYS VS. SILURES)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a title="Jakeys VS. Silures" href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/522492_342652352503139_928642489_n.png"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-2291 aligncenter" alt="522492_342652352503139_928642489_n" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/522492_342652352503139_928642489_n.png" width="506" height="567"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/10889_619537551396047_724006372_n.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-2292 aligncenter" alt="10889_619537551396047_724006372_n" src="http://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2013/03/10889_619537551396047_724006372_n.jpg?w=211" width="506" height="567"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>capital city roller derby</category><category>co-ed roller derby</category><category>image</category><category>mean city roller derby</category><category>men's roller derby</category><category>merby</category><category>roller derby</category><category>the jakey bites</category><category>the skelpies</category><category>the tayminators</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2013/03/08/lets-hear-it-for-the-boys/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 16:57:25 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>