<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scottish Roller Derby Blog (Posts by wearethedrd)</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/authors/wearethedrd.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:scottishrollerderby@gmail.com"&gt;SRD&lt;/a&gt; 
 &lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/"&gt;
 &lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-NC-SA"
 style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
 src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 11:56:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Dundee's call for skaters in double header event!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/16/dundees-call-for-skaters-in-double-header-event/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dundee is hosting a double header on the &lt;strong&gt;25th August &lt;/strong&gt;at the &lt;strong&gt;DISC in Dundee&lt;/strong&gt; with tickets sold on the door for &lt;strong&gt;£6!&lt;/strong&gt; There will also be a donation table for Dundee's local &lt;em&gt;WRASAC&lt;/em&gt;, looking for wellness packages donations and home goodies, as listed on their &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/191754218184900/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-27218 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/fbimage-01.png?w=212" alt="FBImage-01" width="262" height="371"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open at &lt;strong&gt;12:3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0, &lt;/strong&gt;with the Bonnie Colliders taking on&lt;strong&gt; Mean City&lt;/strong&gt; first and the Silvery Tayzers taking on a mixed side of skaters from across the land!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to an unfortunate drop out of a previous opponent. The Silvery Tayzers have switched up the second game to a mixed side open to opt ins! DRD are still on the look out for skaters to play in this game, starting at &lt;strong&gt;3pm. &lt;/strong&gt;It is open to: WFTDA gender policy, ideally advanced, skaters and Dundee are offering hosting, if that is needed. If you would like to opt in for the game, all you need to do is email &lt;strong&gt;DundeeRollerDerby@gmail.com&lt;/strong&gt; with your details! The deadline for opt in to play is &lt;strong&gt;22/08&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/2018.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the run up to these fantastic games, we had a wee catch up with both Mean City and The Bonnie Colliders to see how the sides are shaping up!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;"Throughout our sessions we have remained focused on our skills and gameplay while having the best time with our fellow meanies. We look forward to the challenge, the team building and most importantly, skating on track with the Bonnie Colliders."&lt;strong&gt; - Megatron&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Mean City)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;"The Colliders are buzzed to be playing on their home turf! We have a strong team and have outlined strong focuses for each skater. New tactics for ourselves and new players coming into our team have us really excited for this game. Especially since we haven't had the chance to play the wonderful meanies yet!" &lt;strong&gt;- Tiny Tearaway&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Bonnie Colliders)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-27230" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/39127098_1349993311803752_1458506761269936128_n.jpg?w=300" alt="Mean City" width="300" height="200"&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;"..We are super excited in anticipation of our bout with the Bonnie Colliders on the 25th August.  It is sure to be an exciting game that is both challenging and exceptionally rewarding.  As a league we are keen to show everyone a good time while playing our beloved sport with some amazing skaters." - &lt;strong&gt;Magatron&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Mean City)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-27231 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/08/32915322_1821085297956877_529342680438669312_n.jpg?w=300" alt="32915322_1821085297956877_529342680438669312_n" width="300" height="225"&gt;"Playing with other local leagues is such a rewarding challenge, we've all seen each other play in open scrims and each others' games, and its really fun to have us all come together! The Colliders work hard as a team, and as part of the DRD. We all grow together, work together and have fun together! We can't wait to get on track!" - &lt;strong&gt;Tiny Tearaway&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Bonnie Colliders)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/191754218184900/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
Where: D.I.S.C.
When: Doors open 12:30&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>mean city</category><category>silvery tayzers</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/08/16/dundees-call-for-skaters-in-double-header-event/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 08:00:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Granite City host Double Header</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/24/granite-city-host-double-header/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A double header to hit Granite City on the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28th of July&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;! The &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beach leisure centre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; of &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aberdeen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is home to Granite City Roller Derby's &lt;strong&gt;Fight Hawks&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Northern Fights&lt;/strong&gt;; both taking on tricky opponents in this derby day duo! &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doors open at 12:30&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; with the first whistle at 1pm, entry on the door for&lt;strong&gt; £4 (under 12's go free!).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-27076" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/36548337_10157716666129012_6781758626013904896_o.jpg" alt="Granite City Roller Derby" width="2048" height="1153"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start off the day it's the battle of the B teams, with the &lt;em&gt;Fight Hawks&lt;/em&gt; taking on Dundee Roller Derby's &lt;em&gt;Bonnie Colliders&lt;/em&gt;! We caught up with the captains to see how they are preparing for the weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-27075 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/37395447_1902795173120396_2721404236385484800_n-e1532295713922.jpg?w=200" alt="Image courtesy: Len Rizzo" width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fight&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Hawks Captain&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Skeevy Wonder #64&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How long skating:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;4 and a half years apparently! Time flies.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How long captaining team:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;About 8 months&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the season been for your team so far?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We're only really just kicking into gear, but it's been great figuring out our team's strengths and helping build the confidence of our newer skaters. We had a great time in Portugal, where we may not have come back with any gold medals, but we came back with heaps of goals and ideas.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have you been preparing for the upcoming game:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Following on from those pointers from our tournament in Coimbra, we've been drilling our weaknesses and honing our strengths. Practice, practice, practice!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you find playing teams within Scotland, does it change your game prep playing such a geographically close league?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;As a team, the Hawks have played teams all over Scotland, a few in England, and even teams from Spain and Portugal. We haven't played the Colliders in a long time, but being closer to Dundee and knowing more of their skaters and their styles and preferences, we have a better idea of what kind of game we are going in to. As far as I'm concerned about geographical closeness, it means I can have a proper breakfast that's not from a service station and a bit of a lie in! Boost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything in particular you say to your team to get prepped for the game? Any words of wisdom?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;As a B team, we're here to learn constantly, and get as much from every game as possible. That doesn't mean we're not competitive however, it just means win or lose we're taking away valuable experiences.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonnie Colliders Captains&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; ALLY-J &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;#92 &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;amp; Tiny Tearaway #931&lt;img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-27090" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/37711946_10156238091771068_2068850209923792896_n.jpg?w=141" alt="37711946_10156238091771068_2068850209923792896_n" width="141" height="300"&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Long Skating:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; 3 years, 6 years respectively.
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long Captaining Team&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; our first year!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the season been for your team so far?:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; It’s been a really good start, our focus skating as a team has been awesome! We constantly strive to do our very best, even if we lose a game we can still be really proud of each others performance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How have you been preparing for the upcoming game?:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; We've been pushing ourselves a lot at training. Working alongside the Tayzers to increase our knowledge of the game and to build our skills. &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you find playing teams within Scotland, does it change your game prep playing such a geographically close league?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We've played further afield against Copenhagen which was many of the Colliders' first game outside Scotland. Playing teams closer to home is just as exciting. Seeing the talent that Scotland has is incredible and being able to play alongside these people makes it all worth it. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything in particular you say to your team to get the prepped for the game? Any words of wisdom?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Don’t let the other team get into our heads! That every single person has an amazing set of skills to use, and not to forget it!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this B-team-bust-up Granite's A team &lt;em&gt;The Northern Fights&lt;/em&gt; will be taking on &lt;em&gt;Vagine Regime UK, &lt;/em&gt;a team formed by a fully inclusive community of LGBTQIA+ individuals and their supporters across the UK. We put a few questions to each of the captains to understand the teams individual run ups to games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-27098" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/37753945_1909703029096277_5673277440076546048_n.jpg?w=300" alt="Image Courtesy: Len Rizzo" width="300" height="199"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Northern Fights Captain:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Lizzee Rascal #314&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How Long Captaining?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;First year
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Long Skating?: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;5 Years&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the season been for your team so far?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;This season has been great so far. We had quite a change in the team at the beginning of the year and sadly said goodbye to old friends and welcomed some new ones. We have been focusing on British Champs, where we've been competing in Tier 3 North. It has been a fantastic challenge for us and has really pushed us to train hard. We have finished second in our tier and I couldn’t be prouder of the Fights.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have you been preparing for the upcoming game?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We've been focusing on developing and building as a team for champs throughout 2018. The upcoming game, being an exhibition game, will be a refreshing change from this, with a lot of the pressure of champs being taken off. We have still been training hard and want to bring our best game at the weekend.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you find playing teams such as VR? Does it change your strategy or prep at all?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Playing against VR is a different experience for us, as they bring a pool of talent from across the UK and will perhaps use tactics that we haven’t been up against before which will make for a challenging yet fun game.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vagine Regime captain:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Kami-Tazzy #360&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-27096 alignright" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/07/37825317_1875280102519140_1499359558181584896_n.jpg?w=200" alt="Image Courtesy: Nick" width="200" height="300"&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How Long Skating:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; 7. 5 years&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How long Captaining:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;First time for VR.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the season been for your team so far, do rosters change a lot?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It's been great so far. Back in April we had a tough but close game with the Rainy City C team, a great game to kick off the season with. We're really looking forward to playing Granite's awesome Northern Fights. VR UK contain a very large number of members, of all levels, from all over the UK, including some of the best players the UK can offer. Because of that, rosters are always changing, but it mainly depends on location, bout clashes, level and availability.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you prepare your skaters for upcoming games?:&lt;/strong&gt; S&lt;em&gt;ince skaters are generally from different leagues/teams it's difficult to prepare physically. Therefore communication and trust is key here. We'll have discussions on positions, and other strengths that everyone can bring. This will help the captains, LUM and Bench to come up with line up plans and strategies to fully challenge our opponents. It's certainly a bonus to have skaters on the team that have played together before, but things still may get shuffled around on the day to maximise our full potential.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;How do you find putting together a mixed team to play established leagues, is there anything in particular you look for in skaters?:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Depending on availability, we try to put together a strong as possible team to challenge our competitors to the max. We try to get the right mix of skaters of every position. However this is not possible at all times, we have had jammer heavy rosters in the past or vice versa. This is not really a problem, as a lot of the players are very adaptable and give it thier absolute all. We may be a challenge team but we're still a competitive team who like to rise to the challenge and aim to triumph in every game that we play.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align:right;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything in particular you say to your team to get them prepped for the game? Any words of wisdom?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I ask them to bring all their focus, good sportsmanship and determination on and off the track. Additionally teamwork, integrity and to set individual as well as team goals. This sport is brilliant but it can also be mentally tough at times. One main advice I give to a lot of people is that if things don't go as planned in a jam, I encourage them to put it behind them, store it away if needed, reset and focus on the next jam. Also most importantly enjoy yourselves and embrace all the achievements, no matter how small or big they are.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;Event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/235019877294396/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;
Date: 28/07/2018
Price: £4 on the door&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was co-written by Dundee's correspondent G. Patterson and Granite's Correspondent C. Meikle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>2018 season</category><category>a chat with...</category><category>aberdeen</category><category>articles</category><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>granite city roller derby</category><category>up coming games</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><category>vagine regime uk</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/07/24/granite-city-host-double-header/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:45:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Heads to Paris!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/28/dundee-heads-to-paris/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend (30th June) &lt;strong&gt;Dundee Roller Derby&lt;/strong&gt; are heading out for their first international tournament!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26923" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/35026408_1880109745361514_2182274897437261824_o.jpg" alt="35026408_1880109745361514_2182274897437261824_o" width="1055" height="559"&gt; Artwork by Lila Poppins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paris is Burning!&lt;/em&gt; is hitting the streets of France's capital as hosts &lt;a href="http://www.laboucheriedeparis.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;La Boucherie de Paris Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt; invite three WFTDA teams to compete in sanctioned games across the weekend. [&lt;a href="https://wftda.com/rankings-may-31-2018/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;WFTDA Rankings May 2018&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Boucherie de Paris (aka Les Quads de Paris)[276]
GO-GO Gent Roller Derby[287]
London Rockin' Rollers[279]
Dundee Roller Derby[225]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dundee side are looking strong, coming off their 373 to 144 win against Glasgow Roller Derby last month[&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/101336" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;], with the Rockin' Rollers coming in at 267 to 132 against the Glasgow side earlier this month in Tier 1 British Championships[&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/99761" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;]. GO-GO Gent will be looking for a close rematch having played the Rockin' Rollers in tournament earlier this year; narrowly missing the win with 201 to 155 in favour of the Rollers[&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/100250" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;]. With both Dundee and the Parisian team having not played the tournament attendees previously, it looks like a fantastic weekend of derby is upon us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-26936 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/feminist-killjoy-peter-troest.jpg?w=300" alt="Feminist Killjoy - @ Peter Troest" width="244" height="244"&gt; Feminist Killjoy - Image courtesy Peter Troest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representing Dundee Roller Derby, as well as &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ResistanceRDG/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Resistance Roller Derby&lt;/a&gt;, Feminist Killjoy will also be attending to referee hot off the heels of their involvement in the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/297187537481887/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;WFTDA Recognised Officiating Clinic in Marburg&lt;/a&gt;, hosted by Roller Derby Marburg!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-26935 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/06/headshots.png" alt="headshots" width="425" height="370"&gt; The Silvery Tayzers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dundee are taking their 15 skater strong Silvery Tayzer roster to the city of Paris in the hopes of making a name for themselves in the European derby scene. Previously DRD have played in Copenhagen, celebrating Copenhagen Roller Derby's 5th birthday in a DRD v CRD double header[&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/96660"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;]. The Parisian tournament is an excited step forward for the Dundee side in opening game avenues for WFTDA sanctions for their recent full WFTDA membership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event Page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/203472333711192/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>events</category><category>go-go gent roller derby</category><category>la boucherie de paris</category><category>london rockin rollers</category><category>tournament</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/06/28/dundee-heads-to-paris/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 09:00:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee's Derby Rebrand!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/11/dundees-derby-rebrand/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dundee league previously known as DRG have re-branded to Dundee Roller Derby this month. Although league members have been hinting at this for a while, the financial and business aspects, have led to a longer than expected timeframe for this re-brand.
&lt;img class="  wp-image-26597 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/04/29884504_2031848993705292_1278327300_o.png" alt="Quote from DRD" width="410" height="410"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With it well underway however, we spoke to a few league members to understand what this means to them, obviously paired with a few snapshots of the league!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"For me, every single league member deserves to be part of our name, rather than only those that identify with the word "girls"."&lt;/em&gt; - Gegg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"I started roller derby at 36, I hadn't been a girl for a long time. Think this is brilliant and so much more inclusive".&lt;/em&gt; - Emma Belter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"It shows the progression and maturity of our league. We showed what we can do on track last year and made our name as a league by our games, now we are taking another step and showing our league for who we really are and what we believe in. Seeing everyone as an individual and including all as part of DRD"&lt;/em&gt;. - Goldginger&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"When we say: We Are The DRD at games, it really will mean "we" now!"&lt;/em&gt; - Nichola&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"The change of name represents the bigger changes that are happening in roller derby worldwide, and our name will now finally reflect every member of our league."&lt;/em&gt; - Liston&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"I personally identify as a girl, but it took me a long time to be okay with that, and I think it's really cool that people that don't are now part of the league not just in person but in name to!"&lt;/em&gt; - Amy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"The rebrand shows we are a league inclusive and transparent to everyone. Everyone is heard!"&lt;/em&gt; - Tiny Tearaway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It means to me that we can be fully inclusive of everyone, and convey that message on to this and the next generation as well that anyone can do Derby, you just have to believe in yourself!"&lt;/em&gt; - KinKhey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"This change signifies that we are not just skaters here. We are officials, volunteers, NSOs, friends and family. Dundee is an inclusive league of everyone; anyone wishing to be a member of our league can be and that is now represented in our name."&lt;/em&gt;- Shuggs Bunny&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="26605,26604,26602,26603,26598,26600,26599,26601" type="rectangular"]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller derby</category><category>rebranding</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/04/11/dundees-derby-rebrand/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 12:00:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2018 Seasons beginnings for DRG!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/28/2018-seasons-beginnings-for-drg/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a late start due to the very wonderful &lt;em&gt;Roller Derby World Cup&lt;/em&gt; earlier this year in Manchester (!), Dundee Roller Girls are hosting their Season Opener on &lt;strong&gt;15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of April 2018&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;D.I.S.C. in Dundee&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boasting an action packed day for both DRG's A and B team, doors open at &lt;strong&gt;12:30&lt;/strong&gt; with tickets on the day at &lt;strong&gt;£6.&lt;/strong&gt; You can look forward to &lt;em&gt;Fair City Rollers&lt;/em&gt;' Fear Maidens facing off against the Bonnie Colliders at 1pm, with &lt;em&gt;Auld Reekie Roller Girls&lt;/em&gt;' All Star Reserves taking the track against the Silvery Tayzers at 3pm!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a new season of games, come new captains! So we thought we would have a wee chat with both teams' captains to see how the season is shaping up. First up is ALLY-J and Tiny Tearaway captaining the Bonnie Colliders!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="26529,26530" type="circle" columns="2"]
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table style="width:100%;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Questions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;ALLY-J&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;Tiny Tearaway&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;931&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Position&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Jammer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Jammer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Derby Hero&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Hubs &amp;amp; Mayhem&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Lady Trample and Mayhem&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Motto&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Lets do dis"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Nothing is impossible, the word itself says "I'm possible""&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How long have you been skating?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I’ve been quad skating with DRG since March 2016, so 2 years now (time flies!) but used to inline skate from the age of 10!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I have been skating 6 years this coming May (scary) and I have been with DRG for 2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;What does this season hold for the Colliders?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We've had the opportunity of playing in Copenhagen, Newcastle and in our home town, and this season we're going to build as a whole Team! We totally found our feet working with each other, and we are looking at focusing on attendance, positivity and building our knowledge of the game!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Yes its going to be very exciting for the Colliders. We have some fantastic games lined up already and a strong team full of skaters determined to be the best.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;As a B team, what challenges to you face?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Finding our way of working together as a team. Fitting in our newest skaters and helping them gain lots more skills and understanding of the game.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We are all part of a very supportive league so the challenges I see aren’t limited to us as a team. We face the same challenges as the A team; attendance, working together well and pushing ourselves to the best of our abilities.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How does the league, as a whole, carve space for the B team?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;As a league, our A and B team train together, which is an amazing opportunity. We are constantly learning from each other, talking over drills and skills; with us skating alongside folk from Team Scotland, really being able to learn from the best is our greatest asset.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;B team, A team who? We're a league that trains together. Skaters for both teams, crossovers and new skaters. We all do the same drills and are expected to put the same amount of hard work and effort into every one from the newer skaters to those who were on Team Scotland.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;And if you could set goals for yourself and for the team this season?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;My personal goal is to work on my jammer skills and tactical knowledge. I want to work well for the team and push myself this season! For the Colliders: to focus on ourselves as a team. Although we are all building our personal skills, I really want everyone to bring positivity and sportsmanship to the Colliders.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Our B team has played and flourished with smaller numbers the past season. It would be great to see us play with higher numbers. This would give us the chance to have a solid jammer rotation and walls that are to be reckoned with. To be part of that jammer rotation is my goal for this season.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Second up is the captains of the Silvery Tayzers, Seaton and Bosies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="26532,26531" type="circle" columns="2"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table style="width:100%;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Questions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;Seaton&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:center;"&gt;Bosies&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;102&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;37&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Position&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Pivot/ Offence&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Blocker&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Derby Hero&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Serelson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;Kid Block&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;Motto&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Shitemare"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"SITFU"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How long have you been skating?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;6 years, started and stayed with DRG since then.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Skating for six years, initially with GCRD and have been with DRG for almost 2 years&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;What does this season hold for the Tayzers?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I'll probably cry and give dramatic speeches alot. Hoping that as a league we'll be able to continue to perform like we did last season but also move passed that, honing in our skill set. The Tayzers have always performed under a "get the job done, nae fancy shit" mentality and I want to continue that while progressing within the WFTDA rankings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;We are continuing to evolve the skills, tactics and endurance that we've developed last season. Which will set us in good stead for the exciting and tough games we have lined up for this year.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;As an A team skater, how do you stay ontop of your game&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I hydrate and then spew it up if I go too fast.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Pepsi Max, avocados and hummus. And cross training.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;How has becoming a WFTDA league changed your priorities and training?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;I think it gives us clear global equivalents to try to compete against, which we haven't really had before. It's good to be able to feel super involved with the development of the sport as a whole, as well as having access to more teams.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;It allows us to skate against teams of a similar calibre at national and international level, as well as competing in tournaments! This emphasises the need for a strong mental game, the ability to work as a tight unit and to continue to function when the fatigue sets in!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="text-align:right;"&gt;And if you could set a goal for yourself and your team?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;Finish a game without a spew or a cry, working on my mental game is a constant priority as well as my on track skills. As a team, I just want to end every game as a happy wee unit proud of what we have just done.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align:justify;"&gt;My personal goal is the same as it was when I first started skating, which is to get lower! As a team if we can continue to work together, support each other on and off track and leave each game with a sense of achievement, then that's a job well done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26534" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2018/03/fbimage-01-1.png" alt="FBImage-01 (1)" width="6035" height="8534"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15th April 2018&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; Dundee DISC&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/908750512641504/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Event Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; 12:30-5pm&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; £6 on the door&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>annoucements</category><category>articles</category><category>auld reekie roller girls</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>fair city rollers</category><category>interviews</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2018/03/28/2018-seasons-beginnings-for-drg/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 09:00:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee Sevens Extravaganza!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/27/dundee-sevens-extravaganza/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;October 21st&lt;/strong&gt;, Dundee Roller Girls will be showcasing all the charisma, uniqueness, nerve and talent roller derby has to offer by hosting their open to all: &lt;strong&gt;Sevens Extravaganza&lt;/strong&gt;!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-24432" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/save-the-date.png" alt="Save The Date" width="3100" height="1430"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Seven teams consisting of only seven skaters will battle against each other in 21 minute games of high intensity roller derby! All in the hopes of being crowned the most sickening team of all!!
&lt;p&gt;This is the first time that DRG are bringing the thrills of a sevens tournament to Dundee, with no timeouts, no official reviews and only 7 skaters per team! What more could you want from a day of derby? How about 7 awesome &lt;strong&gt;RuPaul's Drag Race&lt;/strong&gt; inspired team names with their very own catchphrases???
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Laganja Estranja&lt;/em&gt; – &lt;strong&gt;YES GAWD!
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Adore Delano&lt;/em&gt; –&lt;strong&gt; PARTY!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Team Shangela&lt;/em&gt; – &lt;strong&gt;HALLELOU!
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Alaska&lt;/em&gt; -&lt;strong&gt; HIIEEEEEE!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Bianca Del Rio&lt;/em&gt; –&lt;strong&gt; Not Today Satan
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Bob the Drag Queen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; – Purse Furst
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Jinkx Monsoon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; – Water off a Ducks Back&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-24507" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/filal-7.png" alt="Dundee Logos for Sevens" width="1536" height="1236"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DRG still have team applications open so don’t miss out! Apply here with your team of seven: &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdEzC2MrWUOW7SsJge19qlwrMAsFYKzOEuvuFXFflaLUzoFFw/viewform" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Application for Full Seven&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not quite got a full team of seven? Don't worry Dundee have thought of that as well and are now accepting single skater applicants to skate in a mixed side: &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdwK9wmfSPJ5DJCjT8a8hQqBhGlZYDLB9-rP-fTRLbPv-pZPQ/viewform?usp=sf_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Application for Single Skaters
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you think Dundee have left out the most on-the-nose team name you could think of: WELL THINK AGAIN! Team RuPaul has been left for the most important group of the whole day.... The Officials!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=" size-medium wp-image-24515 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/09/21744549_10155556403215821_1030918533_n.jpg?w=250" alt="Officials are the best aren't they??" width="250" height="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spectator tickets will also be available for your friends and family to come to this full day event at &lt;strong&gt;Dundee International Sports Complex (D.I.S.C)&lt;/strong&gt; on Mains Loan. There will be a chance to buy Dundee's Merch (including the limited edition coveted Tie Dye shirts!!), a classic bake sale for all your daily cake consumption needs as well as a handful of local business to be announced as vendors, across &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/dundeerollergirls/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;DRG's Social Media&lt;/a&gt; in the upcoming weeks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you come and stay? Or will you just Sashay Away?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;Doors are open at &lt;strong&gt;0930&lt;/strong&gt; with first whistle at &lt;strong&gt;10am&lt;/strong&gt;!!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color:#ff0000;"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:#000000;"&gt;Tickets on the door: &lt;strong&gt;£6
&lt;/strong&gt;Check out the event page for more details: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/119203058730604/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>derby sevens</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>tournament</category><category>tournaments</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/09/27/dundee-sevens-extravaganza/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 11:30:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Late 'n' Lite #5</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/08/24/late-n-lite-5/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girls' are hosting their fifth installment of their Late 'n' Lite Referee and NSO bootcamp! On the &lt;strong&gt;28th August &lt;/strong&gt;at &lt;strong&gt;7pm untill 10pm&lt;/strong&gt; all in the very lovely &lt;strong&gt;Manhattan Works &lt;/strong&gt;and all for only a &lt;strong&gt;fiver!
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-23661" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/08/20615708_1539342979464445_2470722261485695775_o.jpg" alt="Courtesy: Dundee Roller Girls" width="664" height="493"&gt; Late n Lite Attendees!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time they will be focusing on how officials, on or off skates, can work together as a team. Working on communication and how each individual contribute to the smooth (and safe!) running of the game. With the off skates session covering the ever popular position of Penalty Tracking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To round the night off DRG's officials will be inviting you to take these newly hones skills onto the track as the bootcamp officiates Dundee's very own skaters in a wee intraleague scrim!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One half of Dundee Roller Girls' Head of Officials, Tiny Tearaway, had this to say about the bootcamps. Catch her and the other DRG refs in teaching action on the 28th!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16027" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/courtesy-allyson-jf.png" alt="Courtesy Allyson JF" width="1077" height="1077"&gt; &lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iny Tearaway&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; - &lt;/strong&gt;"We really love being able to run these bootcamps, having our officiating pals over to Dundee and being able to not only host an off skates workshop, but also an on skates one, with the added scrim, is such a great experience. I'm really grateful to help set these up and be a part of it all."  &lt;/em&gt;(Image Courtesy: Allyson Jane-Foster)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/316028685524711/?acontext=%7B%22source%22%3A5%2C%22page_id_source%22%3A133126163419474%2C%22action_history%22%3A%5B%7B%22surface%22%3A%22page%22%2C%22mechanism%22%3A%22main_list%22%2C%22extra_data%22%3A%22%7B%5C%22page_id%5C%22%3A133126163419474%2C%5C%22tour_id%5C%22%3Anull%7D%22%7D%5D%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;August 28th&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;7pm - 10 pm
Manhattan Works, Dundee
£5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>late n' lite</category><category>officials bootcamp</category><category>referees</category><category>roller derby bootcamps</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/08/24/late-n-lite-5/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 19:13:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>DRG's Bonnie Colliders Battle Bairn!</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/18/drgs-bonnie-colliders-battle-bairn/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller girls' are hosting their second home game this season as a single header! On the &lt;strong&gt;22nd of July &lt;/strong&gt;at the &lt;strong&gt;D.I.S.C.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Dundee&lt;/strong&gt;, the Bonnie Colliders are taking on Bairn City (&amp;amp; pals!) which looks to be a mighty match! With doors opening at &lt;strong&gt;12:30 &lt;/strong&gt;and first whistle coming in at &lt;strong&gt;1pm,&lt;/strong&gt; it's gonna be a short and sweet single header. Differing from DRG's usual doubles hitters,  these two familiar sides will most certainly make the trip worth while!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-22412 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/07/19621172_1505774156154661_5391157900722134871_o.jpg" alt="Photo Courtesy: Laura MacDonald" width="520" height="736"&gt;
We thought we would catch up with the Bonnie Colliders Co Captains for 2017, &lt;strong&gt;Breezy Does It #289&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;HullabaLou #17&lt;/strong&gt;, to learn a bit more about leading and shaping a B team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids="22420,22421" type="circle" columns="2"]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q1: How has the season gone so far for you guys? You've have a few games already and you seem to come out strong both sides.
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breezy:  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;This season has been amazing so far, we've played those two games and won both, which is super exciting! The team is really starting to gel together and we are getting better every time we play. We've had a few newer skaters join us and they are coming on great and are fitting in well with the team.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HullabaLou: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's just been so epic this season, I am so so proud of everyone! To see our wee team taking the skills that we drill together every week at training and scrims, and put them into practice during games is fantastic – whether it’s fancy new toe stop spins, some super controlled one-one blocking or crushing offense; the commitment and effort from every person on the team is something that I respect hugely and do not take for granted as a Captain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q2: And so the Colliders have played a Bairn side a few times, with the most recent in 2015 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/71209" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;[FTS]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;. How does that change your look on this match-up?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I was off on maternity for all of 2015 so unfortunately wasn't part of the team on that one but I was there for the previous year and it was such a tough game! Bairn have continued to grow so much since then, really we're looking at them as a brand new opponent. Which for a lot of our Colliders this season - they will be!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The 2015 game&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; was one of the firsts for quite a few of us who had just been rostered for the B team, and was definitely quite an experience for us haha! Bairn are so lovely and we genuinely can’t wait to play them again, but will definitely be needing as many of our Collidoscopes (our loyal fans) to support us as possible!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q3: How do you guys approach a game when you are captaining, what goes through your mind?
&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;B:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I approach all games in a similar manner, nervous anticipation! The difference as a Co-Captain is that I like to check in with all the skaters to find out how they're feeling, as Lou and I want each skater to enjoy themselves and feel comfortable on game day. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ll we want as Captains is to ensure our team has an absolute blast on game day, I just want to help them smash their goals and whip out those hard-practiced skills! Colliders are definitely all about soaking up the sheer enjoyment of simply playing roller derby together! To quote our wonderful co-chair Milky “It’s just a made-up game on roller skates” and so I try to focus on that…we are from Fundee after all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q4: With the Silvery Tayzers (Dundee's A team) getting quite a lot of focus now with the league being full WFTDA members, do you feel that adds more pressure for you guys, or is it the opposite and you loose some track time as a B team?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DRG train as a league, first and foremost. We all skate together. We have skaters who've just passed their minimum skills alongside our Team Scotland skaters. It is a huge benefit to all our skaters as we work together to push each other on in every aspect. As a team, the Colliders do get lots of track time together to work as a unit, and practice our tactics and skills, but training alongside the Silvery Tayzers really pushes us out of our comfort zones and helps us develop further. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DRG definitely think of ourselves as a league rather than 2 teams – we train together, scrim together and thoroughly support each other; the success of the Tayzers and their sweeeeet wftda ranking (266th!)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/rankings" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;[16/07/2017 FTS]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; has only boosted our league spirit. And likewise when the Colliders smash it, the mad support from the rest of the league is just unparalleled. Personally, that’s one of the things I love most about DRG: Our wonderful bouting committee have always placed an equal importance on getting games for both Colliders and Tayzers….so short answer – no, we never lose track time!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Q5: With that in mind, what do you guys aim for, for yourselves and your team? It must be hard to maintain such a close-knit team, with skaters moving on to the A team or with the new intake coming up.
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; My aim is to work alongside all of our current skaters and those moving up from the new skater programme to encourage them to practice in the hopes that our team can grow stronger. As for keeping the team close knit, I think that comes from our training atmosphere. Lou and I are very open in terms of communication and encourage skaters to bring any issues to us in the hopes that everyone feels driven but not pushed, as being a Collider is always about having the best experience possible and taking away as much as you can from both training, scrimmage and game days!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I think that as a team we definitely drive ourselves forward and regardless of experience-level our training committee has always worked us hard to constantly improve our play. Being a B team, the roster is a lot more dynamic; newer skaters come up, more experienced skaters move to the A team, and it changes a lot. We do actively focus on learning how each other blocks/jams so can we gel on track but because we all train together, even when a skater does reach a certain level experience and makes that tough decision to bout exclusively with the A team, it doesn’t really feel like we’ve lost them because we'll be drilling/scrimming with them the week after anyways. Saying that we did have a very emotional locker-room-team-cry after a speech from last season’s stepping down Captains… but I think that just goes to show how much we bond as a team…or perhaps how emotionally unstable a bunch of us are…possibly both.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out more about the upcoming game (&lt;strong&gt;Saturday 22nd July&lt;/strong&gt;) Check out the facebook event page here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/146108915947622/?acontext=%7B%22source%22%3A5%2C%22page_id_source%22%3A133126163419474%2C%22action_history%22%3A%5B%7B%22surface%22%3A%22page%22%2C%22mechanism%22%3A%22main_list%22%2C%22extra_data%22%3A%22%7B%5C%22page_id%5C%22%3A133126163419474%2C%5C%22tour_id%5C%22%3Anull%7D%22%7D%5D%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Colliders vs Bairn and pals!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doors open: &lt;strong&gt;12:30
&lt;/strong&gt;Tickets: &lt;strong&gt;£5 (on the door)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>a chat with...</category><category>articles</category><category>bairn city rollers</category><category>bonnie colliders</category><category>captains</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/07/18/drgs-bonnie-colliders-battle-bairn/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 08:30:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee's Beginner Bootcamp Bonanza</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/16/dundees-beginner-bootcamp-bonanza/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-20568" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/bootcamp-banner-blog.png" alt="Skate Tay Victory!" width="727" height="315"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dundee Roller Girls are hosting their first ever bootcamp on the &lt;strong&gt;first of July&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;Manhattan Works, Dundee! &lt;/strong&gt;Open to all, this bootcamp is welcoming pre mins skaters as well as recently passed individuals looking to cement their derby skillz! This event boasts four hours (&lt;strong&gt;11am - 3pm) &lt;/strong&gt;of minimal contact training, with on skates tickets selling out on day 1 - &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;spectator tickets are left for a mere £10 a head!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breaking the day down into sections: the five DRG coaches are Goldginger #77, G-Wrecks #713, Hubs #88, Landsborough #792 and Liston #07! Attendees can look forward to the following lessons:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;♥ Wall work with Hubs and G-Wrecks! ♥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter  wp-image-20812" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/walls.png?w=300" alt="walls" width="446" height="336"&gt; &lt;em&gt;"We can't wait to get started on our block for the bootcamp! Sharing skating skills with newer skaters and encouraging everyone, no matter their skating levels, to engage with the core skills needed to further roller derby in Scotland is something we both really want to be a part of! It's really the best way to start the summer!!"&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;♥ Jammer work with Landborough and Goldginger ♥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter wp-image-20811" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/jammers.png" alt="jammers" width="437" height="336"&gt; &lt;em&gt;"Our league has really benefited from specific jammer drills and discussions on how to approach the Star. Being able to share our experiences not only on a skills level but also a coaching level is a really exciting prospect! We'll work you hard but it'll be worth it!"&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;♥ Footwork with Liston ♥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-16584" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/03/laura-liston.png" alt="Laura Liston" width="271" height="355"&gt; &lt;em&gt;"The building blocks for good wall work always starts with footwork! Lateral movement, recaptures and even jammer work relies on skaters having a strong base of footwork! I'm hoping to break down some of the more daunting skills for skaters to work on before bringing them into the wall! If you're stronger as one, you're stronger together."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to on skates tickets selling out on the first day, the DRG have added extra off skates spectator tickets to allow more to attend! Spectators will be welcomed in discussions of skills and drills throughout the day, to ask questions to any of the coaches as well as take notes, pictures and videos. As this bootcamp is aimed at post/pre mins, the coaches are hoping that skaters will take their newly polished skills back to their leagues to extend the learning process around Scotland (and further afield!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information please visit the event page: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1852866768310688/?ref=br_rs" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
Link for off skates tickets (£10) can be found: &lt;a href="http://www.brownpapertickets.com/event/2932707" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>coaching</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>roller derby bootcamp</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/16/dundees-beginner-bootcamp-bonanza/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 09:00:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dundee's Double Header Doozy</title><link>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/02/dundees-double-header-doozy/</link><dc:creator>wearethedrd</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dundee Roller Girls are hosting their first double header of the season on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17th of June&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DISC in Dundee! &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-19815 alignleft" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/front-cover-flyer-2017.jpg" alt="front cover flyer 2017" width="266" height="376"&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt; DRG's&lt;em&gt; Silvery Tayzers&lt;/em&gt; will be building on their win from last months Seaside Sirens game &lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/91484" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;[FTS]&lt;/a&gt; by taking on Leicestershire's &lt;em&gt;Dolly Rockit Rollers&lt;/em&gt;!
&lt;p&gt;As always with Dundee double headers, DRG's B team, the &lt;em&gt;Bonnie Colliders,&lt;/em&gt; will be taking to the track first to face off against the Scarborough Slammers! After a strong season opener against Arcadia Roller Derby [&lt;a href="http://flattrackstats.com/bouts/89734/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;FTS&lt;/a&gt;], as part of &lt;em&gt;Shepsk8: For Pulmonary Fibrosis,&lt;/em&gt; the Colliders will be looking to stand out in their first home game this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two roller derby games will be alongside the usual merch and vendors stalls, including businesses from the local community. As well as the forever popular Cake Stall, boasting sweet and savoury choices! DRG are hoping to run a few hook-a-duck games and a tombola!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="  wp-image-19806 aligncenter" src="https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/2017/06/18402053_10100849149297024_2173969429062502634_o.jpg" alt="Bonnie Colliders at Shepsk8 - Laura MacDonald" width="383" height="255"&gt; Image Courtesy: Laura MacDonald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tickets are on sale now over at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://m.bpt.me/event/2957826" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;BrownPaperTickets&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;for&lt;strong&gt; £5&lt;/strong&gt; with tickets on the door for &lt;strong&gt;£6&lt;/strong&gt; for DRG's first home game double header on &lt;strong&gt;17th June!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doors open   : 12:30&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; First Whistle: 13:00&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the event page for more details: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1448002145256378/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;facebook event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>articles</category><category>double header</category><category>dundee</category><category>dundee roller girls</category><category>home game</category><category>upcoming bouts</category><guid>https://www.scottishrollerderbyblog.com/posts/2017/06/02/dundees-double-header-doozy/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 09:00:28 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>